<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890213-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-13-89 2345EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ChildAbuse     02-13 0176</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Child Abuse,0181</SECOND>
<HEAD>Malnourished And Badly Battered Child Found On Subway; Parents Charged</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A couple who reported their 7-year-old son missing were charged Monday with child abuse after the bruised and malnourished boy was found on a subway car with cigarette burns and black eyes, police said. <PERSON> Rene </PERSON> <PERSON> Samacarit </PERSON>, 28, and <PERSON> Zorida </PERSON> <PERSON> Maldonado </PERSON>, 31, of <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> were charged with second-degree assault and endangering the welfare of a minor, said police spokesman Sgt. <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Donnell </PERSON>. The couple reported the boy missing at 2:30 p.m. Less than half an hour later, <ORGANIZATION> Transit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> found the malnourished and beaten child on a subway in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>, <PERSON> O'Donnell </PERSON> said. The boy, who had run away from home, was taken to <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vincent </LOCATION><LOCATION> 's </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> with multiple injuries, including cigarette burns, bruises, black eyes, a throat infection and malnutrition, <PERSON> O'Donnell </PERSON> said His parents identified him at the hospital and were charged following an investigation, <PERSON> O'Donnell </PERSON> said. The boy's 3-year-old sister has been turned over to the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Child </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Welfare </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> O'Donnell </PERSON> said. The children's names were not released.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890213-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-13-89 0001EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LesbianGuardianship     02-13 0780</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lesbian Guardianship,0802</SECOND>
<HEAD>No End In Sight For Ugly Guardianship Battle Between Parents And
Lesbian</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TONY KENNEDY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NASHWAUK, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON> retired from the backbreaking life of a miner on <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>'s Iron Range, he looked forward to years of peace and leisure. Instead, the 58-year-old <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Della </PERSON>, are spending their golden years at war with a lesbian professor over who should care for their severely brain-damaged daughter, <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON>. The professor, <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, says she deserves to be Ms. <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON>'s caretaker because the two secretly considered themselves married before Ms. <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON> was paralyzed in a 1983 automobile crash caused by a drunken driver. <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON> and his wife say the claim is bogus. They insist <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>'s interest in their daughter centers on money <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> has generated by publicizing the case in speeches across the country and a book. `` I hate her with a passion,'' <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON> said from his home in rural <LOCATION> Nashwauk </LOCATION> in northeastern <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>. `` I ca n't picture an end to this.'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> says the money is intended to help Ms. <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON>, and she questions her parents' motives. `` They would rather she be a vegetable than a lesbian,'' she said. `` Until Sharon's rights are protected, I will fight this.'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, who has become a national spokeswoman for gay and lesbian rights, has helped establish two funds for her friend and organized rallies in 21 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cities in August to observe `` Free Sharon Kowalski Day.'' According to court records, the two women had lived together for four years. Ms. <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON>, 32, who was a high school physical education teacher, had named <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, 41, as the beneficiary of her $ 50,000 life insurance policy before the accident. The courts have acknowledged the relationship but have kept <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON> as his daughter's guardian, giving him power to make decisions for her and initially allowing him to deny <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> visiting privileges. But in December, a judge ordered a re-evaluation of Ms. <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON> to determine how soundly she thinks and whether she is capable of making decisions about her own care. Ms. <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON>, who is in a nursing home near <LOCATION> Nashwauk </LOCATION>, has lost the use of her limbs and is unable to speak but can use the fingers of her right hand and communicates by typing, shaking her head and using an alphabet board. Under the judge's new order, anyone is allowed to see her if she `` reliably requested'' to see them. Ms. <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said she was granted supervised visits because Ms. <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON> asked to see her in interviews with a psychiatrist. A week ago, the two visited over four days for the first time in 3 -LCB- years. `` I think <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> is soon going to let everyone know that she can control her own future,'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said from Ms. <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON>'s bedside. `` She smiles and she chuckles and she has responded so well. She's been happy to see me. After the re-evaluation, the judge could go as far as declaring Ms. <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON> competent to handle her own affairs, but her parents say such a finding would be impossible. They say <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> has exaggerated Ms. <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON>'s mental abilities and her chances for rehabilitation. `` We're never going to have the real <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON> back,'' said her mother. `` You might get a good response from <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> one day and the next day _ nothing. It would take a miracle to see her recover.'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, who teaches physical education at St. <ORGANIZATION> Cloud </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, said Ms. <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON> wants to go home with her to St. Cloud; the Kowalskis say their daughter has never expressed that desire to them. <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said she could provide better care for Ms. <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON> because she has more talent and education than her parents. `` I made a lifetime commitment to <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON>, and I want to honor that,'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said. Ms. <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON>'s doctor, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, opposes moving her from the nursing home. He said home care would be out of the question because <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> is not certified to care for someone as severely disabled as Ms. <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON>. Meanwhile, <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> admits she has started other relationships. `` I have found that there are several people in the world that I can have relationships with,'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said. `` But I do n't know if I can fall deeply in love with another person like I did with <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON> and <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> say they are likely to be battling each other as long as Ms. <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON> is judged incapable of handling her own affairs. `` If this keeps up I probably do n't have much time left,'' said <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON>, who has suffered two heart attacks in the past year that he attributes to the stress. `` My heart can only take so much.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890213-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-13-89 0001EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Italy-Drought     02-13 0201</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Italy-Drought,0206</SECOND>
<HEAD>Italians Pray for Rain In Drought-Stricken Areas</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thousands of people prayed for rain in northern Italian churches and some parched communities planned religious processions, hoping to bring an end to one of the worst droughts in years. At 1,300 Roman Catholic churches in the diocese of <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION> on Sunday, priests invoked `` the rain that restores the earth and air,'' according to the diocese. Churchgoers in <LOCATION> Bergamo </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Genoa </ORGANIZATION> have also been praying for rain as sunny, dry weather threatens crops and left ski slopes bare. Several parishes in small towns south of <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION> were planning processions along the Adda river if rain did not arrive in the next few days, the Italian news agency <ORGANIZATION> ANSA </ORGANIZATION> reported Sunday. <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> has received only half the precipitation it usually gets in the September-January period. The <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION> area has had one rain shower since November 24, while <ORGANIZATION> Genoa </ORGANIZATION> has been dry for four months. The lack of rain has prompted limits on private water use and contributed to brush fires that have scorched thousands of acres in northern <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>. The dry weather is the result of a high-pressure system that has remained over the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> for months, meteorologists say.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890213-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-13-89 0002EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Jamaica-Election     02-13 0768</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jamaica-Election,0792</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Image for Jamaica and Michael Manley</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT GLASS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KINGSTON, Jamaica (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In returning <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Manley </PERSON> to power, <PERSON> Jamaicans </PERSON> opted for a new style of leadership, decisively rejecting the tough economic solutions and autocratic demeanor of conservative incumbent <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Seaga </PERSON>. The island also emerged from its short but tense election campaign with an improved record on controlling political violence. Preliminary indications were that the charismatic <PERSON> Manley </PERSON>, a radical-turned-moderate leader with a new pro-business image, won 44 of 60 seats in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> in Thursday's voting. <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>'s leading political analyst and pollster, <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indies </ORGANIZATION>, said he thought there would be no fundamental policy shifts under <PERSON> Manley </PERSON>, who was prime minister from 1972 to 1980. `` There will be the same policies, but a different style of leadership,'' <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> said. `` He really feels obsessed with correcting his mismanagement during the 1970s.'' <PERSON> Seaga </PERSON>, a technocrat and hard-nosed manager, was regarded as a friend of big business, which is wary of <LOCATION> Manley </LOCATION>. `` There definitely are going to be memories of what happened in the past,'' said <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Thwaites </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Private </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sector </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>, the country's main business group. But he said if <PERSON> Manley </PERSON> carries out his current proposals, `` there will be very little change in the economic policies of the country.'' <PERSON> Manley </PERSON> appropriated private farms and heavily taxed business during his previous government. Now, he says he has `` abandoned all thoughts of nationalization'' and wants to give private enterprise a free hand in developing the economy. <PERSON> Seaga </PERSON> improved the island's economy, especially tourism, but he did it by doubling the foreign debt to about $ 4 billion, raising taxes, laying off thousands of workers and cutting back spending on health and education. Prices rose sharply, leading to food riots in 1985. `` The program he -LRB- <PERSON> Seaga </PERSON> -RRB- has carried out has been very rigid,'' said Stone. `` And he's paying the price for it.'' <PERSON> Seaga </PERSON>, a staunch ally of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and close political friend of <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, said he was afraid the results of his economic measures had not reached enough people. `` You see the results, yes, but the results have not reached enough people, -LRB- so -RRB- that enough people will say ` Yes, well, we took the medicine and we've benefited,''' he said recently. He said he was forced to take unpopular measures because of the near-bankrupt state of the economy when he took office in 1980 after eight years of <PERSON> Manley </PERSON> rule and the collapse of the bauxite industry in 1983. He said younger voters had no memories of how bad things were under <PERSON> Manley </PERSON>. <PERSON> Manley </PERSON>, known by his most ardent supporters as `` <PERSON> Joshua </PERSON>'' after the Old Testament prophet, pledged to revitalize schools and hospitals he said were neglected for eight years under <PERSON> Seaga </PERSON>'s cost-cutting administration As prime minister, <PERSON> Manley </PERSON> gained an international reputation as a firebrand socialist. He forged close ties with <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> and brought in scores of <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> doctors and technicians. In recent years, he has turned sharply to the political center as a social democrat. The 64-year-old leader has been saying he is an older and wiser man, and on election night Thursday he thanked the <LOCATION> Jamaican </LOCATION> people for giving him a `` second chance.'' <PERSON> Manley </PERSON> said he would restore relations with <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> but was more interested in working with the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration and Western lending institutions such as the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monetary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>. He said his first foreign trip as prime minister will be to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to establish `` the widest and most constructive'' relationship possible with the new administration. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration wo n't be pleased that <PERSON> Manley </PERSON> is reopening the <ORGANIZATION> Cuban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>, which was closed by <PERSON> Seaga </PERSON>, but <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials say they are encouraged by <PERSON> Manley </PERSON>'s pledge to limit the <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> presence and influence to formal diplomatic ties. Policy issues were overshadowed during the campaign by fears that bloodshed among rival political supporters would further split the nation of 2.4 million and wreck tourism, which brings in $ 600 million a year and is <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>'s top earner of foreign exchange. The tourism industry still is recovering from a sharp drop in visitors in the aftermath of Hurricane Gilbert, which slammed into the island Sept. 12, killing 45 people and causing $ 1 billion in damage. In 1980, when <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>'s last nationally contested election was held, an estimated 700 people were murdered over a nine-month campaign. This time, 13 died in campaign-related shootings and stabbings. But in comparison with the mayhem of 1980, the election appeared to mark a turning point in Jamaican politics.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890213-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-13-89 0006EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Paraguay-Adjusting     02-13 0867</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Paraguay-Adjusting,0896</SECOND>
<HEAD>Paraguayans Adjust To Political Change</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM H. HEATH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ASUNCION, Paraguay (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The gunfire has stopped, the dictator is gone and the celebrating is over. Paraguayans now must get down to the business of adjusting to life without the only president most of them have ever known. On the surface, the future looks brighter for this South American nation of nearly 4 million _ holding promises of new leadership and perhaps a more representative government. The likelihood that another general will replace ousted leader Gen. <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>, now in exile in neighboring <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, bothers few Paraguayans. Neither does the certainty that political power will remain in the hands of the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, a pillar of <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>'s support throughout his nearly 35 years in power `` It does n't make any difference what kind of government we get, it has to be better than the one we had,'' said 20-year-old <PERSON> Celso </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>, one of the thousands of citizens who went into the street to celebrate the fall of the 76-year-old dictator. Gen. <PERSON> Andres </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>, whose tanks and troops ousted <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> in a violent coup Feb. 3, seems to be many things his predecessor was not. <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> quickly dissolved <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and called for elections May 1 in which all parties _ except the Communists _ can participate. He promised to respect human rights, freedom of expression and the <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>. He named an 11-man Cabinet that even opposition members grudgingly admit includes <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION>'s most successful and talented administrators and technocrats. The new government will have to deal with urgent problems, including poverty, economic stagnation, 30 percent annual inflation and a foreign debt of nearly $ 2 billion. The church, which had become a leading opposition body in this predominantly Roman Catholic nation, promised the new president its support. <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>, 65, has denied rumors he may be linked to drug traffickers who move cocaine through <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION>, and he pledged to cooperate with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and international agencies seeking to end the drug trade. In <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION>'s first presidential press conference, the affable, self-assured cavalry general left open the possibility he may run for president. `` I am simply a soldier, not a politician,'' <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> told reporters. `` However, if I can be useful to my country, I will do what I am asked.'' <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Argana </PERSON>, the new foreign minister who was seen as the party's most likely presidential choice, quickly denied reports he would run and endorsed <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, which claims membership of 1.4 million and has ruled since 1947, has said it will call a convention soon to select candidates and new party leaders. The 101-year-old party was badly split in August 1987 when a small but fanatical pro-Stroessner group usurped party leadership in a battle over how to prepare for post-Stroessner rule. The <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> backers, an inner circle of militant government and party officials, favored continuation of hard-line authoritarian rule, possibly under <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>'s eldest son, <PERSON> Gustavo </PERSON>, an air force colonel. The majority, calling themselves `` traditionalists,'' favored some relaxation of iron rule and the eventual replacement of <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> with a civilian president. Recently, the situation was complicated by <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>'s failing health. The nation, accustomed to seeing his picture every day in the newspapers, was astounded in September when he vanished for two weeks for an unannounced prostate operation. In a nation where virtually every decision was made by the president, the wheels of government ground to a halt. `` The president used to personally sign most government documents,'' said a foreign diplomat. `` Some of our transferring personnel even received shipment orders for their household goods signed by him.'' <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>'s decision to act, diplomats and politicians say, came when <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> ordered him to give up command of the powerful <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> and retire, or accept a political post, possibly defense minister, without command of troops. <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>'s downfall sent citizens _ 70 percent of whom had known only <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> as president _ into the streets to celebrate. Rival politicians, bitter enemies for years, embraced, danced and sang. The nation's opposition political parties face new problems. Most were unrecognized because they had not been allowed to participate in the political process. `` The hinges of our political limbs are rusty from lack of use,'' said <PERSON> Euclides </PERSON> <PERSON> Acevedo </PERSON>, president of the left-leaning <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Febrerista </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON> <PERSON> Laino </PERSON>, popular head of the National Accord, a loose grouping of four opposition parties, suggested the opposition needs `` as much as a year'' to organize to effectively compete with the <ORGANIZATION> Colorados </ORGANIZATION> in elections. Political leaders largely discount the possibility that <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> or his son <PERSON> Gustavo </PERSON> could effectively organiize any effort to return to power. <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> supporters were hard to find after the coup and they spoke with reluctance. `` I have to admit that I do n't think that <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> was all bad,'' said a taxi driver as he drove through streets of happy demonstrators following the coup. `` He gave us peace and he built schools for our children and roads where there were only mudholes before.'' `` Look at those people,'' he said, nodding toward the demonstrators. `` If <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> were still in power, most of them would be cheering for him instead of <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890213-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-13-89 0025EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Transvestites     02-13 0166</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Transvestites,0169</SECOND>
<HEAD>First Transvestites To Be Convicted Under New Law</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KUALA LUMPUR, Malaysia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two men who dressed and behaved like women in public were both fined by the <ORGANIZATION> Moslem </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Religious </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> under a law that took effect this year, a newspaper reported today. The Star said <PERSON> Ismail </PERSON> <PERSON> Awang </PERSON>, 31, and <PERSON> Amdan </PERSON> <PERSON> Osman </PERSON>, 42, were the first to be convicted under the law, which applies to Moslems in <LOCATION> Kedah </LOCATION> state. Under the law, a transvestite caught in a public place can be fined up to 1,000 ringgits -LRB- $ 366 -RRB- or jailed for six months. The two men each paid $ 183 fines in lieu of spending four months in jail. The two were caught in a raid by Religious Affairs Department officers on a street in Alor Star on Feb. 4, Prosecutor <PERSON> Ustaz </PERSON> <PERSON> Mansor </PERSON> <PERSON> Osman </PERSON> told the court Sunday in <LOCATION> Alor </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Star </LOCATION>, 210 miles north of the capital, the newspaper reported. The two were wearing skirts and T-shirts and were soliciting when arrested, the paper said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890213-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-13-89 0032EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     02-13 0493</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0513</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LINCOLN, Neb. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When your name is <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON>, you have to have a sense of humor. Just ask him. `` I remember once I needed a reservation at a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, hotel and I called and made it in my name,'' <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> said recently. `` But when I showed up, they had no reservation. They thought it had been a prank call. ... `` You ca n't take it seriously or your life would be miserable,'' said <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON>, who works for the <ORGANIZATION> Nebraska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assistance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> was born in <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> in 1931 during his namesake's presidential administration Given his name, it's only natural he once bought a pickup truck from a man named <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Harding </PERSON> -LRB- not the 29th president -RRB-, and that his office mate when he worked for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Missouri </ORGANIZATION> was <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> Wendell </PERSON> <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON> -LRB- not the former <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> -RRB-. He said most people have forgotten former president <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON>, but many kid him about the <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> vacuum cleaner. `` You have to get used to people laughing at you,'' he said. `` My name shocks people,'' <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> said, `` so I started saying <PERSON> Herb </PERSON> over the phone. But a few years ago, <ORGANIZATION> Burger </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> King </ORGANIZATION> had an advertising campaign featuring a guy named <PERSON> Herb </PERSON> and I started finding ` Where's <PERSON> Herb </PERSON>?' posters all over my office.'' Although he has n't changed his name, <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> has given his son a different start. `` My son's name is <PERSON> Michael </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> said. `` I would never do that -LRB- name him <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> -RRB-. Children have enough to worry about.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CHARLOTTE, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> sweet potato growers have an identity crisis on their hands. Just last month, they finally got rid of the name `` yam'' from the name of their trade group to make a distinction between their product and the related African tuber. The state grows no yams, but its $ 60 million crop represents 40 percent of the nation's sweet potatoes. Now the federal government has decided sweet potato is really one word: sweetpotato. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> is apparently worried that consumers might think a sweet potato is an Irish potato that's sweet. `` That's the government bureaucracy for you,'' grumbled <PERSON> Milton </PERSON> <PERSON> Horne </PERSON>, a salesman for <ORGANIZATION> Corbett </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farms </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Wilmington </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> wants the state's growers, and their trade group, to go along. The <ORGANIZATION> N.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sweetpotato </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> has agreed, says <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeargin </PERSON>, executive director of the group. But the Sweet Potato Council of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, a Washington-based grower group, stands by its spelling. `` Just because the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> does it that way means <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> does also,'' said director <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoecker </PERSON>, noting with pride: `` But we at the council do not.'' <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commissioner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> does n't see what all the fuss is about. `` To heck with how you spell it,'' <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> said in an interview with The Charlotte Observer. `` We'll spell it any way they want as long as people are buying them.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890213-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-13-89 0043EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Tower-OldBoys Bjt   02-13 0790</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tower-Old Boys, Bjt,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Senate `Old Boy Club' in Disarray</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s `` old-boy club,'' which for generations has cheered on former senators if they advanced into the upper reaches of the executive branch, has come unglued under the weight of former Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON>'s nomination to be secretary of defense. Tower's <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> confirmation is in serious jeopardy, the nominee battered by unproven accusations of heavy drinking, womanizing and lack of objectivity when it comes to defense contractors. Many had expected that Tower's nomination to be the nation's defense chief would enjoy an effortless slide down a carefully greased chute Tower, after all, had been one of the powers of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> where he served for two dozen years and presided as chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> _ the same panel now being asked to confirm him. If he expected special treatment, he did n't get it. Instead, his nomination became snared in a web of allegations and <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> investigations. Sen. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, D-Ga., the current <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> chairman, had made clear months before last fall's election that he intended to subject new nominees for top Pentagon positions to intense scrutiny in an effort to improve the quality of key officials `` I said several times that it was n't going to be an old-boy hearing, that we were going to have a thorough review.'' <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> says. `` The presumption that it was going to be something less was wrong from the beginning. Period.'' <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> calls the Tower screening `` the most exhaustive process and investigation anyone's gone through in my memory in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>.'' `` I think everybody thought that the old-boy network would work as it always has and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON> would go sailing through, but it has n't worked that way,'' said Sen. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Exon </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Neb </LOCATION>., the <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>'s second-ranking Democrat Many members, including <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, speak of the process of sifting and judging the merits of allegations against Tower in terms of personal pain. The pain is evidently more intense against the backdrop of a courtly, clubby institution in which members routinely refer to colleagues as `` distinguished'' and `` honorable'' and hasten to smooth over the wounds of legislative combat with flowery compliments. `` This is a painful process,'' <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> says. `` It's painful for the nominee, painful for the president, painful for the committee and painful for me. It's frustrating. It's not enjoyable.'' In part, Tower's troubles may stem from the fact that he apparently entered the confirmation process with a relatively low reservoir of good will among his former colleagues. Many senators say privately that they were not fond of what they say was Tower's testy temper and autocratic operating style. Few are willing to say that in public _ but some are. `` Tower is a former member of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. But it is probably also the case that he does n't have a lot of intimate friends here or any aura of popularity or good will,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Lugar </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ind </LOCATION>., who was chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Foreign Relations committee at the time Tower headed Armed Services `` He is not necessarily a person who ingratiates himself with anybody,'' <PERSON> Lugar </PERSON> said. Some Republican senators are saying that while they remain publicly supportive of the Tower nomination, it is more out of a sense of loyalty to President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, rather than out of any sense of loyalty or affection toward Tower. `` They are saying, ` we owe it to the president, not Tower,''' <PERSON> Lugar </PERSON> said. `` I do n't notice anything clubby in this one at all,'' he said. The question inevitably is raised of whether the Tower nomination is being hammered by old-fashioned partisan politics. Some Republican operatives are saying exactly that, accusing the Democrats who control the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> of causing difficulties for the new administration in part to assert their majority status, and in part as an expression of frustration over their party's defeat in last year's presidential contest. Not so, says <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, whose own credentials are hardly those of a left-wing <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> basher. Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Va </LOCATION>., a former secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> and the panel's ranking Republican, backs him up The two lawmakers say they have worked as 50-50 partners throughout the hearings and investigations and constantly shared information. `` <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> has been fair, equitable and _ steadfastly _ he has been non-political,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> said late last week. <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> said he put the question of fairness directly to Tower himself. `` I said, ` <PERSON> John </PERSON>, if you were in the position <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> and I now find ourselves in ... would you do it any differently?''' The answer? `` Sen. Tower looked us right in the eye and said, ` No,''' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Knutson </PERSON> covers <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890213-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-13-89 0044EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TreatyEnforcers Bjt   02-13 0859</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Treaty Enforcers, Bjt,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviets Serious About Arms Treaty, US Inspector Says</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX8</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Soviets are bending over backwards to comply with the treaty calling for destruction of all intermediate-range missiles, a sign that they are eager for a more sweeping pact to slash nuclear arsenals, says the chief <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> inspector. `` The whole thing is going a whole lot better than we expected,'' said Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Roland </PERSON> <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON>, who in 19 previous years of dealing with the Soviets had found little reason to love them. <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON>, 52, has served two stints as a military attache in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and was commander of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> liaison office in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> in 1985 when Soviet soldiers shot and killed American Maj. <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicholson </PERSON>. `` Each of us has some unpleasant little anecdote,'' said <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON>, whose face was smashed when the truck in which he was riding was rammed from behind by a <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> vehicle in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> five months after the <PERSON> Nicholson </PERSON> incident. But, says <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON>, `` we are professional officers.'' And `` there is a political will on both sides to make this thing work. But I am under no political pressure to whitewash the process,'' <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON> said in an interview. He said the Soviets clearly view verification of the Intermediate-range Nuclear Forces, or INF, treaty as a foundation for cooperation on the more ambitious Strategic Arms Reduction Treaty _ START _ to cut long-range superpower weapons by 30 to 50 percent. START talks are stalled while the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration reviews overall <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy. START, said <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON>, `` is going to be much more complicated'' to verify because the number of weapons involved is much larger and because it calls for reduction rather than elimination of specific systems. Overhead satellites will remain the backbone of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> verification, said <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON>, but like the INF pact, START calls for on-site inspections on demand at dozens of locations in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and the Soviet bloc. Under the INF regime, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> also is allowed to keep 30 inspectors outside a Soviet mobile missile plant in <LOCATION> Votkinsk </LOCATION>, 700 miles east of <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, while the Soviets leave a similar group in <LOCATION> Magna </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON> and the other 250 Americans assigned to the inspection agency consult regularly with the START negotiators, and some of the military officers on the START team have accompanied the INF inspectors on their rounds to make sure that lessons are learned. `` There are certain minor provisions for which we would prefer different wording,'' said <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON>, noting a requirement that inspectors tour a facility within one hour of arrival, no matter what time they get there. Since <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON> supervised the creation of the <ORGANIZATION> On-Site </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inspection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> in April 1988, the Soviets have destroyed 30.8 percent of their 1,836 short - and medium-range missiles, and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has destroyed 30.5 percent of its 867 <ORGANIZATION> Pershing </ORGANIZATION> 2 and ground-launched cruise missiles `` We're both a little ahead of the curve'' for the three-year destruction period, said <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON>. The treaty, negotiated over six years and signed in December 1987, bans ground-launched superpower missiles with ranges of 300-3 ,000 miles He acknowledges that there have been `` a lot of minor glitches. They have been resolved in a gentlemanly way. There is a tradition now of resolving these at the lowest possible level.'' One glitch can not be blamed on the Soviets, said <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON>. An X-ray machine to be used at <LOCATION> Votkinsk </LOCATION> has not been delivered yet, forcing the Americans to rely on their eyes to spot any medium-range SS-20 missiles the Soviets might try to sneak out of the factory among longer range SS-25's. Last month, Sen. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.C. </LOCATION>, a conservative opponent of arms control, accused the Soviets of preventing use of the X-ray device and therefore violating the treaty. <PERSON> LaJoie </PERSON>, however, said, `` it is not a Soviet-imposed delay.'' If the Americans are suspicious, said <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON>, they can always demand to inspect the inside of the missile canister, a right they can exercise eight times a year. The treaty bans all SS-20 missiles. <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON>, who spent much of his time as a military attache peering at the outside of Soviet bases under the suspicious gaze of Russian counterintelligence agents, marvels at the `` unique access'' his team is given on strategic rocket bases. `` Everything we have observed is something we have n't observed before,'' he said. But that's not a license to spy. `` Neither side wants the other to move into a sensitive area with a lot of gear,'' said <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON>. Each team is allowed to carry only one camera, a quick-developing model to photograph disputed items. Since completion of `` baseline'' inspections last summer to verify the actual number of weapons in each arsenal, only one photograph has been taken, by the Soviets, of a ground-launched cruise missile that already had been partially disassembled, a minor deviation from protocol, according to an administration official. Another small misunderstanding arose after an American failed to count one item on a list of weapons components to be destroyed. The misunderstanding was cleared up quickly through an exchange of telegrams, according to the official, who spoke on condition he not be further identified.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890213-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-13-89 0106EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     02-13 0907</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0940</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Singer-songwriter <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>'s `` Graceland'' album will be reprised this week as musicians, comedians and politicians get together in a fund-raiser for charity. <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Masekela </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ladysmith </PERSON> <PERSON> Black </PERSON> <PERSON> Mambazo </PERSON> and other musicians will join <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> on Thursday night in a benefit performance for the homeless. Tickets start at $ 1,000. <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> and rhythm-and-blues singer <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> also will perform, and Gov. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> is scheduled to speak. Proceeds will be divided between <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>'s Children's Health Fund, which provides health care for homeless children in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, and the <ORGANIZATION> HELP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, which builds transitional housing for homeless families.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ROCK HILL, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>'s daughter gave birth to a son during the weekend _ a 6-pound, 10-ounce boy named partly after his famous, television evangelist grandfather. The <ORGANIZATION> Bakkers </ORGANIZATION>' first grandchild, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>, was born at 1:32 a.m. Saturday, to <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>, 18, and her husband, <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>, 26. Mother and baby were in good condition Sunday at <ORGANIZATION> Piedmont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, hospital officials said. `` I had been praying for a boy, and the Lord gave me what I wanted,'' a tired but happy Mrs. <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON> said. The couple named their son for <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>; <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>, whose middle name is <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>; <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>'s father, who also is named <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>; and <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>'s stepfather, <PERSON> James </PERSON>
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>HUNTSVILLE, Ark. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former Gov. <PERSON> Orval </PERSON> <PERSON> Faubus </PERSON> sold memorabilia from his long political career, but he could n't part with a few mementos _ like documents validating his election to six consecutive terms as governor. `` I still have six certificates of election,'' <PERSON> Faubus </PERSON> said Sunday, a day after he took in $ 5,000 from the auction at his mansion atop Governor's <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>. `` I think we had about 1,000 items listed _ a few large and most of it small stuff. Political memorabilia must have been nearly half of it,'' said the 79-year-old <PERSON> Faubus </PERSON>, who served as governor from 1955 to 1967. He has lost three comeback bids for governor, most recently in 1986. One item that fetched $ 40 was a boat paddle embossed with a likeness of <PERSON> Faubus </PERSON> and the slogan, `` <PERSON> Faubus </PERSON> for <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>,'' from his 1964 race. The most popular political items were license tags, numbered `` 1,'' reserved for the chief executive. `` I was amazed at the prices. One went for $ 115, and the cheapest one was $ 95,'' he said. About 200 people attended Saturday's auction at <PERSON> Faubus </PERSON>' 9,000-square-foot house, which is being sold to a <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> antique dealer whom <PERSON> Faubus </PERSON> declined to identify Sunday
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PLAINFIELD, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nobel Peace Prize-winning <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> helped to reopen a convent that had been closed for 17 years, saying she saw the nuns there doing `` something beautiful for God.'' Closed because of declining membership, <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mary </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convent </ORGANIZATION> is now home to 13 nuns who belong to <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Missionaries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Charity </ORGANIZATION>, Contemplative Order, said the Rev. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mirandi </PERSON>, pastor of <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mary </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>. About 1,500 people packed inside the church shoulder-to-shoulder to listen to the 78-year-old <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON>, who has become known as the `` Saint of <LOCATION> Calcutta </LOCATION>'' for her work with the poor in that Indian city. `` I hope they're going to do something beautiful for God,'' she told the congregants at Sunday morning Mass. `` It is very important to help each other and share with each other. I will pray that God's blessing be with you all. <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> founded the <ORGANIZATION> Missionaries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Charity </ORGANIZATION>, an order of 3,000 nuns in 87 countries, in 1950. She became known as the `` Saint of <LOCATION> Calcutta </LOCATION>'' for her work with the poor in that Indian city. The three-story convent in this northern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> city was built in 1910 and previously had been used by the Sisters of Charity.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sir <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Lean </PERSON>, director of the Oscar-winning epic `` Lawrence of <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>,'' has urged <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> to take risks on quality films. `` Spend some money on risky subjects,'' said <PERSON> Lean </PERSON>, who won the director's Academy Award for the 1962 movie. `` It's no good being safe in this business. We've all got to be gamblers.'' Lean made his comments Sunday at the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> premiere for the recently restored three-hour, 40-minute director's cut of `` Lawrence of Arabia.'' The premiere benefited the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> and its campaign to restore and preserve classic films. The new version already has been released in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Joining Lean here were composer <PERSON> Maurice </PERSON> <PERSON> Jarre </PERSON>, director of photographer <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> A </PERSON>. Young and film editor <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Coates </PERSON>. All three won Oscars for their work on the movie, which won seven Academy Awards, including best picture. Actors <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Quinn </PERSON> and <PERSON> Omar </PERSON> <PERSON> Shariff </PERSON>, who both starred in the film, also attended the screening, along with director <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON>, actors <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Peck </PERSON>, <PERSON> Rob </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowe </PERSON> and <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Alda </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: Longer version moved on sports wire.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>HOUSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With 14 seconds left in his 18th and final <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Basketball </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> All-Star Game, <PERSON> Kareem </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdul-Jabbar </PERSON> finally hit a sky hook. After missing five sky hooks, he made his sixth to score the West's final field goal in its 143-134 victory over the East on Sunday. `` I would have been disappointed if it had n't dropped,'' said the 41-year-old <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> Laker center, who is retiring at the end of the season, his 20th season. `` I wanted to get a field goal.'' <PERSON> Abdul-Jabbar </PERSON> was able to play in the game because of an injury to teammate <PERSON> Magic </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890213-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-13-89 0107EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SaintValentine     02-13 0614</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Saint Valentine,0630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Umbrian Steel Town Claims Its Beheaded Saint Was The Real Valentine</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DENNIS REDMONT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Asssociated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TERNI, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Led by their Communist mayor, the people of <LOCATION> Terni </LOCATION> have launched a crusade to reclaim St. Valentine, the patron saint of lovers who has attained greater fame abroad than in his native country. On Sunday, the city in central <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Umbria </LOCATION> region launched a yearly award ceremony dedicated to acts of love around the world. Next year, it plans to offer free honeymoons to newlyweds. This steel town wants its decapitated 3rd century bishop to really be its valentine. The Roman Catholic saint for lovers has been as much a mixture of myth, religion and tradition as Easter bunnies or <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON>, who eventually became a jolly red-suited <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Claus </LOCATION>. The Vatican Congregation for the Causes of Saints says 17 Valentines are listed in the official encyclopedia of saints _ including ones from <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. `` But we are relatively sure that <LOCATION> Terni </LOCATION>'s is the real Valentine because he is the oldest,'' says <PERSON> Ivani </PERSON> <PERSON> Rossi </PERSON>, president of the Valentian Cultural Center. He has been working to bring back what he says is `` real significance'' to the festivity rather than `` a growth in the Valentine gift industry.'' According to historical accounts from the Middle Ages, Placido, the prefect of <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, had the spiritual head of <LOCATION> Terni </LOCATION>'s Christians beheaded on February 14 of the year 270 after having him imprisoned and whipped. <PERSON> Valentino </PERSON> had a garden where, according to legend, he allowed children to play or lovers to meet. While he was jailed <PERSON> Valentino </PERSON> handed the keys of the garden to two carrier pigeons with a message inviting the children of <LOCATION> Terni </LOCATION> to return there during his absence. After his martyrdom, <PERSON> Valentino </PERSON>'s body was brought back here by his followers and buried. The funeral urn was discovered in a cemetery during the 17th century and is now kept in a basilica, minus a tooth given at the time to <PERSON> Leopold </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>, who venerated the saint and funded the basilica's construction. Benedictine monks spread the cult of the saint to Anglo-Saxon countries including <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Although <PERSON> Valentino </PERSON> remained the patron saint of <LOCATION> Terni </LOCATION>, town residents _ as well as most Italians _ did n't realize how famous he was becoming abroad, according to the current bishop of <LOCATION> Terni </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Franco </PERSON> <PERSON> Gualdrini </PERSON>. `` We found, for example, that people knew more about the American mafia ` St. Valentine's Day Massacre' than about St. Valentine himself,'' <PERSON> Gualdrini </PERSON> said in an interview, referring to the Prohibition-era slaying of seven men in a <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> garage by <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Capone </PERSON>'s mobsters. `` The commercial value of St. Valentine outstripped his spiritual value,'' he said. `` This was something we had to change, considering <LOCATION> Terni </LOCATION> had probably the world's best known saint.'' A few years ago, the traditionally Communist administration of <LOCATION> Terni </LOCATION>, led by Mayor <PERSON> Giacomo </PERSON> <PERSON> Porazzini </PERSON>, decided to work with the local church on a mutually beneficial project _ restoring some luster to <LOCATION> Terni </LOCATION> and its saint. A tourist marketing test in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> showed the city and the area, with spectacular waterfalls and walled medieval towns and churches, had potential appeal. Now, more than 20,000 Japanese tourists stop at the basilica and tour the area each year _ and <LOCATION> Terni </LOCATION> has its annual ` love' awards ceremony. Among winners Sunday were Nobel Peace Prize-winner <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Calcutta </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> <PERSON> Erich </PERSON> <PERSON> Segal </PERSON>, best-selling author of `` Love Story''; actor <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Ustinov </PERSON> and an Italian rescue brigade that recently returned from the Armenian earthquake zone. Next year, the prize ceremony will be carried on a worldwide satellite television program and the city will begin to offer free one-week honeymoons to selected newlyweds.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890213-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-13-89 0110EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-CentralAmerica     02-13 0677</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Central America,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prospective Latin Aide Calls For Downgrading Contras</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Democrat who is set to become <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's top aide for <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> was once a strong supporter of the Nicaraguan Contras but now believes other strategies should be pursued for achieving a settlement in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Aronson </PERSON>, who once advised President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> and Vice President <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON>, believes the new administration should make an all-out effort to build on the peace agreement the five Central American presidents signed in August 1987. <PERSON> Aronson </PERSON>'s views were outlined in a little-noticed paper he co-authored last October which was intended to influence the debate over <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> as the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration was bowing out. The report was published by <ORGANIZATION> Freedom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, a human rights group based in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Eight others participated in writing the paper, titled `` Peace Through Democracy, A Bipartisan Initiative for the Central American Crisis.'' Although there have been some objections to <PERSON> Aronson </PERSON>'s prospective appointment, administration aides say Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> has indicated that his decision is final. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> has placed high priority on filling the post, vacated last month by <PERSON> Elliott </PERSON> <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON>, with someone who will have more success than <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON> did in forging a bipartisan policy on <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. While the policies of the new administration are still in the planning stage, the Central Americans themselves are engaged in a flurry of diplomatic activity. Central American foreign ministers met in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> last week and the five regional presidents were opening a two-day meeting today in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> to discuss the future of the Nicaraguan Contras and other issues. <PERSON> Aronson </PERSON>, 42, helped write a pro-Contra aid speech for President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> several years ago but the report he helped write last fall suggests his views on rebel aid have shifted in light of new developments. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> has discussed the <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> issue only in general terms but what he has said appears to be consistent with the substance of the report co-authored by <PERSON> Aronson </PERSON>. While hinting that <PERSON> Contra </PERSON> aid may be a last resort at some point, the report suggests that continued pursuit of that approach is tactically unwise because of hostile public opinion in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` Those who favor the immediate resumption of military aid to the <LOCATION> Nicaraguan </LOCATION> resistance are in danger of once again launching a military policy from a weak political base,'' the report said. It said few believe there is a broad enough consensus in support of <LOCATION> Contra </LOCATION> aid to sustain that approach for a substantial period. Instead, the report recommends giving a `` rigorous test'' to the <LOCATION> Esquipulas </LOCATION> agreement, signed by the five <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> presidents 18 months ago. Among other provisions, the agreement commits <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s leftist government to establish democracy and also bars continued <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to the Contras. Six months after the agreement was signed, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> suspended military aid to the rebels, most of whom have since fled to camps along the Honduran border where they receive <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> humanitarian assistance. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration was deeply mistrustful of the agreement, seeing it as a mechanism that would relieve Contra military pressure on the Sandinista government without ensuring a democratic outcome in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. American officials have repeatedly accused the Sandinista government of dragging its feet in adopting democratic reforms. <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON> maintained that Contra military pressure was the only way to ensure a democratic evolution in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Aronson </PERSON> suggests that the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration should have pursued more vigorously the opening created at <LOCATION> Esquipulas </LOCATION>, the site in <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> where the agreement was signed. The <ORGANIZATION> Freedom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> report said the accord has `` greater moral and political validity than other approaches being considered.'' On the other hand, it said the agreement has a number of weaknesses, including a lack of `` compelling verification and enforcement mechanisms'' and a reluctance `` to confront Soviet and <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> involvement in the region's turmoil.'' Among other recommendations, the report calls for the establishment of a bipartisan task force to determine whether the agreement is an appropriate instrument for bringing about peace and democracy in the region.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890213-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-13-89 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ReformCaucus     02-13 0713</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reform Caucus,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Caucus Looks for Action After Bush's Reform Pledge</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONNA CASSATA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The image and words heartened members of the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reform </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Caucus </ORGANIZATION>. There was President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, standing on the deck of the 1,048-foot-long carrier <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> last month at the huge <ORGANIZATION> Norfolk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> and telling <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> personnel and contractor employees that he wants `` tighter controls and higher standards in weapons procurement.'' `` I'm very hopeful. I know the president intends to make changes,'' says Sen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Roth </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, R-Del. `` We have a tremendous opportunity in the next few years,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Boxer </PERSON>, D-Calif. <PERSON> Roth </PERSON> and <PERSON> Boxer </PERSON> _ representatives of different sides of the aisle and different sides of the Capitol _ last week were named co-chairs of the caucus, an informal, bipartisan organization of <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> members The Republican-Democratic, House-Senate mix is standard. During the 100th <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, the caucus membership totaled 136 with 27 members of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and 109 members of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>. Seventy-eight were Democrats and 58 were Republicans. Members are `` of a like mind concerned about reform in the military,'' said <PERSON> Boxer </PERSON>. At times during the eight-year tenure of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s predecessor, <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, the caucus was frustrated. For example, in 1983, it led the fight for the creation of an independent Pentagon operational test and evaluation office, but the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration delayed the installation of a test director until two years later. During the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> presidency and the accompanying record peacetime military buildup, scandals surfaced about <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> payment of exorbitant prices for hammers, wrenches and toilet seats. Of a more serious nature, the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has been pursuing a two-year probe of alleged purchasing fraud. The case involves charges that private consultants, hired by military contractors, bribed <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials to obtain inside information that gave companies an edge in bidding for <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> work. `` <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is the true father of the caucus,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Colo </LOCATION>., a member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and a frequent critic of the past Republican administration The caucus says its purpose is not to advocate `` overall increases or decreases in defense spending, only more effective expenditure of those dollars allocated for national defense.'' `` The notion is not to argue what weapons are needed. We're trying to find a way to make the most of the military for less money,'' said <PERSON> Boxer </PERSON> The caucus began in 1981 after former Rep. <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitehurst </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Va </LOCATION>., noticed an article in The Wall Street Journal on military reform The story's author was former <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> senator and onetime presidential candidate <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>. In reading the article, <PERSON> Whitehurst </PERSON> found that he shared some of the same views as <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>. The senator and the congressman huddled on military reform, joined forces with a handful of others and formed the caucus. Initially, the organization concentrated on such military reforms as maneuver tactics and leadership training. Later, as the caucus increased in numbers, it turned its attention to purchasing reform and conventional weapons. The organization says its activities `` are intended to support the regular committee work for a more effective national defense.'' `` We've held hearings we could n't get the <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> to hold. The caucus has pushed <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Boxer </PERSON> said. The caucus has no budget, no dues, not even an official phone number. Its staff is the staff of the co-chairs who handle mailings and pay for events. The caucus holds frequent briefings and seminars for members on such issues as the <ORGANIZATION> Bradley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fighting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vehicle </ORGANIZATION>, the military budget and conventional defense. This congressional session, the focus will be on promoting legislation to strengthen the procurement system and whistleblower protection, and tighten the revolving door between the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> and the defense industry, said <PERSON> Boxer </PERSON> and <PERSON> Roth </PERSON>. Affecting the reform effort will be the budget crunch facing the Pentagon. In his speech Thursday, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> proposed a $ 308.8 billion defense budget for fiscal 1990, eliminating the 2 percent increase proposed by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in January. `` With less funds available, it will be critically important that we get the biggest bang for the buck,'' said <PERSON> Roth </PERSON>. `` Centralized procurement within the department _ this kind of approach is the highest priority on the agenda.'' <PERSON> Roth </PERSON>, who has been called a `` cheap hawk,'' jokes that he has to `` live up to his reputation.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890213-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-13-89 0114EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FortuneTellers     02-13 0308</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fortune Tellers,0316</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gambling Resort's Fortune Tellers May Be Subject To Criminal Checks</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOYCE A. VENEZIA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 People who predict the future will have to reveal their past if officials in this gambling resort get their way. City council last week unanimously passed a measure to require palm readers to undergo a criminal check, fingerprinting and positive identification when they go for their annual license. The city currently charges a $ 400 license fee for readers to practice their trade. `` The city ca n't deal in morality, but it can regulate things better,'' said <PERSON> Councilwoman </PERSON> <PERSON> Louise </PERSON> <PERSON> Palmentieri </PERSON>, who proposed the measure. The council will take a final vote Wednesday. Many established readers support the effort. `` People come in here to work for a couple of months, and we do n't know who they really are,'' said <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, part of a palm-reading family that has operated here for more than 50 years. `` We want the tighter restrictions. It gives us the best protection.'' <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Annette </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Boardwalk </LOCATION> phrenologist _ someone who claims to detect character traits in the shape of a person's skull _ said the legalization of gambling 10 years ago has increased demand for fortune tellers' services and the need for tougher licensing regulations. `` We get a lot of bus people who want a reading to see how their luck is running,'' she said. `` Most of <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s readers have been here for a long time. But since the casinos came, a lot of new -LRB- readers -RRB- came in.'' <LOCATION> Altantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> required non-resident workers to register with the city from 1953 to 1972, but it was dropped after civil rights groups complained it violated individuals' rights, Police Chief <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Pasquale </PERSON> said. `` It was a good system, though, because we found people who were wanted for murder in other states,'' <PERSON> Pasquale </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890213-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-13-89 0119EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     02-13 0743</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sheep Production Once Exceeded US Cattle Herd</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When it comes to livestock, it may be hard to realize today that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was once a nation of sheep, not cows. Not anymore, of course. The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> reported last week that the nation's cattle inventory, although down slightly, totaled nearly 99.5 million head on Jan. 1. The number of sheep and lambs increased a bit for the third straight year to 10.8 million. Even milk cows, at 10.2 million head, nearly matched the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sheep flock. And dairy cow numbers were the smallest since 1872. `` Sheep and lamb production has long been an important segment of our economy,'' the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> said in a supplemental report. `` Since colonial times, production of sheep and lamb for meat and wool has substantially contributed to our food and fiber industry.'' Before the 1900s, wool production was most important, while sheep and lamb output for meat was incidental. But the report said `` there was a marked change'' from 1870 to 1920 as the production of lambs for slaughter became increasingly important. The <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> began officially estimating sheep and lamb numbers right after the Civil War. On Jan. 1, 1867, those totaled 46.3 million head having a value of about $ 108 million, or about $ 2.40 per head. `` There were about one-third more sheep than cattle in this earliest count,'' the report said. `` By 1884, sheep and lamb numbers increased to 53.3 million head but exceeded cattle numbers for the last time.'' According to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> records, the cattle inventory in 1867 was 28.6 million head worth an estimated $ 547.9 million, an average of $ 19.13 per head. By 1884, when sheep totaled 53.3 million head, cattle were at 49.8 million. The following year, in 1885, sheep were estimated at 49.6 million. `` Sheep and lamb numbers passed through many cyclical phases,'' the report said. `` Inventory declined after 1884 until 1897 and then increased again until 1909, when almost 50.8 million head were on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> farms and ranches.'' The next peak for sheep and lambs was in 1932 when nearly 54 million head were reported. The all-time high was in 1942 when 56.2 million head were being raised to help with the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> effort in World War II, both for wool and meat. Inventories dropped after the war, declining to fewer than 30 million head by 1950 and then mostly leveled off. After 1960 through most of the 1970s, sheep and lambs continued to decline and than hovered just under 13 million head from 1977 to 1982. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> flock dropped to below 10 million head, an all-time low, on Jan. 1, 1986, before the modest recovery of recent years. A number of causes are blamed for the demise of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sheep industry, the report said. Mostly it has stemmed from a reduced demand for wool, reflecting the intrusion of synthetic fibers and cheaper substitute materials, plus a declining demand for lamb in consumer diets. One big problem has been the difficulty in obtaining and keeping reliable herders to manage and care for range flocks, which are located mostly in the West. The increased competition for public range land also was cited. `` Another important factor which has contributed to the decline is the increasing problem of predators -LRB- such as coyotes -RRB- in many range and farm-flock producing states,'' the report said. `` Also, relatively large imports of lamb and mutton have contributed to the decline of the domestic sheep industry.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Last month's trade figures released by the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> showed an impressive gain in the value of agricultural exports from levels the year before, says an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> analysis. Agricultural exports in November, the most recent figures reported, topped $ 3.3 billion, up $ 500 million from a year earlier and the highest for a single month since December 1984, the report said. The gains reflect higher export prices due to tighter <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> supplies stemming from last summer's drought. But from a volume perspective, the gains were more modest, the report said. November shipments rose 2 percent from a year earlier to 11.4 million metric tons. `` So far this year, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agricultural exports ... are commanding a $ 50 per ton premium on the world market over year-ago levels,'' the report said. `` The largest price increases have been in those commodities most severely affected by last summer's drought _ wheat, feed grains and soybeans and products.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890213-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-13-89 0123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Theater 1stLd-Writethru a0812 02-13 0360</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Theater, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0812,0363</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Without Apologies' Is Full of Old-Fashioned Laughs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Eds: CORRECTS fiancee, 5th graf, ``In the...</BYLINE>
<HEAD>Eds: No PMs planned.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new comedy, `` Without Apologies,'' is full of the old-fashioned kind of laughs that come when belief is suspended and theater not overly concerned with realistic situations. `` Without Apologies'' is playing at the off-Broadway <LOCATION> Hudson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Guild </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Theater </LOCATION>, where it had its <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> premiere Sunday. Irish actress <PERSON> Pauline </PERSON> <PERSON> Flanagan </PERSON> shines in the role she also had at the play's debut at the <LOCATION> Dorset </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, Theater Festival. As <PERSON> Gwen </PERSON>, a plump, droll and sensible housewife in a genteelly shabby home, she dithers with delicious timing and inflections. The <PERSON> Thom </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> comedy is about the later years of the characters from `` The Importance of Being Earnest,'' the 1895 play that led to playwright <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilde </PERSON> being sued for having libeled the Beaumont family. In the 34 years since <PERSON> Ernie </PERSON> <PERSON> Beaumont </PERSON> -LRB- <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Pagan </PERSON> -RRB- left <PERSON> Gwen </PERSON>, his bride-to-be -LRB- Miss <PERSON> Flanagan </PERSON> -RRB-, at the altar and ran off with <PERSON> Cecily </PERSON> -LRB- <PERSON> Carrie </PERSON> <PERSON> Nye </PERSON> -RRB-, the fiancee of his brother, <LOCATION> Algy </LOCATION> Beaumont -LRB- <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON> <PERSON> Knudson </PERSON> -RRB-, the two couples have had no contact. <PERSON> Gwen </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Algy </LOCATION>, the two left behind, married and live in her mother's house, with her mother and a renter upstairs. When <PERSON> Ernie </PERSON> and <PERSON> Cecily </PERSON> arrive virtually unannounced for a visit, they bring their daughter <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON> -LRB- <PERSON> Laura </PERSON> <PERSON> Brutsman </PERSON> -RRB-, dressed like a child but 30. An unforgiving <PERSON> Gwen </PERSON> says it would be inconvenient for them to spend the night, but they inform her they're broke and moving in permanently. That sets up the plot: <PERSON> Will </PERSON> <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON> get together with the renter -LRB- <PERSON> Edmund </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> -RRB-, a jazz drummer who aspires to be a comedian? <PERSON> Will </PERSON> <PERSON> Cecily </PERSON>, played by the blonde, willowy Miss <PERSON> Nye </PERSON>, forsake plummy-voice <PERSON> Ernie </PERSON> for <LOCATION> Algy </LOCATION> and scramble the family again? And there's one more question: Will the <LOCATION> Beaumont </LOCATION> descendants sue <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, director <PERSON> Edgar </PERSON> <PERSON> Lansbury </PERSON> and masterful set designer <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Wulp </PERSON>? With jokes about the footstool, a brotherly competition over war wounds and Miss <PERSON> Flanagan </PERSON> crooning her comic lines up and down her vocal register, one is simply laughing too much to care.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890213-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-13-89 0125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AssaultWeapons     02-13 0851</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Assault Weapons,830</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gun Groups Fight Assault Weapon Limits</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gun owner groups are opening fire on congressional efforts to outlaw semiautomatic assault weapons such as the one used in last month's <PERSON> Stockton </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, playground massacre that left five children dead. `` I think a lot of people could get hurt politically in voting for this bill,'' says <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON>, public affairs director of the <ORGANIZATION> Citizens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> for the Right to Keep and Bear Arms. He and other gun lobbyists were on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> last week to combat a bill sponsored by Sen. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, that would halt sales of AK47s, Israeli-made Uzis and a host of other military-style weapons with banana clips, wire stocks and sinister-looking snouts that roughly fall under the heading of assault rifles. Led by the efficient and well financed <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rifle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, gun lobbyists base their muscle on support from hundreds of thousands of hunters and other gun owners across the country who fear they will lose their weapons. Lawmakers have long been reluctant to tangle with the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> for fear of repercussions at election time. The <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>'s power, however, may have waned a bit in recent years when lawmakers approved a ban on plastic guns that fail to register on metal detectors and required the attorney general to come up with a plan to keep firearms out of the hands of criminals. The <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> ended up supporting the plastic gun ban after initial opposition failed to scuttle it. Handing the more complicated assignment to the attorney general represented a compromise struck after the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> balked at a House-passed plan to do no more than study the problem. Opponents of the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>, however, say there is no question that it still wields considerable power. `` The <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> has intimidated members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in a political sense with their money and their political muscle,'' says Rep. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Feighan </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, who was defeated last year in an effort to win approval of a seven-day waiting period for gun buyers. He is trying again this year. <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>, however, was re-elected handily while under attack by the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>. His supporters say the criticism was offset somewhat by an endorsement from the <ORGANIZATION> Fraternal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Order </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION>, based in part on his support for gun control. They say the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> may well pass assault rifle legislation this year. The current round began shortly after a Jan. 17 incident in which a gunman opened fire with an AK47 on 400 children on a playground outside the <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Stockton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. Five youngsters died and 29 were injured along with one teacher Three persons remain in the hospital. First to respond with legislation was Rep. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Berman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Calif </LOCATION>. `` The slaughter of citizens on the streets and children in the schoolyard by weapons designed for slaughter on the battlefield must be stopped,'' delared <PERSON> Berman </PERSON> His bill, however, has not generated wide support, even among gun control advocates, mainly because it bans possession of assault rifles and thus requires owners to turn them in to police or the local sheriff. By contrast, <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>'s bill would ban sales of the weapons but not possession. Trying to collect huge numbers of semiautomatic rifles already in private hands could plunge the bill into a political quagmire, control advocates fear. Other <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> congressmen, including Reps. <PERSON> Vic </PERSON> <PERSON> Fazio </PERSON>, D-Calif., and <PERSON> Fortney </PERSON> H. -LRB- Pete -RRB- Stark, <LOCATION> D-Calif </LOCATION>., have been searching for a less stringent And any bill clearly has a long, hard haul to reach floor passage. In the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> Democrat <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>'s Judiciary subcommittee on the Constitution is believed to be closely divided over whether to push legislation this year. But even if it is blocked there, <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON> still can go to the floor and appeal to the whole <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> to attach his bill to other legislation. <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> lobbyists say guns dubbed assault weapons are not much different from more traditional hunting guns. They call the major difference cosmetic and point to the military-style appearance of the AK47s and Uzis. `` There is no functional difference between those firearms that are currently being called assault rifles and what would be called traditional hunting rifles,'' says <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> federal lobbyist <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Conover </PERSON>. He claims that <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>'s measure would not only outlaw rapid-fire grease guns and pistol-gripped, round-drummed `` streetsweeper'' shotguns but such old standbys of the sportsman as the wooden-stocked <PERSON> Remington </PERSON> model 4. The same disclaimer of any `` functional difference'' was expressed at last week's hearing by <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Conroy </PERSON>, acting deputy associate director for law enforcement of the bureau of alcohol, tobacco and firearms. But he also expressed sympathy with the aim of the legislation to take assault weapons out of the hands of criminals. <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman have been arguing that a ban on the weapon would not really work because it would be disobeyed by criminals and kept out of the hands of law-abiding hunters and other sportsmen. But <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON> scoffs at that notion. `` We know of only one instance in which this was used for hunting,'' he declared last week. `` When a psychopath in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> went hunting school children.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890213-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-13-89 0131EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-ToddBridges     02-13 0538</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Todd Bridges,0557</SECOND>
<HEAD>Drug Addiction Turned Actor Into `A Sick Kid,' Mother Says</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Todd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bridges </PERSON> is `` a sick kid'' victimized by drug addiction, according to the mother of the former teen-age star of `` Diff ` rent Strokes,'' who is jailed on attempted murder `` It's hard to believe it's come to this,'' said <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Bridges </PERSON>, adding that family problems and early celebrity status have hurt her 23-year-old son. Earlier this month, Bridges was charged with shooting <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Clay </PERSON>, 25, in both arms and the chest in a house known as a drug hangout. An associate, <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> <PERSON> Duckett </PERSON>, 30, is accused of slashing <PERSON> Clay </PERSON>'s face with a knife. Bridges is being held without bail until his preliminary hearing Friday and faces a maximum sentence of life in prison if convicted. `` I do n't know what a drug addict is capable of,'' his mother said last week. `` But I know that <PERSON> Todd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bridges </PERSON>, my son, is not capable of shooting someone like that.'' The attack came 10 days after Bridges was arrested for investigation of possessing cocaine near the house, police said. Previously, he received a suspended sentence in January 1987 after pleading no contest to making a bomb threat, and he was fined for carrying a concealed weapon in 1983. `` The drugs and the pressure have made <PERSON> Todd </PERSON> a sick kid and he should n't be made out to be some criminal,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bridges </PERSON> said in an interview in Sunday's Los Angeles Daily News. She said her 1984 divorce from <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Bridges </PERSON> contributed to their son's troubles. `` I'm only just understanding how deeply hurt <PERSON> Todd </PERSON> was,'' she said. Actor <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> <PERSON> Bain </PERSON>, who played Bridge's adoptive father in the TV situation comedy `` Diff ` rent Strokes,'' said Bridges was angry and erratic toward the end of the series, apparently because of financial problems and his parents' `` He was so sensitive,'' <PERSON> Bain </PERSON> said. `` Just the kind of kid you knew was n't going to handle all the problems real well.'' Bridges made his first commercial at age 6 and starred in the television comedy series `` Fish'' four years later. At age 12 he landed the role as <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>'s brother <PERSON> Willis </PERSON> on `` Diff ` rent Strokes <PERSON> Johnnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Cochran </PERSON>, Bridges' attorney, said his client's problems are common to young stars after their first big success. `` Like other child stars, <PERSON> Todd </PERSON> grew up faster than other kids,'' <PERSON> Cochran </PERSON> said. `` When the series ended -LRB- in 1985 -RRB-, the adjustment was real tough for him.'' Bridges had trouble getting work after the show's last season. He began using drugs 18 months later, Mrs. <PERSON> Bridges </PERSON> said. `` All of a sudden he started coming home looking strange,'' she said. Bridges told his mother last June of his drug problem, she said. He spent one month in a drug rehabilitation center and stayed clean until November, she said. But his close friend <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Arragon </PERSON> was killed when his motorcycle hit a passing truck, prompting Bridges to take his first drink in six months that night, Mrs. <PERSON> Bridges </PERSON> said. `` That was the last straw,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bridges </PERSON> said. `` After that he began living with those hoodlums in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> -RRB-. He got so crazy I almost called an insane asylum to pick him up. I was afraid he would die out there.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890213-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-13-89 0113EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Salvador-RebelR&amp;R Bjt   02-13 0766</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Salvador-Rebel R&amp;R, Bjt,0791</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rebels Relax As Politicians Debate Their Election Proposal</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY9</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS GRANT MINE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LAS FLORES, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 30 leftist rebels lounge in the shade of tile-roofed porches in the center of this farming town, taking some time to relax while the government considers their proposal to take part in elections. The fighters, some as young as 13, savor soft drinks and snacks out of cellophane bags, flirt with the town's shy girls, cradle babies not seen for weeks or months, play cards with the townfolk. Three rebels, one of them missing half an arm from a prematurely exploded grenade, kick a soccer ball in the cobbled street. There has been a sharp decline in fighting since the <ORGANIZATION> Farabundo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> said last month that it would participate in presidential elections if the March 19 balloting is postponed for six months. The insurgents have also declared a complete truce during the meeting of five Central American presidents taking place in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> today and Tuesday. As the lazy afternoon in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Flores </LOCATION> last week showed, the guerrillas have been permitted at least a brief respite from their arduous life in the mountains. <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Eusebia </PERSON> <PERSON> Benavides </PERSON>, 65, was looking for the son she had n't seen in eight years among the men lounging in the plaza Sitting on a rock beneath its only shade tree, she cast glances full of tentative hope at a tall guerrilla fighter who regarded her with equal anxiety. After a few awkward minutes, the rebel leaned his M-16 against a wall and crossed the 20 yards of sun-baked square separating him from Mrs. <PERSON> Benavides </PERSON>. `` Madre?'' he said, as she _ sure now that they were face to face _ stood. `` My son,'' she said. Mrs. <PERSON> Benavides </PERSON> and her son, who goes by the nom de guerre <PERSON> Ramon </PERSON>, embraced. `` I did n't recognize him at first,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Benavides </PERSON> said later, patting her son on the knee as they sat on a stoop. Smiling a campesino smile with more gaps than teeth, she said, `` He was just a kid when he went away.'' <PERSON> Ramon </PERSON> was on R & amp; R because the insurgents initiate most combat in the nine-year-old war against the U.S.-backed government that has claimed an estimated 65,000 lives. The Jan. 24 guerrilla proposal was a dramatic turnabout: the insurgents would participate in elections if they were postponed and if other security and anti-fraud conditions were met. The reduction in attacks in recent weeks prevents the guerrillas' enemies from accusing them of extending an olive branch with one hand while delivering blows with the other <PERSON> Ramon </PERSON> took from his knapsack a photograph wrapped in plastic of a young woman and a baby. `` This is your grandson and daughter-in-law,'' he said, handing his mother the picture. Mrs. <PERSON> Benavides </PERSON> told of their frustrated attempt at a reunion last October. Advised by a guerrilla `` correo'' _ boys and girls used as messengers _ that <PERSON> Ramon </PERSON> would come down from the mountains to <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Flores </LOCATION>, she made the arduous 10-hour bus trip from her southern province. She waited three days in vain before going home. The day she left, he arrived in town. `` Since no one could give me news of him, I thought he was probably dead. I'm so happy to be able to see him now'' said the old woman, her skin rough and wrinkled from decades of fieldwork. `` I'm in poor health and I know it will be the last time. If the guerrilla proposal is rejected _ as appears likely _ the lull that allows reunions is likely to end. The rebels say they will resume battle with a vengeance. `` The people will realize the government and armed forces are not interested in peace. They'll see there is no alternative but to escalate the struggle,'' said <PERSON> Olga </PERSON>, a mid-level guerrilla officer who uses no other name. At long intervals, bombs exploded on the far side of a hill outside <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Flores </LOCATION>, 35 miles northwest of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. `` Tests,'' said <PERSON> Olga </PERSON>, indicating with her chin the direction of the blasts. Besides resting, the guerrillas are manufacturing and stockpiling what they call `` popular armament'' _ mines, mortars and grenades they make with pipes, powder, wood, rope, burlap, nails and anything else that works. Though they have not definitively rejected it, the Salvadoran armed forces and the government of President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Napoleon </PERSON> <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> and have reacted coolly to the guerrilla proposal. And though the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration has called the guerrilla's proposal `` a step forward,'' there appears to be little chance the overture will prosper
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890213-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-13-89 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Japan-AircraftTechnology     02-13 0879</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan-Aircraft Technology,880</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fighter Deal with Japan Under Fire</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARTON REPPERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
