<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 2332EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Hungary-Opposition     10-22 0347</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hungary-Opposition,0367</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hungarian Opposition Names Presidential Candidate</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TEDDIE WEYR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BUDAPEST, Hungary (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The major opposition group nominated historian <PERSON> Lajos </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuer </PERSON> to run for president in multiparty elections, group leaders said Sunday. The Hungarian Democratic Forum made the nomination at a three-day congress that opened Friday as parliament ended a landmark session in which it adopted laws to open the way for the first multiparty parliamentary elections in more than 40 years. The elections are to be held next year but the presidential balloting is to be held by the end of the year; no date has been set. Subsequent presidents are to be appointed by the new parliament. The ruling <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> is backing <PERSON> Imre </PERSON> <PERSON> Pozsgay </PERSON>, a popular reformer, as its presidential candidate. The parliament created the presidency in constitutional amendments adopted at its last session. After his nomination Sunday, Fuer acknowledged that <PERSON> Pozsgay </PERSON> had built up `` a media advantage,'' but he said he believed he still had a `` good chance of winning.'' The Democratic Forum claims 20,000 members. In his acceptance speech to the 850 delegates, <PERSON> Fuer </PERSON> said: `` We can risk anything for democracy and for <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, but we can not risk Hungarian democracy for anything.'' <PERSON> Fuer </PERSON> said he was dedicated to `` European Christian values.'' He also praised Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, saying that without `` his courage and -LRB- reform -RRB- initiatives, what is happening now here could not have taken place.'' The Democratic Forum is one of several prominent opposition groups that signed an agreement with the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> to hold direct presidential elections before the end of the year. The <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> dissolved itself two weeks ago to create a the new <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. That party professes democratic ideals but continues to hold power until the multiparty elections. Delegates to the Democratic Forum's congress also elected <PERSON> Jozsef </PERSON> <PERSON> Antall </PERSON> as their new chairman. <PERSON> Antall </PERSON> told a news conference that former chairman <PERSON> Zoltan </PERSON> <PERSON> Biro </PERSON> had objected to the group nominating its own presidential candidate. <PERSON> Biro </PERSON> was quoted by the independent daily <PERSON> Mai </PERSON> <PERSON> Nap </PERSON> as saying he considered <PERSON> Pozsgay </PERSON> a `` suitable'' presidential candidate.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 2338EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Boeing     10-22 0350</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Boeing,0360</SECOND>
<HEAD>Boeing, Machinists Leaders Talk, But Not To Each Other</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>'s chairman and the <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION> union on strike against the airplane builder planned to talk about the labor dispute Monday, but not to each other. No new negotiation sessions were scheduled as the strike by 57,800 machinists nationwide enters its 20th day. <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Shrontz </PERSON> was scheduled to speak Monday to a select group of media and business leaders on `` The <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> Strike: The Inside Story.'' The meeting before the <ORGANIZATION> Seattle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Roundtable </ORGANIZATION> will be closed and none of the comments can be published. <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Keiser </PERSON>, communications director of the <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, said she objects that media leaders would agree to such a gathering. `` These are the people who set the tone for news coverage, and they're part of a secret group of the business leaders of <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>,'' she said. `` What kind of corporate dogma are they learning in those meetings?'' The labor council and <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION> union scheduled their own briefing on the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> strike. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lodge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> 751 </ORGANIZATION>, planned to talk to labor leaders in an on-the-record session open to the media and scheduled for the same time as <PERSON> Shrontz </PERSON>'s speech. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Seattle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> vice president and group secretary, said the off-the-record sessions permit speakers to talk candidly without fear their remarks will turn up in headlines. The speakers' remarks often are the same as those they've already made in public forums, he said. The group, founded in 1933 by The <ORGANIZATION> Seattle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> and the chamber, includes members from the Times, <ORGANIZATION> Seattle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post-Intelligencer </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> television stations <ORGANIZATION> KOMO </ORGANIZATION>, KING and <ORGANIZATION> KIRO </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunsire </PERSON>, editorial page editor for the Post-Intelligencer and a member of the group, said he considers the meetings a valuable resource. He likened them to off-the-record briefings given occasionally to newspaper editoral boards. `` If it were up to me, however, these meetings would be on the record,'' <PERSON> Dunsire </PERSON> said. A Wednesday negotiating session called by federal mediator <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON> ended with no progress after several hours.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 2340EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Black     10-22 0122</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Black,0126</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shirley Temple Black Wants Embassy To Sing Blues Away</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The halls are alive _ or soon will be alive _ with the sound of music emanating from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> Temple </PERSON> <PERSON> Black </PERSON>, the former child star and <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s new ambassador to <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>, plans to form a singing group to help keep mission personnel happy, <ORGANIZATION> Newsweek </ORGANIZATION> reports in its Oct. 30 issue. Since <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> employees in that country are barred from socializing with non-governmental Czech people, <PERSON> Black </PERSON> plans to enliven the lives of the lonely Americans with song, the magazine said. Her agenda includes learning the lyrics of `` The Sound of Music,'' Christmas carols, `` and maybe we'll do charades,'' the ambassador said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 2340EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-The'90s-Intro     10-22 0267</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-The '90s-Intro,0270</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Decade of Promise and Peril</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: This may be used as an introductory ``box'' to the periodic
AP series ``The '90s,'' the first installment of which will move shortly.
Advance first for Mon AMs, Oct. 23.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Advances in science and technology promise to make the 10 years that begin this Jan. 1 a decade of unparalleled accomplishment. But damage to the atmosphere, accumulation of solid wastes, the spread of AIDS and other threats also make the 1990s a decade of potential peril. `` By many measures, time is running out,'' warns <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Worldwatch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> In a series of periodic articles over the next month, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> will examine the progress and the challenges expected in the coming decade in such areas as the environment, medicine, space exploration, transportation, computer technology and urban development. The articles, written by AP specialists, will discuss: the `` greenhouse effect'' and other atmospheric problems; cleaning up solid wastes in the next decade; the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> energy picture; the projected growth of the AIDS epidemic; prospects for progress against heart disease and cancer; the future of artificial and transplanted organs; the promise of genetic clues to disease; space exploration in the 1990s; expected advances in mass transportation; the automobiles of the'90s; the dazzling computer technology of the next decade; the demographic outline of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in the 1990s, and the expected urban sprawl of the 1990s. The series will end with a Media General-AP poll on what ordinary Americans expect in the'90s, and a comprehensive article offering an overview of the coming decade.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 2340EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Wray     10-22 0211</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Wray,0217</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fay Wray to Speak at Special Screenings of her Films</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FORT WORTH, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Film legend <PERSON> Fay </PERSON> <PERSON> Wray </PERSON> says she never expected the story of a girl and her ape to have staying power. `` I thought ` King Kong' was an unusual story at the time, but I never thought it would have any endurance to speak of,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Wray </PERSON>, 82, who is to appear here at a weekend film festival. Ms. <PERSON> Wray </PERSON>, a leading lady in 1930s films, said she feels her career includes `` a small body of enduring work, I suppose, to look back on with pride and affection, and somewhat more that I can ignore in good conscience.'' She retired once _ in 1942 _ but returned to acting in the 1950s following her husband's death. She played character parts in handful of forgettable movies, such as `` <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> and the Bachelor'' and `` Dragstrip Riot.'' She also has produced a number of stage plays and her autobiography, `` On the Other Hand'' was issued last winter. Ms. <PERSON> Wray </PERSON>, who lives in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, is scheduled to appear Friday and Saturday at the <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION> Film Festival in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, where she will speak after screenings of `` King <PERSON> Kong </PERSON>,'' `` The Mystery of the Wax Museum,'' and `` The Wedding March.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 2341EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MilitarySchool-Drugs     10-22 0331</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Military School-Drugs,0339</SECOND>
<HEAD>Latin American Military Officials Learning Ways to Fight Drug Trade</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELLIOTT MINOR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COLUMBUS, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s School of the <LOCATION> Americas </LOCATION> is teaching officers from <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> how to fight the narcotics trade. `` The students are concerned about narcotics,'' said Col. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> DePalo </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, commandant of the school at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Benning </LOCATION>. `` They recognize it as not only a threat to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, but it's now become apparent to them through an increased number of drug addicts in their own countries.'' The school, relocated from the <ORGANIZATION> Panama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zone </ORGANIZATION> in 1984 under the terms of the U.S.-Panama canal treaties, trains military personnel from 18 <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> nations, said <PERSON> DePalo </PERSON>. Six new courses are aimed at violent drug traffickers, <PERSON> DePalo </PERSON> said. Subjects include use of ranger units, strategic intelligence and disarming booby traps. The classes range in length from a month to a year. The school has no structured semester-type system, and individual officers set up their own schedules. DePalo, who is fluent in Spanish, visits a Latin American country each month to meet with military leaders, to promote the school and to make sure its courses are relevant. As far as winning the battle against drug trafficking, the key will be in getting the countries to limit and supress the supply, he said. `` They say we need to do more on our end in controlling consumption and they're right,'' <PERSON> DePalo </PERSON> said. `` This thing has to be attacked consistently and unrelentingly, but at least the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> public has awakened to the fact, it appears, that this is a serious national security threat, more serious than the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> at this point.'' The School of the <LOCATION> Americas </LOCATION>, founded in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> in 1947, has trained more than 50,000 officers and enlisted military personnel from <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. It moved to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1984 after this country and <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> were unable to reach an agreement that would have kept it operating in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 2345EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-SFQuake-Lab Bjt   10-22 0834</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SF Quake-Lab, Bjt,830</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quake Turns Northern California Into Giant Laboratory</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT DVORCHAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP National Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Five Soviet engineers came to study building design. Nine Mexicans flew in to check disaster preparedness. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> wanted precise detail on how much the earth moved. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> police looked at emergency response. For all its havoc, last week's earthquake is now an international case study for experts focusing on how and why the earth convulses, what structures survive its tremors, and how to save shaken lives. `` If there's any comfort for the people who lost loved ones, it may be that all professionals learn from each one of these disasters. It means we can do better the next time,'' said <PERSON> Ian </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckle </PERSON>, deputy director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> For </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Earthquake </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineering </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> `` In a sense, it is a laboratory. Teams from around the world will come to learn from this,'' he said. Buckle was appointed by Gov. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON> to investigate the collapse of the elevated, two-tiered section of Interstate 880 in <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>, where people and vehicles were smashed between slabs of concrete and steel. The freeway was built in 1957 before design load requirements were tightened because of lessons learned in the 1971 <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fernando </LOCATION> earthquake, Buckle said. Existing roads and bridges were supposed to be upgraded to conform to new codes. `` New bridges were not just designed for strength but ductility, the ability to be pliable without collapsing. They well knew they had not brought that highway up to code. Maybe this will accelerate that program,'' Buckle said. I-880 was scheduled for improvements, but the state had deferred the work was because officials thought the highway was structurally sound. In their labs, engineers tinker with theories on computers on how to make things strong enough to withstand jolts. Now they can correlate their computer models against what happened in heavily populated <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, just as they learned lessons from quakes in <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. `` We ca n't simulate these forces in a lab. The forces are so large,'' Buckle said. `` We do n't get very many opportunities to test theories or new design roles.'' Not all lessons are technical. Police and fire departments from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>, sent monitors to observe the search and rescue work at I-880, where a burly dockworker was plucked from the crumbled concrete four days after the Tuesday temblor. `` In this business, we all try to learn from each other's disasters, what were the pitfalls and what goes well,'' said <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION> police Sgt <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitman </PERSON>. On Friday, five Soviet engineers walked through <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Marina </LOCATION> district, an upscale neighborhood where as many as 60 buildings crumbled or were damaged beyond repair The <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> experts sought to learn lessons they can use in the rebuilding of <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>, which was rocked earlier this year by an earthquake of similar magnitude. The death toll there was 25,000, blamed partly on shoddy construction of brick and mortar homes. `` Your city is much better than ours was because we had prepared only for a 6.0 <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale earthquake,'' said <PERSON> Nathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Kotylar </PERSON> through an interpretor. Both quakes registered 6.9. A nine-member delegation from <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> came to learn about getting ready for an earthquake because that country was underprepared for the 1985 earthquake that ravaged <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. `` They did not have a national system of disaster preparedness or a civil emergency agency,'' said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Flores </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Earthquake </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Preparedness </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Project </ORGANIZATION>. He said his office had also been contacted by several states hoping to learn from <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s experience, and he expected delegations from <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> when things settle down. `` This was a tragedy, but it would be even more of a tragedy if we did n't learn what we could,'' <PERSON> Flores </PERSON> said. The greatest number of earthquake sleuths concentrated on the epicenter on <LOCATION> Loma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Prieta </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> in the Forest of <LOCATION> Nisene </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Marks </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, 10 miles from <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION>. Two plates of earth slipped 11 miles underground with enough fury to move mountains, flatten freeways, buckle bridges, crumple buildings and interrupt baseball's premier event, the World Series. Geologists and seismologists swarmed the mountain, searching for cracks on the surface that would show where the San Andreas Fault ruptured. Baffled scientists have been unable to locate the main fissure. `` We should see surface displacement of as much as 3 to 4 feet,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Streitz </PERSON>, a geologist with the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Division of Mines and Geology. `` It's a jigsaw puzzle with 10,000 pieces,'' said geologist <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwartz </PERSON>. The quake triggered 90 instruments around the area that had been preset to measure the speed of movement in buildings, structures and the ground. A comprehensive analysis of those readings will take up to a year, although Japanese experts have already asked <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> officials for them via fax machines. Experts will also focus on schools and hospitals to see how they survived. Undamaged structures will be studied for design features that helped them get through.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 2352EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SFQuake-DisasterCenter     10-22 0760</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SF Quake-Disaster Center,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>Disaster Center Long on Volunteers and Information, Short on Victims</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUE MANNING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Volunteer lines were long and stacks of information huge, but the victims were few Sunday at this city's only <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> disaster center And the visits did not change the lives of those who did show up. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> opened seven one-stop disaster relief centers Sunday, one each for the counties affected by last week's earthquake. Volunteers helped people fill out applications for low-interest loans, individual and family grants, temporary housing, counseling, tax information, legal service referrals, Social Security, veteran's benefits or hiring a contractor. The centers opened at 1 p.m. By 3:35 p.m., 126 people had registered at this center set up in a gymnasium at the <LOCATION> Presidio </LOCATION> army base, just blocks from the <LOCATION> Marina </LOCATION> district, one of the areas hardest hit by the 6.9-magnitude quake that struck at 5:04 p.m. Tuesday. By the end of the day, 565 applications for assistance had been submitted to <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> at all seven disaster centers, said <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Cogan </PERSON>. In addition, 6,241 applications had been accepted over a special telephone hotline. Federal officials expressed disappointment at the Presidio turnout. `` Typically we have the longest lines on the first day,'' said <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Allan </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. Only 35 or 40 people were in line when the center opened, he said. At the entrance to the gym, temporary <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> employees waited to help, but they outnumbered victims all afternoon. <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Nash </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jody </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosendin </PERSON>, both <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> volunteers, were concerned about the low turnout. `` It's been a lot slower than we thought,'' Ms. <PERSON> Nash </PERSON> said. `` Most of the people want money right now and we ca n't give them money.'' But doctors, psychologists and counselors were available, she said. `` I just heard about some aid. I have nothing but these clothes,'' said <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Hancock </PERSON>, who lived in one of the Marina apartment houses leveled by an earthquake-triggered fire. `` The apartment building was totally demolished. It burned down. It's not even a pile of rubble. It's a hole,'' said <PERSON> Hancock </PERSON>, a title insurance writer. He's been sleeping and eating at a <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> shelter, although he moved in with a co-worker Sunday. He's spent his days distributing supplies for the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>. `` Just seeing everybody else being so confused and upset, it's contagious and scary,'' he said. <PERSON> Hancock </PERSON> did not leave the relief center with a new place to live or any more clothes, but he took several forms he would fill out for help later. Those included an application for temporary housing that could shelter him for up to a month. But <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> will take at least 72 hours to process that application. <PERSON> Reg </PERSON> and <PERSON> Christine </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> were on their honeymoon in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> when the earthquake struck. They came home to find themselves homeless. `` We've got all our belongings sitting in an apartment we have no access to,'' <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said. They were allowed into their rented apartment in the <LOCATION> Marina </LOCATION> district to gather clothing, but the building is structurally damaged and considered unsafe. The Millers said inspectors had n't decided yet if the building could be repaired. But even if it can, the Millers say they are unsure if they will return permanently. `` We always knew the <LOCATION> Marina </LOCATION> had problems because it is built on a landfill. We saw fourth-floor apartments at the ground floor level and the thought of people being trapped is pretty upsetting,'' <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said. The owner of a four-unit <PERSON> Marina </PERSON> apartment building came to the center to find out what could be done about cracked sidewalks, an open water main, structural cracks, plaster debris and other damage. `` The building has n't been inspected yet, but the building next to it had to be bulldozed,'' the landlord said. He declined to give his name. Helping others has eased the shock and sense of loss for some people, <PERSON> Hancock </PERSON> said. But there are so many little things that people do n't think about. He spent several hours at a bank Saturday proving who he was, without identification papers, so he could access the modest balance in his savings account. He waited in line at a post office to file a change of address form so his mail would go to a co-worker's home rather than a charred, vacant lot. `` I've walked 100 miles in the last couple of days. I see no faces I recognize. Getting word about my neighbors has been almost impossible. It's nuts. It's like nobody ever lived there. I feel like I'm in <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 2354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SFQuake-County-Glance     10-22 0537</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SF Quake-County-Glance,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>County-by-County Damage, Deaths and Injuries</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a county-by-county summary of death, injury and damage reports from Tuesday's earthquake as gathered from the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, other agencies and reporter observations: <LOCATION> ALAMEDA </LOCATION> <LOCATION> COUNTY </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> and communities east of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> -RRB- _ Mile-and-a-quarter-long section of upper deck of Interstate 880 in <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION> collapsed, with 38 bodies recovered from the freeway wreckage so far. One man, 57-year-old Buck Helm of <LOCATION> Weaverville </LOCATION>, was found alive in the wreckage Saturday and was in critical but stable condition at a hospital Sunday. Up to 150 people were evacuated from a housing project Sunday when severe cracks were found in another section of I-880 that borders their apartments. The <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> says <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> sustained 95 percent of the county's 349 injuries and $ 1.5 billion-plus in damages. The <ORGANIZATION> OES </ORGANIZATION> reported 200 businesses, including nine residential hotels, and 1,400 homes were damaged, at least 10 buildings destroyed and 600 people displaced. <LOCATION> SAN </LOCATION> <LOCATION> FRANCISCO </LOCATION> _ Ten deaths, 566 injuries, 1,800 people displaced, most in the devastated <LOCATION> Marina </LOCATION> district. Property losses estimated at $ 2.5 billion. Sixty residential buildings were destroyed in the Marina. More than 1,000 apartment buildings damaged, but no citywide figures were available Sunday on the total number of buildings damaged. About 2,000 Marina residences, including those damaged beyond repair, remained without gas and electric service Sunday. The two main state office buildings near the Civic Center are closed indefinitely because of major structural damage. <LOCATION> SAN </LOCATION> <LOCATION> MATEO </LOCATION> <LOCATION> COUNTY </LOCATION> -LRB- borders <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> to south -RRB- _ No deaths, 282 injuries, damage estimated at $ 350 million. 600 homes damaged, 320 in <LOCATION> Pacifica </LOCATION>. Three businesses destroyed and 600 damaged. Facade of the Amfac Hotel in <LOCATION> Burlingame </LOCATION> collapsed, injuring seven. <LOCATION> SANTA </LOCATION> <LOCATION> CRUZ </LOCATION> <LOCATION> COUNTY </LOCATION> -LRB- south of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mateo </LOCATION> -RRB- _ Four deaths, all in <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION>, 862 injuries and 4,500 people displaced. Damage estimated at $ 1 billion, including $ 83 million to the city of <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION>, where six downtown commercial buildings must be razed. <LOCATION> Watsonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Capitola </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Scotts </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> also hard-hit. Houses in the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION>, site of the 6.9 quake's epicenter, and along the coast lost to fires and landslides County-wide, at least 275 homes destroyed and 2,066 damaged. Several mountain passes closed by landslides and fissures in roads. <LOCATION> SANTA </LOCATION> <LOCATION> CLARA </LOCATION> <LOCATION> COUNTY </LOCATION> -LRB- city of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION> and communities on southeastern end of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> -RRB- _ Five deaths, 650 injuries including 93 people admitted to hospitals. Damage estimate $ 560 million. Sixty-five homes and six businesses destroyed. Damage, including the most minor to severe, to 104,000 dwellings and 384 businesses, according to city reports to county OES. Thirty buildings collapsed in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gatos </LOCATION>, on fringe of <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION>. Highway 17 in <LOCATION> Scotts </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, east of <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION>, closed by rockslide. <LOCATION> SAN </LOCATION> <LOCATION> BENITO </LOCATION> <LOCATION> COUNTY </LOCATION> -LRB- south and east of <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION> -RRB- _ No deaths. Seventy-five minor injuries. Damage estimate $ 100 million. Twelve commercial buildings and light industrial buildings heavily damaged. Thirty-two single-family homes destroyed, 92 homes damaged. MONTEREY COUNTY -LRB- south of <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION> -RRB- _ Two deaths, six injuries. Seventy homes damaged. Damage estimate $ 100 million. <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> sustained $ 3.6 million in damage to 15 homes and 29 businesses. <ORGANIZATION> Moss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Landing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lab </ORGANIZATION>, a university research facility, destroyed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 2354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SFQuake-Weaverville     10-22 0512</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SF Quake-Weaverville,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Happy Townspeople: Big Buck Helm Was ``Too Arrogant to Die''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HAL SPENCER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WEAVERVILLE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Friends of big Buck Helm, latest legend in this misty mountain town, are n't surprised he survived his entombment under a collapsed freeway. They say he's too tough and too proud to die. `` Buck's a happy-go-lucky, generous guy, but let me tell you, I would n't want him mad at me,'' said local inn owner <PERSON> Patsy </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON>. `` He's just too arrogant to die,'' her husband, <PERSON> Bill </PERSON>, said with a grin. `` Now we've got something to brag about besides the fact that we live in the only county in the state without a single traffic light,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON>. `` He's the legend of <LOCATION> Weaverville </LOCATION>. ... This town will throw a big party when Buck gets back, you can bet on it.'' As Helm, 57, lay in a big city hospital bed after almost four days in his car under <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION>'s collapsed I-880, his feat was the main topic in the neon-lit cafes and service stations crowding this town's historic Gold Rush buildings. `` Out of all those people under there, he was the one to get out alive. We're all just so happy,'' said <PERSON> Cathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Heald </PERSON>, another friend, as she sat in Helm's favorite hangout, the Nugget Restaurant. `` I just knew inside he was all right.'' Helm's survival was a shock to <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Whipple </PERSON>, an engineer with the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transporation </ORGANIZATION> who was inspecting the collapsed freeway when he saw a man wave at him through the window of a crushed car. `` It stopped my heart,'' said <PERSON> Whipple </PERSON>. `` I thought maybe the wind was blowing and that's what caused it. I thought I might be losing it.'' About five hours later <PERSON> Helm </PERSON> was carried out of the rubble as exhausted workers cheered. In <LOCATION> Weaverville </LOCATION>, people are aware that <PERSON> Helm </PERSON>'s condition remains critical from the ordeal. `` We're praying for Buck in all our Masses,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON>, pastor at the Roman Catholic church here. `` Everybody is so glad he's alive.'' `` Buck is n't a churchgoer,'' said <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> McConnell </PERSON>, a friend. `` But there is a spirituality about him and that's one of the reasons he survived.'' Across the street from the <LOCATION> Weaverville </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hotel </LOCATION>, a small crowd gathered to await the arrival of a newspaper vendor so they could read front-page news about `` Old Buck.'' `` Buck likes to tell a good story,'' said a laughing <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Nickerson </PERSON>, who waited with the others. `` He'll get to tell this at least 3,500 times.'' <PERSON> Nickerson </PERSON> was referring to the population of <LOCATION> Weaverville </LOCATION>, about 250 miles north of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> Trinity </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION>. The town depends on timber, sportsmen and tourists for its livelihood. Helm has lived here off and on since boyhood. He finally moved his wife and children back for good several years ago. He and his wife, <PERSON> Lorene </PERSON>, have since divorced, but friends say they remain close. Family members rushed to <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> to be with <PERSON> Helm </PERSON>, who spends the work week on the <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> docks, sleeping in a van, and weekends at home.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SFQuake-OaklandHomeless     10-22 0671</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SF Quake-Oakland Homeless,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>More Low-Rent Hotels Condemned, Forcing Poor Into Streets and Shelters</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID FOSTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OAKLAND, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new wave of homeless hit the streets on the weekend as safety inspectors condemned low-rent hotels damaged by <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s devastating earthquake. Evacuees sought refuge in <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> shelters, friends' homes and, when they could afford it, other hotels that may yet be condemned. The number of hotel residents displaced could hit 900 by the time all the city's buildings are inspected, officials said. The evacuations angered many residents, both because they had been allowed to remain in unsafe buildings for so long and because they were given only a few minutes to leave. `` Saturday evening, I came back here and saw all the commotion. People were out on the sidewalk, pretty emotional,'' <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Haines </PERSON>, 52, said Sunday. He was standing outside the condemned Hotel Menlo, wondering when he could return to his room in the eight-story brick building to pick up the rest of his belongings. <PERSON> Haines </PERSON>, whose old apartment was damaged by the quake, moved into the Menlo on Thursday, paying a nonrefundable $ 137 for the week. The building looked fairly sound: the exterior was missing a few bricks and showed a few cracks, and the interior did not appear seriously damaged, <PERSON> Haines </PERSON> said. But engineers decided Saturday that the building had sustained structural damage. The building was condemned and residents were told to leave. `` I got one box of clothes and my shaving gear,'' <PERSON> Haines </PERSON> said. `` That's all I could take. I tried to grab my TV, but they said to leave it.'' He moved to another hotel, but was afraid that it, too, might be condemned, and his cash is running out. <PERSON> Haines </PERSON> hoped to borrow money from co-workers when he returned to his job Monday so he could buy lunch. <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> emergency planner <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Warland </PERSON> said some evacuations were poorly executed, but that officials have changed procedures and now provide bus transportation and more time for residents to gather belongings. `` It's a very volatile situation,'' <PERSON> Warland </PERSON> said. `` They're frustrated and they're frightened They do n't have many possessions, and they're very protective of the possessions they do have.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>, already operating three shelters in <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>, opened another one Sunday to handle the swelling numbers of evacuees. About 400 people used the shelters Saturday night. The <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> was working with the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> to get people into more permanent housing. But that process was frustratingly slow for people who had been cramped inside shelters for days. `` When's this going to end?'' <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Mendonca </PERSON>, 49, said Saturday as he stood outside <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> elementary school, where 160 cots were lined up in the auditorium. Despite the wind-whipped rain, <PERSON> Mendonca </PERSON> said he had to escape the crowded, stuffy shelter for a while. `` I do n't want to be here,'' he said. `` I've got a job. All I do n't have is a pad.'' During the quake, <PERSON> Mendonca </PERSON> ran from his apartment under a shower of falling bricks. Saturday, he was allowed to salvage belongings from his condemned home, only to find that looters had beaten him to it. `` They took my television and ate my food,'' he said. Some shelter occupants said they had been promised more permanent housing by Monday; others said they were told it could be much longer. Many people are staying in their damaged homes, often without electricity or gas, showing up at <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> feeding stations for meals. <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said stations in <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION> were serving about 3,000 meals a day. Some 4,000 customers in the <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION> area were without gas, but <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> said it hoped to restore full service by Monday. A preliminary assessment showed that the quake destroyed or heavily damaged 120 houses, 250 apartment units, and 163 businesses in the communities of <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Leandro </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Hayward </PERSON>, all on the east side of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SFQuake-SurvivorVignettes     10-22 1181</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SF Quake-Survivor Vignettes,1150</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 The deadly earthquake that shook thousands of square miles around <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> last week left those who walked away with stories to tell. Here are six personal recollections from the 1989 earthquake.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By RANDY BURNETT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Garage mechanic, 38, Boulder Creek</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 We were just sitting down, trying to watch the game. Funny thing is, I ca n't tell you what game I was starting to watch. The first instinct I've always had with earthquakes is to wait for it to pass. I did n't want to wait for this one. We got out of the house in a hot hurry. I talked to a few other <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> vets and they all thought they were ` in country' for a minute. It was like a shock akin to an attack. For the next 45 minutes, we checked to see who had gotten hurt. That store -LRB- <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON>'s Place, a general store -RRB- is the whole community thing right there and that's where everybody met. People worked together well, nobody asked questions, they just did. I was running the generator; others were stocking the shelves. People were looking for other people, trying to keep an even keel. It was more like the way things were ` in country.' The worst of it is, the aftershocks are not getting smaller, they're getting larger. In <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, you got to where you could sleep in a certain state. You got to where your body can sleep, but your mind's awake. I think that's what everyone is learning to do now.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>___</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By DANNA FABELLA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Director Alameda County foster care, Oakland</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 I was in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION> at a conference. By the time I got home, boy! the phones were jammed. You could n't get out. My phone was n't working at home I had n't realized how bad my husband was stressed out trying to reach me. He was in <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>. I went to work the next day because I knew we would have some major work to do with the agency. Once I got to work I did n't even think of my own personal life. One of the good things, you get so busy you do n't really think about your own being. When I got home at about 11 that night. I was exhausted and went to bed and did n't even try to call. He called me about 3 in the morning and absolutly cried because he was so upset. I said I was really sorry, because I knew I was OK. I just was so busy trying to organize the workers here that I did n't even think that you would be worried about me. So he was horrified.''
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>___</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By RALPH BEVERLY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Unemployed, 35, San Francisco</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 I was waiting for the World Series to come on. I was sitting on the bed, just kicked back. I was so relaxed and all of a sudden I heard this -LRB- sound -RRB- _ it was like a bang. And I thought, ` Oh, another little earthquake. Cool.' ... But then, it felt like a giant took -LRB- the building -RRB- and shook it. First I looked up and I saw the ceiling, I mean the whole ceiling came down. I mean all of it, at once. I said, `` Oh, no.'' Then ... it shook so hard that the floor cracked. It more than just cracked _ it's like it broke, snapped in half. That's when I really got scared. I've been through earthquakes before, but not like this one. ... I was running for the door, because it kept shaking and they say get under a -LRB- doorway -RRB-. I did that, but that did n't work. Everything just rumbled, so I ran out of the building _ fast. Everything was falling ... the walls were cracking, everywhere. One weird thing, though. Hardly any glass broke _ mostly the wood and plaster, which maybe in one way was lucky. -LRB- I thought -RRB- `` Is this my last day on this Earth?'' They say there's going to be one bigger than this one? Lord help us all, really.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>___</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By RAY NIDDS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Elevator Repairman, 55, San Francisco</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 I'll never forget where I bought my watchband. I was in <ORGANIZATION> Woolworth </ORGANIZATION>'s at Market and <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> when the quake hit. I just slammed my money down on the counter and ran. I said to myself, ` I do n't want to die in <ORGANIZATION> Woolworth </ORGANIZATION>'s.' When the building started shaking, at first I thought it might be from the Muni trains underneath. For a second, I thought the shaking was over, then there was a ` boom' and it was like a giant had picked the building up and slammed it to the ground. I almost knocked over a little old lady on the way to the street. There was broken glass out there and a lot of dust flying. Then I went to my buildings to see if anyone was trapped in elevators. ... I worked until 2 o'clock and they called me at 5:30 or 6 in the morning to come back in to work. We all got about three or four hours' sleep those first two nights.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>___</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By SUZANNE DOWLING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Mother, 22, San Francisco</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 I was taking a nap, actually. <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> -LRB- her 4-year-old son -RRB- was watching cartoons. I heard him scream _ that woke me up _ and everything was really shaking. He ran into the bedroom. I grabbed him and lay down on top of him. The first thing I thought was, ` My God, this is it.' I heard things crashing around, I looked out the bedroom door and saw my refrigerator come out of the kitchen into the living room. When everything stopped, I packed everyone a change of clothes and left. I did n't know what else to do. ... -LRB- It was -RRB- like being in a tunnel underneath a freight train. <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> described it as ` the planet was falling apart.' He thought it was the whole world. He wanted me to call his grandmother in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> and make sure they were OK.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>___</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By DAVID POWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Handyman, 42, Corralitos</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 I had just walked outside -LRB- my girlfriend's home near the Forest of <LOCATION> Nisene </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Marks </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, about 3 miles from the epicenter -RRB-. There was no reason. We talked about it later. We had just walked outside. I immediately said I hope the center was underneath my feet, otherwise there are going to be a lot of people dead. I immediately began to shake. I do n't believe I've stopped yet. It seems to me that the ground shakes every once in a while, but no one else feels it. It seemed to me the ground went down 2 feet then immediately it came back up and kind of rolled around. It was like the ocean going through the ground. You could hear it coming, then you feel it, then you hear it go up there. The worst part of the whole thing was not the earthquake _ it was over suddenly and it was done. The aftershocks were a terror. It's like, now it's happening again, but it does n't happen.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a AM-BRF--Sotheby'sSale     10-22 0167</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Sotheby's Sale,0170</SECOND>
<HEAD>Single Owner Auction Draws Record $131 Million</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The private art collection of the late <ORGANIZATION> Campbell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Soup </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> chairman drew $ 131 million at auction _ the highest total for a single owner's collection, <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION>'s said Saturday. The collection of <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dorrance </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> was sold over four sessions this week and included paintings by <PERSON> Pablo </PERSON> <PERSON> Picasso </PERSON>, <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Monet </PERSON>, <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Gogh </PERSON> and <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Cezanne </PERSON> as well as garden statues, French furniture and assorted porcelain, said <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON> said the <PERSON> Dorrance </PERSON> collection `` possessed strong sense of character which appealed to a wide spectrum of collectors.'' At the first session Wednesday, `` Woman With a Red Umbrella,'' by <PERSON> Henri </PERSON> <PERSON> Matisse </PERSON> drew $ 12.4 million _ a record for the artist. That first session itself eclipsed the previous record for a single owner auction. The previous record for a single owner collection was set last year when the collection of <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> executive, sold for $ 85 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 0011EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SFQuake-HelmFamily     10-22 0299</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-SF Quake-Helm Family,0308</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hopes Were Getting Dim, Family Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFFREY BARNARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OAKLAND, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The family of earthquake survivor Buck Helm was beginning to lose hope before he was dramatically pulled from the wreckage of a crumpled highway, his ex-wife said Saturday. <PERSON> Lorene </PERSON> <PERSON> Helm </PERSON> broke down in tears and cut short a news conference at <LOCATION> Highland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> General </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> as she described how the family learned that Helm had survived. `` By -LRB- Saturday -RRB- our hopes were getting pretty dim, but we said if anybody can make it Buck can make it,'' she said. Ms. <PERSON> Helm </PERSON> said she had been in contact with missing persons officials Saturday morning, providing them with medical information. `` A few minutes later, the children heard there was a possible survivor,'' she said. `` A few minutes after 12 ...'' and she broke down in tears. A son, <PERSON> Marc </PERSON>, then offered `` special thanks to the workers who found my father.'' `` He's a great man,'' <PERSON> Marc </PERSON> said as he turned away from reporters to end the session. Helm works and lives in <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>, but spends weekends 250 miles away in <LOCATION> Weaverville </LOCATION> visiting his children. Family members became concerned immediately after Tuesday's earthquake, Ms. Helm said. `` My daughter contacted me at work and told me there was an earthquake and she feared her dad might be in it,'' she said. They made repeated attempts to phone the area, but could not get through. The next day, they called Helm's employer, the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Longshoremen </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Warehousemen </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, and found that he was not at work and had not phoned in sick. `` Buck is the type of person who unless something is very wrong he's always at work,'' Ms. Helm said. `` Since he had not called his family, we knew something had to be seriously wrong.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 0159EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-HomosexualBan     10-22 0416</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Homosexual Ban,0428</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: Pentagon Rejects Ending Ban Against Homosexuals</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Pentagon has rejected a draft report by a military research center that concludes the armed forces should reconsider their policy of barring homosexuals from the service, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported Sunday. A senior official said in an internal <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> memo that the report was flawed, offensive and wasteful of government resources, the newspaper said. In a statement Friday, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> said the report did not respond to the original research request and has asked the author of the study, Dr. <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarbin </PERSON>, to prepare another report dealing soley with security questions. The unclassified report by the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Personnel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> says the Pentagon should reconsider its policy of barring homosexuals, a conclusion <PERSON> Sarbin </PERSON> said would most likely be repeated in the new report. <PERSON> Sarbin </PERSON> is a research psychologist and part-time consultant at the center. The report and the Pentagon correspondence were made available by members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> who believe the military should stop discriminating against homosexuals and allow them to serve in the armed forces. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>, D-Colo., criticized the Pentagon for rejecting the report `` The report was an excellent academic survey of available literature. The problem is that the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> does n't want to deal with it,'' <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON> told the Times. The internal correspondence that criticized the document said the report went far beyond its job of determining security risks posed by homosexuals in the military while it examined the general question of whether they were suited for the military. The report, which was completed 10 months ago, dealt only briefly with the issue of security. The Pentagon has said that people who engage in homosexual behavior undermine `` discipline, good order and morale.'' In 1982, that policy was expanded to include men and women who have a `` propensity'' to homosexual behavior. The report said the government would probably be forced by court rulings to reconsider its court rulings. The internal <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> correspondence was written by <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Alderman </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, deputy under secretary of <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> for Policy. He said the center responsible for the report had no authority to conduct research on whether homosexuals were suitable for military service. He also said the Pentagon found the report `` to be technically flawed, to contain subject matter -LRB- Judeo-Christian precepts -RRB- which has no place in a <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> publication, -LRB- and -RRB- to reflect significant omissions with respect to relevant court decisions concerning personnel security.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 1051EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-SpaceShuttle 1stLd-Writethru a0689 10-22 0269</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Space Shuttle, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0689,0270</SECOND>
<HEAD>Astronauts Prepare For Early Return to Earth</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 4 grafs to UPDATE with Atlantis coming home three
hours early, sted 90 minutes. PICKS UP 4th graf pvs, `The astronauts ...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> told <ORGANIZATION> Atlantis </ORGANIZATION>' astronauts Sunday to come home three hours early on Monday to avoid high winds at the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> landing site. Flight controllers had been working on a plan to land one orbit early but decided after looking at the forecast to shorten the flight by two orbits because of high winds expected in the afternoon. Each orbit takes 90 minutes. The new landing time at <ORGANIZATION> Edwards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION> Mojave </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Desert </LOCATION> is 9:33 a.m. PDT. To prepare for the return, commander <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> and pilot <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> McCulley </PERSON> tested Atlantis' flight control systems and reported them in good condition. The astronauts were awakened Sunday with the <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Fogarty </PERSON> song `` Center Field'' _ the second wakeup call of the night. Earlier, an alarm sounded, signaling a high temperature reading on an auxiliary power unit heater. A crew member solved the problem by adjusting a sticky thermostat and shifting the position of the shuttle so the section of the vehicle housing the unit was not in the sun. Later Sunday, the five crew members planned to hold a news conference in space, answering questions from reporters at the Johnson Space Center in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>. The Galileo probe they dispatched Wednesday continued to perform well as it sped along more than 800,000 miles from Earth on a 2.4-billion-mile, six-year trip to <ORGANIZATION> Jupiter </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 1058EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-TrainCollision 1stLd-Writethru a0699 10-22 0192</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Train Collision, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0699,0191</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Injured in Train Collision</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 3 grafs to UPDATE with two engines also derailed,
3rd person injured was Amtrak employee; PICKS UP 4th graf, `One of ...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>UPPER SANDUSKY, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An <ORGANIZATION> Amtrak </ORGANIZATION> passenger train and a freight train collided Sunday, injuring three people, authorities said. The <ORGANIZATION> Amtrak </ORGANIZATION> train, traveling from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, collided at 5:43 a.m. with a <ORGANIZATION> CSX </ORGANIZATION> train, said <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Hare </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> Amtrak </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman. Two <ORGANIZATION> Amtrak </ORGANIZATION> engines, a freight car and an <ORGANIZATION> Amtrak </ORGANIZATION> baggage car derailed, authorities said. An <ORGANIZATION> Amtrak </ORGANIZATION> engineer and firefighter were injured, Ms. <PERSON> Hare </PERSON> said. Hospital officials said a third <ORGANIZATION> Amtrak </ORGANIZATION> employee also was taken for treatment. One of the injured had a minor fracture, said <ORGANIZATION> Wyandot </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> administrator <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Harbaugh </PERSON>. The condition of the others was not immediately known. It was not known why the trains were on the same track, officials said. Investigators from the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> were expected to arrive later. Sheriff <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hetzel </PERSON> said about 220 peoplewere aboard the <ORGANIZATION> Amtrak </ORGANIZATION> train. Buses were sent from <LOCATION> Toledo </LOCATION> to take them farther west, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 1123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--CollegeCarnage     10-22 0129</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--College Carnage,0131</SECOND>
<HEAD>42 Injured, College Closed After Students Trade Gunfire</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DHAKA, Bangladesh (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Student groups trying to hang banners on the same gate broke into an argument that escalated into a gunbattle, police said Sunday. At least 42 people were wounded. Police said the trouble broke out Saturday when members of the Islamic Student Forum and a coalition of 16 secular groups tried at the same time to hang banners from the gate at <ORGANIZATION> Mohand </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chand </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in the northeastern town of <LOCATION> Sylhet </LOCATION>. Ten of the injured were in serious condition, <LOCATION> Sylhet </LOCATION> police said, speaking on condition of anonymity. The college was closed for the rest of the month, they added. <LOCATION> Sylhet </LOCATION>, 120 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION>, is in the heart of <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION>'s main tea-growing region.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 1124EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Reagan     10-22 0511</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Reagan,0527</SECOND>
<HEAD>Japanese Salute Reagan at Gala Benefit</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos upcoming.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELAINE KURTENBACH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>YOKOHAMA, Japan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With a chorus of `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> the Beautiful,'' the Japanese paid a warm tribute to former President <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and his wife <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> at a gala benefit concert Sunday. The concert, organized to benefit the <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> Presidential Library, began and ended with the patriotic song and featured <PERSON> Perry </PERSON> <PERSON> Como </PERSON>, <PERSON> Placido </PERSON> <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Harlem </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boys </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Choir </ORGANIZATION> and Japanese stars <PERSON> Yuzo </PERSON> <PERSON> Kayama </PERSON> and <PERSON> Toshihiko </PERSON> <PERSON> Tahara </PERSON>. `` You'll never know, <PERSON> Ron </PERSON>, how much we need you. Please come here with <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> to stay,'' went the final tribute, set to the tune of `` You Are My Sunshine.'' The concert was organized by the <ORGANIZATION> Fujisankei </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, which is sponsoring the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION>' visit at a cost of $ 7 million. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Fujisankei </LOCATION> have refused to confirm reports he is being paid $ 2 million for his appearances. The Reagans waved to the audience and performers and sang along with them in a final chorus of `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> the Beautiful.'' Scenes of events during <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s presidency were shown on huge video screens near the stage, which was lit in pastel pink, lavender and blue. The scenes were subtitled with phrases praising <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> for `` restoring public confidence in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'' and helping to `` maintain peace throughout the world.'' The audience of more than 10,000 paid $ 35 to $ 70 to attend the event at <LOCATION> Yokohama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arena </LOCATION>, 18 miles south of <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. `` I thank you for your interest in the presidential library ... I want to thank all of you,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said in brief comments after the concert. `` I'm at a loss for words.'' Earlier, the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> toured a mountainside art museum in <LOCATION> Hakone </LOCATION>, 63 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, owned by <LOCATION> Fujisankei </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> stopped along the way to shake hands with delighted Japanese museum - goers but did not respond to reporters' questions about his reported fee Fujisankei, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s largest media group, owns the newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Sankei </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shimbun </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Fuji </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telecasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Nippon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hoso </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s biggest commercial radio network, among dozens of other companies Like its chairman, <PERSON> Nobutaka </PERSON> <PERSON> Shikanai </PERSON>, many of the company's media outlets espouse conservatism and nationalism At the time of Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s death and the controversy it spawned over his role in World War II, the <ORGANIZATION> Fuji </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> TV </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> network </ORGANIZATION> generally carried few critical views of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s imperial system. The network's low-brow programming contrasts sharply with the company's impressive art collections, including its outdoor sculpture garden in <LOCATION> Hakone </LOCATION>. On Monday, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> begins the two-day official portion of his visit, during which he will meet with Prime Minister <PERSON> Toshiki </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON>, Emperor <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON> and other Japanese leaders. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will receive other tributes during his visit. The Japanese government plans to award him the Grand Cordon of the Supreme Order of the Chrysanthemum _ one of its highest honors _ for promoting friendship between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and working to protect the free trade system during his eight years in office. The only other <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> president to receive the honor was <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON>. The Reagans are scheduled to return to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> Oct. 28.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 1124EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Cheney     10-22 0102</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cheney,0105</SECOND>
<HEAD>American Defense Secretary Starts Foreign Tour</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Defense Secretary <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> arrived in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> on Sunday on the first stop of a three-week foreign tour that will focus on the changing situation in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and the reduction of conventional military forces. Cheney scheduled meetings with <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> Defense Minister <PERSON> Jean-Pierre </PERSON> <PERSON> Chevenement </PERSON>, Premier <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Rocard </PERSON>, and other officials. He leaves Monday for <LOCATION> Portugal </LOCATION> for two days of <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> talks, then heads for <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>. He also will be visiting with American military forces abroad. <LOCATION> Cheney </LOCATION> is expected back in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> on Nov. 10.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 1125EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Kuwait-Arms     10-22 0197</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Kuwait-Arms,0201</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kuwait Shelves Plans to Buy Mirage 2000s</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KUWAIT (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A senior military commander was quoted Sunday as saying that <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> has decided against buying French-made Mirage 2000 jet fighters because it has enough <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warplanes to meet its needs. It was the first remark by a senior <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> official that the government had decided against purchasing the French warplanes. Both the emir, <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaber </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Sabah </PERSON>, and Defense Minister <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Nawaf </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Sabah </PERSON> said last month that <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> had not yet decided whether to buy the sophisticated planes. Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Jaber </PERSON> <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Sabah </PERSON>, deputy chief of staff of the armed forces, told the daily <ORGANIZATION> Al-Anbaa </ORGANIZATION> that a deal with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for 40 F-18 warplanes is enough to fulfill <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>'s needs for the time being. `` <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> considers the F-18 warplane suitable for its air force,'' he said. `` But this does not mean that other planes are inferior to it. The Kuwaiti air force is not in need of more arms.'' The $ 1.8 billion deal for the F-18s was concluded during a visit to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> last year by Crown <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> and Prime Minister <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Saad </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Abdullah </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Sabah </PERSON>. Delivery starts in 1994.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 1125EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--BusAccident     10-22 0127</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Bus Accident,0129</SECOND>
<HEAD>25 Killed When Bus Overturns</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JAKARTA, Indonesia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A bus overturned on a road east of <LOCATION> Jakarta </LOCATION> on Sunday, killing at least 25 people and injuring dozens of others, police said. The bus was carrying 78 people from <LOCATION> Purbolinggo </LOCATION> in central Java to <LOCATION> Jakarta </LOCATION> when it overturned 16 miles east of the capital, said a police officer. The police officer, who spoke on condition of anonymity, would not give further details. The newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Suara </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pembaruan </ORGANIZATION> said about 40 people were injured. The bus was being driven at high speed and had passed some other vehicles before the accident, the newspaper quoted a passenger as saying. The passenger said the bus went out of control and hit an overpass support before it overturned.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 1126EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-China     10-22 0413</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China,0424</SECOND>
<HEAD>Paper Denounces Writer, Says He'll Be Punished</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An official newspaper accused a well-known <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> writer and dissident of `` polluting the thinking of youth'' by taking part in the spring pro-democracy movement and said he will be punished. The blistering commentary, which was published Friday and seen in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> on Sunday, was the first public attack on 71-year-old <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruowang </PERSON>, a prolific essayist who was put under house arrest in June. `` <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> is a writer in name, but his fame comes not from some outstanding writing but from some people calling him a ` democracy fighter,''' the Shanghai-based newspaper <PERSON> Wen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hui </PERSON> <PERSON> Bao </PERSON> said in a half-page commentary. `` He even attacked Comrade <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON>, calling him a ` power behind the throne,' and saying that ` the days when 1.1 billion people will submit to a monarch are over.''' An unknown number of students, professors, writers and other intellectuals have been jailed since the army crushed the democracy movement in June. <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> papers since have reported <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> was taken into custody, but efforts to telephone his home for confirmation were unsuccessful. <PERSON> Wen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hui </PERSON> <PERSON> Bao </PERSON> did not say where <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> was but said: `` In the end he will be punished according to the law,'' indicating he faces trial. <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> has been jailed both by the Nationalists, for supporting the Communist revolution, and by the Communists, for criticizing their failures. For years, the official media and publishers have refused to print his works, but he found an outlet in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> publications. <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> was one of three intellectuals expelled from the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in 1987 after an earlier series of student protests. One of the others was <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s most famous dissident, <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> <PERSON> Lizhi </PERSON>. When government controls eased in 1988, <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> and other intellectuals founded a journal, `` The New Enlightment,'' that published daring, probing essays on subjects such as alienation in a socialist society. He marched along with students in <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> during the spring democracy movement. <PERSON> Wen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hui </PERSON> <PERSON> Bao </PERSON> quoted him as saying during the protests: `` The day I have longed for has arrived. ... One thing is certain, once this student movement has begun, it can not be repressed.'' `` For so many years <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> has used his tongue and poor pen to oppose socialism and incite counterrevolution,'' <PERSON> Wen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hui </PERSON> <PERSON> Bao </PERSON> said. `` His falsehoods and heresies won the acclaim of some people and the cheap applause of some immature youth. Now his set of tricks has been exposed.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 1127EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-China-Quake     10-22 0529</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-Quake,0545</SECOND>
<HEAD>Village Rebuilds From Killer Quake</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-SF Quake, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Wan </PERSON> <PERSON> Degui </PERSON> had just moved into a new house with three rooms when the earth came alive beneath his small village. `` I only lived in it for 12 days,'' he matter-of-factedly told a Western reporter touring the region. `` But when the quake hit, it just collapsed.'' Wan, like other peasants in <LOCATION> Guiren </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Village </LOCATION> in northern <LOCATION> Shanxi </LOCATION> province, made few demands of the government after the worst quakes the region has seen in more than a decade. `` If we can resolve it ourselves, we will. If not, we will rely on what the government can do,'' Wan said, but added, `` what the government can not do we will have to do ourselves.'' The first of six strong tremors hit Wednesday night, and the others followed Thursday, leaving 29 people dead and 50,000 homeless. In a sympathy telegram sent Sunday to the quake-struck area in <LOCATION> Shanxi </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hebei </LOCATION> provinces, about 135 miles west of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, the government called on residents to show a `` spirit of hard struggle and self-reliance.'' Wan's neighbor, <PERSON> Guan </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON>, was doing his best. As the sun set Saturday, he was still sawing boards for the frame of a makeshift shelter he hoped would get him and his family of three through the winter. His house collapsed, as did 95 percent of the homes in his farm village of about 2,400 people set on a dusty, barren plain. Five people were crushed to death, and two were injured, Wan said. The homes were mainly one-story structures of packed clay with some stones and bricks to help hold them together. Three days after the quakes, villagers set up housekeeping in tents of straw and quilts. Their pigs and horses roamed the dirt paths. `` I was inside the house watching television, when I heard a loud sound, like thunder. When the ground started to shake, we rushed outside,'' said <PERSON> Guan </PERSON>. `` After the third quake, most of the houses had collapsed,'' he said. His cat was crushed to death. His wife, young son, dog and another cat escaped. His house in ruins around him, <PERSON> Guan </PERSON> still offered guests a traditional warm welcome, pulling out a red vinyl-padded folding chair and a glass of hot water boiled over an outdoor stove. His family has been sleeping since the quake in a straw tent, but soldiers who arrived in the village Friday were helping him build a stronger, although still temporary shelter. `` Yesterday there were five soldiers, today there were eight,'' he said. Altogether, several hundred soldiers came to the village, residents reported, bringing clothing, instant noodles, crackers and bowls. No one complained about the slowness of reconstruction efforts or the government's failure to immediately provide shelter for the homeless, who have huddled around fires and under makeshift tents during the near-freezing nights. `` Every family is living like this,'' <PERSON> Guan </PERSON> said. `` We have no other choice.'' `` My lips have blisters from the cold and my entire body is uncomfortable,'' said <PERSON> Liu </PERSON> <PERSON> Rongxiang </PERSON>, a matronly woman who was bundled in several sweaters and a quilted jacket. `` My only hope now is to have a home, whether it's good or bad.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 1127EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BRF--BlazeLawsuit     10-22 0144</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Blaze Lawsuit,0147</SECOND>
<HEAD>Settlement in Suit Claiming Bored Guard Set Fire</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GAINESVILLE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A security company has agreed to pay $ 8.75 million to settle a lawsuit that claimed an industrial fire was started by a bored night guard who passed the time by tossing flaming paper balls at a trash can. The <ORGANIZATION> Wells </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fargo </ORGANIZATION> guard acknowledged tossing the fireballs in 1985 but said he extinguished them before continuing his rounds. That was just before flames destroyed <ORGANIZATION> Vital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION>' main plant, which made video equipment for TV studios. Attorney <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Cunningham </PERSON> confirmed Friday that the settlement had been reached between his clients _ Vital and <ORGANIZATION> Firemen </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> _ and <ORGANIZATION> Baker </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION>, parent corporation of <ORGANIZATION> Wells </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fargo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. The 1986 suit alleged that <PERSON> Wells </PERSON> <PERSON> Fargo </PERSON> failed to check the background of the newly employed guard, train him and supervise him.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 1127EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BRF--AbortionSession     10-22 0148</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Abortion Session,0151</SECOND>
<HEAD>Abortion Special Session Cost an Estimated $500,000</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TALLAHASSEE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION>'s two-day special session on abortion produced no laws but will probably end up the most expensive such exercise in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> history. A survey of agencies involved in the session determined that spending totaled more than $ 473,000, with some reporting outstanding bills that are likely to push the cost to more than $ 500,000. Most special sessions cost about $ 40,000 per day, but past sessions did not involve as much planning and security as the Oct. 10-11 one on abortion. More than 600 law enforcement officers stood guard while some 20,000 people demonstrated on both sides of the issue. Gov. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> called the session to take advantage of a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruling in July allowing more curbs on abortion. Fourteen bills died in committees without reaching the floor of either house.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 1128EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r e AM-GreatestAlbums     10-22 0265</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Greatest Albums,0275</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Clash Heads Rolling Stone LP List</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> Calling,'' by the swaggering rock group the Clash, topped a list of the 100 greatest albums of the 1980s picked by the editors of <ORGANIZATION> Rolling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stone </ORGANIZATION>. `` The 100 Greatest Albums of the'80s,'' selected by 10 editors of the magazine, appears in the Nov. 16 issue. The Clash, a now defunct band whose lyrics featured aggressive working-class politics that became the staple of the punk movement, recorded `` <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> Calling'' in 1980. The rest of the top 10, in descending order, are: `` Purple Rain,'' by <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> and the Revolution; `` The <PERSON> Joshua </PERSON> <PERSON> Tree </PERSON>,'' by the Irish rock group U2; `` Remain in Light,'' by the Talking Heads; `` Graceland,'' by <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>; `` Born in the <LOCATION> U.S.A. </LOCATION>'' by <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Springsteen </PERSON>; `` Thriller,'' by <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>; `` Murmur,'' by R.E.M.; `` Shoot Out the Lights,'' by <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> and <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, and `` <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>,'' by folk singer <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>. The surprise listing is the record by the <PERSON> Thompsons </PERSON>, whose album did n't make the charts but was critically acclaimed when <ORGANIZATION> Hannibal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION> released it in 1982. Nostalgia was a big factor on the list. Forty-nine of the albums were released from 1980 through 1983. And the five 1989 releases on the list are by artists who made their claims to fame during an earlier time. They are: `` <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>,'' by <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON>, No. 19; `` Oh Mercy,'' by <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dylan </PERSON>, No. 44; `` Freedom,'' by <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, No. 85; `` Steel Wheels,'' by the <ORGANIZATION> Rolling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stones </ORGANIZATION>, No. 87, and `` Full Moon Fever,'' by <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Petty </PERSON>, No. 92.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 1128EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-CarouselAuction     10-22 0409</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Carousel Auction,0421</SECOND>
<HEAD>Antique Carousel Sold, Animal by Animal, in Auction</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER VILES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIDDLEBURY, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It was enough to make a little girl cry. The hand-carved carousel at Quassy Amusement Park, a favorite of <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> children since 1919, was auctioned off piece by piece to high-rolling antiques dealers and collectors for a total of $ 638,000. By Saturday afternoon, the four dozen wooden horses, zebras, giraffes and other animals that had ridden together for decades were being separated and taken to faraway places like <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state. `` It chokes you up a lot more than you thought it would,'' said <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Frantzis </PERSON>, whose family has owned the amusement park for three decades. The merry-go-round was built in 1902. Quassy bought it in 1919 and operated it until this summer. Experts say only about 70 hand-carved wooden carousels remain of the estimated 6,000 that dotted the American landscape at the turn of the century. The Quassy carousel fell victim to a trend _ a bidding frenzy among private art collectors that has caused the value of antique carousels to skyrocket. The <PERSON> Frantzis </PERSON> family said it could no longer afford to maintain or insure the carousel and decided to replace it with one made of fiberglass. Bidding opened when <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Filler </PERSON>, a scrap-iron dealer from <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, bid $ 20,000 on the prize of the carousel, a lion. <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> antiques dealer <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Pemberton </PERSON> outbid Filler, offering $ 60,000. He said he would restore the lion and sell it. `` We've never had a lion and we wanted to get one,'' <PERSON> Pemberton </PERSON> said. One after another, the wooden animals were sold _ sea horses, camels, reindeers, a tiger and a goat. A camel went for $ 25,000, a tiger for $ 45,000, a giraffe for $ 27,500, and finally, the Wulitzer organ went for $ 21,500. Filler ended up buying six animals. The <PERSON> Frantzis </PERSON> family had hoped a collector would purchase the entire carousel and keep it intact, but no one came forward. Schoolchildren in <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Saybrook </LOCATION> even wrote to <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>, asking him to buy the merry-go-round. But <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> was not in the park when bidding on the individual pieces was complete and auctioneer <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Norton </PERSON> offered one last chance to keep the colorful herd together. A bid of $ 766,000 _ 20 percent above the total of the separate bids _ would have saved the carousel. No one raised a hand. `` The machine has been sold piecemeal!'' <PERSON> Norton </PERSON> shouted.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0029 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 1130EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-WinnieMandela Bjt   10-22 1002</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Winnie Mandela, Bjt,1029</SECOND>
<HEAD>Winnie Mandela Returns to Forefront of Opposition Politics</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto JOH1</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GREG MYRE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SOWETO, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government banned her, the anti-apartheid movement censured her and potential legal battles cloud her future. But <PERSON> Winnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> has survived and is reclaiming her role as one of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s most prominent and defiant activists. Mrs. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>, wife of jailed <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>, vanished from public view in February when leading anti-apartheid groups repudiated her and accused her self-appointed bodyguards of waging `` a reign of terror.'' In recent weeks, however, Mrs. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> has emerged with high-profile appearances at several opposition rallies. The relentless speculation about her husband's release, expected within several months, keeps her at the center of the political stage. `` She is blunt, rash, emotional and speaks from the heart _ that is why people respond to her and why she is controversial,'' said <PERSON> Fatima </PERSON> <PERSON> Meer </PERSON>, author of a best-selling biography of <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>. `` Even during the crisis, <PERSON> Winnie </PERSON> had the support and loyalty of many, many people,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Meer </PERSON> said in an interview. `` She will remain highly visible and widely respected.'' When six of <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>'s closest <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> colleagues were freed from prison Oct. 15, Mrs. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> accommodated one of them, <PERSON> Wilton </PERSON> <PERSON> Mkwayi </PERSON>, at her home in <LOCATION> Soweto </LOCATION>, the huge black township outside <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>. She appeared that day at a rally for the freed prisoners. She prepared to sit alongside them at a news conference, but activists who organized the meeting politely directed her to a seat behind the <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> leaders. The releases are widely seen as a trial run for freeing <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>, 71, the country's best known black leader and possibly the world's most famous prisoner His release is considered necessary before black leaders _ even relatively conservative ones _ will negotiate with the white-led government. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> lives in a suburban-style ranch house on a prison farm outside <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Town </LOCATION>. In recent months he has met several times with his wife, as well as with anti-apartheid leaders who denounced her. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> reportedly told his wife not to talk to the press. She remained silent for several months but has begun to speak out again. `` I am of no significance to anybody as an individual,'' she told <ORGANIZATION> Tribute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Magazine </ORGANIZATION>. `` To attack me is to attack <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>, to attack the <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION>.'' There has been no formal public reconciliation between Mrs. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> and the anti-apartheid movement, but the overt criticism of her has stopped. One activist who requested anonymity said anti-apartheid groups are attempting to resolve their disputes with Mrs. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> before her husband is released, `` but several problems remain.'' He refused to elaborate. Several anti-apartheid leaders, including some who earlier denounced Mrs. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> for `` violating human rights in the name of the struggle against apartheid,'' refused recently to speak about her on the record. The <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> has expressed concern about some of her statements, and spokesman <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Sebina </PERSON>, based in <LOCATION> Lusaka </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Zambia </LOCATION>, noted she has no formal position in the organization. But he added that Mrs. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> `` remains an important part of the struggle.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>'s provocative statements and courageous defiance of government restrictions made her one of the most visible symbols of black resistance. Her followers often referred to her as `` Mother of the Nation.'' She married <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> in 1958, when she was a 24-year-old social worker and he was a 40-year-old <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> leader. Four years later he was arrested, and he has been imprisoned ever since. She was under police restrictions almost continuously from 1963 to 1986, was arrested numerous times and held in solitary confinement for 17 months in 1969-70. The repeated police action only inspired defiance in Mrs. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>, now 55 and the mother of two grown daughters. She often appeared at funerals of slain activists, dressed in flowing dresses of black, green and gold _ the colors of the outlawed <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> _ to give fiery speeches and clenched-fist salutes. But her questionable political judgment, sometimes imperious style and reluctance to consult with anti-apartheid groups led her into repeated conflict with both the white authorities and the black community. Long-simmering disputes boiled over early this year when Mrs. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>'s bodyguards, known as the <ORGANIZATION> Mandela </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> soccer club, were accused of abducting four youths and beating one of them, 14-year-old <PERSON> Stompie </PERSON> <PERSON> Seipei </PERSON>, to death. Nine people associated with the club are in custody for the boy's death. He allegedly was kidnapped by the soccer team in December and beaten at Mrs. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>'s home. <PERSON> Seipei </PERSON>'s body was found in a field, and the other three youths have given affidavits implicating members of <ORGANIZATION> Mandela </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION>. The group seldom played soccer, but often stayed at Mrs. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>'s home and accompanied her at public appearances. They were involved in repeated confrontations with police, journalists and local street gangs. The accused, in custody since February, have pleaded innocent. No trial date has been set. Anti-apartheid groups said in February they were `` outraged at Mrs. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>'s complicity in the abductions and assault of <PERSON> Stompie </PERSON>.'' She has denied any wrongdoing. Police Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Jaap </PERSON> <PERSON> Joubert </PERSON>, who headed the investigation, declined to comment when asked if she might be charged. The death of <PERSON> Seipei </PERSON> was one of several controversies that have dogged Mrs. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> since she unilaterally lifted her police banning order in 1985. At a rally in 1986, she endorsed the `` necklace'' killings, whereby militant activists torched gasoline-soaked tires placed around necks of suspected government collaborators. The government then lifted the ban on quoting Mrs. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> in the apparent belief she would do more harm to her reputation by speaking out than by being silenced. In 1987, she was sharply criticized for building a mansion on a hillside in <LOCATION> Soweto </LOCATION>, surrounded by tiny, overcrowded matchbox houses. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> reportedly has told his wife not to move into the house. The <ORGANIZATION> Mandelas </ORGANIZATION>' small rented home was burned in a July 1988 arson attack by <LOCATION> Soweto </LOCATION> youths feuding with the soccer club. Community leaders urged Mrs. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> to disband the team, but she ignored their advice.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0030 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 1131EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Israel-Europe     10-22 0149</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Israel-Europe,0152</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israel to Open New Embassy to European Community</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> will soon open a new embassy in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> to handle relations with the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said Sunday. The embassy, which will be in addition to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s embassy to <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Luxembourg </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION>, will open once a building is found and an ambassador appointed, said the spokesman, who traditionally is not identified by name. Foreign Minister <PERSON> Moshe </PERSON> <PERSON> Arens </PERSON> will hold a two-day meeting in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> starting Monday with Israeli diplomats in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s relationship with the European trade bloc after it becomes an integrated market in 1992, the spokesman said. The 12-nation group plans to lift virtually all trade barriers between them in three years. <PERSON> Arens </PERSON> also will meet with officials of <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Luxembourg </LOCATION> on a European visit that will last from Monday to Thursday, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891022-0031 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-89 1145EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Brites     10-22 0340</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Brites,0354</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bright &amp; Brief</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SALT LAKE CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
