<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891211-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-11-89 2350EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AmputeeCheerleader     12-11 0242</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Amputee Cheerleader,0251</SECOND>
<HEAD>Double Amputee Cheers Her Team On</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BUCYRUS, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When she was born, <PERSON> Beth </PERSON> <PERSON> Cole </PERSON>'s doctors said she would never be able to walk, but the 14-year-old high school freshman has overcome congenital bone defects and is now a cheerleader. After enduring years of operations, including amputation of both feet, she attends <ORGANIZATION> Wynford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Royals </ORGANIZATION> basketball games, wearing artificial limbs that fit over the calf up to the knee. `` My parents and God have helped me,'' she said before dashing onto the court at a recent basketball game. `` She has the guts and potential that are God-given,'' said her father, <PERSON> William </PERSON>. `` We take very little credit. She's done it on her own.'' At birth, <PERSON> Beth </PERSON>'s hips were dislocated and the bones in her legs were n't formed. Doctors said she would never walk. At three months, doctors wrapped her body in a full cast, hoping to straighten her hips. She wore the cast until she was 11 months old. After hundreds of treatments by specialists at <ORGANIZATION> Shriners </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> for Crippled Children in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, she finally decided at age 10 to undergo amputation instead of bone fusion. After the first amputation, she walked into her fourth-grade classroom on the first day of school with a prosthesis on her right leg and a pair of crutches. She underwent the second amputation in June 1988, but only after playing for the seventh-grade girls volleyball team and trying out for cheerleading.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891211-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-11-89 2343EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Germany-Degree 1stLd-Writethru a0642 12-11 0762</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Germany-Degree, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0642,0786</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Yorker Gets Degree 56 Years After Fleeing Nazis</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: CORRECTS throughout spelling of name from Rubenstein to Rubinstein.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE BOEHMER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FRANKFURT, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than a half-century after fleeing the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION>, 81-year-old <PERSON> Nina </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubinstein </PERSON> on Monday received her doctorate in sociology at <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION> university. `` It's the last thing I expected in my life,'' said <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubinstein </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. `` I'm elated, I'm proud, I'm surprised.'' The dean of <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Johann </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolfgang </PERSON> <PERSON> Goethe </PERSON> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s sociology department, <PERSON> Lothar </PERSON> <PERSON> Brock </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubinstein </PERSON> was awarded the degree magna cum laude It was a big surprise for the retired <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> interpreter, who was 25 when she fled the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION> in 1933, leaving behind her completed 247-page thesis for her doctorate. She first fled to <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and then to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, when <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>'s troops marched on <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. `` I'm not particularly proud of myself in general, but I thought the dissertation was rather good,'' Miss <PERSON> Rubinstein </PERSON> said. It was delivered in German. `` But frankly I did not expect a magna cum laude. That was a very enormous surprise,'' she said, chuckling. Miss <PERSON> Rubinstein </PERSON> arrived in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> last week to take part in a colloquium Friday, part of 75th anniversary celebrations at the universtiy's social sciences department. `` I'm absolutely shattered. I think I never have been so exhausted, not only physically, but psychologically too, after that day on Friday,'' the soft-spoken Miss <PERSON> Rubinstein </PERSON> said. As part of the colloquium, Miss <PERSON> Rubinstein </PERSON> read several poems, taking an active part in the ceremonies, said Professor <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Kettler </PERSON>, who was instrumental in arranging for her to get the degree. <PERSON> Kettler </PERSON>, of <ORGANIZATION> Trent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Peterborough </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ontario </LOCATION>, said it took him a year, along with <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubinstein </PERSON>'s half-sister, <PERSON> Hanna </PERSON> <PERSON> Papanek </PERSON>, to make arrangements for awarding the doctorate. `` It was like one of those ideas you suddenly have in the shower,'' <PERSON> Kettler </PERSON> said. `` This is the university facing up to its responsibility to its students and faculty. She did the work and deserves to be recognized for it.'' Miss <PERSON> Rubinstein </PERSON> was born in <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> in 1908 to parents of Jewish descent, who fled their native <LOCATION> Latvia </LOCATION> as political exiles after the failed Russian revolution of 1905. She lived in neutral <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> from 1914 through 1917, where she had fled with her mother to avoid World War I. Later she returned to <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> to study, and in 1928 began working toward her degree under the noted sociology professor, <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> <PERSON> Mannheim </PERSON>. Miss <PERSON> Rubinstein </PERSON> recalled how she enjoyed being in Mannheim's presence, and how the students used to meet him at Cafe <PERSON> Laumer </PERSON> in the university area of <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Bockenheim </LOCATION> district `` We very often met there with <PERSON> Mannheim </PERSON>. Of course, all the young ladies there adored him, he was extremely attractive, I've never forgotten that,'' she said Miss <PERSON> Rubinstein </PERSON> then pointed out photographs showing herself, and other students reading and chatting at the cafe with Mannheim, taken between 1930 and 1933. `` He went to <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> right away'' after the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION> came, Miss <PERSON> Rubinstein </PERSON> said. `` I never saw him again. I lost contact with him.'' <PERSON> Mannheim </PERSON>, who last worked at the <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economics </ORGANIZATION>, had published dozens of manuscripts on sociology, including `` Man and <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> in an Age of Reconstruction,'' in 1935. He died in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> in 1947. Miss <PERSON> Rubinstein </PERSON> said she was ready to defend her thesis, titled `` The <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Emigration </LOCATION> after 1789 _ A Contribution to the Sociology of Political Emigration,'' when the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION> took over <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION> university in 1933. She said a Nazi student retrieved her thesis, which she left behind on a desk in the university, before she fled to <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> she worked as a translator and secretary for a literary agency, but fled again in 1940 when the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION> invaded <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, leaving everything behind, including her thesis. A French neighbor kept Miss <PERSON> Rubinstein </PERSON>'s belongings, and after the war traced her to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and sent the thesis to her, she said. Miss <PERSON> Rubinstein </PERSON>, who worked as a simultaneous translator, `` mostly in Russian,'' for the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, shelved the thesis for years until her half-sister, Ms. <PERSON> Papanek </PERSON>, a research professor of anthropology at <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, began trying to get it published. Later, efforts by Ms. <PERSON> Papanek </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kettler </PERSON>, and <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION> university's <PERSON> Brock </PERSON> and Professor <PERSON> Claudia </PERSON> <PERSON> Honegger </PERSON>, arranged for Miss <PERSON> Rubinstein </PERSON> to finally receive her degree. Miss <PERSON> Rubinstein </PERSON> said she will return to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Thursday. `` I'm incredibly tired and I have the feeling when I come back to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> I'm going to go to bed and stay there for a couple of days,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891211-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-11-89 2355EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CoddledKiller     12-11 0908</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Coddled Killer,0931</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mob Informant's Hideway Was Listed in Auto Records</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KAREN SCHWARTZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BROOKSVILLE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A mob informant and his <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> police guards developed such a loose relationship over 3 -LCB- years that they frolicked in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> together and sold vehicles to each other, even though the protected witness was serving a prison term. And security was so lax that anybody looking for informant <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> _ a prized witness who traveled to court surrounded by police sharpshooters _ had only to look in <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> auto title applications to find the address of his supposedly secret hideaway. His widow, <PERSON> Debra </PERSON>, and her lawyer also alleged in recent interviews at her <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> home that police told Mrs. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> to turn in phony receipts for <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>'s expenses. A <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> attorney general's report also said <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>, serving a 10-year prison term for murder at the time he was a protected witness, illegally had guns and improperly collected welfare and often was allowed to roam freely. He frequently was ferried to <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> with his guards, some of whom allegedly brought their girlfriends. `` It was just as if they were a bunch of fraternity guys, skydiving, drinking, women,'' said <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, Mrs. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>'s attorney Mrs. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>'s revelations are the latest about her husband's custody that have surfaced since he died June 11, 1988 They flabbergast the man who founded the federal witness protection program. `` Our prime goal is to keep him alive, to keep him in the right frame of mind to testify,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Partington </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> marshal recently named <LOCATION> Providence </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> R.I. </LOCATION>, public safety commissioner. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>, 43, died of a heart attack while on an unsupervised skydiving trip to <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>. The attorney general's report later acknowledged police knew he had a history of heart problems. Police found cocaine in his car. <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> state police are investigating, but previous reports by the attorney general and The <ORGANIZATION> Providence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal-Bulletin </ORGANIZATION> showed the state spent as much as $ 169,000 on <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> and his wife during his 3 -LCB- years in police custody _ purchases included bullets, liquor, jewelry, concert tickets and 52 skydiving trips. Two of <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>'s guards have committed suicide since his death and two were reassigned from the police intelligence unit to the uniform division. Former <ORGANIZATION> Providence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mancuso </PERSON>, who became the attorney general's chief drug enforcement officer while continuing to be paid by <LOCATION> Providence </LOCATION> after stepping down as chief, recently resigned from the attorney general's office and the force, citing continued publicity about the <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> case. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> was supposed to be a key witness against six reputed mobsters but testified against only one before his death. Because he died, charges against most of the others were dropped. Under an agreement with the attorney general's office, <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> lived at the <LOCATION> Providence </LOCATION> police station from his arrest in February 1985 until his transfer to a <LOCATION> Glocester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> R.I. </LOCATION>, safe house in January 1988. Mrs. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> alternated between living in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and with her husband in <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. Police and the attorney general's office refused to release the safe house address, but it was listed on a March 1988 title application <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> filed at the Motor Vehicle Registry in connection with a car loan. `` That is unbelievable,'' <PERSON> Partington </PERSON> said. `` You do n't have to be a police chief or security expert to say it's unthinkable'' for <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>'s address to be in public records. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> paid Detective <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> $ 3,000 for a 13-year-old <PERSON> Harley </PERSON> <PERSON> Davidson </PERSON> motorcycle in April 1988, according to sales tax documents provided by a source close to the investigation who demanded anonymity. `` I know about a motorcycle,'' said <PERSON> Ward </PERSON>, who declined to answer other questions. <LOCATION> Providence </LOCATION> and state police and the attorney general's office wo n't comment on the case. <PERSON> Mancuso </PERSON>, who stepped down in 1988, denied knowledge of any transactions between <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> and his guards, but would say no more. Mrs. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> won ` t talk about many things because of the pending state police investigation. But <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> said that among her other allegations are that: _ <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> sold a <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cordoba </ORGANIZATION> to police matron <PERSON> Eva </PERSON> <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON> in early 1986. No title could be found under either name and <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON> referred questions to Mrs. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>. <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON> said she took over loan payments on <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>'s 1984 Buick after his death. _ <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> told his wife her sixth-anniversary ring in 1987 was bought from <PERSON> Ward </PERSON>, who denies it. _ Police officers told her to get phony receipts to include with the ones submitted to the attorney general for <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>'s expenses _ receipts the attorney general's report says often were not reviewed. Mrs. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> says she never heeded the officers' advice and wo n't name them. Mrs. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> said her husband made at least a dozen state-paid trips to <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> for family visits and to clear up outstanding charges, including a prison break. <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> said the guards often brought girlfriends. <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> said the guards and women would stay in hotel rooms while <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> would stay with his wife at her home, more than a mile away. It could not be determined who paid for the rooms or if the guards watched Mrs. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>'s house. <ORGANIZATION> WPRI </ORGANIZATION> televison in <LOCATION> Providence </LOCATION> recently broadcast home videos of <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> and his guards frolicking in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and at a vacation home in <LOCATION> Narragansett </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> R.I. </LOCATION>. One tape showed an officer, with his arm around <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>, saying: `` The criminal justice system has been very, very good to us, huh <PERSON> Peter </PERSON>?
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891211-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-11-89 2355EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Corsica-Blast     12-11 0147</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Corsica-Blast,0150</SECOND>
<HEAD>Separatist Group Blows Up Tourist Complex</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CALVI, Corsica (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Masked men set off explosives that destroyed 80 apartments under construction in a tourist complex, police said. The separatist <ORGANIZATION> Corsican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> claimed responsibility. Police said two men wearing hoods tied up 11 people living at the site, mostly construction workers, and drove them to a village 15 miles away before detonating the blast early Monday in the apartment complex in <LOCATION> Calvi </LOCATION> on the northwestern coast of this French Mediterranean island. No injuries were reported. The <ORGANIZATION> Corsican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> claimed responsibility in a statement made public in the <LOCATION> Bastia </LOCATION>, the nearest major city, saying it was fighting `` speculative enterprises which will lead eventually to the marginalization of our people on their own land.'' A similar attack last month destroyed 135 apartments under construction at <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lucia </LOCATION> di <ORGANIZATION> Porto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vecchio </ORGANIZATION> in southeastern <LOCATION> Corsica </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891211-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-11-89 2356EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Czech-Jews     12-11 0840</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Czech-Jews,0871</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jewish Community Has Staged Its Own Uprising</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Czechoslavia</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MORT ROSENBLUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PRAGUE, Czechoslovakia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Parallel to the revolution around it, <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>'s 700-year-old shrinking Jewish community has staged its own tumultuous uprising and deposed old leaders who had accommodated the Communists. Freedom might fire the dwindling band with fresh life, the new leader said, but even that may not be enough. Furor erupted when the Council of Jewish Communities did not protest the police beating of student demonstrators Nov. 17. It was the only Czechoslovak religious group to remain silent. Rabbi <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Mayer </PERSON> sent his own letter, decrying `` brutality and arrogance,'' then threatened to quit if <PERSON> Bohumil </PERSON> <PERSON> Heller </PERSON> and <PERSON> Frantisek </PERSON> <PERSON> Kraus </PERSON> did not relinquish command of the council. Young Jews already had criticized the two, in another letter, for what they described as sacrificing principles to appease authorities. In a noisy open meeting Sunday, <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> Jews reinstated <PERSON> Desider </PERSON> <PERSON> Galsky </PERSON>, a 68-year-old historian who was council president until Czechoslovak authorities forced him out in 1985. `` Everyone is watching me now,'' <PERSON> Galsky </PERSON> said, `` but I can not create a heaven in 24 hours. These will be difficult times.'' His main concern is that simple attrition will accomplish what <PERSON> Adolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> could not: turn <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>'s 13th century Old-New Synagogue into a museum. The Nazis found 47,000 Jews in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> and killed most of them, but spared the medieval Jewish Quarter, with its relics and documents, as a museum of deviant culture. Jews returned after the war, but more than 1,000 are on community rolls, fewer than 2,000 others live in the city and three-quarters are over 65. About 10,000 Jews live elsewhere in <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>. `` For every 20 who die, two or three others join,'' said <PERSON> Mayer </PERSON>. `` We are very worried about the numbers.'' Asked whether new freedoms in <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> would help the Jews, he replied without a pause: `` No.'' <PERSON> Mayer </PERSON> said the government Council on Religious Affairs probably would end its subsidies, and the community would find it hard to survive. Jewish leaders accept the money on grounds the state seized priceless objects in the 1950s and never paid compensation. Pressed on the subject, <PERSON> Mayer </PERSON> chuckled and added: `` On balance, I suppose I'd rather have freedom.'' <PERSON> Galsky </PERSON> said he was negotiating to keep the annual stipend, equivalent to about $ 30,000, but only if other religious groups retained theirs. `` We hope that Jews around the world will help us,'' he said. Money aside, many <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> Jews think a more open <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> will bring out Jews who once feared praying in public. `` I think things will be better,'' said <PERSON> Vida </PERSON> <PERSON> Neuwirthova </PERSON>, a 27-year-old puppeteer who runs a Jewish children's troupe and works with the Jewish choir. `` We badly need young people.'' Her choir has emerged from years in which authorities would not let it perform in public because choir members refused to exclude the wife of <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON> <PERSON> Klima </PERSON>, a dissident writer whose works were banned until recently. Ms. <PERSON> Neuwirthova </PERSON> knows it will be an uphill fight. She has yet to persuade her husband, who is not a Jew, to allow a bar mitzvah when their 2-year-old is 13. `` He does not want his son to be different,'' she said. Bar mitzvahs average one every two years, but <PERSON> Galsky </PERSON> plans to encourage foreign Jews to come to <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> for bar mitzvahs and weddings in what he calls the oldest continuous Jewish congregation in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. Saturday morning services are in a narrow, vaulted room off the locked main temple. A dozen old men in shawls murmur Hebrew, sitting at a kitchen table whose plastic cover is patterned with gaily colored animals. Much livelier is the community's kosher restaurant in the building next door, not to be confused with the nearby Old Synagogue Restaurant, which serves roast pork and dumplings. Tourists normally outnumber Jews in the cobbled streets that wind among houses built centuries ago by merchants and intellectuals. Two old synagogues are museums, containing 300,000 of the silver ornaments, prayer shawls and documents <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> planned to display. At the old Jewish cemetery, visitors thread their way among broken stone tombs where people were buried up to nine deep to save precious space. Only for holidays, and in times of crisis, do <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> Jews come out in force, and the question is how long there will be enough. `` Who knows?'' reflected <PERSON> Galsky </PERSON>. `` In 10 years, we might still be all right. But in 20?'' At the open meeting, <PERSON> Jiri </PERSON> <PERSON> Radvansky </PERSON>, a 33-year-old pediatrician who reads no Hebrew and wears no yarmulke, drew loud applause for a tongue-lashing. He said he joined the community as a child to be among other Jews and was distressed to see people leave it over the years because of internal squabbles. Clearly, he was unhappy about compromises made with communism. <PERSON> Radvansky </PERSON> excoriated Jews who fight among themselves as their numbers dwindle, and proposed a group for people interested in Jewish culture, whatever their own religion. `` We must stop this stupid bickering and protect our heritage,'' he said. `` Otherwise, we will disappear.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891211-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-11-89 2357EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Taiwan-Culture Bjt   12-11 0912</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Taiwan-Culture, Bjt,0941</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Arts Blossom As Intellectuals Probe A Dark Past</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN POMFRET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TAIPEI, Taiwan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Artists and intellectuals in <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> are excavating the dark past of the Nationalist government, sparking a cultural boom in this economic powerhouse. Movies, court cases, a radio drama and the recent election campaign have created a flood of pressure on this island of 20 million to confront its past. The boom has also given voice to native Taiwanese, who make up 85 percent of the population but have had scant political influence since 1949 when the <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> seized power after losing a civil war to the Communists on mainland <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. `` We are awakening after a long sleep,'' says <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Chiang </PERSON>, editor of the prestigious Journalist magazine. `` We are finally learning who we are, where we came from.'' Taiwanese have always regarded their rocky island as `` the orphan of <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>,'' as a popular song goes. Since the 17th century, they have been ruled by Spaniards, Dutch, Japanese and Chinese from the mainland. When the Nationalists took power, they imposed the culture of the mainland on the little island. Mandarin Chinese replaced Taiwanese dialect in the classroom and students were fined if they spoke the local patois. Taiwanese history was dominated by Chinese history. Only fools or gangsters spoke Taiwanese on TV. `` I do n't know how many times my teacher made me stand with a board around my neck, saying ` I ` ll never speak Taiwanese again,''' said <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> <PERSON> Shui-pien </PERSON>, a leading opposition politician. `` The mainlanders made us feel like Taiwanese natives were second-class citizens.'' A change came in 1987 when then-President <PERSON> Chiang </PERSON> <PERSON> Ching-kuo </PERSON> ended 38 years of martial law. <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>'s astounding economic growth had created an increasingly sophisticated population which no longer tolerated harsh political repression. The government relaxed its tight controls on the press, legalized opposition political parties and began tolerating some dissent. A further boon to the cultural boom came in June, when Communist Chinese troops in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> crushed a pro-democracy movement. The tragedy in Tiananmen Square sparked Taiwanese to probe Nationalist abuses. In October, `` City of Sorrow,'' an award-winning film, opened in <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> to packed houses. The movie was the first to explore the Feb. 28, 1947 massacre, when Nationalist troops slaughtered tens of thousands of Taiwanese after clashes between island natives and mainland immigrants. A deaf-mute plays the central role and witnesses the horrors _ a powerful metaphor for <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>'s silenced intellectuals. In its portrayal of a gangster clan, the movie probes the politically sensitive question of organized crime's influence over politics. Ironically, the film is reported to be backed by gangland money. A wildy-popular radio drama also has its roots in <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>'s past _ the <LOCATION> Japanese </LOCATION> occupation from 1895-1945. <PERSON> Liao </PERSON> <PERSON> Tien-ting </PERSON> is <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hood </PERSON>, who robs Japanese imperialists and gives to the poor. The show draws thinly veiled parallels between <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s occupation and Nationalist government domination in <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> Its announcer has entered politics and is a strong supporter of the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Progressive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>'s recent election campaign, the first multiparty race in its history, also made use of the past and Taiwanese culture. One successful candidate for the Legislature, <PERSON> Yeh </PERSON> <PERSON> Chu-lan </PERSON>, advocated independence from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, a seditious act under the Constitution. Her victory gave voice to an undercurrent of support, especially among native Taiwanese, for cutting all ties with <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. Taiwanese folk songs filled the air at her rallies. A guerrilla theater troupe acted out scenes of alleged <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> brutality _ the 1947 killings and the death of <PERSON> Yeh </PERSON>'s husband, a dissident who immolated himself in April to escape police interrogation. The troupe also portrayed scenes from a 1979 riot in the southern city of <LOCATION> Kaohsiung </LOCATION>. On Dec. 10, 1979, tens of thousands of people demonstrated in <LOCATION> Kaohsiung </LOCATION> for human rights and hundreds were injured in a brawl. The government rounded up more than 150 dissidents and dozens were sentenced to long jail terms. A celebrated court case has also returned attention to the bloody clash. In September, fugitive dissident <PERSON> Hsu </PERSON> <PERSON> Hsin-liang </PERSON>, wanted for allegedly fomenting the riot, was arrested as he tried to slip into <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> on a fishing boat. <PERSON> Hsu </PERSON>'s case sparked exposes in the increasingly free press. In October, the Journalist claimed police used torture and intimidation to extract confessions of participants in the riot. Other reports have called for an investigation of the killings of the wife and daughter of one of the <LOCATION> Kaohsiung </LOCATION> dissidents, <PERSON> Lin </PERSON> <PERSON> Yi-hsiung </PERSON>, jailed after the clash. `` The government should have forgetten the case and welcomed <PERSON> Hsu </PERSON> back,'' said opposition figure <PERSON> Chen </PERSON>, also <PERSON> Hsu </PERSON>'s attorney. `` Instead, they were too worried about losing face, so they're prosecuting him That has opened up this old wound and the opposition is profiting from the controversy.'' Some intellectuals oppose this use of <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>'s history and culture as a political weapon. <PERSON> Hou </PERSON> <PERSON> Hsiao-hsien </PERSON>, who directed `` City of Sorrow,'' says he made the movie to return history to the people. `` The Nationalists and the opposition are using the February 28 incident like a trump card,'' he said in a recent interview. `` The movie was my way of butting into their card game and turning the trump card over. February 28 is our history, it does n't belong to political parties.'' President <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Teng-hui </PERSON>, the country's first native Taiwanese leader, has asked his people to forget about the ugly past and look to the future. But, <PERSON> Hou </PERSON> counters: `` If we do n't talk about it now, we are doomed to repeat it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891211-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-11-89 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RhodesList     12-11 0349</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rhodes List,0388</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Rhodes Scholars</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the 32 students chosen as American <PERSON> Rhodes </PERSON> scholars for 1990, listed by district where the application was filed. The city provided by the candidate may not in every case be a hometown. Applicants may apply either in their home state or the state where their college is located:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>District One, New England</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Warren </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Blacksburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Tanya </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollard </PERSON>, <PERSON> Blue </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Reza </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandjei </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Palo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alto </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> and also <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Basilios </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tsingos </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Manchester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.H. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>District Two, Middle Atlantic</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Jennie </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Potomac </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Military Academy S. <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Grose </PERSON>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaziano </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>
</TEXT>
<NOTE>District Three, Southern</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Carolyn </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Pensacola </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Military Academy. <PERSON> Suzanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Corley </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Bristol </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Presbyterian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Elwell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Fairfax </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Station </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Georgetown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Renee </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lettow </PERSON>, <PERSON> McLean </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Princeton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>District Four, Great Lakes</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Georgie </PERSON> <PERSON> Holder </PERSON> <PERSON> Boge </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Bloomington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Princeton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and also College of <PERSON> William </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mary </PERSON>. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Barley </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Georgetown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> <PERSON> Monroe </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Louisville </ORGANIZATION> and also <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lyons </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Princeton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>District Five, Middle West</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hale </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Kansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Janelle </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Larson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Kansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Duke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Grinnell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>District Six, Gulf</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Shin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Balot </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Metairie </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Chapel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Baton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rouge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Louisiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>District Seven, Southwestern</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> <PERSON> Deanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Matthews </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Escondido </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Mount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Holyoke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Martina </PERSON> <PERSON> Vandenberg </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gilroy </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Pomona </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Tara </PERSON> <PERSON> Silvestri </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>District Eight, Northwestern</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bridget </PERSON> <PERSON> Clarke </PERSON>, Grand Rapids, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Montana </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Sommerville </PERSON>, Grand Forks, <LOCATION> N.D. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Austin </PERSON>. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Muench </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Bloomington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Reed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dechet </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Vancouver </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Princeton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891211-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-11-89 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DismantlingCatastrophic     12-11 0907</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dismantling Catastrophic,0928</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bureaucracy Shifts Into Reverse To Dismantle Catastrophic-Care Program</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NANCY BENAC</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal bureaucrats and private insurers are scrambling to rework health insurance benefits, adjust premiums and spread the word that the end is near for <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION>'s year-old catastrophic health care program. In addition, millions of senior citizens are refiguring their expected 1989 tax bills, the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> is scrapping Form 8808 before it hits the printing press, and states are trying to figure out how they will cover an extra $ 300 million to $ 400 million in health care expenses for the poor. The Medicare Catastrophic Coverage Act _ expected to cost $ 48 billion in its first five years _ was enacted with fanfare in 1988 to protect 33 million elderly and disabled people against financial ruin from the staggering costs of prolonged illness. But even before most of the benefits took effect, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> voted last month to dismantle the program because of a firestorm of protest from senior citizens who complained it cost them too much. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has promised to sign the repeal measure. Under repeal, the <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Care </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Financing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> must take back the extended hospitalization and nursing home coverage it has offered <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> beneficiaries for the past year and scrap plans to provide expanded coverage of drug and doctor bills and other medical expenses. <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hays </PERSON>, the acting <ORGANIZATION> HCFA </ORGANIZATION> administrator, said a top priority for the agency is to get notices out to <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> beneficiaries explaining the new limits on their hospital and nursing home benefits. `` We want to make sure that there is n't confusion,'' <PERSON> Hays </PERSON> said. The agency also can forget about providing additional medical benefits that `` we had invested enormous energy and time in preparing to implement,'' he said. The <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, meanwhile, have the tasks of rolling back the income tax surcharge on the elderly and the extra Medicare premium that financed the catastrophic program. The surtax was canceled completely; the extra premium will be scrapped at the end of the year. <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON> said taxpayers will be instructed to ignore two lines on this year's 1040 tax forms _ lines 54 and 55 _ which refer senior citizens to the elusive Form 8808 that never got beyond the prototype stage. Higher-income senior citizens would have used 8808 to calculate their added income tax liability for the <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> benefits. Senior citizens who paid extra amounts in quarterly income tax payments or through wage withholding to cover the <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> surtax will get any overpayments back as part of their income tax refund, <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON> said. About 40 percent of the elderly would have paid some surtax _ $ 22.50 for every $ 150 of federal income tax liability _ with about 6 percent paying the maximum amount of $ 800 per person this year. Scrapping the tax is the type of last-minute change it is easy to spring on taxpayers, <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON> said. `` Everybody enjoys hearing news that they do n't have to pay a tax that was on the books,'' he said. The <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, meanwhile, is complaining that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> did not give the agency enough lead time to stop withholding extra Medicare premiums that helped finance the catastrophic benefits. It may be April or May before extra payments of about $ 5.30 a month no longer are deducted from Social Security checks, with the overpayments to be refunded later. The premiums of $ 4 a month during 1989 will not be refunded. `` The bottom line is that Social Security will unscramble this egg, but we did not lay it,'' said Social Security Commissioner <PERSON> Gwendolyn </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>. The repeal also is causing last-minute maneuvering among private insurers who will pick up some of the benefits being canned by the government. About 70 percent of elderly Americans purchase private `` medigap'' insurance to fill the gaps in their Medicare coverage. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commissioners </ORGANIZATION> has until Dec. 15 to draft transition regulations for medigap policies, and private insurers have until Jan. 30 to revise their policies and premiums and notify policyholders of the changes. Any changes, however, will be retroactive to Jan. 1, when the government benefits expire. `` Insurance companies are doing their best, they're just grumbling about how long it took <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to make up their mind,'' said <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Richards </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>. `` It's kind of a ` We'll muddle through' situation. We just hope <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> does n't change their mind again next year.'' The association has estimated medigap premiums will rise 20 percent to 25 percent next year due to the combined effects of rising medical costs and the repeal of the catastrophic package. Fallout from the repeal also is reaching state governments. The repeal legislation left in place expanded Medicaid costs for the states, while scrapping provisions that would have offset some of the new expenses, said <PERSON> Alicia </PERSON> <PERSON> Pelrine </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Governors </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> `` Grumbling is probably a tame word to describe what is going on out there,'' Ms. <PERSON> Pelrine </PERSON> said. `` States are already so maxed out on their ability to accommodate various -LRB- federal -RRB- mandates ... that a lot are saying, ` We do n't know how we're going to pay for this.''' <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Officers </ORGANIZATION>, said the original catastrophic legislation would have cost states $ 900 million, but the repeal bill boosts those costs by an additional $ 300 million to $ 400 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891211-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-11-89 0053EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Foreigners     12-11 0700</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Foreigners,0721</SECOND>
<HEAD>Authorities Limit Chinese Contact With Foreigners</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERRIL JONES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 From discos to dormitories and hotels, authorities are stepping up moves to limit foreigners' contacts with Chinese. Black sedans without license plates and full of security men have been parked outside the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy recently. Plainclothes police and surveillance cameras are being increased elsewhere to keep track of who's meeting whom. `` Police are cracking down on <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> girls who meet with foreigners,'' said a clothing saleswoman who is obliged to attend meetings where workers denounce `` American imperialism.'' `` It does n't matter if you're just friends or colleagues, they'll just assume the girl's a prostitute,'' she said. The stepped-up monitoring comes amid a crackdown on prostitution, increased warnings about AIDS and general wariness of associating with foreigners since the military crackdown on pro-democracy protesters in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> in June. The Chinese government claims the June turmoil was instigated with foreign help. In November, the Culture Ministry canceled a planned exhibition at the <ORGANIZATION> French </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> of a <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> painter, and this month police halted plans by the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Correspondents </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> to show works by six Chinese artists. Western diplomats and journalists have been turned down for routine interviews and meetings by numerous government ministries and think tanks. A well-known `` English corner'' in a public park where people gathered on Sundays to practice English also has been banned. Diplomats and foreign journalists have long lived in special compounds with armed guards and surveillance cameras. Entering taxis are checked for Chinese, who are supposed to be screened by the guards. A year ago large cameras were installed at the compounds' main entrances and inside elevators. Reporters who inquired about the measures were told they were taken because African children had beaten Chinese staff workers. Workmen last month installed more video cameras at the compounds, and two weeks ago security agents of the <ORGANIZATION> Diplomatic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION>, which provides staff for embassies and foreign press bureaus, began staking out apartment entrances. `` They're here to stop some of the foreigners who are bringing girls back to their apartments,'' a utility worker for the diplomatic bureau said. `` It's part of the ` Sweep Out the Six Evils' campaign.'' <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> began the Six Evils campaign some months ago to wipe out prostitution, gambling, drug use, selling women and children, pornography and belief in superstition. Police have stepped up monitoring of discotheques at posh hotels such as the Palace in central <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. `` There have been more than 10 plainclothes police here every day since late November,'' a hotel employee said. `` Whenever they see a Chinese girl with a foreigner, they separate them and quiz them about what the other person's name is, what their job is,'' the employee said. `` If their answers do n't match that means they just met That's how they catch them.'' The disco is frequented by `` professionals,'' some of whom appear almost every night with different partners, said the employee, who saw one Chinese woman being taken away in handcuffs last month. Punishment for prostitution is strictly enforced, and a few foreigners have been expelled from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> for buying sex. Monitoring of AIDS has been strengthened in recent months, and an unidentified foreigner with AIDS was expelled from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in September. A receptionist at a major Chinese-run hotel was fired recently for being friendly with an Arab guest. `` My boss brought out videos taken by the security cameras of me talking to the guest and accused me of making friends with a foreigner,'' the woman said. `` He would just come over and talk to me. I thought it was fun to practice English.'' University students, who led the pro-democracy movement that was crushed by the army, are uneasy about foreign contacts. One student of <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Normal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> declined to see an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> friend because she believed being seen with a foreigner might jeopardize her application for a passport to study overseas. Chinese students live in dormitories segregated from foreign students and researchers. `` It's a big trouble to go visit foreign students,'' said a student at <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` You have to register, leave your I.D. card downstairs, then leave by 10 p.m.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891211-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-11-89 0055EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Peru-Accident     12-11 0163</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Peru-Accident,0167</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thirty-Five Killed In Truck Crash</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AREQUIPA, Peru (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A truck carrying people home from thermal baths in a remote area of the <LOCATION> Andes </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> tumbled off a mountain road and down a ravine near the <LOCATION> Colca </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, killing 35 people, police say. The accident occurred Saturday night near the village of <LOCATION> Chivay </LOCATION>, 50 miles north of <LOCATION> Arequipa </LOCATION>. Police said the victims had spent the day at hot springs in the mountains and were returning home to <LOCATION> Chivay </LOCATION>. Police said they did not know how many people had been in the truck. It was the second major truck accident in a week in <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>. Nineteen people were killed and 21 injured on Dec. 3 when a truck carrying fans and members of a soccer team crashed near <LOCATION> Nazca </LOCATION>, 310 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION>. The upper <LOCATION> Colca </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> region where Saturday's accident occurred is a rugged, sparsely populated area more than 11,000 feet above sea level, 550 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891211-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-11-89 0056EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Czech-FreeMan     12-11 0560</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Czech-Free Man,0578</SECOND>
<HEAD>Freedom Overwhelms Czech Father</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Czechoslovakia, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MORT ROSENBLUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PRAGUE, Czechoslovakia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In a vast sea of arms outstretched in victory, <PERSON> Zdenek </PERSON> <PERSON> Machon </PERSON> joined in singing the national anthem, but, choking on emotion, he could barely get out the words. `` I can look people directly in the eye now, people from other countries,'' he said. `` We are a free people again. We are part of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> again.'' <PERSON> Machon </PERSON> was among 100,000 Czechoslovaks who on Sunday returned to <LOCATION> Wenceslas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> where only three weeks ago they first gathered to tell the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> that, after 41 years, enough was enough. On Sunday, they celebrated the naming of the first non-Communist dominated government since 1948. He is a big man with a thick mustache, but he showed no embarrassment at the tears trickling down his face. It was the students who first rose up, and <PERSON> Machon </PERSON> has three in his family. `` I am so thankful to my children for setting us free,'' he said. `` And I am so happy that they can now live their lives in freedom.'' From the towering statue of King Wenceslas on horseback to the gates of <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>'s medieval <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Town </LOCATION>, the distance of eight football fields end to end, Czechoslovaks shared the same thoughts. There were speeches and chants, but their message was all in their moist, red eyes. `` You have to understand how we felt in 1968,'' said <PERSON> Machon </PERSON>, now 47. `` We had one child then, and now we have three. Life will be different now.'' In 1968, a Soviet invasion brought an abrupt halt to the Czechoslovaks' last try for freedom. The people's only weapon were the `` V'' signs they aimed at the tanks. The next morning, the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> daily, <PERSON> Rude </PERSON> <PERSON> Pravo </PERSON>, carried a picture of resisting crowds, with each person holding up two fingers. The caption said they were threatening to attack Socialist troops in two minutes. This time, there was no confusion over the `` V'' victory sign. At the first strains of the national anthem, <ORGANIZATION> Machon </ORGANIZATION>'s two thick fingers were joined by 200,000 others. At every chant, he leaned over to translate for a foreign reporter, eager that the world not miss any part of <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>'s triumph. His wife beamed and nodded happily. `` How can I explain what this means?'' said <PERSON> Machon </PERSON>, who is a geophysicist. `` When I went abroad to meetings, I could not look at people. We were different, inferior, ashamed.'' When a Frenchwoman spoke from the fourth-floor balcony, delivering a message of support from European theater groups, he glowed. After she finished, the crowd chanted, `` Merci, Merci.'' The setting said as much as <PERSON> Machon </PERSON>'s explanation. Throughout four decades of <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> rule, Czechoslovaks spoke in private of whom they were and what they would be again someday. <PERSON> Machon </PERSON> knew Sunday was that day. With the crowd, he chanted, `` We want <PERSON> Havel </PERSON>!'' demanding the now-vacant presidency for <PERSON> Vaclav </PERSON> <PERSON> Havel </PERSON>, the playwright who spent four of the last 20 years in prison for insisting on exposing the hypocrisy and brutality of Communist rule. As with <PERSON> Masaryk </PERSON> and others after him, Czechoslovaks in crisis rallied to a man of letters rather than a politician. `` It is a wonderful day, wonderful,'' <PERSON> Machon </PERSON> said. `` How can I say it?'' Instead of trying, he hugged the reporter and wept again.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891211-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-11-89 0057EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BisonHunt     12-11 0734</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bison Hunt,0753</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bison Hunt Begins Anew With Support From Animal Scientist</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM LACEKY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HELENA, Mont. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Bison that blunder over the line from <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> are fair game for hunters again this winter, but park officials expect the harvest to be smaller than the 500 taken last season. Just how many of the big, furry, dumb beasts will wander outside the park boundaries to graze depends on how severe the winter is and how pinched the food supply within the park, officials say. Hunters are n't allowed to shoot buffalo in the park. But statements by a leading zoologist have added weight to the state's contention that the slaughter of wandering bison is necessary to prevent the spread of brucellosis among <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> cattle herds, despite the outrage such killings may produce. Dr. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> A & amp; M <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> specialist in the highly infectious bacterial disease, said previous claims by park officials that the bison bug could not be transmitted to cattle have proven false. `` <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> has spent in excess of $ 260 million of federal and state money to rid the domestic livestock of brucellosis,'' <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said. `` So you can see why you're not real crazy to get it back again.'' <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, scientific adviser to a committee on brucellosis in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, said the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> could do more to eradicate brucellosis in the Yellowstone herds by isolating and slaughtering infected bison. But that would mean killing the animals on park property, and that is n't going to happen, he said. `` We're talking big-time political and economic concessions if they were to do that,'' <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said. The Park Service says that unless scientists can prove brucellosis was not in the park when <PERSON> Yellowstone </PERSON> was created in 1872, it may classify the bacteria as a `` native species.'' Park policy forbids eradication of any native species. Eradicating brucellosis from the buffalo herd could prove useless if the organism is native to the area and simply reinfects the animals, said <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Anzelmo </PERSON>. And the buffalo would no longer be a wild, free-roaming species if they were treated like domestic cattle, she said. Brucellosis, also called Bang's disease, causes domestic cattle to lose their calves. It can cause undulant fever _ characterized by recurring fever and aching joints _ in humans who get it through unpasteurized milk or direct contact with infected animals. It generally ca n't be transmitted through meat. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has been trying for decades to eliminate the disease from commercial herds. So far, <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> says, 27 states are free of brucellosis, with the disease most prevalent in the South. Brucellosis was eradicated from <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> cattle in 1984. Last year, due to food shortages caused by the massive 1988 forest fires and an ensuing harsh winter, hundreds of hungry bison wandered north onto <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> cattle ranches. Hunters were called in to snag strays, and a record 569 bison were killed. Of these about half were found to be infected with brucellosis. Park officials counted 418 buffalo in the northern herd last week and estimate a park total of about 2,000 animals in the park's three major herds. <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, where most of <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> is located, does not permit the shooting of stray bison. Animal rights activists sought unsuccessfully to stop last year's hunt, which to some was sadly reminiscent of the massive buffalo slaughter of a century ago that signalled the final taming of the Wild West. Although the bison season legally began Oct. 1, it does not actually start until and unless bison begin leaving the park. That usually happens in December, although it may not happen at all if the winter is mild. `` The biologists ca n't predict whether they'll move as they did last year,'' <PERSON> Anzelmo </PERSON> said. `` We hope not. Maybe only a few will leave the park.'' Previously officials have said they expect no more than 200 to be harvested this year. In preparation for the hunt, 3,217 people have paid $ 5 to apply for a bison permit. If summoned by the wildlife department to hunt, Montanans pay $ 200 for a license, while non-residents pay $ 1,000. The hunt itself is less than thrilling. Buffalo are accustomed to seeing humans, and game wardens lead each hunter directly to the animal to be killed. The hunters shoot at close range at animals that often are standing still, grazing.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891211-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-11-89 0058EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WVaSenateCorruption     12-11 0682</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-WVa Senate Corruption,0701</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Former State Senators Face Sentencing in Corruption Probe</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By A.V. GALLAGHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHARLESTON, W.Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three men who held the most powerful jobs in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> face stiff prison terms and fines this week after being snared in a corruption investigation that swept through the Legislature. Former Senate President <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON> and former Majority Leader <PERSON> Si </PERSON> <PERSON> Boettner </PERSON> go before <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Copenhaver </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> on Wednesday. Former Senate President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Tonkovich </PERSON> faces sentencing Thursday. The three, all Democrats, are the latest <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> public officials to fall to investigations by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Carey </PERSON>. <PERSON> Carey </PERSON>, 35, also has nailed a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Delegates </ORGANIZATION> member, a top <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> aide and two lobbyists on various corruption charges. And he obtained an indictment of a Charleston-area dog track owner who allegedly fed some of the corruption with dollars bet at the track. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> already was reeling from two forced resignations this summer. Treasurer <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Manchin </PERSON> stepped down to avoid a state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> trial on articles of impeachment after he was disgraced over the loss of $ 279 million in a state investment fund. Attorney General <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> quit after conceding he changed his testimony during child custody proceedings. <PERSON> Carey </PERSON> says his work is n't over yet, but he repeatedly has declined to elaborate. `` These cases do show the system is corruptible, as are most systems of government,'' <PERSON> Carey </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Carey </PERSON>'s investigations have caused consternation in the Statehouse, where Democrats outnumber Republicans 30-4 in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and 80-20 in the House. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Burdette </PERSON> has asked <PERSON> Carey </PERSON> to conclude the investigation as soon as possible. `` It makes my job tougher,'' said <PERSON> Burdette </PERSON>, who at age 34 took over from <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON> as <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> president. `` It's undermined the public's confidence in state government,'' <PERSON> Burdette </PERSON> said. He supports the investigations, however. `` I think it's a necessary purge of that element of public officials in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>,'' said <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Chambers </PERSON>. <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON>, 54, who spent 18 years in the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> before becoming <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> president in 1988, resigned and pleaded guilty Sept. 11 to extorting $ 10,000 from dog track interests. He faces fines of $ 250,000 and 20 years in prison. <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON>'s plea briefly interrupted the extortion trial of <PERSON> Tonkovich </PERSON>, 43, <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> president from 1984 to 1987, when he left the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> for an unsuccessful bid for governor. <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON> then became a prosecution witness against <PERSON> Tonkovich </PERSON>. <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON> admitted that he had pocketed $ 10,000. The scandal cost him a job as a bank executive vice president. Three days later, <PERSON> Tonkovich </PERSON> pleaded guilty to extorting $ 5,000 from casino gambling interests in return for help on a bill to legalize gaming. The bill was not passed. Witnesses testified that <PERSON> Tonkovich </PERSON>'s aide, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Cain </PERSON>, had pressed them for campaign donations. <PERSON> Cain </PERSON> admitted being part of a laundering scheme to get $ 15,000 in gaming money for <PERSON> Tonkovich </PERSON>. <PERSON> Cain </PERSON> and track and insurance lobbyist <PERSON> Bonnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Wymer </PERSON> pleaded guilty to federal income tax charges and both testified against <PERSON> Tonkovich </PERSON>. <PERSON> Cain </PERSON> and <PERSON> Wymer </PERSON> were sentenced to probation Thursday. Last December, state Delegate <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> McCormick </PERSON> was convicted of extortion. Lobbyist <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Vandergrift </PERSON> revealed he paid money to <PERSON> McCormick </PERSON> for help on a bill, and also said he lavished $ 160,000 on the Legislature in three years. <PERSON> Vandergrift </PERSON>, lobbyist for a group of foreign doctors who sought to ease restrictions on their obtaining <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> medical licenses, pleaded guilty to a federal income tax charge and spent less than six months in prison. He admitted he had not filed income tax returns for 16 years. <PERSON> Boettner </PERSON> pleaded guilty Sept. 23 to federal charges of income tax evasion for taking money from the same lobbyist who paid off <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON>. <PERSON> Boettner </PERSON>, who faces 20 years in prison and fines of $ 250,000, also testified against <PERSON> Tonkovich </PERSON>. The lobbyist, <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Annunzio </PERSON>, committed suicide Dec. 4, 1988, police said. Facing a February trial is dog track owner <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON>. He is alleged to have paid $ 10,000 to <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON> and offered $ 13,000 to <PERSON> Tonkovich </PERSON> through <PERSON> D'Annunzio </PERSON> for help on a bill that increased his track's take by $ 1.1 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891211-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-11-89 0232EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--ScalpReattached     12-11 0149</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Scalp Reattached,0157</SECOND>
<HEAD>Doctors Reattach Woman's Scalp After Industrial Accident</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BIRMINGHAM, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Doctors reattached the scalp of a woman after it was ripped off when her hair got tangled in a machine at a yarn mill. <PERSON> Sheila </PERSON> <PERSON> Mobbs </PERSON>, 33, was in satisfactory condition Sunday, and was moved out of an intensive care unit at <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospitals </ORGANIZATION>, said a nursing supervisor who would only give her name as <PERSON> Kay </PERSON>. The accident occurred Friday at the <ORGANIZATION> Leesburg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yarn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mill </ORGANIZATION> in northeastern <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, where Mrs. <PERSON> Mobbs </PERSON> works. Mrs. <PERSON> Mobbs </PERSON>' husband, <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON>, said his wife did n't know how the accident occurred, but she fell and her ponytail became entwined in the spinning machine. The Gaylesville woman was taken to <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION> along with her scalp, which was transported in a sealed container. Mrs. <PERSON> Mobbs </PERSON> underwent a 14-hour operation at <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospitals </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Mobbs </PERSON> said. `` The doctors said it went well,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891211-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-11-89 0055EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-GenericDrugs Bjt   12-11 0618</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Generic Drugs, Bjt,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Administration Considering New Fees on Generic Industry</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration plans to propose that generic drug companies pay `` user fees'' to help beef up government regulation of an industry reeling from a bribery and fraud scandal, sources say. The plan drafted by the <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> would impose registration fees on generic drug makers and charge them another fee for each application they file, said a source who spoke on the condition of anonymity. The fees would raise about $ 18 million as part of a $ 144 million package of <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> fees the administration plans to propose in its fiscal 1991 budget, the source said. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration, like the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, favors user fees because they raise money without raising taxes. Plans to extend these fees to the drug industry have been proposed before, only to be axed by opponents on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. But this time, a plan directed at the generic drug industry is believed to have better chances, largely because of disclosures this year that some generic drug makers have bribed <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> officials, cheated on safety tests and otherwise sidestepped <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> regulations. `` There has been some <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> concern about the ability of the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> to do its job,'' said one source at the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, which includes <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION>. `` I think you'll find they're more receptive to talking about <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> user fees than talking about user fees in general. Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>, D-Mich., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> investigations subcommittee, demonstrates some evidence of a shift in opinion His panel uncovered the problems that have led to the bribery convictions of several generic drug company executives and <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> employees and the recall of more than 80 generic drugs. <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>, who has opposed user fees, `` is increasingly coming to favor them'' for the generic drug industry, as long as the money raised is used exclusively to strengthen the generic drug approval system, said an aide to the congressman who spoke on the condition he not be identified by name. The generic drug industry opposes the plan, which would hit generic companies only _ not brand name drug makers _ with a registration fee of about $ 6,000 on each company and another charge of about $ 17,000 for each generic drug application they submit for <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> review. `` It's like putting a tax on one side of the industry because of a couple of wrongdoers,'' said <PERSON> Dee </PERSON> <PERSON> Fensterer </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Generic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pharmaceutical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. She said the fees could add up to `` a substantial amount of money,'' especially if the companies had to pay the application fee for each dosage of the same product. `` It starts to be very expensive.'' She added that `` any user fee is going to get passed on'' to consumers in the form of a price increase. Though she could not say how much the fees might add to the cost of a generic drug, she said it would not be large enough to make generics less competitive with the more expensive brand name products. The makers of brand name products also oppose user fees, even when the costs are imposed only on their competitors. Many say if the generic fees are approved it would only be a matter of time before a similar plan were imposed on the name brand companies. In a letter to <ORGANIZATION> HHS </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> earlier this fall, the <ORGANIZATION> Pharmaceutical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, representing brand name makers, said the fees are unjustified because they `` would constitute the collection of revenues for services performed for the benefit of the general public and not for the specific benefit of an applicant or registrant.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891211-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-11-89 0055EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-Louisiana-Senate     12-11 0307</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Louisiana-Senate,0320</SECOND>
<HEAD>State Senator Collects 70 Percent of Delegates in Louisiana Caucuses</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 State Sen. <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Bagert </PERSON> easily outdistanced state Rep. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> and Secretary of State <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> <PERSON> McKeithen </PERSON> in <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> caucuses across <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, giving him a boost in his bid to oppose incumbent <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bagert </PERSON> won 383, or 70 percent, of the 544 delegates selected at 14 caucuses Saturday. <PERSON> Duke </PERSON>, a former <PERSON> Ku </PERSON> <PERSON> Klux </PERSON> <PERSON> Klan </PERSON> leader whose election to the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> last year was opposed by national <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leaders, won 27 delegates. <PERSON> McKeithen </PERSON> won 25 and 109 of the delegates were uncommitted. `` Folks who supported us today have given us a tremendous boost in our quest to defeat <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Bagert </PERSON> said Saturday. Nearly half of the 1,200 delegates to the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION>'s Jan. 13 state convention in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> were chosen Saturday. Another 660 are party officials. <PERSON> Bagert </PERSON>'s strong showing does not mean he has the nomination for the fall 1990 election locked up. Delegates' pledges of support are not binding. `` You need the credibility of the party behind you. It gives you a stamp of approval,'' <PERSON> Bagert </PERSON> said. Formal endorsement against <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>, a Democrat, also would mean Republican support in the form of money, newsletters and volunteers. Both <PERSON> Bagert </PERSON> and <PERSON> McKeithen </PERSON> have said they'd drop out of the race if they did n't win <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> nomination. <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> has said he'll run even if he is n't endorsed. `` <PERSON> Bagert </PERSON> was by far the strongest candidate,'' said <PERSON> Darryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Gissel </PERSON>, state <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> director. <PERSON> Duke </PERSON>, who said he does not expect the party's endorsement, blamed his weak showing on limited time to drum up support. `` We've organized this thing for three days. They've been at it for three months.'' <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> said. `` I'm encouraged, given the time we spent on it. <PERSON> McKeithen </PERSON> could not be reached for comment at his office or his home.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891211-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-11-89 0104EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PlowsharesPains     12-11 0809</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Plowshares Pains,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>Capital Fears the Impact of Defense Cuts on the Industry's Workers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE FEINSILBER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Cuts in defense spending wo n't hurt the economy, analysts say, but could be traumatic for a workforce accustomed to satisfying a single complacent customer _ the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> _ instead of the competitive marketplace. A third of the nation's engineers and scientists work in defense and by some estimates 26 million people depend on the military economy, so there's considerable concern in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> about the recoil that will be felt the defense budget is sharply reduced, as seems likely. Analyst <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaufmann </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Brookings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION> thinks defense spending could be half its current size in 10 years. Both the new era opened by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> at <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> and the pressures of the deficit point to dismantling the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> Era defense buildup. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruby </PERSON>, chief operating officer of <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aerospace </ORGANIZATION>, says a number of firms are already planning `` downsizing.'' Some economists say the government also should be designing retraining, counseling, job search and relocation programs to ease the transition for defense workers. `` We put over a billion and a half dollars into building planes we did n't need'' to preserve jobs, says <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Korb </PERSON>, who was an assistant defense secretary in the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. `` I'd like to see the government come up with a plan to help people in a graceful and humane way, but you talk about an industrial policy in this country and they call you a communist,'' he says. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> is looking at the issue. It has scheduled hearings for Tuesday on `` the economic consequences of reduced defense spending and the winding down of the Cold War.'' `` Depending on its size and speed, a substantial cut in defense spending phased in over a number of years could be one of the best things that could happen to the economy and should not be looked on as something likely to cause recession or unemployment,'' says <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Schultze </PERSON>, who was President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>'s chief economic adviser. `` One thing this country does not have is a surplus of is skilled engineers and skilled workmen.'' But conversion of defense workers, technicians, managers and plants to the civilian economy will be trickier than it was after World War II, when <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> stopped making tanks and resumed making DeSoto automobiles without missing a step. There was enormous pent-up demand for civilian products, too. But government planners cite society's needs _ for environmental cleanup, recycling of plastics, health care _ which may be able to adopt defense industry technology. `` I hope trade associations will see the relationship between a mayor who is worried about defense cuts in his community and about waste management; if you're smart, you can walk in and say, ` I can solve them both at once,''' says <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tepper </PERSON> <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> of the Council on Economic Priorities. Defense managers have grown accustomed to working in the hothouse environment of <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> contracting, with no competition from overseas, a single, cooperative customer and cost-plus-profit accounting. `` Defense contractors are used to being told what the market is,'' says consultant <PERSON> Jacques </PERSON> <PERSON> Gansler </PERSON>, author of `` Affording Defense'' and a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> procurement official in 1972-77. `` The commercial world is n't like that.'' But <PERSON> Seymour </PERSON> <PERSON> Melman </PERSON>, retired professor of industrial engineering at <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and a pioneer advocate of planned conversion, rejects the view that the economy can absorb defense budget cuts without severe dislocations. He argues for an elaborate government efforts to prepare defense workers and to create productive civilian jobs for them. `` What are they going to work at?'' he demands. `` Making shoes? Eight-five percent of our shoes are imported. Consumer electronics? All imported. Machine tools? Half are imported.'' Moreover, <PERSON> Melman </PERSON> argues, defense managers are incapable of making the leap without retraining. `` No major military-serving enterprise has demonstrated an autonomous ability to carry out the sort of occupational switch that is needed to go civilian,'' <PERSON> Melman </PERSON> wrote in his book, `` Profits Without Production.'' `` If you unleash these people, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> will turn into a third-rate economy,'' <PERSON> Melman </PERSON> says. `` They ca n't hack it. We will lose the capability of repairing the damage.'' Under a conversion legislation sponsored by Rep. <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, defense contractors would be required to put 1.25 percent of receipts into a fund to pay the costs of economic adjustment. Laid-off workers might get 90 percent of their lost salaries while they are retrained for civilian jobs. <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Project </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> Washingon </LOCATION> research outfit, says, `` Workers find work when the economy is healthy; you can plan the dickens out of what to do with a worker but when we're in a recession you ca n't do anything for him.'' <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> says although counseling, retraining and relocation programs are critical, `` income supplements, however, slow the adjustment process.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891211-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-11-89 0023EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-CentralAmerica 2ndLd-Writethru a0754 12-11 0806</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Central America, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0754,0824</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nicaragua Asks That U.N. Move To Demobilize Contra Rebels</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Eds: LEADS with 6 grafs to UPDATE with Sunday meeting over. Picks
up 4th pvs, `The source ...' ^By ELOY O. AGUILAR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN JOSE, Costa Rica (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> proposed at a gathering of Central American presidents Sunday that <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> observers in the region be given new powers and personnel to start disbanding the U.S.-backed <ORGANIZATION> Contra </ORGANIZATION> rebels, a Nicaraguan source said. But after the summit's first day, the Nicaraguans were no closer to getting agreement on their proposal. `` Nothing has been done,'' Foreign Minister <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Escoto </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> told reporters after the day's session had ended. `` The demobilization of the Contras must be complied with,'' he said. `` The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> must begin to function in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>.'' Also Sunday, the Salvadoran government rejected a truce proposed by leftist rebels fighting in that country. In return for demobilization of the Contras, the Nicaraguan government would consider resuming its cease-fire and `` technical talks'' with the leadership of the Honduras-based rebels, said a Nicaraguan source after the opening of the two-day summit. The source close to the <LOCATION> Nicaraguan </LOCATION> delegation, who refused to be identified, also said <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> was willing to allow the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> group to verify that no weapons are sent from <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>'s leftist rebels The <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> observers were approved four months ago to monitor the voluntary repatriation of the Contras and make sure that one country's territory was not being used to launch attacks on a neighbor. The source, however, said the Nicaraguan government was not optimistic about acceptance of the proposal in view of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' `` bipartisan decision to keep the Contras alive until after the February elections in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>.'' <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> canceled its cease-fire with the Contras on Nov. 1, accusing them of disrupting registration for the Feb. 25 elections. Also at Sunday's opening session, the Salvadoran government rejected a cease-fire proposal by the leftist rebels of the <ORGANIZATION> Farabundo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, or <ORGANIZATION> FMLN </ORGANIZATION>. The rebels asked for the dismissal of seven high-ranking military leaders in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> and `` full respect for human rights and democratic liberties of political and social organizations.'' The Salvadoran government instead asked the rebels to make a commitment not to launch attacks in urban areas and offered to resume negotiations in <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> proposed a truce in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> from Dec. 12 through Jan. 15 `` to give the <ORGANIZATION> FMLN </ORGANIZATION> and the government time to begin negotiations for a permanent cease-fire.'' <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> also proposed that the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> be given powers to verify such a cease-fire in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. The five Central American presidents opened their meeting in an atmosphere of frustration and pessimism, hoping the superpowers would help rescue the flagging peace efforts in the region. `` We must face that reality'' that the superpowers' help is needed, said Costa Rican Foreign Minister <PERSON> Rodrigo </PERSON> <PERSON> Madrigal </PERSON>, who commented on the presidents' discussions. He added that regional agreements will not have much validity in those places where parties in the conflicts have close ties to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Attending the summit are presidents <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> of <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Vinicio </PERSON> <PERSON> Cerezo </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Azcona </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoyo </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. The presidents met briefly in a conference room, listened to a welcoming speech by Costa Rican Information Minister <PERSON> Jorge </PERSON> <PERSON> Urbina </PERSON>, and then went into a private session. <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> on Saturday had called the superpowers, without naming the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, `` two-faced.'' He said they spoke about political solutions while encouraging military activities. `` We must demand from them a definition of their roles, what they have done themselves or through other countries to exert a negative or positive influence in the region,'' <PERSON> Madrigal </PERSON> said. He did not suggest how the superpowers might respond, but one source, speaking with the condition of anonymity, said the two might send representatives or observers to negotiations between the warring parties. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> supports the Nicaraguan rebels fighting the leftist Sandinista government. It also backs <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> in its civil war against leftist insurgents. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> accuses the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> of providing arms and aid to <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and the Salvadoran rebels. This summit had been scheduled to be held in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, but it was changed to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION> when <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> suspended relations with <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> last month. <PERSON> El </PERSON> <PERSON> Salvador </PERSON> took the action after two small planes were found in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> carrying surface-to-air rockets that <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> said were being flown from <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> to the <ORGANIZATION> FMLN </ORGANIZATION>. One plane crashed and the other was burned at a rural airstrip. Agreements reached at an August summit in <LOCATION> Tela </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>, called for the Nicaraguan Contra rebels to disband by Dec. 5. However, their forces, headquartered in camps in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>, have remained in place.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891211-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-11-89 0107EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MagnetSchools     12-11 0739</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Magnet Schools,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Magnet Program Provides Mixed Blessings</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TAMARA HENRY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COLLEGE PARK, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
