<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890112-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-12-89 2328EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Archbishop-Assassination     01-12 0365</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Archbishop-Assassination,0376</SECOND>
<HEAD>Suspect In Archbishop Romero's Assassination Released</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MILT SOSIN</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Salvadoran accused of conspiring in the 1980 assassination of Archbishop <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Romero </PERSON> was freed on bail Thursday night after his homeland's high court denied a request for his extradition, his attorney said. <PERSON> Alvaro </PERSON> <PERSON> Saravia </PERSON> had been ordered held by President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Napoleon </PERSON> <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>'s government, which accused him of arranging <PERSON> Romero </PERSON>'s assassination on orders of right-wing legislator <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> d'Aubuisson </PERSON>, who denied the allegation `` <PERSON> Saravia </PERSON> telephoned one of my associates at 8:30 tonight and told him ` I'm out,''' said his <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> attorney, <PERSON> Neal </PERSON> <PERSON> Sonnett </PERSON>. <PERSON> Saravia </PERSON> was released on $ 10,000 bond pending deportation hearings, he said. The <ORGANIZATION> Salvadoran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruled last month there was n't enough evidence linking <PERSON> Saravia </PERSON> to the murder, and said he would not be subject to arrest if he were sent home. <PERSON> Saravia </PERSON>, a former captain in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>'s air force, had been jailed in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> since November 1987, when he was arrested for a traffic violation and authorities found he had been in the country illegally since 1985. The Salvadoran government withdrew its extradition request after its courts ruled that there were no grounds for arresting him on charges he had violated his visa, and that the extradition request itself was illegal. <PERSON> Romero </PERSON>, an outspoken critic of right-wing death squads, was shot by a sniper while saying Mass in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> on March 24, 1980. In November 1987, President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Napoleon </PERSON> <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>'s government accused <PERSON> Saravia </PERSON> of arranging the assassination and released the testimony of <PERSON> Amadeo </PERSON> <PERSON> Garay </PERSON> <PERSON> Reyes </PERSON>, who allegedly drove the sniper to the church. The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruled that <PERSON> Garay </PERSON>'s testimony was not credible, partly because he waited more than seven years to come forward with his story. The court also said Attorney General <PERSON> Giron </PERSON> <PERSON> Flores </PERSON> did not have the constitutional power to ask the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to send <PERSON> Saravia </PERSON> back to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Flores </PERSON> had directly asked the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for <PERSON> Saravia </PERSON>'s extradition The case went to the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> after <PERSON> Saravia </PERSON>'s attorney requested a hearing <PERSON> Sonnett </PERSON>, who is also representing Panamanian Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> against federal drug charges here, said <PERSON> Saravia </PERSON> had gone home to his wife, who has been living in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890112-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-12-89 2341EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ManJailed     01-12 0548</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Man Jailed,0565</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prisons Don't Want Cancer Victim Jailed in Sewer Dispute</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRUCE SMITH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHARLESTON, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Wilburt </PERSON> <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON>, the 73-year-old cancer victim jailed in a dispute over a sewer hook-up, was freed Thursday after a state prison and a county jail both refused to accept him as a prisoner. <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON> spent Wednesday night in the <ORGANIZATION> Lieber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Correctional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Ridgeville </LOCATION>. But he was released after state officials decided they lacked authority to imprison an inmate for civil contempt of court. <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON> was then sent back to <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, but Sheriff <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Cannon </PERSON> said the county jail could n't house him because it is overcrowded. He also said the jail did n't have the medical facilities to treat <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON>, who suffers from rectal cancer. <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION> attorney <PERSON> Gedney </PERSON> <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> then asked for a hearing before Circuit Judge <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Howell </PERSON>, who found <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON> in contempt last November. `` <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Cannon </PERSON> and I came to the same conclusion if he could n't go to <PERSON> Lieber </PERSON>, he sure could n't go to the county jail,'' <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> said. Before the hearing, <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> said he and the judge discussed options in the case and said <PERSON> Howell </PERSON> said a motion to appeal the contempt order could be considered. `` I appealed the judge's opinion which will postpone him -LRB- <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON> -RRB- going back to jail,'' <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> said. He said appeals to the state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> can take some time and `` hopefully he'll be a free man for at least several months.'' `` Judge <PERSON> Howell </PERSON> today looked at a difficult problem and found a way out that was satisfactory to everybody and was legally correct,'' <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> said. `` We're so weary and thankful and we're just going to go to bed,'' <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON>'s wife <PERSON> Hattie </PERSON> said later from the couple's home. `` It's been a rough day.'' The contempt order stems from <ORGANIZATION> Siegels </ORGANIZATION>' refusal to obey an earlier 1986 court order that he connect his <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Island </PERSON> home to a sewer line. The <ORGANIZATION> Siegels </ORGANIZATION> have had a decade-long dispute with the <ORGANIZATION> James </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> over connecting the sewer. They say the tap-in point is too far from their septic tank and would cost them an additional $ 2,000 and cause them to destroy several large pine trees in order to make the connection. <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> X. </PERSON> <PERSON> Archibald </PERSON>, a spokesman for the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corrections </ORGANIZATION>, said the issue arose as to whether <PERSON> Lieber </PERSON> should house the prisoner after <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON> arrived at the prison Wednesday. `` They referred it to the department's legal advisor in <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> who researched the matter and he said we lacked the authority'' to house a prisoner jailed for civil contempt, <PERSON> Archibald </PERSON> said. He said the decision was based on an attorney general's opinion of some years back. The <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON> case was later the topic of a discussion between Corrections Department legal advisor <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Batson </PERSON> and state Attorney General <PERSON> Travis </PERSON> <PERSON> Medlock </PERSON> and <PERSON> Medlock </PERSON> concurred in the decision, <PERSON> Archibald </PERSON> said. On Wednesday, <PERSON> Cannon </PERSON> escorted <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON> from the modest <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Island </PERSON> house, which was draped with an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> flag and where yellow ribbons were tied around five large pine trees. <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON> said he was going to prison for his principles and that he had been treated unfairly compared to other residents in the area who had sewer lines closer to their homes or had not been forced to hook onto the sewer.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890112-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-12-89 0633EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LandfillProtest     01-12 1059</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Landfill Protest,1084</SECOND>
<HEAD>GSX Waste Landfill Symbolic of State's Waste Dilemma</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TRIP DuBARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SUMTER, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> is home to wealthy cotton plantations, stately antebellum mansions and a growing share of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s toxic wastes. Now, with a 10-year-old waste landfill's license up for renewal, a debate is looming over the state's role as the nation's `` septic tank.'' `` We have been taken advantage of,'' said state Rep. <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hallman </PERSON>, who resigned in November as chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> to take a seat in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION>. He's pushing legislation that would tighten state control of waste disposal. The <ORGANIZATION> GSX </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> landfill in <LOCATION> Sumter </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> is one of two commercial hazardous waste landfills in the Southeast _ the other is in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> _ and is the tomb for a half-million tons of chemicals. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> is also home to two hazardous-waste incinerators and one for infectious waste; the Barnwell low-level nuclear waste landfill, and the troubled <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plant </LOCATION> that produces nuclear bomb fuel. `` It all plays in. The reason GSX has become an issue is not because it is the only issue, but because it's a symbolic issue,'' said Democratic state Sen. <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Leventis </PERSON>, a long-time critic of the landfill. Some 130,000 tons of chemical garbage will be buried at GSX this year, about 70 percent from industries in more than 30 other states and <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>. Two incinerators, in <LOCATION> Roebuck </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, can accept a total of 58,920 tons a year of hazardous waste; 75 percent is from other states. A third can take 36,500 tons of infectious waste, which comes from 10 states and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Chem-Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> low-level radioactive waste landfill at <LOCATION> Barnwell </LOCATION> _ the only one in operation in the nation _ took 900,000 cubic feet of contaminated clothing, tools and other debris in 1988 and expects the same this year. The state produces 85,000 tons of hazardous waste a year, according to the health department. It has plenty of room for its neighbors' garbage. `` It seems we're a patsy for somebody, does n't it? It seems that the federal government has found a place that does n't resist,'' said <PERSON> Shelly </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Sumter </LOCATION>, a retired hotel manager and <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> major. `` It just seems that we're getting more than our share. `` I feel that at some point in time, that place will be a real problem to us, and that we should n't be required to take other states' waste.'' The 279-acre GSX landfill opened in 1978. Its bottom rests 10 feet above an aquifer and its lip is 400 yards from <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Marion </LOCATION>, one of the <PERSON> Santee </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON> lakes created in World War II to provide hydroelectric power to underdeveloped areas and <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>'s defense-related industries State and company officials say the hard claystone from which the landfill is carved makes it a natural location. But siting standards for hazardous waste landfills are only now being drafted and are not expected before the end of 1989. <ORGANIZATION> DHEC </ORGANIZATION> has decided not to wait for the standards to make a decision on the landfill's permit, and officials say they can be applied retroactively. GSX encases its waste in two layers of clay 3 feet and 5 feet thick, separated by two hard plastic liners and a leak detection system. The waste is tested on arrival to ensure that it's not flammable, radioactive, explosive or laced with dioxin, then it is mixed with concrete and buried. `` GSX is doing a good job in doing what they're doing. I think they're handling it in a safe manner,'' said Gov. <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>. Some area opponents, however, say constantly changing burial requirements have made them unwilling participants in a test of developing technology. When federal regulations changed in 1985 from one layer of clay and plastic to two, earlier burial cells were not retrofitted. And a monitoring system crucial for detecting leaks has been upgraded from eight to about 50 wells since 1983. `` As technology progresses, we adopt it,'' said GSX Vice President <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>. `` Certainly nobody's claiming perfection, but we just do the best we know how to do.'' <PERSON> Hallman </PERSON>, a Republican who calls <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> `` the septic tank of the nation,'' has organized a bipartisan environmental caucus of 18 state <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> members he hopes will push legislation endorsed by the <ORGANIZATION> DHEC </ORGANIZATION> board phasing out permanent burial of chemical waste by 1992 and creating a state-owned disposal site so <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> could refuse out-of-state waste. Court rulings have said that prohibitions on out-of-state waste headed to a private facility interfere with interstate commerce. The <ORGANIZATION> DHEC </ORGANIZATION> board also called for burial fee increases from $ 13 to $ 95 per ton for in-state waste and $ 18 to $ 180 per ton for out-of-state waste. The money would go into an existing state fund to be used for any cleanup at the site. A 1985 <ORGANIZATION> DHEC </ORGANIZATION> study estimated that cleanup costs would approach $ 1 billion if all of the landfill's holding cells were breached. The state requires only $ 6 million in insurance, though <ORGANIZATION> GSX </ORGANIZATION> maintains a $ 30 million policy. House members rank the <ORGANIZATION> DHEC </ORGANIZATION> proposals second behind the politically charged issue of auto insurance reform among the biggest issues facing them this year. The proposals will be challenged by manufacturers _ including the state's biggest industry, textiles _ who use the GSX site extensively. They say such moves could increase costs and mean the loss of jobs. The <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Textile </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> voted in December to fight. `` Closing of the facility would create more problems than it would solve and could lead to improper disposal of hazardous waste in other locations,'' said <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Blair </PERSON> <PERSON> Rice </PERSON>, chairman of the group's environmental committee. A November public hearing on the GSX permit drew a rowdy crowd of 2,000 people, many of whom stayed seven hours to berate <ORGANIZATION> DHEC </ORGANIZATION> and GSX. <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Boykin </PERSON>, who first opposed the landfill and helped organize Citizens Asking for a Safe Environment after a 1984 hearing, says it has mobilized her as she expects <ORGANIZATION> SRP </ORGANIZATION> and the other environmental dilemmas to affect others. `` We grew up truly believing that government would protect us,'' she said. `` I think we've come to realize that our state and federal government are not necessarily going to protect us. We're going to have to protect ourselves.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890112-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-12-89 0636EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-ArtandRebellion     01-12 0727</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Art and Rebellion,0747</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RONI RABIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890112-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-12-89 0639EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--BogusDollars     01-12 0145</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Bogus Dollars,0149</SECOND>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890112-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-12-89 0639EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ReaganSwanSong Bjt   01-12 0748</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan Swan Song, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890112-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-12-89 0221EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     01-12 0824</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,810</SECOND>
<HEAD>Farmers Union Opposes Decoupling Payments</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farmers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> says it will wage a lobbying battle in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> against a proposal to let farmers collect federal subsidies without regard to the kind of crops they produce. <ORGANIZATION> NFU </ORGANIZATION> president <PERSON> Leland </PERSON> <PERSON> Swenson </PERSON> said Wednesday that the idea, known as `` decoupling,'' would be `` devastating for farmers and rural communities, endanger the environment and destabilize the position of Third World farmers.'' <PERSON> Swenson </PERSON> said at a news conference that decoupling would be a `` short-term welfare program'' and will be opposed vigorously by <ORGANIZATION> NFU </ORGANIZATION> lobbyists. The idea of decoupling has been around for years but has not had great support on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. One of the early decisions by the incoming <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration will be whether to embrace decoupling as a way of containing government farm costs. Under some versions of decoupling, federal payments targeted to farmers would gradually be reduced over four or five years and perhaps then be eliminated altogether as producers are weaned from federal crop subsidies. The <ORGANIZATION> NFU </ORGANIZATION>'s main rival, the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION>, at one time supported decoupling but since has backed off to give it a closer look. One of the biggest advocates is the <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, a Washington-based conservative think tank, which recently issued a report saying that one of the first jobs of the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration should be to cut subsidies and `` get farmers off the dole.'' Decoupling, the <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> report said, would allow federal payments to farmers to be based on a flat rate and targeted to those most in need. As it has been for more than half a century, payments now are pegged to specific kinds of crops and levels of production _ the larger the farm, the larger the subsidy. Under decoupling, farmers would simply be given a cash payment and then be free to grow or not grow any crop they choose. `` Planting decisions would then be based on market signals _ consumer demand for a product _ rather than on what is required by <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> report said. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Grizzle </PERSON>, who wrote the <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> report, said in a telephone interview that decoupling makes sense as a way of getting crop programs away from government subsidies and into a market-oriented economic environment. `` In my judgment, it's a charade now to think that most of the production that is linked to subsidy payments is being grown for the marketplace,'' <PERSON> Grizzle </PERSON> said. `` It's a mindset, almost like a crutch.'' <PERSON> Swenson </PERSON>, however, called decoupling proposals a `` cop-out'' and released a report analyzing a decoupling bill introduced by Sen. <PERSON> Rudy </PERSON> <PERSON> Boschwitz </PERSON>, R-Minn., in 1985 as the Family Farm Protection and Full Production Act <PERSON> Swenson </PERSON> said the bill continues to have some support in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, along with backing from big grain companies such as <ORGANIZATION> Cargill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> `` It's really a cop-out in addressing the real issue of adopting and implementing a farm program which enhances the market price for agricultural commodities,'' <PERSON> Swenson </PERSON> said. `` It implies that the family farm structure of agriculture is not important.'' The analysis used figures attributed to the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paul </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, showing that the <PERSON> Boschwitz </PERSON> bill would reduce federal price support loans sharply for major crops, including wheat to $ 1.60 per bushel from $ 2.06 this year, and corn to $ 1.30 per bushel from the 1989 rate of $ 1.65. `` Lowering of world prices, a result of decoupling, would aggravate the situation of Third World farmers, who are our best potential customers for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> food exports,'' <PERSON> Swenson </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> NFU </ORGANIZATION>, he said, will draft its own alternative to decoupling to `` assure consumers an adequate and dependable supply of food'' and `` enhance the market price of agricultural commodities.'' Although <PERSON> Swenson </PERSON> did not disclose details of what <ORGANIZATION> NFU </ORGANIZATION>'s plan might include, he said it would `` reduce the budget impact of farm programs'' and allow for continued expansion of agricultural exports. The 1988 drought helped siphon off huge stockpiles of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> grain, boosting market prices for wheat to an average of $ 3.89 per bushel last month from $ 2.70 a year earlier. Corn in December, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, averaged $ 2.54 per bushel, compared with the year-earlier mark of $ 1.72 per bushel. <PERSON> Swenson </PERSON> was asked if the <ORGANIZATION> NFU </ORGANIZATION> would recommend an increase in federal price supports to as much as current market prices. He replied, `` Or higher.'' The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration for eight years has been committed to a market-oriented farm policy, less reliance on federal controls and freer world trade. Those goals are expected to continue under the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration. But <PERSON> Swenson </PERSON> is not convinced at this time that foreign countries will go along with current <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agricultural trade objectives in the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration any more than they have in the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> years. `` There is n't such a thing as a free market,'' <PERSON> Swenson </PERSON> said. `` It does n't exist, will not exist, either in this country or any other major exporting country in the world.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890112-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-12-89 0027EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Mexico-Union 4thLd-Writethru   01-12 0795</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mexico-Union, 4th Ld-Writethru,a0793,0816</SECOND>
<HEAD>Workers Begin Returning After Crackdown On Union Bosses</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS grafs 4-5, `Also, sources...they said' to UPDATE with attorney
general's office saying union leader told investigators he bought weapons.
Pick up 6th pvs, `Reynosa, which...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRIS ANGELO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Oil refinery workers nationwide began returning to work Wednesday, ending a series of strikes and rallies to protest the bloody arrest of their union bosses on weapons and corruption charges. The government continued its crackdown on <PERSON> Joaquin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> <PERSON> Galicia </PERSON>, leader of the powerful <ORGANIZATION> Oil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>. He and about 50 associates have been arrested on fraud, weapons and tax evasion charges, said a spokesman for the attorney general's office, <PERSON> Fernando </PERSON> <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>. Meanwhile, authorities said two of <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> <PERSON> Galicia </PERSON>'s bodyguards _ who were arrested in the sweep _ reported that their boss ordered the 1983 slaying of a mayor who headed a union local, officials said. The attorney general's office said in a statement late Wednesday that <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> <PERSON> Galicia </PERSON> told investigators he purchased scores of weapons in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> <PERSON> Galicia </PERSON> told investigators the weapons were brought into <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> by his `` good friend,'' <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Cruz </PERSON> <PERSON> Contreras </PERSON>, a former mayor of <LOCATION> Reynosa </LOCATION>, the statement said. <PERSON> Cruz </PERSON> <PERSON> Contreras </PERSON> gave the weapons to <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> <PERSON> Galicia </PERSON> on Dec. 10, it said. <LOCATION> Reynosa </LOCATION>, which has a refinery and petrochemicals plant, lies across the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> border from <LOCATION> McAllen </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. It is a stronghold of oil workers allied with <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> <PERSON> Galicia </PERSON>. Strikes by refinery workers broke out Tuesday night after the arrests began. The union corruption investigation is widely seen as a challenge to the union by the new administration of President <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON>. Guards were posted at gas stations and refineries and many motorists, fearing shortages, formed 30 - and 40-car lines to fill up their tanks at stations in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tampico </LOCATION> and other cities But petroleum workers began showing up at their jobs later Wednesday after a union official called for the strikes to end. `` They -LRB- workers -RRB- should report for work. They should forget marches, work stoppages and rallies because, despite the protest of the union of the arbitrary arrest of its leaders, we do not want to affect the industry or the population,'' <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Leon </PERSON>, acting coordinator of the union. He said the message was from <PERSON> Salvador </PERSON> <PERSON> Barragan </PERSON> <PERSON> Camacho </PERSON>, the union secretary-general, who was under arrest at a cardiology hospital on Wednesday. <PERSON> Barragan </PERSON> reportedly checked into the hospital after the arrests began. <PERSON> Vania </PERSON> <PERSON> Munoz </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the state-owned oil monoply <ORGANIZATION> Pemex </ORGANIZATION>, said production of crude oil and petrochemicals has returned to normal. `` We are all going back to work to show that we do not have any problem with the company,'' said <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> <PERSON> Trevino </PERSON>, 23, a worker at the <ORGANIZATION> Ciudad </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Madero </ORGANIZATION> refinery in <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> <PERSON> Galicia </PERSON>'s hometown, 220 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> on the Gulf of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> It was not known how many workers struck Tuesday and how many returned. Some refineries were harder hit than others. About 4,200 of the 6,000 workers had failed to report for early shifts Wednesday at the <ORGANIZATION> Petroleos </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mexicanos </ORGANIZATION> refinery in <LOCATION> Ciudad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Madero </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Acevedo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cadena </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Petroleos </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mexicanos </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. He said production was reduced to `` less than half'' of his company's daily capacity of 185,000 barrels of gasoline. But operations were reported back to normal at the <LOCATION> Azcapotzalco </LOCATION> refinery in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> <PERSON> Galicia </PERSON> was arrested Tuesday when soldiers blew down his door with a bazooka rocket in a raid on his home in northeastern <LOCATION> Ciudad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Madero </LOCATION> city, the <ORGANIZATION> Notimex </ORGANIZATION> state news agency said. One federal agent was killed in the ensuing shootout with <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> <PERSON> Galicia </PERSON>'s bodyguards, said Attorney General <PERSON> Enrique </PERSON> <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON> <PERSON> del </PERSON> <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON>. He denied the arrest was an attack on the union, saying: `` It is the prosecution of crime committed by individuals.'' Police confiscated 200 Uzi machine guns at the house, <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON> said. Numerous weapons also were found at <PERSON> Barragan </PERSON> <PERSON> Camacho </PERSON>'s home. Two bodyguards of <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> <PERSON> Galicia </PERSON> told authorities Wednesday that he ordered them to take part in the 1983 killing of <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Torres </PERSON> <PERSON> Pancardo </PERSON>, a union local leader and mayor of <LOCATION> Poza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Veracruz </LOCATION> state, where an oil refinery is located, a source at the attorney general's office said on condition of anonymity. <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> <PERSON> Galicia </PERSON> has had a long-running feud with <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>, who took office Dec. 1, and <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramon </PERSON> <PERSON> Beteta </PERSON>, who headed <ORGANIZATION> Pemex </ORGANIZATION> until about a year ago when he left to become governor of the state of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>, then budget and planning secretary, and <PERSON> Beteta </PERSON> had cut into the lucrative business <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> <PERSON> Galicia </PERSON> and the union had enjoyed through the control of millions of dollars in <ORGANIZATION> Pemex </ORGANIZATION> subcontracts. <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> is the world's sixth-largest crude oil producer. Production from the country's nine refineries is 1.4 million barrels a day.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890112-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-12-89 0223EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SolicitorCandidates     01-12 0700</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Solicitor Candidates,700</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890112-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-12-89 0223EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Father'sWill     01-12 0211</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Father's Will,0216</SECOND>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890112-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-12-89 0226EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DemocraticChairman     01-12 0336</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Democratic Chairman,330</SECOND>
<HEAD>Brown Wins Labor Backing In DNC Race</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Labor Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> is supporting longtime <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> activist <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>'s bid to be the next party chairman, giving the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> attorney labor's influential backing in the five-man race. The <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> announced the endorsement Wednesday following a 90-minute meeting of president <PERSON> Lane </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> and 16 other members of its national political committee. The endorsement was announced in a two-sentence statement that said <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> was the `` consensus'' choice of those at the meeting. It did not list any reason for the endorsement or refer to public endorsements of another candidate, former Rep. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stanton </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, by building-trades unions affiliated with <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION>. Of the 404 votes on the <ORGANIZATION> DNC </ORGANIZATION>, 46 are cast by union representatives. But labor's influence is considered far greater than those numbers suggest. All five candidates to succeed <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> met with <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> leaders last week in hopes of securing the endorsement. `` This endorsement represents a vote of confidence by the representatives of the working men and women of this country,'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said in a statement. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> and <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiner </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> state party chairman, are viewed as the front-runners to replace <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON>. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> has the support of many national Democrats, but few if any of them vote. <PERSON> Weiner </PERSON>'s base stems from his role as president of the Assocation of <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> Chairs The other candidates are former congressmen <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>. All five last week began a series of joint regional meetings around the country. The <ORGANIZATION> DNC </ORGANIZATION> will pick a successor to <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> next month. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> is a veteran party insider who advised the unsuccessful presidential campaign of <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. Critics of <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>'s candidacy argue that his election would suggest that the party is lining up behind <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s liberal stands. Among such critics is <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, a moderate who said Wednesday evening that his `` campaign continues to move forward'' despite the labor endorsement of <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890112-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-12-89 0226EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-IranContra-CIA     01-12 0341</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran Contra-CIA,0350</SECOND>
<BYLINE>Reports U.S. Withheld Documents To Protect Latin American Contacts</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 To avoid identifying several Latin American government officials as working for the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration withheld certain documents from the trial of Lt. Col. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>, The <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> reported today. Quoting unidentified sources close to the Iran-Contra inquiry, the newspaper says the administration feared that any discussion of the documents in court might disrupt <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence in several countries. One source said some of the withheld documents were declassified during congressional investigations of the Iran-Contra affair, but were later reclassified in an effort to limit discussion of the incidents they describe, the <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> said. Special prosecutor <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> asked that the two major charges against <PERSON> North </PERSON> be dismissed after the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration refused to allow certain documents to be used in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION>'s trial. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> is expected to act on <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s request this week. The newspaper said some of its sources are closely tied to <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s defense team while others either worked closely with <PERSON> North </PERSON> in the past or participated in the 1987 congressional investigation into the Iran-Contra affair. One of the sources is a senior administration official who advises the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> on Central American security policy, the newspaper said. Countries listed in the documents, the sources said, include <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION> where _ respectively _ North's resupply network aiding the Nicaraguan Contra rebels built an airstrip, controlled part of an air base and attempted to buy military aircraft. North's activities in these countries were central to <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s legal strategy to show that the former <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> aide conspired to defraud the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and steal government property by using the profits from arms sales to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> to purchase supplies for the Contras Those are the charges <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> says he must withdraw. In each case, the sources said, <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> has documentary evidence, including invoices, receipts and other legal papers, showing transactions involving <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> arms sales profits and Contra supplies.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890112-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-12-89 0640EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-Savimbi     01-12 0190</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Savimbi,190</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Reported to Pledge Support to Angolan Rebel</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Angolan rebel leader <PERSON> Jonas </PERSON> <PERSON> Savimbi </PERSON> has President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s assurance of continued <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> support until the Angolan government reaches a settlement with him, according to a published report today. The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported that the assurance was contained in a Jan. 6 letter from <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The vice president also said the incoming <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration will push other governments to work for an agreement between <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Savimbi </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION> movement, according to the newspaper. In the letter, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> promised to `` continue all appropriate and effective assistance to <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION>'' until <PERSON> Savimbi </PERSON>'s political goals are reached. That means covert military aid, which has cost about $ 15 million annually for the past two years, the newspaper said, quoting an unidentified <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> aide. On Dec. 22, <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> signed an agreement providing for the phased withdrawal of Cuban troops from <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, along with the independence of <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>, the neighboring territory which is administered by <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has no formal ties with the government of <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, partly because of the presence of the 50,000 Cuban troops.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890112-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-12-89 0641EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Brazil-FastTrain     01-12 0124</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Brazil-Fast Train,0125</SECOND>
<HEAD>Brazil Will Have High Speed Train</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BRASILIA, Brazil (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> will introduce <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s first high speed train, which will connect its two main cities, <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Janeiro </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Sao </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paulo </LOCATION>, about 280 miles apart, in two hours, authorities say According to initial studies, the train will be able to exceed 132 mph. A <ORGANIZATION> Transport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> source said Wednesday that bidding among national and foreign companies interested in installing and operating the line will begin Jan. 28 and construction should start in about a year. The winning company will have the right to operate the high speed train for a period of from 30 to 50 years and will have complete control in setting ticket prices, the source said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890112-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-12-89 0641EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MissileCrisis     01-12 0431</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Missile Crisis,430</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CALLAHAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890112-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-12-89 0638EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     01-12 0370</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0381</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LINCOLN, Neb. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It was not the type of ceremonial presentation that a governor makes every day, but it was n't in recognition of the kind of senatorial circumstance that arises every day, either. Gov. <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> <PERSON> Orr </PERSON> made a special trip from her second-floor office Wednesday to call Sen. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> McFarland </PERSON> from an <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and present him with a can opener, bedecked with a big ribbon, `` in case you ever find yourself locked in the can again.'' <PERSON> McFarland </PERSON> somehow managed to break a dead-bolt lock on the door of a small bathroom on the Capitol's eighth floor last week. He was there for nearly an hour before maintenance workers got clearance to take the door apart and let him out. `` I heard that you had had some difficulty and thought this might be of some value to you if this unfortunate type of thing happens again,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Orr </PERSON> said. `` Governor, I accept this in the spirit in which it is given and, believe me, I wo n't leave home without it,'' <PERSON> McFarland </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Artist <PERSON> Krandel </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Newton </PERSON> is getting ahead by sketching behinds. On warm days, <PERSON> Newton </PERSON> sets up his business called `` The Original Butt Sketch'' in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>' West End, a section of downtown that on weekends attracts thousands to its restaurants and boutiques. And there he is out in the open, sketching with charcoal, his subjects lifting their jackets high enough for <PERSON> Newton </PERSON> and the rest of <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> to see their posteriors. Clothed, of course. `` You'd be surprised, but after I start the first sketch, people just crowd around and I end up doing 60 or 70 on a Friday or Saturday night,'' <PERSON> Newton </PERSON> said. `` Eighty percent of them are women.'' He says he's in such high demand, traveling all around the country, that he's really getting behind in his work. It was a festival in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> last month, an auto convention in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> next week, he said in an interview. <PERSON> Newton </PERSON> gets $ 10 a sketch or 8 cents a pound, but not too many customers care to weigh themselves in public. The thrifty and thin save money if the scale records no more than 125 pounds.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890112-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-12-89 0619EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Italy-DrySpell     01-12 0555</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Italy-Dry Spell,0568</SECOND>
<HEAD>Skiers Angered, Farmers Worried By Drought</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PIERO VALSECCHI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MILAN, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890112-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-12-89 0458EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     01-12 0049</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0051</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Wednesday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 02; 05; 06; 11; 22; 28.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 13; 16; 30; 40; 44; 48. Supplementary 14.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 2-9-2; 9-6-6-5; 0-7-2-4-6; 0-4-6-2-5-5.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890112-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-12-89 0651EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a BC-Opera     01-12 0438</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Opera,0457</SECOND>
<HEAD>Opera Is Based on O'Neill Play</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: No PMs Planned</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890112-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-12-89 0651EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--OfficerSpanked     01-12 0131</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Officer Spanked,0134</SECOND>
<HEAD>Undercover Officer Agreed To Paddling ... All In The Line Of Duty</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An undercover police officer took a paddling while posing as a high school student so he would n't miss an opportunity to make a drug buy, officials said. The 25-year-old officer, whose identity is being kept secret, ran afoul of school law when he was late for classes, said <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Ward </PERSON>, principal of W.T. White High School. Given the choice of after-school detention and missing a scheduled drug buy or corporal punishment, the officer submitted to the spanking, <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> said. An assistant principal administered the paddling before school officials found out the `` student's'' real identity, <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> said. The drug investigation at W.T. White High resulted 16 arrests, said police narcotics Lt. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890112-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-12-89 0237EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Homeless     01-12 0378</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Homeless,360</SECOND>
<HEAD>RETRANSMITTING a0425 to correct cycle designator</HEAD>
<HEAD>HUD Selects Federal Property That Can Be Used For Homeless</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARTON REPPERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890112-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-12-89 0614EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     01-12 0980</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1020</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890112-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-12-89 0107EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Germany-Libya     01-12 0738</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Germany-Libya,0767</SECOND>
<BYLINE>Kohl On Libya-West Germany Link: `There May Be Some Evidence...'^
^By TERRENCE PETTY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BONN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
