<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890611-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-89 2330EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Colombia-Plane     06-11 0276</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Colombia-Plane,0287</SECOND>
<HEAD>Small Plane Makes Emergency Landing During Storm, Four Killed, Officials
Say</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOGOTA, Colombia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A small commercial plane with 20 people aboard made an emergency landing near the Venezuelan border during a storm Sunday, killing four people and injuring 12, the government said. The plane, a Canadian-built Twin Otter operated by the private domestic company <PERSON> Aerotaca </PERSON>, landed on a bank of the <LOCATION> Casanara </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> because of a driving rain, said <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. The report did not say what damage the plane suffered or how the four people died, and it did not give the breakdown of passengers and crew. A press report said all people aboard the twin-engine plane were Colombian. Among the passengers were Colombian folk singer and composer <PERSON> Arnulfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Briceno </PERSON> as well as reporters and television cameramen invited by the state-owned company <ORGANIZATION> Ecopetrol </ORGANIZATION> to retrace the route taken by <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> <PERSON> Bolivar </PERSON> during the final battles on Colombian independence from <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> 170 years ago, said an agency spokesman. The names of the other passengers and crew were were not immediately available and it was not known whether <PERSON> Briceno </PERSON> was among the victims. The plane was flying between <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION> and Tame, an oil town 220 miles east of the capital, the spokesman said, speaking on condition of anonymity. A company source said the pilot reported the plane could not land in Tame because of the heavy rain and was fly on to <LOCATION> Bucaramang </LOCATION>, the largest city in eastern <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>. Authorities declared the plane missing when it failed to reach its destination. Some Colombian <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> units searched for the plane, but it was not immediately clear who spotted the aircraft.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890611-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-89 0002EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-RinkFumes     06-11 0395</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Rink Fumes,0405</SECOND>
<HEAD>Seven Overcome by Carbon Monoxide at Ice Rink Released From Hospital</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEAVERTON, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Seven people hospitalized after being overcome by carbon monoxide in an ice skating rink were released Saturday, and special precautions were taken to avoid more problems. The seven were among 25 people sickened by gas emitted from an ice grooming machine, known as a Zamboni, during a hockey tournament at the rink Friday. The others were treated with oxygen at the scene. A faulty exhaust system on the Zamboni apparently caused it to emit the carbon monoxide, which stayed close to the ice, said <ORGANIZATION> Tualatin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Valley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rescue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> dispatcher <PERSON> Rod </PERSON> <PERSON> Nodland </PERSON>. He said the carbon monoxide readings in the arena were at safe levels Saturday. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McBride </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Valley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arena </ORGANIZATION> general manager, said large fans were set up Saturday to circulate air at the rink and the ice grooming machine was fitted with a catalytic converter to reduce its emissions. He theorized that extra refrigeration used to keep the ice solid in recent warm weather brought the temperature so low in the arena Friday that carbon monoxide from the Zamboni stayed near the ice and would n't disperse normally. This was the second year in a row that carbon monoxide poisoning has occurred at the rink during a hockey game for the Rose Festival, the city's annual June festival. Paramedics were first alerted to the problems at the rink Friday night when a parent sought aid for a child that was vomiting. Several children complained of dizziness and nausea, and at least one child fainted. Dr. <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Lorts </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Providence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> said one boy brought there Friday night was treated for 90 minutes in a glass-enclosed, pressurized chamber, where pure oxygen was pumped into the boy's lungs Because of the relatively low levels of the carbon monoxide in Friday's incident, <PERSON> Lorts </PERSON> said, it is unlikely that any person at the rink would suffer long-term ill effects. Carbon monoxide is odorless, tasteless and colorless and is produced during combustion. Capt. <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Kline </PERSON>, who headed <ORGANIZATION> Tualatin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Valley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rescue </ORGANIZATION>'s hazardous-materials team at the rink, said initial readings of carbon monoxide in the building were 120 to 170 parts per million of air He said 50 parts per million was considered the maximum concentration before people felt sick, and 1,500 parts per million would be lethal.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890611-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-89 0017EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-AbortionProtests 1stLd-Writethru a0552 06-11 0806</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Abortion Protests, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0552,0827</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nearly 700 Arrested in Anti-Abortion Demonstrations</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 2 grafs to UPDATE with totals including Richmond
arrests. Picks up 3rd graf: Police arrested ...' Adds 2 grafs with details
from Richmond. No pickup.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JONATHAN W. OATIS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Police on Saturday arrested nearly 600 abortion opponents who tried to blockade clinics around the nation, including one in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> disrupted by shouting and shoving matches between protesters and abortion rights advocates. Protests also took place in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wayne </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind </LOCATION>.; <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Arbor </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>. Police arrested 250 of the approximately 500 members of the national anti-abortion group <ORGANIZATION> Operation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rescue </ORGANIZATION> who staged a sit-in that blocked doors to the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Midland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clinic </ORGANIZATION>, said Police Officer <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Plourde </PERSON> The demonstrators, who prayed and sang hymns, were far outnumbered by about 1,000 chanting abortion rights advocates led by organizers using bullhorns. `` This is disgusting! This is a baby!'' <PERSON> Lorna </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> shouted as she thrust a picture of a fetus at counterdemonstrators. `` This woman's ignorance is the mass ignorance of her movement!'' an abortion rights advocate yelled from the crowd, apparently referring to the debate over when life begins. The ill will prompted pushing and shoving as well as angry shouting matches before about 300 police, including several on horseback, moved in. It took them about three hours to clear the sidewalk in front of the clinic, which offers pregnancy counseling, family planning advice and abortions. `` It's a little bit scary today, there's a lot more fighting,'' said Operation Rescue spokeswoman <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> <PERSON> Bingham </PERSON>. `` Our people are willing to be beaten or arrested to save the lives of the babies.'' Among those arrested was Operation Rescue national field director <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Foreman </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> McGuirk </PERSON>, another group spokesman. The protest was the latest in a series by Operation Rescue as the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> considers a challenge to the <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON> decision legalizing abortion. Among the abortion rights advocates at the rally were <PERSON> Norma </PERSON> <PERSON> McCorvey </PERSON>, 41, of <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, who was `` <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Roe </PERSON>'' in the high court's landmark 1973 ruling, and <PERSON> Eleanor </PERSON> <PERSON> Smeal </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Feminist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Majority </ORGANIZATION> and past president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orgniazation </ORGANIZATION> for Women `` Rescue the homeless; rescue the many thousands of hungry people and children that are already here today,'' Ms. <PERSON> McCorvey </PERSON> said outside the clinic in a message to the protesters. `` Think not about the women who choose to have the right to control their own bodies and destinies. You can not choose their destinies for them.'' Those arrested were booked on trespassing charges, and many refused to post $ 500 bail or to identify themselves, <PERSON> Plourde </PERSON> said. Without positive identification, detainees can not be released on their own recognizance. `` Our standard policy is, ` Do n't post bail,''' <PERSON> McGuirk </PERSON> said. `` Do n't accept probation or plea bargaining. Everyone stays -LRB- in jail -RRB- until they all get out.'' In <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, police arrested all but 10 of the 150 anti-abortion protesters who blocked the doors to the Northeast Women's Center. Protesters surrounded woman trying to enter, said clinic acting director <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Straus </PERSON>. `` Several women left very upset, in tears, crying and in stress,'' she said. `` Their health has been endangered.'' The protest organized by the Pro-Life Non-Violent Action Project of <LOCATION> Southeastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> came three months after a federal judge issued a permanent injunction against disruptive abortion demonstrations in the <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> area. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Clarence </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Newcomer </PERSON>'s order includes a $ 5,000 fine for each violation. The center will return to court to accuse the protesters of violating the injunction, said <PERSON> Straus </PERSON>. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> McMonagle </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Pro-Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southeast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pennsylvania </ORGANIZATION>, said the protesters `` do n't let injunctions keep them from saving lives.'' The center also was involved in a case considered the first in the nation accusing protesters of violating anti-racketeering laws. Last March, the 3rd <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> upheld a jury verdict against 27 leaders of the Philadelphia-area movement. The leaders and Operation Rescue have been been fined about $ 110,000 in the case, which has been appealed. In <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION>, about 90 of the 225 anti-abortion protesters who turned out at <ORGANIZATION> Affiliated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, a downtown clinic, were arrested, police said. Officers had to carry away many, who sat down and refused to move. Nearly 40 abortion rights advocates staged a counterdemonstration across the street. In <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Arbor </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, police arrested 63 of the 100 to 200 protesters who turned out a Planned Parenthood clinic, said Lt. <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Roderick </PERSON>. The protesters, who were arrested on trespassing charges, were released after giving officers their names, <PERSON> Roderick </PERSON> said. In <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, police arrested about 45 anti-abortion demonstrators who were blocking entrances to a clinic. Police Maj. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> said the protesters were charged with obstructing public passage to a building. `` They come and picket a lot, but this is the largest number of arrests,'' <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890611-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-89 0020EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Obit-LopezRega     06-11 0280</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Lopez Rega,0288</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lopez Rega, Notorious Cabinet Minister in Peron Government, Dead</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BUENOS AIRES, Argentina (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> <PERSON> Rega </PERSON>, a police corporal and amateur astrologer who rose to power after he became President <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON> <PERSON> Peron </PERSON>'s personal secretary, died in jail of a heart attack. He was 72. <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> <PERSON> Rega </PERSON>'s death was announced Friday night by Judge <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Irurzun </PERSON>'s office. The son of <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> immigrants, <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> <PERSON> Rega </PERSON> was born Oct. 17, 1916, in <LOCATION> Buenos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aires </LOCATION>. He tried a singing career and then became a policeman before being employed as a bodyguard for <PERSON> Peron </PERSON>, who was elected president in 1946 and then overthrown in a military coup in 1955. <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> <PERSON> Rega </PERSON> renewed his acquaintance with <PERSON> Peron </PERSON> in the mid 1960s when the ousted leader was living in exile in <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION>. He became <PERSON> Peron </PERSON>'s personal secretary and returned to <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> with <PERSON> Peron </PERSON> after the military dictatorship agreed to free elections. <PERSON> Peron </PERSON> was elected president in 1973 and he appointed <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> <PERSON> Rega </PERSON> the minister of social welfare. <PERSON> Peron </PERSON> died July 1, 1974, and his wife, <PERSON> Isabel </PERSON>, who was vice president, became chief executive. <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> <PERSON> Rega </PERSON> was a key adviser to her and gained wealth and power. Critics claim he helped set up the Argentine <ORGANIZATION> Anti-Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION>, a rightist death-squad organization accused of dozens of killings. <PERSON> Isabel </PERSON> <PERSON> Peron </PERSON> was ousted by an armed forces coup in 1976 and <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> <PERSON> Rega </PERSON> fled <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> and went into hiding. He was arrested in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and extradited to <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> in July 1986 to face charges of fraud and conspiracy. Earlier this year he was acquitted of fraud but remained in jail pending trial on charges stemming from his alleged connection to the Anti-Communist Alliance.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890611-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-89 0226EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-China-Defections 1stLd-Writethru a0566 06-11 0344</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-Defections, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0566,0351</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Chinese Diplomats Announce Defection At Rally</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: UPDATES throughout with confirmation from the FBI, men taken
to FBI office and requesting asylum, details of rally, quote from one defector;
ADDS byline. No pickup.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY McGRATH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two men identified as Chinese Consulate diplomats announced they can no longer support their government and said they were defecting at a vigil on Saturday for students slain in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. To the amazement and delight of 5,000 people gathered in front of City Hall, the duo mounted a stage and said that as Chinese nationals and as human beings they could no longer go along with a government whose troops fired on unarmed students. Both men were then taken to the nearby offices of the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>, said a policeman, <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>. They had called the bureau before the announcement, said K.K. Woo, one of the rally organizers. The two announced their intention to request political asylum in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> spokesman confirmed. A Chinese Consulate spokesman said he had not heard about the men's statements and had no information. The men announced their action at a rally where a largely <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> crowd, including some crying and many wearing black arm bands, carried candles and makeshift banners reading `` Their blood, Our tears.'' The crowd cheered when the announcement was made, <PERSON> Woo </PERSON> said. Rally organizers, reading from the men's Chinese business cards, identified the speakers as <PERSON> Zhou </PERSON> <PERSON> Li-ming </PERSON> and <PERSON> Chang </PERSON> <PERSON> Li-mun </PERSON>. But they said they were unsure of the proper English transliteration. One of the diplomats told a local television station he was optimistic about the future of the <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s prodemocracy movement despite the government's political crackdown. `` I think their victory is only temporary. The people will win,'' the man, who was not identified, told television station <ORGANIZATION> KTVU </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION>. The station said one of the men was the vice consul and the other either the consulate's information officer or cultural affairs officer. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> would release no information about the men.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890611-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-89 0239EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Hearns-Shooting 2ndLd-Writethru a0567 06-11 0385</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hearns-Shooting, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0567,0391</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman Found Shot to Death in Boxer Thomas Hearns' Home</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: UPDATES throughout with police confirmation of death, six people
being questioned, quotes from Las Vegas, other details. No pickup. Longer
version also moving on sports wires.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JUSTIN BURKE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SOUTHFIELD, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A woman was shot to death in a bedroom of boxer <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Hearns </PERSON>' home on Saturday night and six witnesses were being questioned, police said. One of the boxer's brothers, accompanied by attorney <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Fink </PERSON>, was at the police station, but <LOCATION> Southfield </LOCATION> police Officer <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Conat </PERSON> refused to say whether <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hearns </PERSON> was among those being questioned. The woman, whose name was not released, was shot once in the head, <PERSON> Conat </PERSON> said. She was in her 20s and known to the <PERSON> Hearns </PERSON> family, he said. She was found about 9:40 p.m. Detectives found a gun they believed was used in the slaying, said <PERSON> Conat </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hearns </PERSON> was in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> where he is to meet <PERSON> Sugar </PERSON> <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> on Monday night in a scheduled 12-round fight for <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON>'s World Boxing Council super-middleweight title at Caesars Palace. `` He's going forward with the fight and he says it wo n't affect him in the least,'' promoter <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Arum </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>. `` He did assure me that the fight would go on and he said it would n't affect his performance. Incidents are incidents and they're unfortunate, but we're all professionals here. `` Is he concerned about his brother? He probably is, but he says he does n't want to think about it, and he wo n't. `` As he says, he'll block it out of his mind until he knocks <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> out Monday night.'' <PERSON> Arum </PERSON> said three people in <PERSON> Hearns </PERSON>' entourage left <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> for <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, including his younger brother, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hearns </PERSON>, who is a student at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nevada-Las </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vegas </ORGANIZATION>. His mother, <PERSON> Lois </PERSON> <PERSON> Hearns </PERSON>, will remain in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> for the fight. `` <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON> talked to her and asked her to stay in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Arum </PERSON> said. `` She is here and she is going to stay.'' <PERSON> Arum </PERSON> said `` it has been made clear to me that the -LRB- dead -RRB- woman herself has absolutely no connection with <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>.'' Asked how he knew that since he did n't know the victim's name, he said, `` They apparently know who she is.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890611-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-89 0731EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Israel     06-11 0346</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Israel,0360</SECOND>
<HEAD>Army Lifts Weeklong Curfew on Gaza Strip</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARJORIE OLSTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s military Sunday lifted a weeklong curfew that confined 700,000 Palestinians to their homes in the <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>, ending one of the longest restrictions imposed in the 18-month Arab uprising. Also Sunday, 15-year-old <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Saeed </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaweeshin </PERSON> died of a gunshot wound in the head suffered in a clash with soldiers Saturday in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>'s Jabaliya refugee camp, <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> reports said. An eight-year-old boy also was killed in the stone-throwing confrontation. Officials at <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hashomer </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION>, where the teen-ager was taken for treatment, declined immediate comment. The army said it is checking the report. <PERSON> Shaweeshin </PERSON>'s death brings the toll to at least 515 Palestinians killed since the revolt against Israeli rule began in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. Twenty-two Israelis have died in the violence. Some 4,000 cars carrying Palestinians left <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> after the curfew was lifted to take workers to their jobs in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> said. But the restriction remained in <LOCATION> Jabaliya </LOCATION> camp, where 53,000 Palestinians had to stay home. The military imposed the curfew June 4 to control the population by issuing identity cards that workers will have to show to enter <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. In the <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> suburb of <ORGANIZATION> Petah </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tikva </ORGANIZATION>, 150 peace activists demonstrated Sunday against the town's plan to require that Arab day laborers wait in a specially designated `` transit station'' on the outskirts. The activists say the plan, to keep Arabs out of the town center, is racist. Police have challenging the legality of the station. Its planned opening Sunday was delayed as town councilors debated. Eight Israeli peace activists who met with <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> representatives in June 1987 were charged Sunday in an <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> court with violating anti-terror laws. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> considers the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> a terror organization and bans citizens from meeting with the group. The activists were led by <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Biton </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> legislator who was not charged because he has parliamentary immunity. If convicted, activists could be jailed for up to three years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890611-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-89 1123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Brites     06-11 0470</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Brites,0490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bright &amp; Brief</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BALTIMORE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Piedmont </LOCATION> Flight 1253 to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> was delayed for more than an hour, but the reason was n't a mechanical problem, bad weather or labor strife _ it was a harmless 4-foot snake. The plane was taxing out to take off from <LOCATION> Baltimore-Washington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> when a passenger saw the serpent slithering down the aisle and alerted a flight attendant, said <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Pickett </PERSON>, spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Piedmont </ORGANIZATION>'s parent company. `` The pilot pulled back to the gate and all the passengers deplaned, the maintenance people did their thing and the plane took off about an hour later,'' <PERSON> Pickett </PERSON> said. Workers had to remove three seats in order to capture the critter, a harmless gopher snake, <PERSON> Pickett </PERSON> said. Airline officials did not know how it got into the plane, he said. The reptile was sent to a pet store.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHUA, N.H. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brehm </PERSON> said she and her daughter and grandson were upstairs in their house one recent afternoon when they heard an odd noise in the living room. About 12,000 bees, apparently swarming or looking for a new hive, had flown down the chimney and tried to take up residence in the <PERSON> Brehm </PERSON> house. Mrs. <PERSON> Brehm </PERSON> made a beeline for the upstairs telephone and called her husband, <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON>, at work. `` I know my wife and daughter do n't like insects, so I thought they were exaggerating,'' <PERSON> Brehm </PERSON> said. `` I expected 10 or 20 bees. I could n't believe what I saw when I got there.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Brehm </PERSON> said she called various agencies, including police and exterminators, but no one would help. She finally persuaded <LOCATION> Peterborough </LOCATION> beekeeper <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Camp </PERSON> to come to her aid. Camp arrived with a beehive, about the same time the fire department showed up to help the family out a second-floor window. Camp coaxed most of the bees into the hive, but a few were left over. `` We were vacuuming bees til 1:30 in the morning and dead ones are still turning up,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Brehm </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CHATSWORTH, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Some residents of <LOCATION> Murray </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> are seeing red over what architects and an interior designer have done with their new school. <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> green is the school color at <ORGANIZATION> Murray </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION>, but parts of the exterior of the new building are trimmed in turquoise. `` It's entirely different from the school color, more a sissy green,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Cochran </PERSON>, a junior. `` I just know it's not our color up there and I do n't like it,'' said <PERSON> Melissa </PERSON> <PERSON> Headrick </PERSON>, who graduated from the high school 10 years ago. But school board members decided last week to keep the turquoise trim on the doors, roof edge and archways. Architect <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Haigler </PERSON>, whose firm designed the building, said the color was selected to blend with the building's main colors, beige and white.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890611-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-89 1133EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Germany-Gorbachev Bjt   06-11 0901</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Germany-Gorbachev, Bjt,0924</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviets Hint at Major Initiatives During Visit</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROL J. WILLIAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BONN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s first state visit to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> is overshadowed by tragedy and unrest in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and an accelerating threat worldwide to the socialist ideology that guides his leadership. But the Soviet president's advance men have been deftly deflecting the distractions, hinting that major initiatives may be in the making during the much-publicized summit. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s four-day visit, which begins Monday, comes with high expectations on both sides. Each speaks of a new era in relations and a historic chance for closing the gap between East and West. Both nations are focusing on the opportunities presented by <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reforms, relegating to the sidelines the reform-related crises in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and among ethnic groups within the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. `` We consider this an extremely important meeting, perhaps the most important one we've had in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Gennady </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON>, the Soviet government spokesman, said in an interview on Friday. Acknowledging West Germans' enthusiasm for the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> leader and his reform program, <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON> said <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> wanted a close look at <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and would go out and `` press the flesh.'' Asked if <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> planned to respond to President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s arms control initiative announced May 29 during the <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> summit in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON> said: `` There is no ground for a quick reply.'' He said the conventional weapons reduction plan outlined by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and endorsed by the Western allies has not been formally presented to negotiators at superpower talks in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>, so an official <ORGANIZATION> Kremlin </ORGANIZATION> response was unlikely. But he said another Soviet step in the disarmament volley was `` possible'' during the summit that opens Monday. Another member of the Soviet advance delegation, political observer <PERSON> Lev </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bezymensky </PERSON> of the magazine <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, told reporters Friday that `` we should let ourselves be surprised'' by what takes place during the summit. <PERSON> Hans </PERSON> <PERSON> Klein </PERSON>, a West German government spokesman, sees the visit as a chance to reach a goal of `` peace with ever fewer weapons.'' Foreign Minister <PERSON> Hans-Dietrich </PERSON> <PERSON> Genscher </PERSON> predicted `` a milestone in German-Soviet relations.'' The atmosphere of hope, however, has been tainted by numerous domestic troubles likely to continue boiling while the Soviet leader is abroad. Ethnic unrest in the Central Asian republic of <LOCATION> Uzbekistan </LOCATION> reportedly prompted some last-minute schedule changes to allow <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to stay in close contact with the Kremlin throughout his visit. The <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> Deputies finally ended its stormy inaugural session Friday. The lawmakers' struggle to redefine the nation's course for democracy and their sharp criticism of the Communist Party amazed the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> people, who watched on television, and preoccupied the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> leadership. Soviets are in mourning over the hundreds of deaths resulting from a train disaster in the <LOCATION> Ural </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> June 3, and the advance delegation indicated <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> would not be attending a gala concert in <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> on Wednesday so as to maintain an appropriately somber atmosphere. But the hosts' eagerness to give the summit the highest profile appears to have won out. `` The Germans have done a very clever thing,'' said <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gremitskikh </PERSON>, another senior <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> official in <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> to prepare the summit. `` They have now made it a concert to benefit the victims of the train tragedy, so we will have to reconsider.'' Both sides have pinned high hopes on the visit and its potential to maintain good momentum in improving relations between East and West. West Germans have embraced <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s call for `` a common European home,'' an aim they see as an opportunity to let the barriers fall between East and <PERSON> West </PERSON> and perhaps lead to an eventual reunification of <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. The conservative <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> daily newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Die </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Welt </ORGANIZATION> reported two weeks ago that the West German government `` expects that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> will stress the German right of self-determination in some form or another when he visits <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>.'' That would soften the <ORGANIZATION> Kremlin </ORGANIZATION>'s traditional view that reunification could take place only under a socialist leadership. Soviet officials have indicated such a gesture is possible, but they have given no clues as to what <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> might say on that subject, or in response to persistent questions about the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall erected by <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> in 1961. <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>, the Soviet foreign minister, visited <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> on Friday for talks with East German leader <PERSON> Erich </PERSON> <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON> described his visit with <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> as a matter of protocol prior to the state visit to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, but the minister declined to specify what matters would be discussed at the <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> summit. The visit is likely to provide a boost to the standing of West German Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> was rated as the most popular foreign statesman ever in a poll released a week ago by the weekly magazine <ORGANIZATION> Der </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Spiegel </ORGANIZATION>, outdistancing even <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, and the <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> visit may help <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> and his <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> party in next week's European Parliament elections. <PERSON> Heinrich </PERSON> <PERSON> Vogel </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Cologne </LOCATION> and a specialist in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> affairs, predicted that the summit would focus on atmosphere rather than substance, mostly because of the sensitive stage in which the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> leader finds himself. <PERSON> Vogel </PERSON> said problems with socialism as an ideology began escalating with the Polish Solidarity movement in 1980 and lately have `` been accelerating at an unbelievable pace, a pace that is really staggering and frightening.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890611-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-89 1138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Mozambique-Fighting     06-11 0170</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mozambique-Fighting,0175</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Says Troops Kill 44 Rebels</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MAPUTO, Mozambique (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Government soldiers killed 44 rebel fighters during a battle in the southern province of <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>, the national news agency AIM reported Sunday. The rebels of the <ORGANIZATION> Mozambique </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resistance </ORGANIZATION> were killed while attempting to attack a military training center Friday in the town of <LOCATION> Machubane </LOCATION>, AIM said, citing a statement by Col. <PERSON> Ernesto </PERSON> <PERSON> Bulele </PERSON>. Machubane is about 120 miles northeast of the capital of <LOCATION> Maputo </LOCATION>. The report gave no additional details and made no mention of government troop casualties. Information on the fighting is often sketchy and can take days or even weeks to reach <LOCATION> Maputo </LOCATION>. The rebels have been fighting since 1977 in a bid to undermine <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION>'s Marxist government. The rebels have devastated the economy of the southeast African nation with hit-and-run attacks on both military and civilian targets. <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION> is one of the poorest countries in the world and an estimated 6 million of its 15 million people are in need of food aid.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890611-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-89 1153EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-HalfMoon     06-11 0435</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Half Moon,0448</SECOND>
<HEAD>Replica Of Henry Hudson's Ship Christened At Albany Dock</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GERMAIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ALBANY, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nearly four centuries after explorer <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON>'s crew mutinied and set him adrift, a replica of his ship has been launched to honor the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION>' contributions to the New World. `` What the sea separates, the shipbuilder unites,'' ship designer <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Benton </PERSON> told a crowd of about 500 Saturday before the christening of the Half Moon. The 85-foot, 120-ton wooden vessel was lowered by crane into the <LOCATION> Hudson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, which <LOCATION> Hudson </LOCATION> discovered in 1609 during his search for a <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> passage to the Orient. Two years later, <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON>'s crew mutinied, setting him, his young son and seven others adrift in a small boat in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Hudson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>. They were never seen again. The replica was conceived by <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Hendricks </PERSON>, a dermatologist who plans to use the Half Moon as a platform to give history lessons on Dutch contributions. <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON> himself was born in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> but was working for the <ORGANIZATION> Dutch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> East </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION> at the time he found the river that bears his name. There's a `` historical blind spot'' that keeps historians from considering Dutch contributions to the New World, <PERSON> Hendricks </PERSON> said. That's partly because the English ousted the Dutch from their early stronghold in the New World in the 1600s, he said. The Dutch first settled the area between English colonies in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, including <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION>, the nation's oldest incorporated city, he said. The ship will spend the summer touring the states once called the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>. At the christening, <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> Consul General <PERSON> Adrien </PERSON> <PERSON> Tieleman </PERSON> said the Dutch have always been proud of their `` small contribution to the mightiest, most free and prosperous nation in the world.'' The Half Moon replica cost about $ 1 million, raised mostly through donations, and took a year to build. The builders are applying finishing touches and the ship's maiden voyage is scheduled for July 5. About 25 people worked to build the square-rigged ship, which will be outfitted with replicas of 17th century cannons, said shipwright <PERSON> Ernie </PERSON> <PERSON> Cowan </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Mayville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> Sailmaker <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Bierig </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Erie </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, hand-sewed the ship's nine sails. About 600 man-hours went into the sails, made of synthetics treated to look like canvas sails of the 1600s, he said. Because ships four centuries ago were built for cargo, the squat Half Moon wo n't win any races, <PERSON> Bierig </PERSON> said. `` It will be on the slow side,'' he said. `` Sailors were cheap and in those days there was no reason you needed speed.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890611-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-89 1157EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-China-Propaganda Bjt   06-11 0665</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-Propaganda, Bjt,0682</SECOND>
<HEAD>Propaganda Campaign Gives Government Side of Events</HEAD>
<BYLINE>With AM-China, Bjt ^By DAN BIERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Communist Chinese propaganda machine is working at a frenzied pace to portray the bloody military occupation of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> as a heroic operation against `` counter-revolutionaries.'' The saturation campaign serves to shield the government from blame for the June 4 massacre in which hundreds, perhaps thousands of people died when soldiers fired at unarmed citizens supporting a movement for a freer society. Word of the assault on the pro-democracy movement quickly spread to several large <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> cities, where huge crowds took to the streets to demand the fall of conservative leaders who ordered the military attack. But hardliners such as senior leader <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON> and Premier <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON> have kept their grip on power, supporting their position with the propaganda barrage. The main vehicle for the campaign has been nationwide television. After a few days of virtual silence on the attack, television began showing grainy black-and-white tapes of angry crowds attacking soldiers and torching military vehicles. Color videotapes of similar scenes soon appeared, often shown dozens of times over several days. Soldiers indiscriminately firing at crowds or crushing people with armored vehicles were not shown. Neither were scenes of hospitals filled with the dead and the injured from the withering attack on <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>'s Tiananmen Square. The videotapes often did not have sound, perhaps so the audience could not hear the gunfire or the angry chants of `` fascists'' directed at the soldiers. The official theme of soldiers as victims soon was expanded, with television showing injured troops lying in hospital beds. In one particularly gruesome scene, an evening newscast showed the charred bodies of three soldiers burned to death, including one who was disemboweled. The campaign also stresses the theme of soldiers as friends. Under guard of rifle-toting soldiers, propaganda trucks with signs reading `` the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> loves the people'' rolled down <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>'s main streets with loudspeakers blaring Scenes of soldiers and citizens helping one another have dominated television, which in recent days have devoted several hours of special newscasts daily to present the government line. On Saturday, television showed a peasant bringing three huge pigs to applauding soldiers. The next day's evening newscast showed troops at an elementary school playing with children and helping them clean their classrooms. The newest phase of the propaganda onslaught has shown dozens of `` scoundrels'' and `` counterrevolutionaries'' under arrest on charges of participating in the demonstrations. Television has shown them questioned at gunpoint and signing confessions. Chinese media also has attacked the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government-funded <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>, which has provided millions of Chinese with an independent account of the weekend bloodbath. In another attempt to quell non-official accounts, television Saturday urged viewers to turn in a `` rumor-monger'' who was shown giving a bloody account of the attack. On Sunday, the evening news reported his capture and the man was shown expressing remorse to security officials. Television interviews with citizens applauding the military action increased during the weekend. `` It gave use great satisfaction to see the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> go into the city and put down the turmoil,'' said one man. Several people who were interviewed said they were shocked by the attacks on soldiers seen on television. `` I was greatly pained to see <ORGANIZATION> PLA </ORGANIZATION> soldiers burned to death and beaten to death,'' primary school teacher <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> <PERSON> Qing </PERSON> told a television reporter. Many Chinese are skeptical of the state-controlled media so it is impossible to know how many people find the propaganda campaign convincing. `` Not a single person will believe it,'' said one <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> student who claimed he saw more than 10 people shot in <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> by soldiers early June 4. But some Chinese who did not see the weekend events themselves could find the relentless television accounts persuasive. `` In <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, people know what happened. But those on the outside do not,'' said another <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> student. `` Most Chinese are peasants. They believe what the government says.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890611-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-89 1158EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-HandcuffCaper     06-11 0393</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Handcuff Caper,0406</SECOND>
<HEAD>Suspects Find Way to Shatter Shackles</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COLUMBUS, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Inmates being driven from one jail to another smilingly showed the officer guarding them their new discovery: that their seat belts made handy tools for breaking handcuffs. The sheriff's office and <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> did n't smile, though, and are warning officers nationwide of the technique. `` There is danger to every law enforcement officer in the country,'' said <LOCATION> Franklin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> O. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>. Ten prisoners learned the seat belt trick while being taken from the downtown jail to the <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> <PERSON> Pike </PERSON> jail, and before the ride was over all were free, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said Saturday. `` When the deputy opened the back of the van, all 10 guys were smiling and said ` See what we did,''' <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said, adding that each prisoner held up his arms to show broken handcuffs. The cuffs that go around each wrist are connected by a chain, attached to each cuff by a swivel that moves freely to ensure that the chain does n't twist. Seat belt clips have one or two holes or slots, that lock them into place with the buckle. The prisoners learned that jamming the swivel link through a hole on the clip stops the swivel from turning freely. `` A quick twist of the wrist, and the chain shears off at the cuff,'' <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. The prank led <LOCATION> Franklin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> authorities to issue emergency bulletins to law enforcement agencies across the state Friday. Similar warnings also would be given nationwide, the sheriff said, and an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said an advisory would be placed in the agency's Law Enforcement Bulletin. `` Although only 10 people know the technique, I guarantee that the entire jail population, all 690 of them, will know how to do it before the day is up,'' <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. `` The only people who wo n't know about it is law enforcement officers.'' <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> ordered seat belts removed from jail vans. He also ordered that prisoners in police cars be cuffed with their hands behind their backs and that the seat belts be locked firmly across them. Handcuff manufacturers were contacted Friday and are studying ways of redesigning the handcuffs, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. The 10 inmates who revealed their discovery may regret the caper. The sheriff was not amused. `` Charge them with destruction of county property,'' he told deputies. `` We'll see how funny they think that is.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890611-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-89 1202EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-CleanAir Bjt   06-11 0722</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Clean Air, Bjt,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Putting Final Touches on Environmental Package</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> worked on the final details Sunday of a package of proposals aimed at cleaning up the nation's air by imposing sharp cuts in acid rain pollutants and reducing the smog that plagues most cities The proposals, to be unveiled at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> on Monday, represent the first time in nearly a decade that the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> has joined in an effort to overhaul federal air quality laws. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> refused to send clean air legislation to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> during his eight years in office. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told a conservation group last week his proposals would represent `` sweeping changes'' in federal air pollution laws and `` significantly improve every North American's quality of life'' whether they live near industrial plants or in the woodland countryside. Environmentalists say <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s clean air package is his severest test so far on whether he plans to make good on campaign promises to take environmental issues seriously. While details of the president's proposals are not yet clear, government and congressional sources said the plan is expected to include: _ Requirements for cutting sulfur dioxide emissions, mostly from older coal-burning electric power plants by 10 million tons by the year 2000 to combat acid rain, which has been blamed for destroying lakes, streams and forests. _ A requirement for industry to install control technology to curb the release of cancer-causing and other toxic chemicals from such facilities as chemical plants and oil refineries. It also is likely to streamline the way the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> regulates such chemicals, allowing them to set standards by broad category rather than chemical by chemical. _ Reductions in smog-causing pollutants from automobiles through a combination of pollution controls and a limited shift to alternative, cleaner fuels instead of gasoline. The urban smog problem, largely caused by automobile pollutants, has been among the thorniest issues facing the administration. Some members of the administration have favored requiring specific curbs to reduce ozone-causing pollutants, while others have favored broader flexibility that would allow the oil and automobile industries to work out how best to meet government-imposed targets. Even though the president's proposals were expected to fall short of what some environmentalists sought, they welcomed his administration's willingness to get involved in efforts to update the 1970 Clean Air Act. Congressional leaders have said that they expect revisions to be enacted by this <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, although probably not until next year. Legislation already has been introduced in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to require stringent reductions in pollutants _ primarily hydrocarbons and nitrogen dioxide from motor vehicles _ that cause ozone pollution which in turn is a key component of smog. Other bills already being considered would require the `` best available technology'' to be enlisted to curb toxic chemical emissions into the air by industry and establish specific benchmarks for cutting acid rain pollutants. The president's proposal was expected to be less demanding of industry than some of the legislation already before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Environmentalists, for example, have sought a reduction in sulfur dioxide from power plants of at least 12 million tons over the next decade and have argued for tightening of automobile tailpipe emission controls to fight urban pollution. The utility industry has called those actions too expensive and some in the administration, particularly the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> and the presidents <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advisers </ORGANIZATION>, have agreed. During a meeting with the president last week on the clean air proposals, industry representatives pleaded that the proposals not be too costly. `` We urged that when the dust settles on clean air, that we have a healthy economy left,'' said <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fay </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Clean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Working </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, a business coalition. After a later meeting attended by environmentalists, the president was told that pollution itself also is costly as well as being pervasive. To make the point they provided a chart showing that during a week last summer the air in <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, where the president has a vacation retreat, had ozone concentrates that were `` unhealthy'' by federal definition on two of the seven days. `` He sat there and said, ` I'm not safe anywhere,' and we said, ` Yes, and its worse in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>,''' recalled <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Prichard </PERSON>, one of the environmentalists at the meeting.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890611-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-89 1212EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-SovietDefector Bjt   06-11 0881</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet Defector, Bjt,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>Defector: Soviet Committee Quietly Shifts Foreign Policy</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Soviet defector has been telling <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government agencies some of the inner secrets of a little understood Kremlin body that plays a key role in charting Soviet foreign policy. Under Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> has shifted course, loosening its ties with Marxist parties in the West and cultivating relations with other less radical elements, said the defector, <PERSON> Evgeny </PERSON> <PERSON> Novikov </PERSON>. `` <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> started to promote the principles of his ` new thinking,' to find new clients, sometimes at the expense of old clients, to find parties and groups that have influence in capitalist countries,'' <PERSON> Novikov </PERSON> said in a recent interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. The new approach has brought closer Soviet ties to <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> and Western European environmental and peace groups that agree with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s approach to disarmament and attempts to lessen international tension, said <PERSON> Novikov </PERSON>. Because his work in the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> centered on Arab and <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> affairs, <PERSON> Novikov </PERSON> declined to speculate on which Western groups were sympathetic to <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s new approach. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence officials, who said they were not familar with the specifics of <PERSON> Novikov </PERSON>'s case, confirmed that <PERSON> Novikov </PERSON>'s description met their understanding of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> They said most <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Western European groups were sophisticated enough to remain independent even while developing contacts with Soviet officials known to be linked to the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. The International Department, for which <PERSON> Novikov </PERSON> worked from 1970 until his defection last year, was the successor to the Comintern, or Communist International, or later the Cominform, disbanded by <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> in 1947. The Comintern was the main organ of <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> influence on communist parties outside the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, a means of molding political platforms and sometimes recruiting intelligence agents, according to numerous accounts by defectors. The <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> shares with the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> responsibility for formulating Soviet foreign policy, which is decided by the ruling Politburo, <PERSON> Novikov </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> carries out state-to-state contacts, while the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> handles party-to-party matters. Senior International Department experts are driven in chauffeured cars, receive salaries equal to those of deputy ministers and have access to intelligence reports from the ministries of defense and foreign affairs, and the <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Novikov </PERSON> said in a paper prepared for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government. Shortly after <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> rose to power in March 1985, he tried to gain control of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and change its inner workings by appointing as its chief <PERSON> Anatoly </PERSON> <PERSON> Dobrynin </PERSON>, who had served as the Soviet ambassador to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> since the 1960s. `` <PERSON> Dobrynin </PERSON>, however, was very much an outsider'' to the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> bureaucracy, <PERSON> Novikov </PERSON> said. Thus <PERSON> Dobrynin </PERSON>'s reform attempts foundered, forcing <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to move him from the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Secretariat </ORGANIZATION> into a newly created post as adviser. `` The old timers in the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> opposed <PERSON> Dobrynin </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Novikov </PERSON>. `` The old cadres sabotaged Dobryinin.'' Last fall, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> reorganized the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Secretariat </ORGANIZATION>, naming his right-hand man, <PERSON> Aleksandr </PERSON> <PERSON> Yakovlev </PERSON>, as head of a newly created <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, which controls the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. The new head of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is <PERSON> Valentin </PERSON> <PERSON> Falin </PERSON>, a former ambassador to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. Before the reorganization, said <PERSON> Novikov </PERSON>, many of the senior officials in the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> dated back to the days of <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Suslov </PERSON> and <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> Ponomarev </PERSON>, two Stalinist holdovers who served under the late Soviet leader <PERSON> Leonid </PERSON> <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON>. <PERSON> Novikov </PERSON> lectured from 1970 to 1985 in the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION>, which he described as a secret school run by the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. His job was to conduct seminars in political philosophy for small groups of students from Marxist parties in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yemen </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> and for two radical Palestinian groups, the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> for the <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> and the Peoples Front for the Liberation of <LOCATION> Palestine </LOCATION>. Professors at the institute drew up classified reports on those movements, based in part on what the students said in class. `` For example, I made a study of the <ORGANIZATION> Yemeni </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, its origins, history, influence of Marxism, influence of Islam, influence on the masses,'' said <PERSON> Novikov </PERSON>. From 1985 until his defection, <PERSON> Novikov </PERSON> was chief of the Arabic editorial office of the World Marxist Review in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>. Arabic versions of the magazine `` were printed mostly in Western countries, and distributed in various Arab countries under titles very different from the original. `` The goal was to pretend it was a national magazine, produced in each nation, but 70-100 percent of it was prepared in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> ... under directions from the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>,'' said <PERSON> Novikov </PERSON>. `` Nowhere did it say it was printed in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>. One percent of the readers would know where it came from.'' <PERSON> Novikov </PERSON> crossed the border in <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> in March 1988, was given asylum by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> there and spent the next seven months briefing Western officials. <PERSON> Novikov </PERSON>, who has the Soviet equivalent of a doctorate, has been living in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> since last September, working as a butler in a small hotel while he tries to launch a career as a consultant in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> affairs. In contrast to past Soviet defectors who complained about insensitivity on the part of their <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> handlers, <PERSON> Novikov </PERSON> said he `` met with a very human attitude from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> government.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890611-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-89 1242EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-HouseRaces Bjt   06-11 1115</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-House Races, Bjt,950</SECOND>
<HEAD>Big Bucks Likely to Characterize Races for Pepper, Wright, Coelho
Seats</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Millions of dollars of special interest money is expected to prime the political pumps as Republicans battle for three historically <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> seats in races spawned by the congressional ethics wars and the death of <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Pepper </PERSON>. `` You're going to see candidates in all of these races spending a good deal of time trying to squeeze money out of the lobbyists, and there's no doubt that millions of dollars special interest funds will pour in,'' says <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Waldman </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Watch </ORGANIZATION>, a citizens group based here. The stakes are not momentous, since Democrats control the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, 259 to 175, and even a Republican sweep would not change things much. For that matter, registered Democrats predominate in all three districts. But Republicans lost face in April with special-election defeats in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, even though they held on in <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>. They want to avenge those losses in the upcoming round. Democrats, on the other hand, want to avoid the embarrassment of an upset. The three districts are: _ The 12th District of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, taking in much of <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, who has represented it since 1955, stepped down as House Speaker on May 31 at the end of a yearlong ethics probe and is expected to resign from the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> itself by the end of the month. _ The 15th District of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, in the rich cotton, fruit and vegetable-growing <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Joaquin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, the nation's premier center of agribusiness House Majority Whip <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, who represented the district since 1979, announced on May 27 that he would resign to head off a protracted controversy over a $ 100,000 `` junk bond'' purchase. _ The 18th <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, taking in much of <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Key </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Biscayne </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Coral </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gables </LOCATION> Rules Chairman <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Pepper </PERSON> died May 30 after representing the district since 1962. There is no denying that the races will cost a bundle. `` We're talking about $ 500,000 at this point, but if we have to go higher, I guess we can,'' says <LOCATION> Modesto </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, Mayor <PERSON> Carole </PERSON> <PERSON> Whiteside </PERSON>, already an announced candidate. `` But I want to earn this race, I do n't want to buy it.'' Candidates in April's <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> race spent $ 500,000 each as did contestants in a <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> election where Republicans eked out victory on April 29. Need for money and lack of time most likely will send the new set of candidates scurrying to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> lobbies that have plenty of ready cash as well as long legislative shopping lists. `` I would think that the Democrats would do what they've done already, which is to organize labor union political action committees to turn on the spigot, and Republicans will do what we can to reach out to the business PACs to help raise money for Republicans,'' says <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. In <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> already is putting out word that he backs <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> attorney <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Geren </PERSON>. <PERSON> Geren </PERSON>, 37, a former <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> staffer, is unlikely to announce, however, until after <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> leaves or at least sets a specific date for his departure. Other Democrats being mentioned as possible contenders include state Sen. <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Parmer </PERSON> and former state Rep. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Millsap </PERSON> as well as Fort Worth Councilman <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilley </PERSON>. Republicans include state Rep. <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, television health show host Dr. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Lanier </PERSON>, airport board member <PERSON> Erma </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, former <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> county Chairman <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> and county Judge <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> English </PERSON>, who switched to the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> at a heavily ballyhooed White House ceremony in 1986. Under <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> law, candidates from both parties slug it out in a single special election, with a runoff between the two top vote getters if no one gains a majority. In <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, Democratic state Rep. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Condit </PERSON> is also campaigning. <PERSON> Condit </PERSON>, 41, is a member of the `` Gang of Five,'' conservative Democrats who warred with liberal Assembly Speaker <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> in 1988. `` I was stripped of all my committee assignments and had my office moved about once a month,'' <PERSON> Condit </PERSON> chortles. The antics helped <PERSON> Condit </PERSON>. `` Fighting with <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> did n't hurt him at all because fighting with a liberal in that district is what you want to do,'' says <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> consultant <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorton </PERSON> of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> Water availability and quality loom as crucial issues in district, where farmers are also irked by pollution damage to crops from autos of increasingly numerous commuters to <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Area </LOCATION> jobs. Both candidates vow to shun negative campaigning. <PERSON> Whiteside </PERSON> does say, however, that `` my opponent already has been involved in special interest politics in <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION>, frankly, is not a whole lot better than <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. I'm glad I was n't there.'' Only one other Democrat has been mentioned as a possible contender: state Rep. <PERSON> Rusty </PERSON> <PERSON> Areias </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> D-Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banos </ORGANIZATION>, another `` Gang of Five'' member. Republicans include <LOCATION> Stanislaus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Chairman <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Keating-Edh </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Fresno </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Supervisor <PERSON> Daran </PERSON> <PERSON> Koligian </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Fresno </LOCATION> Councilman <PERSON> Rod </PERSON> <PERSON> Anaforian </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Merced </LOCATION> businessman <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> and highly decorated <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veteran <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Patterakis </PERSON>. Under <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> law, candidates of both parties are lumped in one race. If no one gains a majority, the top Republican fights the leading Democrat in a runoff. The <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> election, set for Aug. 29, puts the spotlight on the sizeable Cuban-American community in the <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> area. Pepper won their hearts with TV ads in Spanish and firm backing for <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s Contra rebels while cementing ties with just about every other ethnic group in one way or another. In 1988, the 88-year-old lawmaker ran without opposition. Battle lines are drawn again, however, with two Cuban-Americans already in the race on the Republican side, state Sen. <PERSON> Ileana </PERSON> <PERSON> Ros-Lehtinen </PERSON> and millionaire banana importer <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>, a prominent supporter of former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Lt. Col. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>. Among Democrats, state Sen. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON>, a one-time <ORGANIZATION> Claude </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pepper </ORGANIZATION> business partner who plans to get in the race this week, acknowledges that his stand against <ORGANIZATION> Contra </ORGANIZATION> aid could be vexing. `` As a matter of fact, the right-wing Cubans threw rocks and eggs at me'' at an anti-Contra demonstration, he says. He says he has a strategy to counteract the problem that he will reveal this week. `` I think the chances are pretty good for a Cuban-American to be elected,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> strategist <PERSON> Sergio </PERSON> <PERSON> Bendixen </PERSON>. Already announced among Republicans are state Sen. <PERSON> Ileana </PERSON> <PERSON> Ros-Lehtinen </PERSON> and millionaire banana importer <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>, a high-profile supporter of former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Lt. Col. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>. Also mentioned as a possible contenders was GOP state Sen. <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Gutman </PERSON>. Democrats include <LOCATION> Hialeah </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> Commissioner <PERSON> Rosario </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Alex </PERSON> <PERSON> Daoud </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Commissioner <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Gersten </PERSON>, State Attorney <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Reno </PERSON> and former school board chairman <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Cejas </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890611-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-89 1245EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Soviet-Inferno     06-11 0689</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet-Inferno,0707</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Doctors Arrive to Treat Gas Blast Victims; More Than 400 Dead</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN-THOR DAHLBURG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 American burn experts flew to the <LOCATION> Ural </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> on Sunday to treat hundreds of victims of a huge gas explosion that engulfed two trains in flames. Official media said more than 400 people have now died in the tragedy. Authorities said the death toll likely would climb, especially if severely burned patients do not receive immediate treatment. `` We are close to the most critical stage for patients,'' <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> federation Health Minister <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Potapov </PERSON> told the government newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION> said only 32 of the 805 people hospitalized following the June 4 blast had recovered sufficiently to be discharged while another 114, including 28 children, had died. At the site of the huge explosion along the <ORGANIZATION> Trans-Siberian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Railway </ORGANIZATION>, 308 bodies, including the remains of 67 children, have been found to date, the paper said. `` These are terrifying figures, but they are not final,'' it said. Just one search party in which passengers' relatives took part located the remains of three more victims Friday, <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION> said. Previously, state-run media had said more than 190 of the approximately 1,200 passengers aboard the trains were killed when a spark from the railway's electrical line ignited a highly flammable mixture of benzine and propane-butane gas that leaked from a pipeline about a half mile away. The trains, traveling in opposite directions between <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION>'s largest city, <LOCATION> Novosibirsk </LOCATION>, and the <LOCATION> Black </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> resort city of <LOCATION> Adler </LOCATION>, had made unscheduled stops in the valley in the <LOCATION> Ural </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> One train was carrying schoolchildren to vacation camps in the southern <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. The blast had the force of 10,000 tons of <ORGANIZATION> TNT </ORGANIZATION>, half as strong as the A-bomb that fell on <LOCATION> Hiroshima </LOCATION>, said Gen. <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Moiseyev </PERSON>, chief of the Soviet military's general staff. But its true human costs are only now becoming apparent. A government commission looking into the accident, which occurred 750 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, concluded Sunday that `` the dimensions of the June 3-4 railway tragedy are much broader than supposed before,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> news agency reported from the <LOCATION> Ural </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> city of <LOCATION> Ufa </LOCATION>. The commission said the number of passengers aboard the two trains was greater than originally believed, but that even now it is `` impossible to cite excat numbers. `` Night and day in the hospitals of <LOCATION> Ufa </LOCATION>, the fight continues for the lives of the injured,'' <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> added. A group of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> medics flew into <LOCATION> Ufa </LOCATION> on Sunday and headed straight for the city's hospitals to begin helping accident victims, <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said. All the doctors are specialists in treating burns, and the group brought its own drugs and equipment, <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said. The 17-member team from the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Surgical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Brooke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, stopped Saturday in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> on its way to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. The group's leader, Lt. Col. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Becker </PERSON>, said the medics expected to remain in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> for up to 10 days. `` What we've been told is that there are more than 100 children with serious burns and in addition to that, there are an unknown number of adults with significant burns,'' <PERSON> Becker </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>. He said the group, responding to a request for aid from the Soviets, was bringing 18,000 pounds of medical supplies on its giant C-141 transport plane, as well as three Russian-language translators and two administrative officers. State-run television reported last week that 50 percent of the injured suffered burns over more than 70 percent of their bodies. Health Minister <PERSON> Yevgeny </PERSON> <PERSON> Chazov </PERSON> says Soviet doctors lack experience in treating such severe burns, and the Soviets appealed for advice and urgent airlifts of equipment from <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and other officials have charged that workers in charge of the pipeline noticed a drop in pressure caused by the leak but increased pressure instead of shutting the line down. <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Kryuchkov </PERSON> has told <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION> the Soviet secret police sent a team of investigators to the accident site to learn what had happened.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890611-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-89 1253EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-OldestPresidents     06-11 0160</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Oldest Presidents,160</SECOND>
<HEAD>With AM-Senior Citizen Bush Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who turns 65 on Monday, is the 13th oldest president in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> history. He was the fourth oldest ever inaugurated, and only a dozen were older at the end of their terms than <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is now. Forty men have been president. The oldest on Inauguration Day were: <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, 69; <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON>, 68, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Buchanan </PERSON>, 65, and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 64. The oldest <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> presidents ever were: 1. <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, 77, 349 days. 2. <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON>, 70, 98 days. 3. <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, 69, 354 days. 4. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Buchanan </PERSON>, 69, 315 days. 5. <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>, 68, 257 days. 6. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON>, 68, 54 days. 7. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Monroe </PERSON>, 66, 310 days. 8. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Madison </PERSON>, 65, 353 days. 9. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON>, 65, 325 days. 10. <PERSON> Zachary </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, 65, 227 days. 11. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, 65, 125 days. 12. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON>, 65, 9 days. 13. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 65, 0 days.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890611-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-89 1256EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-Honecker     06-11 0421</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Honecker,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>East German Welcomes Bush Arms Plan, Cites New Berlin Wall Policy</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The head of the East German government says President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s proposal for a reduction in conventional arms in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> is a welcome step that is in tune with <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact desires for speedy negotiations, according to a published report. The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> also quoted <PERSON> Erich </PERSON> <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> in its Sunday edition as confirming that East German border guards have been ordered not to use deadly force to stop civilians who attempt to flee into <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> unless the soldiers are threatened themselves. In a two-hour interview conducted last Wednesday in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> quoted the influential <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pact </ORGANIZATION> leader as saying the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> proposal for <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pact </ORGANIZATION> nations to cut conventional arms is `` close to our striving for radical conventional disarmament.'' Questioned on <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s call to `` lock in'' reductions in tanks, artillery, armed personnel carriers and other non-nuclear forces in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> during a 23-nation negotiation on Conventional Forces in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, the paper quoted <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> as replying: `` We are interested in having those proposals included in the negotiations, so that we can identify where the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Treaty states concur -LRB- with <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- and those areas where more intensive negotiations are needed.'' As to nuclear arms, he said, `` We are in favor of the step-by-step elimination of tactical nuclear weapons in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. Of course we know that this ca n't be done in one stroke.'' He raised the possibility that each side might decide to `` keep, say, 10'' weapons. `` One has to enter negotiations and see what progress can be achieved,'' said <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON>, who is head of state and general secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> East </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> German </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. `` Sometimes surprises even occur.'' He rejected <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s call for the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall to be torn down, but said his government wants `` to humanize the border regime'' as part of generally improving relations with <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> said East German border guards are authorized to shoot people trying to flee the country only if the guards are in physical danger or if a soldier or other uniformed person is trying to desert. He did not say when the restrictions took effect, but Western officials have said the policy apparently was adopted as a goodwill gesture prior to <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON>'s visit to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> in 1987. Although 190 people have died trying to flee <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> since the wall was built in 1961, there has been only one confirmed case since the 1987 <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> visit to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890611-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-89 1314EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d w AM-HurricaneHotline     06-11 0149</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hurricane Hotline,150</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hurricane Hotline Resumes</HEAD>
<HEAD>For release at 6:30 p.m. EDT, time set by source</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The `` Hurricane Hotline'' will resume this year when a storm threatens, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atmospheric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> announced Sunday. The hotline is a special telephone service providing regular updates of the progress of named tropical storms and hurricanes. It operates only when such a storm is active. Last year the hotline received more than 100,000 calls during <PERSON> Hurricane </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>, and the year before 700,000 calls were recorded when hurricanes <PERSON> Gloria </PERSON> and <PERSON> Elena </PERSON> threatened, officials said. The hotline number is 1-900-410-NOAA and calls cost 50 cents for the first minute and 45 cents for each additional minute. Most calls cost 95 cents, officials say. The hotline, which has a taped message, is operated by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hurricane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Coral </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gables </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, with assistance from <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> and USA Today.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890611-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-89 1344EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-China-Dissidents     06-11 0436</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-Dissidents,0448</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Zeroes in on Prominent Dissidents</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-China, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAN BIERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government has moved to silence three top dissidents who share a passion for democracy: an internationally known astrophysicist, his college professor wife and a shaggy-haired accountant. The <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> issued an arrest warrant for astrophysicist <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> <PERSON> Lizhi </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Shuxian </PERSON>, who are hiding in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. Meanwhile, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> quoted Chinese sources as saying another dissident, <PERSON> Ren </PERSON> <PERSON> Wanding </PERSON>, was arrested late Saturday. <PERSON> Fang </PERSON>, 53, is the most prominent dissident in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. He was expelled from the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in 1987 on charges of having helped provoke an earlier series of student pro-democracy demonstrations. After his expulsion, <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> continued to condemn Marxism as a failure and to urge democratic change in this authoritarian Communist state. He also sent an open letter to <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON> in January calling for the release of political prisoners. `` Many people do n't agree with Marxism, even workers and students,'' he said in an interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> last year. `` Even people of my generation ... do n't believe in Marxism.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Observatory </ORGANIZATION> professor was at the center of a U.S.-Chinese controversy in February when <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> police prevented him from attending a banquet given by visiting <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. Although he kept a low profile during the recent student-led demonstrations for democracy, <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> just before he disappeared into the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy that he feared he would be arrested as part of a crackdown on liberal intellectuals. His wife is a professor of physics at <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, the country's most prestigious school, and also has criticized the lack of democracy in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. She was elected a deputy to the People's <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>'s Haidian district by <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> students <PERSON> Ren </PERSON> <PERSON> Wanding </PERSON> does not have the international standing enjoyed by <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> but nonetheless has waged a crusade for human rights and democracy in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ren </PERSON>, 44, was jailed in 1979-83 after helping edit an underground pro-democracy magazine. After a long silence, he renewed his call for multi-party democracy late last year with an open letter to the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> and a 22-page essay on freedom. After the recent pro-democracy movement began, he went to universities and student-occupied Tiananmen Square to read his essays on political reform. But <PERSON> Ren </PERSON> insisted he had no formal connection with the student protesters. At a news conference two week ago, <PERSON> Ren </PERSON> told reporters he feared arrest but defended his actions and speeches. `` I must speak,'' he said. `` It is my fate to do such things.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890611-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-89 1348EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Gable-Garland     06-11 0672</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Gable-Garland,0691</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hometowns, Seeking Tourism Boost, Commemorate Judy Garland, Clark
Gable</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By THEASA TUOHY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
