<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890216-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-89 2352EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Cambodia     02-16 0492</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cambodia,0508</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cambodia Resistance Accuses Government of Intransigence in Talks</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER ENG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JAKARTA, Indonesia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Cambodian guerrilla leaders met Thursday with senior officials in the <LOCATION> Phnom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penh </LOCATION> government and charged the officials with merely engaging in a public relations exercise in entering peace talks. The Cambodian officials and the three factions of the resistance coalition held a 45-minute session apart from their larger meeting with other Southeast Asian countries. The Cambodian officials `` maintained the same rigid attitude which is not conducive to a comprehensive settlement of the Kampuchean -LRB- <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> -RRB- problem,'' the coalition said in a statement. `` The plan proposed by the other side is tantamount to asking the -LRB- resistance -RRB- to capitulate to a regime installed by foreign forces,'' the statement said, adding that the government was only engaging in a public relations exercise. The meeting is aimed at ending the war that began after Soviet-armed <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> invaded <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> in late 1978. Vietnamese forces since have battled the guerrillas backed by <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southeast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Asian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>. The guerrilla leaders said a solution was possible only on the basis of a plan proposed by resistance leader Prince <PERSON> Norodom </PERSON> <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON>. <PERSON> Phnom </PERSON> <PERSON> Penh </PERSON> rejected that plan even before the talks began. Resistance spokesman <PERSON> Thiounn </PERSON> <PERSON> Prasith </PERSON> read the statement aloud at a news conference after a 10-minute monologue in which he railed against <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> and the `` illegal'' Cambodian regime it was `` manipulating.'' He denounced <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> for not allowing international supervision of its troop withdrawal and claimed that about 20,000 Vietnamese soldiers recently have disguised themselves in Cambodian uniforms. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> in January said it will end its 10-year military incursion in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> by the end of September. <PERSON> Phnom </PERSON> <PERSON> Penh </PERSON>'s representative, <PERSON> Hor </PERSON> <PERSON> Nam </PERSON> <PERSON> Hong </PERSON>, appeared at the same news conference, insisting his side fervently desires a settlement. The organizer of the talks, <LOCATION> Indonesian </LOCATION> Foreign Minister <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Alatas </PERSON>, said that at the plenary session, the officials discussed the Vietnamese withdrawal, an end to foreign military aid to the guerrillas, and a mechanism for supervision and control of any agreement. The session brought together <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, its ally <LOCATION> Laos </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Phnom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penh </LOCATION> government, the resistance, and the members of <ORGANIZATION> ASEAN </ORGANIZATION>: <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Brunei </LOCATION>. A first round of talks, held in July, achieved no breakthroughs but resulted in a consensus that <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s withdrawal must be linked to measures preventing the return to power of the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>, which killed hundreds of thousands of people in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> before <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> toppled it. The communist <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> is allied in the guerrilla coalition with the forces of <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> and Son <PERSON> Sann </PERSON>. <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON>, widely seen as the central figure in any future Cambodian government, is boycotting the talks because <PERSON> Phnom </PERSON> <PERSON> Penh </PERSON> rejected his peace plan. The plan included calls for dissolution of the <LOCATION> Phnom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penh </LOCATION> government before a general election; introduction of an international peace-keeping force to guarantee any settlement; and specifics from <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> on its pledge to withdraw its troops from <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890216-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-89 2357EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-HijackingSuspect     02-16 0144</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hijacking Suspect,140</SECOND>
<HEAD>Trial Delayed</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The trial of a Lebanese hijacking suspect that was to have started Thursday has been postponed because the judge suffered a mild heart attack. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Barrington </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, scheduled to preside at the trial of <PERSON> Fawaz </PERSON> <PERSON> Younis </PERSON>, is listed in guarded condition in the coronary care unit at <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. He was admitted Wednesday. Prospective jurors have been told to telephone the courthouse next Wednesday to learn when the case will go forward. <PERSON> Younis </PERSON> has been awaiting trial since September 1987 when he was lured aboard an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> chartered yacht in the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Younis </PERSON> is charged with leading the June 1985 hijacking of a Jordanian airliner that was carrying several <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> passengers. The plane was blown up at <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> international Airport after passengers and crew members were allowed to leave the aircraft.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890216-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-89 0041EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Czechoslovakia-Arms     02-16 0232</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Czechoslovakia-Arms,0237</SECOND>
<HEAD>Military Production at Arms Plant To Be Cut by Half</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PRAGUE, Czechoslovakia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government says <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>'s largest armarments plant will halve its military production this year and increase its turnout of heavy equipment for civilian use. The official <ORGANIZATION> CTK </ORGANIZATION> news agency said Wednesday that the cuts are linked to recent disarmament initiatives by <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> and other <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc countries that follow <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s lead in announcing cuts in military manpower and spending. While halving its military production, the plant at <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> in western <LOCATION> Slovakia </LOCATION> will make more equipment for civilian use, such as construction and road-building machinery, <ORGANIZATION> CTK </ORGANIZATION> quoted company director <PERSON> Jozef </PERSON> <PERSON> Uhrik </PERSON> as saying. <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> last month announced it would cut defense spending by 15 percent and trim its armed forces by 12,000 men in the next two years. The cuts are also to include the scrapping of tanks and other hardware. According to <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> figures, <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> has about 145,000 troops. In December, Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s said 50,000 <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> troops would be withdrawn from <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> by the end of 1990. <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> have also announced troop cuts. While the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact cuts seem designed to boost new East-West talks next month in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> on reducing conventional arms and forces across <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, they also benefit the East's <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> governments by freeing up funds for sorely needed economic reforms.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890216-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-89 0041EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-Harmony     02-16 0234</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Harmony,0241</SECOND>
<HEAD>Arab, Jew Promote Coexistence With Music</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two Israeli musicians, an Arab and a Jew, have formed a duo to promote Arab-Jewish coexistence through music. The twosome, called `` The White Bird,'' features <PERSON> Taisir </PERSON> <PERSON> Elias </PERSON> on violin and oud, a lute-like stringed instrument of the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Migel </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartstein </PERSON> on guitar and banjo. <PERSON> Elias </PERSON>, an Israeli Arab from the northern town of <LOCATION> Shfaram </LOCATION>, said he met <PERSON> Hartstein </PERSON>, a Jewish farmer, at the annual <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> Festival last year and `` saw that we have to work together, to maintain this coexistence, this musical dialogue.'' Since then, the two have performed in front of small audiences in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Haifa </LOCATION>, and has twice traveled to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. In March, the musicians plan another tour abroad. <PERSON> Hartstein </PERSON> is a farmer from the <PERSON> Ganot </PERSON> agricultural cooperative near <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Elias </PERSON> teaches at the Jerusalem Academy of Music. Their music is a gentle blend of Eastern tones and Western popular music, with some motifs derived from American country music. `` It is human music, universal music,'' says <PERSON> Elias </PERSON>. `` It is a mid-way meeting between Eastern and Western music. From there, we start to create a special musical language.'' But, according to <PERSON> Elias </PERSON>, there is a political message too: `` The moment a Jew and an Arab play together and create together, they can not hate each other. That's the ideal we strive for.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890216-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-89 0041EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-StickySituation     02-16 0197</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sticky Situation,0203</SECOND>
<HEAD>Couple Stuck On Each Other Become Unglued</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DURHAM, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A convict and his girlfriend united their palms to protest the man's robbery conviction and stuck together for 21 hours. <PERSON> Jeremiah </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, 30, used an instant-bonding glue to affix his right hand to the left hand of <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Birchall </PERSON>, 25, when she visited him at <LOCATION> Frankland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Prison </LOCATION> on Tuesday. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, said his client wanted to publicize his claim of innocence of the robbery charge that led to a 15-year sentence at <ORGANIZATION> Liverpool </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> two years ago. <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> said <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> told him by telephone from the warden's office that the couple, having received the publicity they wanted, separated themselves within a few minutes using soap and water He said there was no intervention by prison officials, who had been talking to the couple since they glued themselves togther at 4 p.m. Tuesday. The lawyer said prison staff treated Miss <PERSON> Birchall </PERSON> `` extremely well,'' making her as comfortable as possible during the protest and giving her train fare back to <LOCATION> Liverpool </LOCATION> when it was over. A prison statement said warden <PERSON> Alistair </PERSON> <PERSON> Papps </PERSON> would consider what disciplinary steps to take against <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890216-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-89 0044EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APAppointment     02-16 0111</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Appointment,0113</SECOND>
<HEAD>AP Names News Editor For South Carolina</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COLUMBIA, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Eva </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Parziale </PERSON>, correspondent in charge of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> bureau in <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, has been named the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s news editor for <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>. The appointment was announced by <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> Chief of Bureau <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Shurr </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Parziale </PERSON>, 28, joined the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> in 1984. She earned a master's degree at <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and rejoined the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> in 1985. She became <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION> correspondent in 1987. A native of <LOCATION> Euclid </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, Ms. <PERSON> Parziale </PERSON> is a graduate of <ORGANIZATION> Bowling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Green </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and began her journalism career with the <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Telegraph </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Painesville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890216-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-89 0045EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-AncientOil     02-16 0634</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ancient Oil,0651</SECOND>
<HEAD>Oil Found That May Have Anointed Kings Of Israel</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NICOLAS B. TATRO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Near the site where the Dead Sea scrolls were found, archaeologists have dug up a 2,000-year-old flask filled with an oil that might have been used to anoint the ancient Israelite kings. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Patrich </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Hebrew </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> unveiled the flask Wednesday and said the oil, which has a honey-like consistency, may be the only surviving sample of the balsam oil used as an aromatic body cream or perfume. `` After conducting extensive laboratory analysis and checking literary sources, there is a good possibility that what we have here is the fragrant balsam oil that was famous throughout the Roman Empire,'' he said. The oil matches a discription of a perfume mentioned by the Roman historian <PERSON> Pliny </PERSON>. Known as persimmon oil, it was distilled from a bush-like plant now believed to be extinct. The ancient perfume was very expensive _ a sort of Chanel No. 5 of its day _ and was coveted throughout the Roman Empire. The persimmon plant, which was different from the modern tree of the same name, grew only in the Dead Sea oasis of En <PERSON> Gedi </PERSON> and around <LOCATION> Jericho </LOCATION>. The ancient Israelites guarded the secret formula for making the oil, going so far as to post warnings against anyone revealing the process. When the Roman legions approached, the Israelites tried to destroy the orchard of plants. <PERSON> Pliny </PERSON>'s writings indicate the <ORGANIZATION> Romans </ORGANIZATION> took over production, archaeologists say. <ORGANIZATION> Hebrew </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> chemist <PERSON> Zeev </PERSON> <PERSON> Aizenshtat </PERSON>, who spent three months analyzing the substance, said whatever fragrance the oil had evaporated in the desert cave, where summer temperatures hover over 104 degrees. He said he was unable to make an absolute identification because there were no surviving samples of the ancient plant to make a comparison. `` This oil is very different from other ancient oils in that it did not deteriorate,'' <PERSON> Aizenshtat </PERSON> said. `` This may be the oldest oil that contains such organic matter and whose properties have not been greatly altered by chemical reactions over time.'' The clay juglet stands 5 inches high and contains about 1 -LCB- to 3 -LCB- ounces of the reddish oil, which is well-preserved and dates to the 1st century B.C. It was wrapped in palm leaves and carefully concealed. It was found last year by the expedition, which includes an American team of volunteers from the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judaic-Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. The flask was buried in a 3-foot-deep pit in the honeycomb of caves at <LOCATION> Qumran </LOCATION>, 50 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> and the site where the Dead Sea Scrolls were discovered in 1947. The scrolls, ancient holy writings including the Book of <LOCATION> Isaiah </LOCATION>, were hidden by the Essene Sect in the 1st century A.D. to avoid plundering by the advancing Romans. The expedition will resume digging soon as part of a 6-year-old project to explore the thousands of caves in <LOCATION> Qumran </LOCATION> overlooking the <LOCATION> Dead </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Menachem </PERSON> <PERSON> Boorstein </PERSON>, a scholar at the Mercaz HaRav Yeshiva in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, said the oil was one of 11 holy fragrances burned as incense on the altar of ancient Jewish Temple. It is mentioned in Exodus and in the collection of Jewish law and commentary called the Talmud. <PERSON> Boorstein </PERSON> said the Talmud describes the oil as highly inflammable and tells the story of a woman killing her daughter by convincing her she should light a candle after rubbing her body with the oil to make its perfume effect stronger. The balsam oil, described by some ancient rabbis as more valuable than gold, was used to annoint the kings of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> after <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Solomon </PERSON> in the 10th Century B.C.E. `` During the ceremony, it would be poured across the king's head in the form of an X,'' <PERSON> Boorstein </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890216-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-89 0119EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FatFine     02-16 0218</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fat Fine,0225</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman Fails to Lose Weight; Must Pay A Hefty Fine</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KENOSHA, Wis. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A woman who was told she could either lose 100 pounds or pay a $ 500 fine as part of her sentence in a marijuana conviction failed to drop the weight and must now put up the dough, a judge said. <PERSON> Tina </PERSON> <PERSON> Usinger </PERSON>, 29, was convicted last year of possession of marijuana with intent to distribute. Judge <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> told her he'd knock $ 5 off the $ 500 fine for every pound she lost before she next returned to court. The unusual sentence had been recommended by her former probation agent, who reasoned that with a better self-image, Ms. <PERSON> Usinger </PERSON> would be less likely to turn to criminal activity. If she lost 100 pounds, she would n't have to pay a fine. But on Tuesday, Ms. <PERSON> Usinger </PERSON> weighed 265 pounds, the same as she did when <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> first fined her. At the sentencing, <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> stayed a two-year prison term for Ms. <PERSON> Usinger </PERSON>. He said he was satisfied that she had met other conditions of probation, including 100 hours of community service work and participation in a drug program. The weight reduction incentive, <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> said, was an option, not a condition of probation. `` If she'd rather pay the fine, that's her choice,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890216-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-89 0133EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Britain-Rushdie     02-16 0743</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Rushdie,0767</SECOND>
<HEAD>Anger Runs Deep In Moslem Community; Vengeance Does Not</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Satanic Verses, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MAGGIE JACKSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The anger over <PERSON> Salman </PERSON> <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> and his novel `` The Satanic Verses'' is quick to flare and shared by many in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s Moslem community, from the sweetmeats shopkeeper to the Bangladeshi banker But while they spare no insult for the author they accuse of blasphemy, many in the city's narrow East End streets do n't seek vengeance and reject <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s order to execute him. The Imams and Mosque council in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> issued an appeal to `` all imams'' _ Moslem clergymen _ to respect British law. An information office representing Prince <PERSON> Reza </PERSON> <PERSON> Pahlavi </PERSON>, son of the late <PERSON> Shah </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, said the Iranian government's reaction exemplifies the `` brutal and arbitrary intolerance that is rampant in <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Islamic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>.'' The statement, however, said the prince was sympathetic to objections to the book. In conversations with immigrants in the East End's <LOCATION> Brick </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lane </LOCATION> shops, some cheered the death call. But many said the author, who has canceled a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> tour and dropped from sight, should live. `` To kill him is not going to solve the problem,'' said <PERSON> Naim </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheikh </PERSON>, the owner of a shop selling leather goods who called for a law that would prevent such books from being written again. `` There must be some way that governments can approve a resolution that in future no writer should have a right to write against any prophet _ <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> or <PERSON> Moses </PERSON>,'' he said. Moslems revere <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> as the prophet who brought <PERSON> Allah </PERSON>'s revelations to mankind in the Koran, the holy book of Islam `` But do I personally agree with the ayatollah? It does n't matter,'' said Sheikh, one of the many Moslem Bangladeshis living in the <LOCATION> Brick </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lane </LOCATION> area `` You ca n't stop the ayatollah. You ca n't stop the people who will do the job ... Anyone who kills <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> will become a hero in the Islamic world.'' Like Sheikh, most Moslems acknowledged they have n't read the book. Most learned about it at one of the five mosques located in a one-square-mile area of this district, from leaflets, or from television reports. `` He insulted our prophet, our religion. From TV we know this,'' said a shopkeeper selling sticky sweets who refused to give his name. Even though they have n't read the book, they are sure it insults their prophet and are quick to say so when the novel is mentioned. `` Our older people read it, they say it's wrong, so we believe them,'' <PERSON> Nassim </PERSON> <PERSON> Khan </PERSON>, a Pakistani Moslem, said as he ate lunch at a modest tandoori restaurant. `` They've been studying for years and years and they should know.'' <PERSON> Maqbool </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali-Kassam </PERSON>, waiting for his takeout tea, boomed from across the room: `` Anyone who denies the religion of Islam shall be killed.'' <PERSON> Ali-Kassam </PERSON>, a taxi cab radio controller who calls himself a follower of the ayatollah, said he believes <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> deliberately meant to insult Islam. Dozens of drivers from his company stayed at the office until early Wednesday morning, he said, arguing about the book and the execution order. `` Some said he did n't mean anything about <ORGANIZATION> Islam </ORGANIZATION>, others wanted him killed.'' Many Moslems believe <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>, 41, insults <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> by portraying him as a character called Mahound, a prophet of a city called <PERSON> Jahilia </PERSON>. <PERSON> Mahound </PERSON> was a medieval corruption of the word <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON>. They are especially angered by one sequence in which prostitutes are given the names of some of <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON>'s nine wives and by the book's implication that <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON>, not <PERSON> Allah </PERSON>, may have been the real author of the Koran. <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> was born into a Moslem family in <LOCATION> Bombay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, and educated in <LOCATION> Cambridge </LOCATION>. He lives in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. His novel has sold more than 100,000 copies since it was published in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> in September to critical acclaim. `` Previously <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> has been criticized, but not in this naked way,'' said <PERSON> Abul </PERSON> <PERSON> Khair </PERSON>, a top officer at the <ORGANIZATION> Sonali </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION>'s state bank, on <LOCATION> Brick </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lane </LOCATION>. `` It is intolerable for Moslems.'' But he does n't agree with the ayatollah. `` We do n't want violence. Islam is a peaceful religion,'' he said. Restaurant manager <PERSON> Asaad </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramjaun </PERSON>, a Mauritian immigrant, said of <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>: `` I think he's the devil himself.'' `` We understand this is a free society, but I think this is freedom of abuse,'' he said. `` But since this is a free society _ he should n't be killed. He should be given a chance.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890216-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-89 0138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Chernobyl     02-16 0528</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chernobyl,0550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Paper Admits Soviets Badly Underestimated Cherobyl Health Effects</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANDREW KATELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Authorities badly underestimated the health problems the 1986 <LOCATION> Chernobyl </LOCATION> nuclear disaster would cause, with reported cancer cases doubling in a region near the stricken plant that was not evacuated, <ORGANIZATION> Moscow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> reported. The article Wednesday in the weekly newspaper said calves are born routinely without heads and limbs in the radiation-contaminated area of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION>. It said more than half the children of the <LOCATION> Narodichsky </LOCATION> region _ an agriculturally rich area within 30 miles of the plant _ have thyroid gland illnesses, which can be caused by exposure to radiation. The newspaper's correspondent, <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Kolinko </PERSON>, said one woman, who cares for pigs at a tainted farm, asked, `` My daughter recently got married. What kind of grandson will I have?'' In all, 31 people died in the immediate aftermath of the explosion and fire at the plant on April 26, 1986. The disaster sent a cloud of radiation around the world. <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> News reported that elevated levels of radioactive cesium-137 were detected among many residents of the Narodichsky region, which was not evacuated after the accident. It said, `` Health officials of the republic insist there is no health danger for people outside a 19-mile zone around the atomic power station.'' Since the accident, Soviet officials stressed time and again that radiation levels were safe in all but the immediate area surrounding the plant. They generally discounted warnings from some Western doctors that cases of cancer and other diseases would soar. The Moscow News article, however, was the second this month in the Soviet press to suggest health problems from the accident were mounting. The official <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> news agency reported Feb. 9 that cancer and other diseases are on the rise in <LOCATION> Byelorussia </LOCATION>, the republic neighboring the <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION> that also was contaminated by <LOCATION> Chernobyl </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said authorities had just determined that one-fifth of <LOCATION> Byelorussia </LOCATION> is contaminated. <ORGANIZATION> Moscow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> said lip, mouth and other cancers doubled among Narodichsky region residents since the accident. <PERSON> Kolinko </PERSON> said residents had a right to be outraged. He wrote that if the government is serious about its pledges, residents `` would have the right to demand _ to demand and not ask _ for full compensation ... not to mention the right to full information about people's health and the condition of the land.'' At the <PERSON> Petrovsky </PERSON> animal farm, the newspaper said, veterinarian <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Kudin </PERSON> reported that during the five years before Chernobyl, three cases of birth defects occurred among pigs and there were no abnormal calves. In the year after the disaster, 37 pigs and 27 calves had birth defects, he said. In the first nine months of 1988, 41 pigs and 35 calves were born with abnormalities _ `` the calves frequently without heads, limbs, eyes or ribs, the pigs goggle-eyed or with deformed skulls.'' The animals had been feeding on fields where wind had blown radioactive particles, the newspaper said. It said that uncontaminated meat and dairy products are brought in for residents, but some people ignore doctors' warnings and drink milk from local cows and pick fruit and vegetables from their garden plots.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890216-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-89 0037EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-ParaguayanMuckraker Bjt   02-16 0678</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Paraguayan Muckraker, Bjt,0697</SECOND>
<HEAD>Crusading Newspaper Plans Comeback After Coup</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELIZABETH LOVE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ASUNCION, Paraguay (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The owner and editor of the popular and award-winning newspaper <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Color began planning its first edition in nearly five years as soon as he heard Gen. <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> had been ousted. `` We're going to come out with the same kinds of stories that prompted them to shut us down before _ corruption, narcotics trafficking, and the violation of human rights,'' said <PERSON> Aldo </PERSON> <PERSON> Zuccolillo </PERSON>. Warming to the subject, the 59-year-old journalist added, `` We want to become permanent reminders to Gen. <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> of the promises he made when he assumed power.'' Gen. <PERSON> Andres </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> toppled <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> on Feb. 3 and almost immediately gave Zuccolillo permission to resume publishing <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Color as he promised to respect freedom of the press and human rights. The newspaper, best known for its investigative stories, was once the most widely read daily in this <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> capital of 900,000 people. `` I am certain that Gen. <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> will not ask me nor anyone to refrain from publishing an article because he does n't like it, `` said <PERSON> Zuccolillo </PERSON>, who founded <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Color in 1967. Zuccolillo frequently clashed with <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> and his aides, enduring threats, arrests and, finally, closure of the 80,000-circulation paper by plainclothes police in March 1984. The stated reason: the paper was provoking class hatred among Paraguayans. In preceding years, seven <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Color journalists were arrested, and one expelled. Zuccolillo himself was jailed twice, the first time for 11 days, the second for a week. He says he's sure that wo n't happen again: `` Now, we'll no longer have the overnight bags that we kept behind the doors in the newsroom in case the police came and took us directly to jail.'' The new issue, to hit the street in about a month, will differ little from editions in the past that won citations from, among other, the <ORGANIZATION> InterAmerican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>. Three years ago, <PERSON> Zuccolillo </PERSON> was awarded the prestigious Maria Moors Cabot Prize from <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s journalism school. `` We're going to investigate everything. We have the staff and the sources of information,'' <PERSON> Zuccolillo </PERSON> said. `` Now you're going to begin to see news sources appear that in other times would hide because they were scared to death.'' In the days following the coup, <PERSON> Zuccolillo </PERSON> saw a constant stream of foreign reporters who tried to get a better handle on Paraguayan politics from a veteran observer. `` I think Gen. <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> has no other option than to fulfill his promises,'' said <PERSON> Zuccolillo </PERSON>. `` The Paraguayan people are totally fed up with <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> and Streossnerism.'' <PERSON> Zuccolillo </PERSON> said hard work and skill, not luck, had kept <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> in power for nearly 35 years. `` <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> had a great Machiavellian political talent to achieve his objectives,'' Zuccolillo said. `` He was a planner, he was very intelligent, he had a great power of synthesis and an extraordinary memory, but he also was immoral, unscrupulous, bloodthirsty and a corrupter.'' Zuccolillo, who broke with Paraguayan tradition by forbidding his journalists to accept government payoffs, plans to trace just how corrupt his former nemesis was. `` The first clues are going to come from outside, from <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` I already have a couple of <LOCATION> Swiss </LOCATION> journalists who are willing to help me, and I'm going to send a couple of reporters from here ... when I get some money together.'' Investigative reports published by <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Color in the past alleged that by overcharging gasoline sold by the private oil company <ORGANIZATION> Refineria </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paraguaya </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> S.A. </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> bilked the country of about $ 800 million over five years in the 1970s. `` <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> might barely have a $ 10,000 bungalow -LRB- in <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION> -RRB-, but he has well over a billion dollars overseas,'' claimed Zuccolillo. <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> was exiled to <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, where he is said to own a home. Zuccolillo dismisses the reservations some have that the <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> government may become the equivalent of `` Stroessnerism without <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>.'' `` You ca n't have Stroessnerism without <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> if you have a free press,'' he said. `` A free press is the antidote of the people against totalitarianism.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890216-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-89 0045EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-BethesdaShootings 3rdLd-Writethru a0776 02-16 0635</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bethesda Shootings, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0776,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS in first 14 grafs with gunman reported to be former mental
patient; Also CORRECTS spelling of Ludington thruout; picks up 9th graf
pvs, Another employee.</HEAD>
<HEAD>Gunman Kills Three Others, Self in Washington Area</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DIANE DUSTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BETHESDA, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A former mental patient described as a `` disgruntled employee'' shot three women co-workers to death and killed himself at the office of a savings and loan association Wednesday, police said. The gunman was identified as <PERSON> Emanuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Tsegaye </PERSON>, 33, of Silver Spring, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, police said. A spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Maryland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Tsegaye </PERSON> had been released about a year ago after five years at the <ORGANIZATION> Clifton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> T. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Perkins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Jessup </LOCATION>, Md. <PERSON> Tsegaye </PERSON> was sent to the mental hospital after he was ruled criminally insane following his arrest on charges of assaulting a police officer. Two victims have also been identified by police as <PERSON> Cynthia </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, 28, of <LOCATION> Landover </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Tanya </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, 23, of <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, Md. The names of the other victims were were not immediately released. Police in this <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, suburb said the three people killed in addition to <PERSON> Tsegaye </PERSON> were all female employees at <ORGANIZATION> Chevy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chase </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Tsegaye </PERSON> also wounded <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, 22, of Silver Spring, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, police said. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, who was shot in the jaw, is in critical condition at <LOCATION> Suburban </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> following surgery. According to <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> police spokesman Officer <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Ludington </PERSON>, <PERSON> Tsegaye </PERSON> got off an elevator at the credit card department of the S & amp; L at the end of the lunch hour, walked down a hallway and through a set of double doors, and shot <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> and one of the women. The Ethiopian native then went into a nearby lunchroom and killed the other two women, <PERSON> Luddington </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Tsegaye </PERSON> then turned his .38 - caliber revolver on himself, <PERSON> Ludington </PERSON> `` It happened very quickly,'' <PERSON> Ludington </PERSON> said. He described the gunman as a `` disgruntled employee.'' A fellow worker said the man was a collector in the credit card department. `` All of the people that I have talked to about it are very disturbed, very surprised by it ... because all indications were that Mr. <PERSON> Tsegaye </PERSON> was doing very well,'' <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Golden </PERSON>, spokesman for the state health department, told <ORGANIZATION> WUSA-TV </ORGANIZATION>. The station said <PERSON> Tsegaye </PERSON> had originally been arrested after approaching a <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> police officer and saying, `` I want to die, kill me,'' and then reaching for the officer's gun. He was charged with attempted murder in that case, according to the television report. A <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> police official said late Wednesday they would not release any details about <PERSON> Tsegaye </PERSON>'s background. Another employee, <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Abellano </PERSON> said he was sitting next to <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> when <PERSON> Tsegaye </PERSON> came into the office. `` First he shot <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> and then I went under my chair,'' he said. <PERSON> Abellano </PERSON>, who was not injured, said <PERSON> Tsegaye </PERSON> had had an argument with a co-worker earlier in the day. He said that person was not injured. <PERSON> Alex </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapin </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, who was on the telephone with an employee of the S & amp; L when the shootings occurred, said he heard screaming in the background. `` I hear a banging at the door and ... I heard somebody say, ` Do n't let him in, don ` t let him in,' <PERSON> Chapin </PERSON> said in a telephone interview. `` And then ... I hear another scream and I hear another shot. ... `` Out of horror, I'm sitting here listening to the phone,'cause I do n't know if it's a hostage situation going on or what. And I waited and waited and waited until I heard the police sirens, so I figure somebody's on the scene at that point. Then I heard somebody say something, ` Why do n't they come up here?' and that's when I heard some more shooting and then the phone went dead,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890216-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-89 0211EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BankBoard-Martin Bjt   02-16 0919</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bank Board-Martin, Bjt,920</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bank Board Member Fails to Keep Stock-Sale Pledge</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD L. VERNACI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A member of the board that regulates the savings and loan industry has not sold his stock in a family business despite a sworn pledge to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and a legal requirement that he do so. The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> learned that <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> continues to hold a 29 percent share in <ORGANIZATION> Pope </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scientific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> Menomonee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, company that makes laboratory glassware. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> has valued his share of the company at $ 100,000 to $ 250,000. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, and other employees of the agency blame a paperwork jam and confusing rules for his failure to sell his stock or be relieved of his promise. The bank board oversees the operation of more than 3,000 savings and loan institutions, regulating their transactions and auditing their records. `` I'm still waiting for an opinion from the ethics people,'' <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said Wednesday. `` Basically, I did n't want to get rid of it because you ca n't get rid of it,'' <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said of his stake in the company. `` It is a very, very small company and it's all family held.'' <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Ann </PERSON>, holds a 51 percent interest in the company and is its president. Her stake in the company is valued at more than $ 250,000, according to <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>'s financial disclosure forms. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> had been chairman of the company from 1983 until he became a member of the bank board. Although the company does occasional work for the government, its business would have little or no occasion for contact with the bank board. But <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> was advised to divest himself of the holding because his stake in the company was so large that under bank board rules, <PERSON> Pope </PERSON> <PERSON> Scientific </PERSON> would be considered his `` alter ego,'' according to a letter from <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Quillian </PERSON>, the board's general counsel and ethics officer. `` This relationship would, therefore, have a substantial effect on <PERSON> Pope </PERSON>'s ability to do business,'' <PERSON> Quillian </PERSON> wrote in a letter attached to <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>'s 1987 financial disclosure form. `` Mr. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> has indicated that he will transfer his interest in <PERSON> Pope </PERSON> to his wife or other relative to avoid any conflict or appearance of conflict from his ownership interest in <PERSON> Pope </PERSON>.'' In sworn testimony during his confirmation hearings before the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> in 1987, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> was asked whether he pledged to abide by the ethics finding. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> responded, `` Yes.'' <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Gottlieb </PERSON> said he knew nothing about <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>'s holding in Pope Scientific or his promise to dispose of it, but a blanket pledge such as the one <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> gave the committee is more than ceremonial. `` Generically, the committee understands all standard statements required by people who testify to be very serious,'' <PERSON> Gottlieb </PERSON> said. `` The committee would n't ask for it unless they thought it was serious, and they expect to be told the truth.'' Under federal ethics laws, the property should have been disposed of within 90 days of <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>'s confirmation by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in August 1987, with notice given to both the Office of Government Ethics and the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said Wednesday that he had sold off his other holdings as promised when he became a member of the board but did not dispose of his Pope Scientific stock because he was waiting for an opinion from the staff. `` I got rid of everything else. ... I liquidated everything I owned at a substantial cost,'' he said. Both <PERSON> Quillian </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Kurtenbach </PERSON>, another agency ethics officer, were in the room with <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> when he was interviewed by telephone, and both said the initial opinion that <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> should sell the stock was wrong. `` There was never any question of impropriety or any conflict of interest,'' <PERSON> Quillian </PERSON> said. `` It was an extremely technical question of the status of the company under the board's regulations. `` We think that in the first instance the interpretation went too far. We bent over backward, as did Mr. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, and on reflection we believe that we were too technical and too strict.'' Nevertheless, neither the ethics office nor the banking committee has been informed of <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>'s intention to keep his share of the company. <PERSON> Kurtenbach </PERSON> said his office was to blame for failure to notify the ethics office and the banking committee. `` I think that was a part where we fell down,'' he said. `` It was just an administrative screw-up.'' The government ethics office, the watchdog agency for the executive branch, also has not received a copy of <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>'s annual financial disclosure report, although one should have been handed over no later than last September, according to <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Zorn </PERSON>, who is assigned to monitor the bank board's ethics compliance. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>'s form, along with those of the other two members of the board, <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Wall </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, are on file at the agency but have not been forwarded to the government ethics office. <PERSON> Kurtenbach </PERSON> said this was because the agency was behind in its paperwork. <PERSON> Zorn </PERSON> said in his discussions with the bank board, there were `` loose ends'' to be tied up with <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>'s finances, one of which was the Pope Scientific stock. The bank board staff was most concerned about <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>'s stock in <ORGANIZATION> MGIC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and his position as senior vice president of <ORGANIZATION> Mortgage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guaranty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> sold the stock, resigned from <ORGANIZATION> MGIC </ORGANIZATION> and promised to take no part in board actions on matters that may come up dealing with <ORGANIZATION> MGIC </ORGANIZATION> or the mortgage insurance industry
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890216-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-89 0209EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Justice-CivilRights Bjt   02-16 0790</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Justice-Civil Rights, Bjt,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Seeks Rights Chief to Reverse Reynolds' Policies</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The four top candidates for the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s chief civil rights job all would sharply change the controversial policies that <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> followed for the last eight years. A leading candidate is <PERSON> Evan </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a disabled-rights advocate who publicly battled <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> over a proposal to reduce anti-discrimination protection for handicapped people. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Equal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opportunity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, is being considered for the post of assistant attorney general in charge of the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s civil rights division, said administration sources. Confined to a wheelchair, <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> has been an advocate for handicapped Americans and once successfully sued the <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> after being told his disability would bar his promotion to supervisor. Also under consideration are <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Rinzel </PERSON>, minority chief counsel to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s permanent investigations subcommittee and <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerry </PERSON>, former head of the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Welfare </ORGANIZATION> who has served as counsel to the Wednesday Group of moderate <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Republicans. A former career <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> employee, <PERSON> Rinzel </PERSON> once headed the criminal section of the civil rights division and set records for the number of cases brought. That performance won him a promotion under <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> to deputy assistant attorney general. Another candidate is <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, longtime career deputy assistant attorney general in the division who early in the civil rights movement prosecuted white supremacists and other rights violators in the deep South, sources said. `` Everyone on the list would turn it around,'' one of the candidates, who knows the others, said on condition of anonymity. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON>, an aide to Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON>, said `` we're looking for someone whose views reflect <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON>'s and the president's views on the importance of the civil rights division.'' `` We're looking for somebody who can work with civil rights organizations,'' said <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON>. The major civil rights organizations tangled regularly with <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> throughout the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> helped formulate and direct the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's policy of challenging affirmative action hiring quotas He also moved to overturn court-ordered busing programs and to restrict federal guarantees for women's rights and the rights of the mentally ill and disabled. Without committing himself on specific issues, President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has said he wants civil rights policy to be sharply different from that followed under <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> reflected the new administration's stance by meeting with civil rights leaders, notably <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. After meeting with the attorney general last month, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> praised <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> and said, `` The lights have been turned back on in the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>.'' <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON> noted <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON>'s `` interest in the civil rights area that goes back to the 1960s.'' `` He knows many of the civil rights leaders first hand,'' <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON> said. `` He is personally committed to making sure the laws are enforced.'' While <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> is still reviewing other applications, <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> `` is certainly a leading candidate,'' said one source, who spoke Wednesday on condition of anonymity. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> confirmed in a telephone interview that he met with <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> this week and was told a decision would be made `` in a couple of weeks.'' The appointment, which will be made by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> with <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON>'s recommendation, is subject to <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> confirmation <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> said he had been told earlier by <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> counsel <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyden </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> that he was a leading candidate for the position and nothing that <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said during their meeting dispelled that impression. `` I just thought it was a good interview,'' <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> said. Without directly criticizing <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION>'s failure to attract black voters was due in part to the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's civil rights record `` I think it's very important for the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> to have a civil rights record they can run on and attract votes from groups covered by the civil rights laws.'' `` I've seen estimates as low as 9 percent of the black voters voted for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in 1988,'' <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> said. `` I do n't think that's good for black people to be taken for granted by the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> or for this country.'' <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, who is confined to a wheelchair because of a paralyzing illness and subsequent injury, headed the <ORGANIZATION> Disability </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> when he battled <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> in 1982. At issue was a proposal by a <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration task force on deregulation to weaken rules prohibiting companies and institutions that receive federal funds from discriminating against handicapped employees. `` It was very important to the disability rights movement that we retain the rules and regulations and <PERSON> Brad </PERSON> was very critical of me,'' <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> said, recalling the dispute. At one point, <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> demanded <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON>' resignation from the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. The proposal to change 1977 regulations enforcing the anti-discrimination law was withdrawn by the administration.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890216-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-89 0208EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Congress-Stocks Bjt   02-16 0724</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress-Stocks, Bjt,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Members of Senate Communications Panel Hold Stock in Industry</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Members of a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> communications panel held stock in the industry and acted on issues that could have affected their holdings, a practice that is forbidden in the executive branch but legal for lawmakers. Critics complain about the double standard on conflict-of-interest rules, but others say it would be impossible to apply the same standards to the executive and legislative branches. The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> selected the communications subcommittee of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> to show examples of stock holdings and congressional action. Financial information for the 11 senators came from their disclosure forms for 1987, the most recent year available. Sen. <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hollings </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-S.C. </LOCATION>, the committee's chairman and member of the subcommittee, had larger holdings in telecommunications than any other senator on the communications panel. On Aug. 21, 1987, he bought about $ 100,000 worth of stock in <ORGANIZATION> McCaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cellular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, the day the company went public. In December, <PERSON> Hollings </PERSON> helped postpone the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>'s plans to hold lotteries for licensing cellular telephones in rural areas, according to Sen. <PERSON> Brock </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, D-Wash. As committee chairman, <PERSON> Hollings </PERSON> had to approve a Jan. 27, 1988, communications subcommittee hearing on the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION>'s proposed lottery idea <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> McCaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, executive vice president of <ORGANIZATION> McCaw </ORGANIZATION>, testified in opposition to portions of the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION>'s plan. <PERSON> Hollings </PERSON> said he did n't know he owned the stock because his broker bought it for him. `` As soon as it was brought to my attention that I owned it, I told him to get rid of it, which he did,'' <PERSON> Hollings </PERSON> said through a spokesman. He said he first found out about his holdings in McCaw in February 1988, but it is unclear whether he made a profit or a loss on the stock. Some of the stock was sold in November 1987. In 1987, <PERSON> Hollings </PERSON> also sold between $ 100,000 and $ 250,000 in stock and $ 2,000 and $ 10,000 in options in <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which in 1986 purchased the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. A communications subcommittee member, Sen. <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Alaska </LOCATION>, said he had no qualms about his longtime interest in <ORGANIZATION> Northern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, which owns two television stations and two radio stations in his home state The holding is worth less than $ 5,000. `` It's not a substantial holding,'' <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> said. His votes include one against a bill extending the fairness doctrine, which required stations to air opposing views. <PERSON> Marla </PERSON> <PERSON> Romash </PERSON>, an aide to Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, D-Tenn., said the senator is sensitive to conflict of interest issues but has n't felt the $ 1,540 in <ORGANIZATION> Tandy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> stock owned by his wife, <PERSON> Tipper </PERSON>, to be an issue <ORGANIZATION> Tandy </ORGANIZATION>, which manufactures electronic goods including telephones, is the parent company of Radio Shack. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> voted for legislation to require all telephones to be equipped with devices so they are compatible with hearing aids. Sen. <PERSON> Wendell </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>, D-Ky., dismissed the notion there could be a conflict between his duties on the panel and the less than $ 5,000 worth of <ORGANIZATION> BellSouth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> stock his wife inherited `` The amount of stock does n't amount to a grain of sand on the beach,'' <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Norman </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>'s spokesman said. One member of the full committee, Sen. <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kassebaum </PERSON>, R-Kan., said she avoided voting `` a couple of times'' on issues that dealt with communications because her family had interests in radio stations Mrs. <PERSON> Kassebaum </PERSON> sold <ORGANIZATION> WREN </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, in <LOCATION> Topeka </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>, for more than $ 250,000 in January 1987. Some other senators have their holdings in blind trusts, including Sen. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, R-Calif., a member of the communications subcommittee, as a way of dealing with potential conflicts The basic federal conflict law makes it a crime for executive branch employees to take government action in which their immediate families have a financial interest, unless a waiver is obtained. The top penalty is two years in prison and a $ 10,000 fine. But no law or rule prevents members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> from holding assets that might conflict with their official duties. So lawmakers can routinely craft or vote on legislation that could affect their financial interests. One argument for not applying the conflict law to them is that their assets are publicly disclosed so voters can decide for themselves if senators or representatives are acting for personal enrichment.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890216-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-89 0207EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Government-Computers     02-16 0377</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Government-Computers,370</SECOND>
<HEAD>Complaint Over Favoritism Prompts Limit on Naval Computer Contracts</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONNA CASSATA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government is limiting the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s authority to award computer contracts after six companies complained the service was unfairly partial to <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Machines </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, which oversees government buying, said Wednesday that for a minimum of 60 days, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> will have to submit for review any computer purchase in excess of $ 2.5 million. Previously, <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION> let the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> award computer contracts of up to $ 10 million. `` This action clearly shows the administrator's intent to increase <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION>'s oversight over <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> computer buys and to fully cooperate with our committee's investigation into alleged favoritism toward <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION>'s systems,'' said Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Conyers </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, D-Mich., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Government Operations The panel, which has been investigating the way computer contracts are awarded, last week asked the government to restrict the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s authority. <PERSON> Conyers </PERSON> cited government statistics indicating that <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION> currently holds almost 55 percent of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s large-scale computer base, compared with the company's 37 percent share government-wide. The committee had received a complaint last November from six <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION> competitors that they have been frozen out of much of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s multibillion-dollar computer market The companies complained in a letter to former <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> that <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> procurement officials had tailored the bid specifications so that only <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION> could win although many of the companies offer `` clones'' or duplicates of <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION> systems at lower prices. The five-page letter was signed by executives of the <ORGANIZATION> Amdahl </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Memorex </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telex </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> PacifiCorp </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Capital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> VION </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> NCR </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Compten </ORGANIZATION>; and <ORGANIZATION> Storage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. A <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said Wednesday the service would have no comment until it reviewed the <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION> decision The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> committee also has asked the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, the investigative arm of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, to investigate complaints that federal agencies are restricting their computer procurements to favor <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> was asked last week to supply to the committee within 60 days a broad evaluation of the extent that federal agencies restrict their procurements to <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION> `` code-compatible'' systems. With expenditures of about $ 17.4 billion last year on computer, communications and data processing equipment and services, the government is the industry's largest single purchaser.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890216-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-89 0206EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-S&amp;Ls     02-16 0538</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-S&amp;Ls,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nader Says Tax the Wealthy, Stock Sales to Finance Rescue</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The wealthy should pay more to resolve the savings and loan crisis, says consumer activist <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Nader </PERSON> in claiming the administration's rescue plan puts the burden on the poor and middle class. `` The people of this country -LRB- are -RRB- demanding that the government sock it to the rich and powerful who caused the savings and loan crime and who will benefit from its resolution,'' he said at a news conference Wednesday. Last week, the president proposed spending $ 200 billion over the next 30 years _ about half of it from general tax revenues _ to sell or close insolvent institutions. <PERSON> Nader </PERSON>, in a 23-page `` Report to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Taxpayers on the Savings and Loan Crisis,'' said spending general tax revenue on <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls would squeeze vital government programs such as education and housing. But he also acknowledged that imposing a major share of the cleanup cost on healthy S & amp; Ls could drive some institutions toward insolvency. As an alternative, <PERSON> Nader </PERSON> offered four tax increase proposals, each of which would raise about $ 10 billion a year, enough to pay the interest on government borrowing to resolve the problem. They are: _ boosting the marginal income tax rate for the nation's wealthiest taxpayers _ childless couples with taxable income higher than $ 149,250 a year, for instance _ from 28 percent to 33 _ levying a 0.5 percent tax on stock sales, which totaled $ 2.3 trillion in 1987 <PERSON> Nader </PERSON> argued this would dampen speculation and encourage long-term investing. _ raising corporate taxes, estimated at $ 107 billion this year, by 10 percent _ a combination of higher deposit insurance premiums and new excise taxes on mutual funds, junk bonds, leveraged buyout deals and mortgages for luxury homes <PERSON> Nader </PERSON> said any increase in deposit insurance premiums paid by banks and <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls should be accompanied by measures restricting institutions from passing on the higher cost to their smallest customers. `` Under the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> plan to bail out the crooked and speculative savings and loan institutions, the people who are working every day and paying their taxes are paying the bill,'' he said. `` Under our plan, the corporations, the banks and very upper income people ... would pay the bill.'' <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Nader </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> group </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> BankWatch </ORGANIZATION>, advocated restructuring the 12 regional <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banks </ORGANIZATION>, owned by the <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L industry but created by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in the 1930s to borrow money from Wall Street investors at low government rates and pass on the money to S & amp; Ls. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said the boards of the regional banks should be appointed by the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>, rather than elected by S & amp; Ls. He said S & amp; Ls should be required to lend part of the money advanced by the regional banks for low income housing and neighborhood redevelopment. `` This is a cash-generating machine which has been appropriated for private purposes and is not pursuing its public housing mandate,'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> Consumer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bankers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, a trade group representing about 900 banks and <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls, rejected the proposal as `` massive social engineering which will be so burdensome as to prevent the <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L industry from ever recovering.'' The bankers said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s plan rescues depositors, not S & amp; L owners.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890216-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-89 0205EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AT&amp;TRates     02-16 0607</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AT&amp;T Rates,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Long-Distance Rates Drop as Local Charges Rise</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAY ARNOLD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> plans to drop its rates for basic interstate long-distance service by an average 1.6 percent on April 1, for a total annual savings to customers of $ 533 million. A consumer advocate complained, however, that for the cuts such heavy-use periods as nights and weekends were insignificant. The rate cut, which is subject to approval by the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, would be the eighth price reduction since <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> T </ORGANIZATION> shed its local operating companies in 1984. Since that time, <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T long-distance rates have dropped more than 39 percent, the company said Wednesday. The proposed rate reduction reflects lower costs for connecting to local telephone networks. Those costs will drop April 1 when the charge residential and small business customers pay to maintain local phone network _ the so-called subscriber line charge _ rises 30 cents per month to $ 3.50. With customers paying more of the costs to maintain the local network, long-distance companies have had to pay less. The <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> has required <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T, the largest long-distance company and the only one subject to federal rate regulation, to pass along these savings to customers by lowering rates. But while most long-distance rates would go down under the new proposal, prices for basic long-distance calls under 292 miles would increase an average of 4.7 percent _ a little less than a penny a minute. Such calls account for about one-third of <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T's interstate traffic. Also, daytime price cuts would be larger than evening price cuts, and night-weekend prices would not change. <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, a spokesman for the rival <ORGANIZATION> MCI </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, said the company had not had a chance to study <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T's proposal thoroughly, `` But, as usual, we plan to remain competitive with <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T.'' <PERSON> Janis </PERSON> <PERSON> Langley </PERSON>, a spokeswoman at another competitor, <LOCATION> US </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sprint </LOCATION>, said: `` In the past we have followed suit, and I anticipate that we will do that in this issue also Those reductions affect us in a slightly different way, but we will pass on whatever is appropriate -LRB- to our customers -RRB-.'' <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Kimmelman </PERSON>, legislative director for the <ORGANIZATION> Consumer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>, complained that <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T was not cutting prices signigicantly in the heavily used night and weekend long-distance time periods. `` It's unfair that consumers have to pay 30 cents more on their local bill without receiving any rate reduction for the long-distance service they use most,'' <PERSON> Kimmelman </PERSON> said in an interview. He said the price cut plan bodes ill for customers if <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T is given more flexibility to set prices, as has been proposed by <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON>. `` If this is a sign of what <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> T </ORGANIZATION> does when given pricing flexibility, it means that less regulation will deny consumers the price reductions for evening, night and weekend services they've experienced in the last three or four years,'' <PERSON> Kimmelman </PERSON> said Under <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> T </ORGANIZATION>'s proposal: _ Basic long-distance service prices would drop an average 1.6 percent Day prices would decrease 3.8 percent, while evening prices would decrease 0.4 percent. _ Rates for <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> T </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> WATS </ORGANIZATION> calls would drop an average 3.9 percent _ PRO WATS rates would drop an average 3.8 percent _ <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> T </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> MEGACOM </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> WATS </ORGANIZATION> rates wouild drop 1.1 percent, and <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> T </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> MEGACOM </ORGANIZATION> 800 prices would be 5.2 percent lower _ Basic <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T 800 service would drop 0.9 percent in price, while 800 Readyline service would decrease 3.3 percent Beginning July 1, <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T 800 service will be billed according to distance, and there will be additional price reductions of 1.9 percent for 800 service and 2 percent for 800 Readyline. _ <ORGANIZATION> Software </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defined </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> prices will decline an average 6.1 percent
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890216-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-89 0219EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DrugSeizures     02-16 0455</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drug Seizures,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Administration Relents on `Zero Tolerance' Boat Seizures</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CALLAHAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government is softening its `` zero tolerance'' policy of seizing boats where drugs are found, saying small amounts will no longer be sufficient reason to seize commercial fishing vessels while in operation. Interim guidelines, written to conform with a congressional mandate that was attached to last November's anti-drug package, were expected to be announced today by <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> Adm. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Yost </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> Commissioner <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Raab </PERSON>, government officials said Wednesday. Under the policy that began last March, federal agents were free to seize vessels within 12 miles of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> coastline if any amount of illegal drugs was found on board. Recreational boat owners were furious, complaining that they could face the loss of millions of dollars worth of property if a crew member or guest possessed a trace of marijuana without the boat owner's knowledge. And commercial fishermen said they could lose their livelihoods even if they were eventually found innocent and their vessels were returned. Late last year, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> narrowly approved modifications that would, in the words of Rep. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Alaska </LOCATION>, `` prevent innocent owners of fishing vessels from being persecuted by well-meaning but overexcited enforcement agents.'' <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> instructed the executive branch to issue new regulations within 60 days and then hold a 30-day public comment period. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration already is a month late, and <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> officials said they do not expect formal regulations to be proposed for at least several weeks. But <PERSON> Yost </PERSON> and <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Raab </PERSON>, in a joint announcement, are issuing interim rules for commercial fishing boats, said officials from their agencies, speaking on condition of anonymity. Under the new rules, seizures of commercial fishing vessels in operation or en route to or from fishery operations will be prohibited if the drugs found are in `` personal use quantities.'' That is generally described as less than one gram of cocaine or heroin and less than one ounce of marijuana. Instead of being immediately seized and escorted to port to await forfeiture proceedings by the <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, fishing vessel operators will be given a summons and ordered to appear before the agency at the completion of the fishing trip. Customs officials then will decide whether the vessel should be forfeited or if a penalty should be imposed. The joint Customs-Coast Guard announcement also outlines expedited administrative procedures for the forfeiture process, setting a maximum 20-day period for a final decision. The announcement will not, however, detail other congressionally mandated changes in the zero tolerance policy, including a provision to protect innocent owners by ordering a vessel's release if owners can prove drug offenses occurred without their knowledge or consent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890216-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-89 0215EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Soviet-Espionage     02-16 0709</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Espionage,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Book Says Bugging Devices Found in Moscow Embassy Code Rooms</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> is denying a report that Americans found bugging devices in the old <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> while investigating allegations that Marine guards let the <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> into the facility. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, also denied allegations that it withheld information on the discovery of the listening devices from the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, which administers the embassy. Both allegations were made by author <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON> in his book, `` <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> Station,'' which expands on earlier reports that the <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> had gained access to the embassy and the highly protected code rooms by sexually compromising <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Marine guards. <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON> wrote that the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> communications intelligence organization, discovered in 1987 that the Soviets had put listening devices in the Communications Programs Units, or code rooms, at <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomatic missions in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> rarely comments on espionage matters. But <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> read a statement Wednesday that `` the intelligence community conducted a review of the evidence, and that review did not substantiate that the CPU area of the embassy was successfully penetrated by the Soviets.'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> also denied an allegation by <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON> that the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> NSA </ORGANIZATION> kept the discovery secret from the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. `` That is just not so,'' said <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>. `` The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> took part in a damage assessment'' based on allegations that Marine guards had allowed the <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> into secure sections of the embassy at night. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> declined to discuss previous reports that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence had discovered bugging devices which transmitted information about what was being written on typewriters in embassy offices other than the communications room. <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON> said in a telephone interview from his home in <LOCATION> Potomac </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, that the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> denial was part of a continuing coverup. `` I think that the intelligence agencies will justify lying in order to protect what they think is the national interest,'' he said. `` In this case they think it is the national interest to say that they found nothing, in order not to let the Soviets know what the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> knows, and whether we can detect it.'' Because of <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> penetrations, said <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> covert activities in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> have been `` totally closed down.'' `` This wiped them out,'' said <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON>, a former newspaper reporter. He said that intelligence sources, whom he declined to identify by name, told him that as many as 25 Soviets were executed in the mid-1980s on charges of spying. Ten of them were in fact <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> agents, <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON> said. Possible KGB penetration of the embassy has been a matter of public discussion for two years. One Marine guard at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> told American investigators in 1987 that he had allowed Soviet agents into secure parts of the building at night, but he later recanted the confession. <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON> argues in his book that the Marine, Cpl. <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Bracey </PERSON>, was telling the truth the first time. <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> had gotten into the embassy several years earlier, apparently by sexually compromising Marine guards using Soviet women. The <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> was denying that Soviet listening devices had been found, said <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON>, in part out of `` embarrassment. They would claim that they did n't want the Soviets to find out what they learned about the bugs.'' He noted that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence officials still decline to show pictures of bugging devices reported to have been found in a new American embassy in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, although the plans to occupy the facility have been suspended because of the bugging. In the book, <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON> wrote: `` In August 1987, the <ORGANIZATION> NSA </ORGANIZATION> made a startling discovery. The power line to the CPU in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> had been replaced. The discovery meant the <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> could have diverted signals from cipher machines within the CPU to the outside. `` Next the <ORGANIZATION> NSA </ORGANIZATION> found that eight-by-14-inch circuit boards, along with chips the size of quarters, had been replaced in the printers. The new components appered to be diverting uncoded signals from the ` red -LRB- uncoded -RRB- side' of the communications circuits to the power line, bypassing electronic filters that were supposed to trap any signals inside. In September 1987, <ORGANIZATION> NSA </ORGANIZATION> found similar sinister devices in the CPU from <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890216-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-89 0219EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Burnley     02-16 0586</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Burnley,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>DOT Considering Petition To Overturn Burnley On Eastern</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former Transportation Secretary <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Burnley </PERSON> says an ethics official let him rule in a case involving <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION> even though he was negotiating at the time for jobs with law firms linked to the company. The issue surfaced Wednesday when the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Line </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pilots </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> asked the department to reject <ORGANIZATION> Burnley </ORGANIZATION>'s decision in December not to investigate <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION>' operations. The union claimed a conflict of interest. The department said it is considering the request from the pilots' union. <LOCATION> Burnley </LOCATION> on Wednesday called the pilots' accusations `` both malicious and without foundation.'' <PERSON> Burnley </PERSON> made his response in a statement released by the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> law firm of <ORGANIZATION> Shaw </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pittman </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Potts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Trowbridge </PERSON> which he is joining March 1. In the statement, <ORGANIZATION> Burnley </ORGANIZATION> said he rejected the pilots' request last year to investigate Eastern only after the department's chief ethical officer `` assured me in writing that I was not disqualified from participating in the matter.'' A Dec. 13 <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> memorandum from ethics officer <PERSON> Rosalind </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Knapp </PERSON> to <LOCATION> Burnley </LOCATION> regarding the airline pilots' request says, `` You are not disqualified from particiapting in this matter. `` I made each decision based on my best judgment of the merits of each matter as set out in the record before me,'' <ORGANIZATION> Burnley </ORGANIZATION> said. He said no one at <ORGANIZATION> Shaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pittman </ORGANIZATION> or any other firm he was considering communicated with him about the pilots' petition and no one at the firms represented `` any of the parties in the proceedings.'' Documents show that <LOCATION> Burnley </LOCATION> last Nov. 22 disqualified himself from matters involving <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Pittman </PERSON> and the firm of <ORGANIZATION> Patton </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boggs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Blow, whose partner <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Hale </PERSON> <PERSON> Boggs </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> sits on <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s board. The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday quoted <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Pittman </PERSON> partner <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Potts </PERSON> as saying the firm gave <ORGANIZATION> Burnley </ORGANIZATION> a list of cases it was handling for <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION>, both owned by <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION>, but <PERSON> Potts </PERSON> said the firm was not handling the matter involving the pilots. <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Hal </PERSON> <PERSON> Paris </PERSON> said the department would consider the pilots' petition to overturn <ORGANIZATION> Burnley </ORGANIZATION>'s action, but <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> said he did not know when a decision would be made. A department statement said the petition for reconsideration would be considered `` in the normal course.'' It noted that the law firm <ORGANIZATION> Burnley </ORGANIZATION> is joining had requested and was being provided documents related to the matter. The pilots asked the department to reconsider <ORGANIZATION> Burnley </ORGANIZATION>'s refusal to conduct a `` continuing fitness'' investigation of Eastern to see that the airline remains financially viable. <LOCATION> Burnley </LOCATION>, in rejecting the original petition, accused the union of trying to put pressure on Eastern by raising new safety concerns. The pilots' petition for reconsideration said that <ORGANIZATION> Burnley </ORGANIZATION> overrode normal agency procedures in rejecting the petition himself rather than letting it be handled by an assistant secretary. The filing said <ORGANIZATION> Burnley </ORGANIZATION>'s actions `` strongly suggest a lack of complete independence or impartiality and an eye cocked towards subsequent private employment.'' It accused <ORGANIZATION> Burnley </ORGANIZATION> of violating the department's ethics rules, which prohibit officials from engaging in actions that would benefit or would appear to benefit their own financial interests or those of prospective employers. The original pilots union petition accused <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> of threatening <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s financial viability by `` downsizing,'' including the planned sale of <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s lucrative shuttle operations to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> real estate tycoon <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>. That sale has received <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> approval but has not yet been approved by the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890216-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-89 0221EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-JacksonCited     02-16 0148</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jackson Cited,150</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jackson Cited for Lack of Campaign Reports</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> has cited <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and an obscure presidential candidate for failing to file campaign finance reports at the end of the year, a commission spokesman said. A couple of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s Democratic presidential campaign committees filed reports last fall but did not file their final reports for the year, according to <ORGANIZATION> FEC </ORGANIZATION> records. The other candidate, Republican <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON>, did not file reports all year, according to the records. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> aide, said he was unaware of a problem in filing the reports. `` I do n't know anything about it but I'll check on it and try to find out what the facts are,'' he said. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Moxley </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> FEC </ORGANIZATION>, said being cited for failure to file carries no penalty unless the commission decides to impose one.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890216-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-89 0310EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-QuayleFamily     02-16 0384</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quayle Family,380</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quayles Move into VP's Residence</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
