<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890404-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-04-89 2329EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Gorbachev-Cuba 6thLd-Writethru a0789 04-04 0954</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Gorbachev-Cuba, 6th Ld-Writethru, a0789,0978</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Leader Speaks To Cuban Parliament</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS graf after 6th, `The issue...' to UPDATE with Baker
comment. Pick up 7th pvs, `There had...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto XHAV1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL PUTZEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HAVANA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said Tuesday that the superpowers should renounce military intervention in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> and make the region a zone of peace. Addressing the Cuban <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>, he also emphasized that Soviet-style reforms are not a universal remedy for other communist countries, including <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>. `` We do not regard our approaches and solutions as some universal prescription for all,'' he said in what appeared an attempt to minimize the difference between <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>'s orthodox communism and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s new pragmatism. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> opposes the `` export of revolution or counterrevolution,'' referring to both Cuban and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. But he also reaffirmed that the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> will continue supplying weaponry to <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s leftist government as long as the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> continues to arm other Central American countries. The issue remains a major sore point in relations between <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> both said they had not had a chance to review <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s speech But <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said his comment on <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> was `` the same old line they've been pushing.'' There had been speculation that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, in a gesture of friendship toward <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, might announce forgiveness of part or all of <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>'s debt to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. But he barely mentioned the subject, merely restating his position that the industrialized nations of the world should try to help ease the burden of debtor nations in the developing world. Cuban President <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>, in a 50-minute introduction that was only three minutes shorter than his guest's address, lambasted the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in a characteristic diatribe. He blamed his longtime adversary for regional conflicts throughout the world and for `` pulling the Third World's leg'' by proposing unworkable solutions to the critical problem of Third World debt. Waving his arms and jabbing his fingers, the 62-year-old <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> rejected suggestions of friction in Soviet-Cuban relations. He said he was in full agreement with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s contention that each communist country must solve the problems of developing socialism in its own way. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, who had been expected to outline Soviet policy toward <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, essentially reiterated his government's longstanding view that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> holds the key to peace in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and must halt its intervention in order to encourage settlement of regional strife. `` We have a real possiblity of guaranteeing peace,'' he said, but all sides must halt military supplies to the region. `` The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> does not seek for itself political, strategic or military advantage in the Western hemisphere,'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said. `` We consider that this hemisphere and all others must not be an arena for <LOCATION> East-West </LOCATION> confrontation.'' In proposing establishment of a `` zone of peace,'' the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> president said his country `` does not have any intention of having in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> naval, air or missile bases or to place there nuclear or other weapons of mass extermination.'' He called on the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and other countries to adopt a similar approach to continue the transformation of <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> into a region of peace, security and stability. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> are principal suppliers of the Sandinista regime in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and leftist guerrillas in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> provides nonmilitary aid to <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s Contra rebels and weaponry to the Salvadoran government, <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> and other nations Soviet sources predicted before <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> left <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> that the Soviet leader would try to persuade <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> to extract <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> from involvement in leftist struggles around the world and concentrate on building the Cuban economy, which after three decades of socialism is still heavily reliant on Soviet aid. `` We are resolutely opposed to any theories and doctrines justifying the export of revolution or counterrevolution, all forms of foreign interference in the affairs of sovereign states,'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said in his speech. He made similar statements after the speech at a news conference, saying that `` power policies have totally discedited themselves.'' Earlier, in an interview with the Soviet news agency <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> suggested that he and <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> are prepared to work for improved East-West relations, indicating some softening in the <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> leader's rigid anti-Americanism. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> a central topic of his talks with <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> on Monday was the `` new thinking'' in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> foreign policy _ an approach that seeks to ease world tensions by reducing military commitments abroad and negotiating settlements of regional disputes that threaten to bring the superpowers into conflict. It is a tenet of <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reform policies at home that the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> must demonstrate to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> it is eager to serve as a cooperative partner in world economic development and dispel the Kremlin's `` enemy image'' of the Cold War era. <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> signed a 25-year accord the Cuban news agency <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Latina </ORGANIZATION> said dashes all speculation about a rift between <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and ratifies their `` traditional relations.'' But despite a show of friendship between he two communist allies, a series of arrests in <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION> on Tuesday underscored the differences between the pragmatic liberalism espoused by <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and the tight control still exercised by <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> 30 years after he led a guerrilla army to victory over a right-wing dictatorship. Police rounded up seven dissidents who were planning a demonstration Tuesday evening in support of <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reforms. Among those detained was <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> <PERSON> Lara </PERSON>, leader of the <ORGANIZATION> Pro-Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, according to government and dissident spokesmen. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON> condemned the arrests, saying they underscore `` the need for ongoing monitoring of the human rights situation in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890404-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-04-89 2335EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TransplantAnniversary     04-04 0543</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Transplant Anniversary,0560</SECOND>
<HEAD>20 Years After Transplant, Cooley Says Ethics, Regulations Hinder
Advances</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF AWALT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOUSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Twenty years after he performed the world's first implant of an artificial heart into a human, Dr. <PERSON> Denton </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooley </PERSON> on Tuesday said further medical advances have been hindered by ethical doubts and regulatory interference. Despite the difficulties, <PERSON> Cooley </PERSON> said on the anniversary of the operation that he expects still greater achievements over the next 20 years. `` The heart is truly a remarkable organ and developing a perfect substitute is going to be a challenge not only for this generation, but for generations of researchers to come,'' <PERSON> Cooley </PERSON> said. `` Research institutions and investigators throughout the world are challenged by this project, and I think that we will see an acceptable, totally implantable permanent device within the next 15 to 20 years.'' It was April 4, 1969, when <PERSON> Cooley </PERSON> and his associates at the <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Heart </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> implanted a totally artificial heart into the chest of <PERSON> Haskell </PERSON> <PERSON> Karp </PERSON>, a 47-year-old printing estimator from <LOCATION> Skokie </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Karp </PERSON> lived for three days on the device and then received a human heart transplant but died a day later when infection and tissue rejection set in <PERSON> Cooley </PERSON> had first attempted a surgical repair of <PERSON> Karp </PERSON>'s heart, but the organ was too badly damaged and it was clear he would not survive, the doctor said. `` This was the first time that we decided we were n't going to pull the plug, but that we were going to give this man that remote chance of survival,'' <PERSON> Cooley </PERSON> said. The first heart transplant had been performed less than two years before. The proven human use of an artificial heart _ which earlier had shown promise in research animals _ elated the surgical team but drew a harsh reaction from some medical professionals and the public. <PERSON> Cooley </PERSON> was censured by the <ORGANIZATION> Harris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> for `` publicity,'' which meant violating the society's guidelines about having a physician's name appear in a newspaper in connection with the name of a patient. `` All the theoretical objections really almost killed the transplant program; that, coupled with the high incidence of tissue rejection, which brought a lot of bad news to the profession,'' <PERSON> Cooley </PERSON> said. Since then, however, the anti-rejection drug cyclosporine came into use and advanced artificial hearts have improved survival until donor hearts can be found. And greater public acceptance has made donor organs more plentiful. However, new obstacles have emerged, including burdensome federal regulations that limit the application of medical research, said Dr. O.H. <PERSON> Frazier </PERSON>, who directs the cardiovascular surgical research lab at the <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Heart </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>. `` I'm not sure today if that first step was n't taken in 1969 how we would take it today,'' <PERSON> Frazier </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Cooley </PERSON> agrees that regulations make research applications more difficult today, but he believes the <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> is not directly to blame. `` I know that the individuals at the -LRB- FDA -RRB- who are responsible for these restrictions are people who are well motivated, but they are responding basically to what the public seems to want,'' <PERSON> Cooley </PERSON> said. `` I do n't believe we ought to live in a completely unregulated society, but I think that our restrictions should be liberal enough that progress can be made.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890404-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-04-89 0027EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r e PM-APonTV-Feinstein 1stLd-Writethru b0280 04-04 0771</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP on TV-Feinstein, 1st Ld-Writethru, b0280,0783</SECOND>
<HEAD>Alan Feinstein Stars In Eighth Television Series</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Subs grafs 4-5, ``Feinstein started ... was coming,'' to correct
character's role in show and spelling of Tuscany. Moved originally in advance
for Tuesday PMs as b0280.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With LaserPhoto</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY BUCK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Feinstein </PERSON> is a seasoned veteran of the performing arts who remembers his acting debut as anything but auspicious. `` I grew up in <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, and started acting as a senior in high school,'' he recalls. `` The very first play I did I blew my lines. I heard my cue, walked on stage and repeated the cue. I could n't remember my line. `` I muddled around and then got off stage as fast as I could. It did n't deter me from pursuing this wonderfully capricious business.'' <PERSON> Feinstein </PERSON> started work on <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' night-time soap opera `` Falcon Crest,'' his eighth television series, in December. He plays <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinclair </PERSON>, a wealthy businessman who becomes involved in tricky dealings with <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Channing </PERSON> -LRB- <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Selby </PERSON> -RRB- and <PERSON> Pilar </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> -LRB- <PERSON> Kristian </PERSON> <PERSON> Alfonso </PERSON> -RRB-. `` He -LRB- <PERSON> Sinclair </PERSON> -RRB- is teaming up with <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Wyman </PERSON> to stop her son -LRB- <PERSON> Selby </PERSON> -RRB- from industrializing the <LOCATION> Tuscany </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> and taking over the winery,'' he said. `` They were talking abut my character before I even showed up. After I was cast I watched the show to see what they were saying about <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON>. They knew I was coming even before I knew I was coming.'' <PERSON> Feinstein </PERSON> had only a two-day rest before starting on `` Falcon Crest'' after completing seven months on the <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> daytime soap `` General Hospital'' as the `` mysterious stranger'' in <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Charles </LOCATION>. `` I was a wealthy developer who ran for the state assembly on ` General Hospital,''' he said. `` I was married but running around with <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Zeman </PERSON>. I was n't a heavy, just a guy in an unhappy marriage. I fell for <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON>, but after I won the election I went off to <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION> and tried to settle with my wife.'' His first professional role was as a football player in an episode of `` Naked City,'' which he got because of his prowess as a college basketball and track and field performer. He'd been lifting weights and looked the part. `` I was only in it for a second,'' he said. `` <PERSON> Sandy </PERSON> <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Aldo </PERSON> <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> were the stars of the episode. I kept a photo copy of the check for $ 24 that I received.'' His first regular role was the soap opera `` Love of Life,'' which he starred on for 2 -LCB- years. Next, he spent six years on `` Edge of Night.'' At the same time, he starred in a Broadway revival of `` A Streetcar Named Desire.'' He was also on `` Search for Tomorrow,'' but only for a very brief time. Next, he was <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Warden </PERSON>'s detective partner in `` Jigsaw <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' then had a role in `` Looking for Mr. <PERSON> Goodbar </PERSON>.'' His other series were `` The Runaways,'' `` Family Tree'' and `` Berrenger's.'' <PERSON> Feinstein </PERSON> also starred in numerous other movies. He was a Zealot warrior in the miniseries `` <LOCATION> Masada </LOCATION>.'' He was a gay football player in `` Alexander: The Other Side of Dawn.'' He was an ex-con in PBS' `` Visions. He's never acted in a Western, though he did play <PERSON> Wild </PERSON> <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Hickock </PERSON> on stage in `` Fathers and Sons.'' `` As a kid I never watched the cartoons,'' he said. `` I watched Lash LaRue, ` Range Rider,' Crash <PERSON> Corrigan </PERSON> and ` Rough Riders.' I did a lot of daydreaming and play-acting. At the age of 7 my ambition was to be a cowboy in the movies.'' <PERSON> Feinstein </PERSON>, who spends his off hours painting, has some of his work on display at a local gallery. `` I paint in acrylics, and my work tends to look like a collage,'' he said. `` I paint objects that tend to be three-dimensional.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Elsewhere in television: TV TO BIG SCREEN _ <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Danson </PERSON> will star as burned-out basketball superstar `` Ghost'' <PERSON> Galvin </PERSON> in the movie `` Ghost.'' <PERSON> Danson </PERSON>, who stars as a burned-out baseball player in <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Cheers,'' is currently starring in the feature film `` Cousins.'' <PERSON> Danson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Fauci </PERSON> acquired the film rights to `` Ghost,'' the first novel of <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Barsocchini </PERSON>. <PERSON> Barsocchini </PERSON> was the ghost-writer for <PERSON> Merv </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON>'s autobiography and is currently producing the movie `` The Fortune Teller.'' He won two Emmys in his seven years as producer of `` The <PERSON> Merv </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> Show.'' ... PARTNERS _ <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> and <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Silverman </PERSON> have formed the <ORGANIZATION> Pierce-Silverman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> to create programs for television and home video. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> is a former president of <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Silverman </PERSON> was formerly head of programming at <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> and was president of <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Each will also keep running separate production companies.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890404-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-04-89 0059EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-NCAA-Newspage     04-04 0129</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-NCAA-Newspage,0133</SECOND>
<HEAD>Michigan Wins College Basketball's National Championship</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Rumeal </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> made two free throws with three seconds left in overtime to give <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> its first national championship in collegiate basketball with an 80-79 victory over Seton Hall Monday night. The championship game in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Collegiate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Athletic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> tournament was the fifth to go into overtime and the first since <LOCATION> Loyola </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, beat <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> 60-58 in 1963. <PERSON> Glen </PERSON> <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> carried the <ORGANIZATION> Wolverines </ORGANIZATION> to the title with 31 points in the final, giving him an <ORGANIZATION> NCAA </ORGANIZATION> tournament record 184, breaking the 24-year-old mark of 177 set by <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Princeton </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>'s coach, <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON>, took over the team just two days before the <ORGANIZATION> NCAA </ORGANIZATION> tournament began and coached them through six victories to the title.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890404-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-04-89 0039EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SpillYellowstoneTeam     04-04 0594</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Spill Yellowstone Team,0607</SECOND>
<HEAD>Yellowstone Fires' Troubleshooters Deployed At Oil Spill</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>With PM-Tanker Spill, Bjt ^By TAD BARTIMUS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEWARD, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The disaster expert whose crew saved two <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> towns from last summer's <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> firestorms now is plotting to defend another national park against the largest oil spill in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> history. `` Our mission is to find out where the marine wildlife and sea birds are today, then set priorities so the oil that kills them can try to be contained,'' said <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Liebersbach </PERSON>, a veteran <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> troubleshooter whose title is incident commander. <PERSON> Liebersbach </PERSON>'s team has found similarities here to <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>. `` In <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> we put firefighters on the ground. Here we're providing logistics for Ph.D. biologists who we're handling as a very intelligent resource, very delicately If they need a boat we get one, if they need a ham sandwich we make one. What they need we try to provide,'' <PERSON> Liebersbach </PERSON> said. The tanker <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Valdez </ORGANIZATION> hit a reef near <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION> on Good Friday night and bled 10.1 million gallons of crude oil into Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON>. Huge fingers of the slick are now extending westward through <LOCATION> Montague </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strait </LOCATION> toward the 660,501-acre Kenai Fjord National Park. The oil was less than 10 miles offshore from <LOCATION> Seward </LOCATION> on Sunday night, but calm seas and gentle breezes made its future course unpredictable. `` It's possible it could miss everything here,'' said <PERSON> Liebersbach </PERSON>, `` but to ignore it would be totally negligent. Knowing what we do, we have to prepare to mitigate it.'' Created by the <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> National Interest Lands Conservation Act of 1980, the new national park is a necklace of bird rookeries, tidal pools, and whale playgrounds draped along 610 miles of the <LOCATION> Kenai </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION>'s eastern coastline. Located 100 air miles southeast of <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION>, most of the park can be reached only by floatplane or boat. It attracted fewer than 60,000 hardy tourists last year, and is more hospitable to its critters than its visitors. Among the animals who cavort in the midnight sun amid the rugged grandeur of the park's coves and inlets are many endangered Humpback and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> gray whales, a few endangered Fin whales, and otters, sea lions, and seals. <PERSON> Liebersbach </PERSON> is in charge of a 40-member-and-growing team of pilots, support personnel, and environmental experts drawn from <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> agencies, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION>, and <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Fish and <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. Although <PERSON> Liebersbach </PERSON>'s home is Fairbanks, he was at a meeting of the government's 18 Class 1 disaster incident commanders in <PERSON> Reno </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>, when his permanent eight-man core unit was activated at the request of the park service. `` The last time we were together was <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>, on the Storm Creek fire,'' said <PERSON> Liebersbach </PERSON>. `` We did n't expect to see each other again until summer.'' Last August and September, he was boss to several thousand civilian and military firefighters who faced down 200-foot walls of flame threatening to incinerate Silver Gate and <LOCATION> Cooke </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Mont </PERSON>. The two towns were saved but <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>'s fires charred nearly one million acres. <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, the team's planning chief, said the spill `` woke us all up and got us ready for the year. It looks like it could be a long one.'' The team set up shop in a small house near park headquarters in <LOCATION> Seward </LOCATION>. Up went the topographical maps. In came the photocopy machine, typewriters, and coffeemaker. Seven phone lines now ring constantly from dawn until midnight. `` An oil slick is like a fire line, it just keeps moving,'' said <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890404-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-04-89 0048EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-AmazonRainForest     04-04 0254</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Amazon Rain Forest,0258</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ecology Group Warns Sarney He Responsible for Amazon</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A group of leading Latin American writers, artists and scholars has told President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> he will bear `` historical responsibility'' for continued destruction of the <LOCATION> Amazon </LOCATION> rain forest. `` We believe that the historical responsibility for destroying the <LOCATION> Amazon </LOCATION> jungle is very great, and future generations of Latin Americans will not forgive it if everything possible is not done to avoid it,'' the Group of 100 warned un a letter, which was released Monday. <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON> has rejected international criticism of the deforestation of the <LOCATION> Amazon </LOCATION> basin as foreign interference in <LOCATION> Brazilian </LOCATION> affairs. The Group of 100 declared that `` to invoke national sovereignty to justify crimes against nature _ like those being committed against one of the richest and most complex ecosystems on <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> _ appears puerile and dishonest to us.'' The group condemned `` criminal burning that razes millions of acres of tropical forests, the clearing of the jungle for colonization and transnational agriculture'' and `` the extermination of ethnic groups whose members are hunted down by the ` modernizers' of agriculture to take over their lands.'' The letter, signed by 28 leading Latin American writers and artists, was delivered to the Brazilian Embassy by group president and poet <PERSON> Homer </PERSON> <PERSON> Aridjis </PERSON>. Among its signatories are <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuentes </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Gabriel </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> <PERSON> Marquez </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Onetti </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Isabel </PERSON> <PERSON> Allende </PERSON>, widow of the slain Chilean President <PERSON> Salvador </PERSON> <PERSON> Allende </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Vargas </PERSON> <PERSON> Llosa </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Ernesto </PERSON> <PERSON> Sabato </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890404-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-04-89 0049EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Cuba-Museum     04-04 0604</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cuba-Museum,0619</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cuban Security Museum Displays Relics Of War With CIA</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL PUTZEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HAVANA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Museum of State Security displays the scorched tail of a small plane, plastic explosives, a tattered 2506 Brigade armband, assault rifles, a radio transmitter and a battered water can with a label in English. The artifacts are part of what <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> presents as its 30-year struggle with the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> and dissident Cubans accused of trying to kill or overthrow President <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>. The museum, which opened this weekend, occupies a refurbished mansion in a once-wealthy neighborhood whose villas now house embassies or government offices. In a small plaza visible from the street, a power boat with a black hull, sea blue decks and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> markings looks at first glance like a private plaything in a country where such luxuries are rare. Closer examination reveals that the boat, driven by powerful Mercury engines, has heavy machine guns mounted fore and aft. <PERSON> Octavio </PERSON> <PERSON> Cruz </PERSON>, the clean-cut, graying guide at the museum, said the vessel made coastal raids until it was captured by agents of the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>'s special police force. Maps inside the museum are dotted with sites of `` imperialist aggression,'' a battle plan for the U.S.-sponsored Bay of Pigs debacle in 1961. There are a rogue's gallery of people accused of trying to kill <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> and relics of what is portrayed as a secret war on the regime he established 30 years ago. At the center of an upstairs room, in its own sealed plexiglas case, is a three-volume set of the yellow-bound proceedings of a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> investigation of 1975. The committee investigation disclosed bungled <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> attempts on <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>'s life _ once with an exploding cigar, for instance, and another time with poison powder that supposedly was scattered on the leader's clothing but did no harm. Asked why the evidence was not displayed, <PERSON> Cruz </PERSON> first said, `` There have been so many attempts they could n't all be put in the museum.'' Later, he said he was n't sure the evidence still existed. He led the visitors into the Hall of Martyrs, lined with portraits of 88 agents of State Security described as having died fighting the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> exiles, counterrevolutionaries or other enemies. A brass plaque beneath each portrait gave the details. <PERSON> Cruz </PERSON> said the museum's purpose `` is to bring to the people a cultural identity and to transmit a story for all visitors fundamentally about a fight and the atrocities carried out against us, and the aggressions of the last century.'' Asked why a meseum opened now to depict events of the 1960s, <PERSON> Cruz </PERSON> said: `` The opportunity is now'' and, in the past, `` the revolution had other priorities.'' In first room of the museum are a giant photo of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> landing at <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> in 1898, during the Spanish-American War, and a huge copy of a letter written in 1895 by <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Marti </PERSON>, patron saint of Cuban independence. <PERSON> Marti </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would `` continue to use <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> as a base to extend its power into the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION>.'' The only other exhibit in that room is an enlargement of a letter <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> wrote in 1958, from a camp in the hills, telling his longtime friend and secretary <PERSON> Celia </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanchez </PERSON>: `` They're firing rockets at us in the mountains. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> was killed, and the Americans will pay dearly for this.'' He also wrote, just a year before gaining power: `` It's becoming clear to me that this war will go on much longer. It will have to go on against the Americans.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890404-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-04-89 0004EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TankerSpill 4thLd-Writethru a0404 04-04 1183</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tanker Spill, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0404,1213</SECOND>
<HEAD>Exxon Apologizes; Captain Still At Large; Cleanup So Far Futile</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 6th graf to restore dropped word, clarify</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto VDX2, VDX4</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID FOSTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VALDEZ, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> apologized and promised compensation for causing the nation's biggest oil spill, which on Monday forced <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> to shut down its $ 12 million herring fishery in Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON> for the season. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> state police, meanwhile, said they expected the surrender Tuesday of <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON>, the former captain of the tanker that spilled 10.1 million gallons of North Slope crude after it crashed into <LOCATION> Bligh </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Reef </LOCATION> on March 24. `` We have reason to believe he'll present himself'' at the state police barracks in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Farmingdale </LOCATION>, said state police spokesman Trooper <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubio </PERSON> in a telephone interview Monday evening. An arrest warrant has been issued in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> for <LOCATION> Hazelwood </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Huntington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, resident is accused of misdemeanor charges of operating a ship while under the influence of alcohol, reckless endangerment and negligent discharge of oil. The oil slick has now grown larger than <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. The state Fish and Game Department announced Monday that the Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON> herring fishery, which generates $ 12 million in annual revenues, will not open this year. Officials have previously closed the sound's sablefish and shrimp fisheries. More than half the spawning habitat used by Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON> herring has been fouled, said <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Haanpaa </PERSON>, a fisheries biologist with the department. That bodes ill for both the fish and the fishermen, who tend to catch herring near their spawning ground. Altogether, the Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON> fishing industry is worth more than $ 150 million annually. In full-page advertisements placed in newspapers around the country Monday, <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rawl </PERSON> said, `` I want to tell you how sorry I am that this accident took place.'' <PERSON> Rawl </PERSON>'s statement also appeared to respond to harsh criticism from Alaskan officials, fishermen and environmentalists who accuse <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> of reacting slowly and inadequately to the spill. `` We believe that <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> has moved swiftly and competently to minimize the effect this oil will have on the environment, fish and other wildlife,'' he said. <PERSON> Rawl </PERSON> also offered to `` meet our obligations to all those who have suffered damage from the spill.'' Four class action lawsuits already have been filed against <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> at the outset of what could be years of litigation over the accident. In an interview from the company's headquarters in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> said he hopes the `` emotional type of atmosphere'' generated by the spill does not prompt <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to reject the oil industry's request to drill in protected wildlife areas. However, that could be precisely the outcome of the spill, <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Lujan </PERSON> suggested in a speech to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ocean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` If the image of an uncareful and uncaring industry prevails among the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> public, then we can kiss goodbye the domestic oil and gas development in -LRB- the <ORGANIZATION> Arctic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Refuge </ORGANIZATION> -RRB-, offshore and in the public lands,'' <PERSON> Lujan </PERSON> said. More than 1,000 seabirds and at least 20 sea otters caught in the oil have died, some found covered with asphalt-hard oil. Officials said the death toll is probably much higher, but they have had time to survey only a slice of the sound's 2,500 miles of coastline. Department of Fish and Game spokesman <PERSON> Jon </PERSON> <PERSON> Lyman </PERSON> said Monday a deer found dead on <LOCATION> Naked </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> about 25 miles southwest of the tanker had apparently eaten contaminated food, an indication of how rapidly the spill was spreading. `` That's bad news. That's the top of the food chain,'' <PERSON> Lyman </PERSON> said. On nearby <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, hundreds of birds lay along the beach, as black and lifeless as the oil-smeared rocks around them. Sheltered coves and rocky points, usually clamoring with the sound of gulls and other shorebirds, were silent. `` Every day, it's getting a little worse,'' otter rescue specialist <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Donohoe </PERSON> said as he squatted by a dead sea duck. `` You clean a beach up, the tide changes, and the oil comes right back.'' Oil is so thick that walking on once postcard-perfect beaches is treacherous, and workers wear hardhats to protect against injuries from frequent tumbles on rocks. Oil sprayed by waves splatters rocks and driftwood logs high above the tideline. Beaches smell like gas station garages. In <LOCATION> Sawmill </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, 11 miles west of <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION>, fishermen said Monday they battling to keep oil away from 2 million salmon at a hatchery. A sheen of oil has worked its way inside a plastic boom stretched across the bay, they said. <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> officials have conceded that beach cleanup efforts so far have been futile. But the company said it began a new assault with more effective gear, more workers and a floating command post. <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shipping </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. President <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Iarossi </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> planned to flush beaches by pumping seawater over them, then collect oil from the water with skimmers `` We intend not to leave until the job is done,'' <PERSON> Iarossi </PERSON> said. `` We intend to leave <LOCATION> Prince </LOCATION> <LOCATION> William </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sound </LOCATION> close to what it was before the tragedy.'' State officials have blasted <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>'s effort to scrub beaches as dismal and ineffective. Less than 4 percent of the thick crude has been recovered. The spill has fouled more than 800 miles of shoreline in Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON>, and the amount grows each day. <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON>, 42, was fired by <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> last week. The skipper admitted drinking before boarding the Exxon Valdez, according to court documents. Blood and urine samples taken nine hours after the accident indicated he was drunk. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Weeks </PERSON>, director of criminal prosecution for the state of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, said authorities in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> have had communication with a lawyer in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> representing <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON>. The tanker accident forced reductions in the flow of oil through the Alaskan pipeline, which carries nearly one-quarter of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' domestic supply of crude oil. <ORGANIZATION> Alyeska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pipeline </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> said the flow was increased Sunday evening with word from the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> that tanker traffic would soon be allowed to return to normal. However, the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> decided Monday to reinstate daytime-only restrictions on oil tanker traffic in <LOCATION> Prince </LOCATION> <LOCATION> William </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sound </LOCATION> after state officials raised concerns, spokesman <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Meidt </PERSON> said. Night traffic was allowed Sunday for the first time since the <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Valdez </ORGANIZATION>, one of the two largest tankers in <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> fleet, ran aground. But after a Monday meeting, the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> decided to again limit traffic until all agencies are satisfied that <ORGANIZATION> Alyeska </ORGANIZATION>, the operator of the <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION> terminal, has the equipment to handle another spill, <PERSON> Meidt </PERSON> said. `` If something were to happen, let's make sure we have enough gear there to respond,'' he said. The pipeline usually carries 2 million barrels of crude a day. That had been reduced to 800,000 barrels a day, causing shortages at <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> refineries and sending oil prices higher. By Monday morning, the pipeline flow had been increased to 1.3 million barrels a day, spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Ratterman </PERSON> said. Pipeline company officials said they did n't expect the latest restrictions in tanker traffic to force another cutback in flow.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890404-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-04-89 0100EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-CapsizedBarge     04-04 0314</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Capsized Barge,0323</SECOND>
<HEAD>Barge Capsizes on Ohio River</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARKERSBURG, W.Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A barge carrying 160,000 gallons of lye capsized on the <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> on Monday, and authorities were trying to salvage the craft without a major spill, state and federal officials said. A spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> said small amounts of a 50 percent lye solution, also known as sodium hydroxide or caustic soda, could be seeping through vents in the barge. `` Common sense tells us, you assume there's some seepage,'' said Lt. Commander <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Adkins </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Huntington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> `` But none has been detected. Because of its high alkalinity, lye is considered a hazardous chemical that could endanger aquatic life and drinking water, officials said. The barge, owned by <ORGANIZATION> PPG </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, was one of 15 being transported by a tugboat around a sharp bend in the <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> at <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bottom </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Murraysville </PERSON>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va </LOCATION> It broke away from the other vessels and drifted close to the rocky shore before running aground between <LOCATION> Parkersburg </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ravenswood </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Adkins </PERSON> said. The outer shell of the 195-foot barge was punctured by a rock shortly before 9 a.m. Monday, <PERSON> Adkins </PERSON> said. The space between the two hulls flooded and the barge capsized. <ORGANIZATION> Kemron </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratories </ORGANIZATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> Marietta </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, company hired by <ORGANIZATION> PPG </ORGANIZATION> Monday to monitor the incident, did not detect an alkalinity increase in the water surrounding the barge. `` It would almost take a catastrophic release to pose a major threat,'' <PERSON> Adkins </PERSON> said. In high concentrations such as the barge is carrying, lye will burn skin and eyes, <PERSON> Adkins </PERSON> said. Swallowing it can be dangerous, he said. `` Drinking water could be infected, so water intake users downstream have been notified,'' he said. The cleanup and removal of the barge is expected to take several weeks. PPG's salvage expert from <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Charles </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La. </LOCATION>, was to arrive early Tuesday, <PERSON> Adkins </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890404-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-04-89 0136EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-StolenAmbulance     04-04 0218</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Stolen Ambulance,0225</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police: Woman Steals Ambulance; Says She Was Late For Work</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A woman who said she was late for work stole an ambulance and struck another car before she was stopped, according to authorities. `` I could n't believe it,'' said <PERSON> Eduardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Fabregas </PERSON>, who was left by the road Monday with two other paramedics and a patient who had complained of respiratory problems. `` The truck was rolling right away from us,'' <PERSON> Fabregas </PERSON> said, `` I thought it was a joke, I thought it was some other fireman pulling a joke on us, taking it around the corner, or something.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> ambulance was parked with its motor running when 32-year-old <PERSON> Aurelia </PERSON> <PERSON> Small </PERSON> jumped in and took off, police said. She sideswiped a station wagon before she was forced off the road by police about 30 blocks away. Ms. <PERSON> Small </PERSON> then told authorities she had stolen the ambulance because she was in a rush to get to work on time, <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> fire spokeswoman <PERSON> Vicki </PERSON> <PERSON> Wade </PERSON> said. However, records show the woman has no job. Ms. Small was charged with auto theft, preventing and obstructing extinguishment of fires, and driving without a license. The truck sustained an estimated $ 1,000 in damage, fire officials said. Another ambulance was dispatched to take the patient to the hospital.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890404-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-04-89 0123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FloralFactotum Bjt   04-04 0574</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Floral Factotum, Bjt,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>Milton Boston: Generalissimo of the Capital's Flower Beds</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The capital is awash in laughing daffodils, a grand chorus of tulips is about to proclaim the arrival of spring, and <PERSON> Milton </PERSON> <PERSON> Boston </PERSON> already is worrying about planting thousands of geraniums, petunias and marigolds for the summer. <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> is chief floral gardener for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in downtown <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, the generalissimo with rake and hoe who oversees the year-long planting of 170 flower beds from the Capitol to the Kennedy Center. His job might seem staggering to backyard putterers. For a month in late fall, the efficient, unflappable <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> and his crew of eight gardeners were busy planting 186,150 tulips, 108,300 daffodils and 22,000 pansies, all of which bloom in the spring. Those flowers are removed by early May. The soil is tilled, fumigated with weed and pest killers, conditioned with perlite and peat moss and planted with bright, hardy annuals for <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s hot summer months They are weeded and fertilized until they die in the first frost. They are replaced by about 3,000 crysanthemums. Then the beds are cleared and the cycle starts again in November. <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, a 26-year <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> veteran, is especially proud of the `` tulip library,'' a broad, looping cluster of 95 small beds of the proud clarions of spring that lies near the <LOCATION> Tidal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Basin </LOCATION> south of the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Monument. This elaborate garden contains 15,000 tulips, most of them imported from <LOCATION> Holland </LOCATION>. Each of the 95 beds containing a different variety, with names as dazzling as their colors _ Queen of Night, Merry Widow, <LOCATION> Apeldoorn </LOCATION>, Oriental Splendor, Smiling Queen, Flaming Parrot, <PERSON> Estella </PERSON> <PERSON> Rijnveld </PERSON>. It's so impressive that it won an admiring tribute from the <ORGANIZATION> Dutch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> says he gets `` great satisfaction'' from his handiwork, which delights more than 23 million tourists who visit <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s national parks and monuments each year `` This is always what I wanted to do,'' said <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, 45, who grew up on his father's farm in eastern <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and migrated to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> after high school. `` All my life I've been used to growing things.'' His annual $ 330,000 budget includes the cost of plants and bulbs purchased wholesale from growers, many from neighboring <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, on the basis of competitive bids and shipped into the capital by truck or van. During plantings, <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>'s crew begins work at 6 a.m. and can leave a flower bed blazing with color before the morning rush hour is over. He says he could n't meet his grueling timetable for the passing seasons without his eight <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> helpers. `` They really work hard and do a good job,'' he said. `` They're all gardeners, and they know what they're doing They can plant 20,000 bulbs in one day.'' In a city beset by violent crimes, <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> is pleased that his flowers are almost never stolen, except by an occasional panhandler intent on selling them for spare change. `` I guess people enjoy them so, they do n't take them,'' he said. `` About the only problem is when people stand in the beds to pose for pictures and mash the flowers down.'' <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> says he once had `` the best-looking yard in the neighborhood'' in suburban <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Heights </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, where he lives with his wife and two children, `` but in this job, I do n't have the time any more to take care of it.'' His loss is <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s gain.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890404-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-04-89 0124EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Flight103 Bjt   04-04 0660</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Flight 103, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Government Steps not Enough, say Flight 103 Victims' Relatives</HEAD>
<HEAD>Laserphotos WX7 and WX8</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government says it will force <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> airlines to take stricter anti-terrorism measures, but people who lost loved ones in the bombing of <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> Flight 103 say the actions are n't strong enough. On the 103rd day after the bombing, the <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> announced orders requiring devices to detect plastic explosives and stricter compliance with aviation security warnings, after Flight 103 relatives met with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The White House meeting on Monday, which was scheduled for 20 minutes but lasted an hour, began a day of emotion-filled activities at nearby <LOCATION> Lafayette </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> church by scores of relatives and friends of the 270 people killed in the Dec. 21 explosion of the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747 over <LOCATION> Lockerbie </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>. The relatives called for a full-scale congressional investigation `` to determine what and where the breakdowns were'' that led to the `` preventable massacre at 31,000 feet.'' <PERSON> Bert </PERSON> <PERSON> Ammerman </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Demarest </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, spokesman for the relatives, said action announced by <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> was `` a positive step forward. We applaud the secretary, -LRB- but -RRB- it's not enough. <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> was in the meeting with the relatives and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <PERSON> Ammerman </PERSON> said all checked and carried baggage should be hand-searched until devices are installed that can detect plastic explosives such as the one believed to have blown up Flight 103 as it was headed from <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. The relatives also proposed better training and pay for airport inspectors and public disclosure of terrorist threats. `` Our loved ones were not given the freedom to make a rational decision regarding their fate based on all the available facts,'' <PERSON> Ammerman </PERSON> said. `` We realize that we will never again be able to laugh, cry or talk with our loved ones,'' he told several hundred people in the park. `` But we are determined to do everything in our power to prevent this senseless and preventable tragedy from occurring again.'' <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON>, at a news conference, outlined new orders affecting <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> airlines, including required installation of plastic explosive-detection systems, such as thermal neutron analysis devices, at high-risk airport throughout the world `` at the earliest feasible date.'' The government already has ordered six of the nearly $ 1 million machines for installation at various airports before the end of the year, but <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> gave no timetable for carrying out the new order, which would involve 100 or more airports. He said it will require some negotiations with foreign governments. A <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> official who spoke on condition of anonymity said it could take years for full compliance with the order. Other steps ordered by <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> include mandatory airline acknowledgement and compliance with security bulletins that warn of possible threats against aviation, an increase in <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> personnel assigned to key <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and foreign airports and upgrading of airport X-ray equipment. <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON>, however, said a public warning system when there are security threats, saying it would cripple intelligence efforts to combat terrorists. `` We must balance the needs of the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people and the industry to know with the need to gather meaningful, significant, relevant information,'' <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> said. He said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told relatives he would look into the possibility of a unified congressional investigation into the explosion. But <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> said he would recommend against. He said government response has been adequate and the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> Yard are capable of solving the crime. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, which represents major <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> airlines, said it supported <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON>'s initiatives, but spokesman <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Neale </PERSON> said the airlines believe the government, not the airlines, should pay for new detection equipment from the growing Aviation Trust Fund. <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> estimated fares might increase from 20 cents to a dollar per ticket but said the requirements would not cause serious delays. The association said any increased security measures should also apply to foreign airlines which carry about half of the Americans traveling abroad.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890404-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-04-89 0210EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     04-04 0883</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,880</SECOND>
<HEAD>Land Values in Midwest Were Stable Despite Ravages of Drought</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> economist says federal emergency aid `` probably helped stabilize land values in the Midwest'' last year after drought ravaged crops across the region. <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON> of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said that surveys by the <ORGANIZATION> Farm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Credit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paul </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, indicate that land prices did not decline in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> in June through November last year. Other surveys indicate that farmland prices rose in the Corn Belt in 1988, he said. Real estate is the main source of loan collateral for farmers. `` While drought assistance has helped stabilize the agricultural economy, the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> estimates that 10,000 to 15,000 commercial farms faced loan repayment problems due to crop losses,'' <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON> said. `` These stressed farmers represent 1.5 percent to 2.5 percent of all commercial farms.'' The Disaster Assistance Act of 1988 was signed into law last Aug. 11 as the scorching summer drought was still at its peak. The law provided up to $ 3.9 billion in federal aid and other measures to help farmers recover. <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON>, writing in the April issue of Agricultural Outlook magazine, said that federal disaster assistance may turn out to be less than foreseen last fall `` because crop losses were smaller than expected.'' `` Also, qualification for drought assistance was based on the whole-farm average yield for each crop, rather than on a field-by-field basis,'' he said. `` The averaging-up of yields, where good fields offset poorer fields, excluded some farmers from qualifying in areas with scattered rainfall.'' Even so, <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON> added, the combination of drought assistance and federal subsidized crop insurance `` has permitted thousands of farmers in hard-hit states to survive last year's bad weather with less financial suffering than had been anticipated.'' <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON> said a full assessment of federal drought aid and insurance benefits can not be completed until all payments and indemnities have been disbursed. But preliminary figures show those had `` substantial stabilizing effects'' in the hardest-hit drought areas. But on Capitol Hill there have been grumblings that <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> has mishandled 1988 relief and has ignored drought conditions now prevailing in parts of the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION>, notably in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> and parts of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Department officials testified that more than 558,000 producers had received disaster payments and emergency feed assistance amounting to more than $ 2.7 billion nationally. In his report, <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON> said that as of early February, more than $ 2 billion in drought payments and almost $ 1 billion in federal crop insurance benefits had been paid to farmers in the top eight states. Farmers in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Dakotas </LOCATION> _ where more than 80 percent of the commercial farms were in drought-stricken counties _ have received nearly a third of the drought payments made so far. Benefits paid to the eight states as of early February, in millions of dollars, included drought aid in the first column, federal crop insurance in the second, and the total in the third:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Ill. 207 97 304 <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> 168 128 296 Minn. 242 60 302 Mont. 149 95 244 N.D. 332 187 519 S.D. 148 49 197 <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> 90 28 118 Wis. 120 7 127
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 American ketchup makers and other tomato processors will have a Japanese competitor bidding for farmers' crops, says an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> report The Kogome Co.. <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s largest tomato processing company, announced it will open a $ 20 million plant next year in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Banos </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, to manufacture tomato products and fruit juice beverages `` Most, if not all, of the manufactured products likely will be exported to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> to take advantage of future market openings for tomato and fruit drink products achieved under a recent U.S.-Japan agreement,'' the department's <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said. The agreement gives <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> exporters of 11 product categories, including processed tomato products and fruit juices, greater sale opportunities in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bryand </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wadsworth </PERSON>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agricultural counselor in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, said the plant will produce institutional-size containers tomato ketchup from tomato paste bought from local manufacturers. In addition, he said, the plant will produce retail-size `` fruit-juice added'' drinks such as orange and apple in both carbonated and non-carbonated form.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dry bean situation has `` completely reversed'' itself from a year ago because of higher prices prompted by the 1988 drought. By January, the average farm price of dry edible beans was $ 29.60 per hundredweight, up from $ 13.40 a year earlier. Price increases were the greatest for beans hit hardest by the drought. For example, grower prices for navy beans in the week of Jan. 24 averaged $ 32 per hundredweight, compared with around $ 10 in January 1988, the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said. Total <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> output of dry beans dropped 26 percent to 19.2 million hundredweight last year, the agency reported. `` The sharpest decreases in production were for red kidney, pintos and navies, the beans grown in states with less irrigation,'' the report said. Another price factor is an improved outlook for bean exports because of poor harvests in several major importing countries, including <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. `` Domestic demand for beans could also improve this year because of recent media attention and industry promotional efforts,'' the report said. Beans are a nutritious food item and are noted for their fiber content.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890404-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-04-89 0209EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ComputerVirus     04-04 0498</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Computer Virus,0510</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cornell Says Ethics, Not Security, The Key to Preventing Computer
Worms</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM KATES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ITHACA, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ethics, not increased security, are the best defense against computer `` worms'' like the one unleashed last fall by a <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> graduate student, a school official said. A special university commission reported Monday that <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> acted alone and with `` reckless disregard'' on Nov. 2 when he launched a debilitating program into the Internet network, causing thousands of computers around the country to clog and overload. The commission concluded that <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> did not intend for the worm to destroy data or files, but that he did want it to spread widely. It said the program was not technically a `` virus'' _ a program that inserts itself into a host program to propagate _ but was a `` worm,'' an independent program that replicates itself once placed in a computer system. Release of the worm was not a `` heroic event that pointed up the weaknesses of operating systems,'' contrary to <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>' claim, the commission wrote. The panel also denied that <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> was a genius for creating the worm. It said although the worm was technically sophisticated, it could have been created by many students. In fact, <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>' `` juvenile act'' did little to provide insights into the already well-known security flaws of the Internet system, a national research network used by universities, industry and government, said <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION>'s vice president of technologies. <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> Provost <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Barker </PERSON> said the incident's greatest impact was the breach of trust it had caused among researchers who use the network However, both cautioned that employing drastic security steps was not a solution to prevent similar incidents. `` Violations of such a trust can not be condoned,'' said <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON>. `` A community of scholars should n't have to build sky-high walls in order to protect a reasonable expectation of privacy _ particularly when such walls would impede the free flow of information and ideas.'' <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> added that it's unlikely any security steps could guarantee an impenetrable system `` in a community of individuals possessed of all the knowledge and skills required to scale the highest barriers.'' Instead, the <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> officials stressed the need for improved awareness of computer ethics, said <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON>. `` I do n't think one can ever feel confident by putting bigger and tighter locks on the door,'' said <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON>. `` That's why it's important to stress ethical considerations. <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>, who is on a leave of absence from school, declined to be interviewed by the commission, which was left to speculate as to the reasons he created the `` worm.'' The panel made no recommendation about disciplinary action against the first-year graduate student in <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION>'s doctoral computer program. <PERSON> Barker </PERSON> said <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>' case would be reviewed by a panel of graduate students and faculty that could permanently bar him from the university. <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>, 23, of <ORGANIZATION> Arnold </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, remains under investigation by a federal grand jury in <LOCATION> Syracuse </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890404-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-04-89 0210EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Opera     04-04 0384</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Opera,0393</SECOND>
<HEAD>Billy Budd Revived at Met</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE SILVERMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The expanding shipboard set that dominates <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Britten </PERSON>'s `` <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Budd </PERSON>'' at the Metropolitan Opera is so spectacular that the work would almost be worth reviving just for the chance to see it in action. Luckily, there was also quite a bit of a musical nature to hold the interest Monday night when the company presented the <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Dexter </PERSON> production for the first time in several seasons. <PERSON> Herman </PERSON> <PERSON> Melville </PERSON>'s classic tale revolves around three sharply drawn characters who inspired some of <PERSON> Britten </PERSON>'s most memorable music: <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Budd </PERSON>, the good and handsome sailor; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Claggart </PERSON>, the evil master-at-arms who is bent on his destruction; and <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Vere </PERSON>, the philosophical captain who reluctantly sends <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> to his death to preserve law and order. Two of the three roles were in excellent hands. Baritone <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> made a first-rate <PERSON> Billy </PERSON>, conveying first his youth and enthusiasm and later his pathos when, chained and awaiting execution, he sings a haunting ballad. As Vere, tenor <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> made a moving figure, especially in the prologue and epilogue where he appears as an old man musing about the distant past. Another composer might have made <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> a tenor, the vocal part traditionally associated with a young hero. But in <LOCATION> Melville </LOCATION>'s ambiguous narrative, Captain Vere may be the real hero, and <PERSON> Britten </PERSON>'s decision to make him the tenor seems to acknowledge this The malevolent <PERSON> Claggart </PERSON> is portrayed more conventionally as a deep bass. <PERSON> Jan-Hendrik </PERSON> <PERSON> Rootering </PERSON> looked sinister enough, but his good-sized voice lacked the bite and menace that <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> brought to the part when the production was new. The men's chorus, which has a major role in the all-male cast, performed lustily, and the orchestra played well under conductor <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Fulton </PERSON>. But it was above all the set, designed by <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Dudley </PERSON>, that commanded admiration. With the aid of the Met's elaborate system of stage elevators, the ship expands and shrinks like an accordion as the action shifts from the main-deck, to the captain's cabin, to the quarter-deck, to the lower gun-deck. The effect is fittingly to make the ship itself the dominant image in the opera, a microcosm where the battle between good and evil is played out to its tragic conclusion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890404-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-04-89 0211EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-JuvenileExtradition     04-04 0496</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Juvenile Extradition,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Death Penalty Opponents Pressing D.C. Mayor To Block Extradition
Bid</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID PACE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Opponents of capital punishment are pressing <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Marion </PERSON> <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> to block the extradition of a juvenile sought by <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> until he's assured the youth wo n't face the death penalty But <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> so far has refused to interject himself publicly into the extradition case involving a 17-year-old black youth charged in the May 1988 firebombing of a <LOCATION> Gadsden </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, apartment. A 14-month-old black child died in the fire. <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Blake </PERSON>, the mayor's deputy press secretary, said <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> would not respond to pleas, made at a Monday news conference by a group of death penalty opponents and church leaders, that he refuse to honor <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>'s extradition request unless state authorities guarantee the youth, identified by the initials <LOCATION> O.M. </LOCATION>, will not be charged with a capital crime. While <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> has remained silent, lawyers for the district government have supported <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>'s bid to extradite the youth, who has been held in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> since his arrest in December on a fugitive warrant from <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>. Superior Court Judge <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Eilperin </PERSON> last week granted <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>'s extradition request, but he stayed his order until today to allow the youth's attorneys to appeal. An appeal was filed Friday with the <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>, which extended the stay until April 10. <PERSON> Alvin </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bronstein </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Project </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> can supersede the court ruling and block the extradition until <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> promises not to seek the death penalty. <PERSON> Bronstein </PERSON> charged that <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>, by allowing his government to support the extradition, has `` forgotten the values that motivated him 25 years ago'' when he worked for racial justice in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> as a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Student </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nonviolent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coordinating </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> SNCC </ORGANIZATION> -RRB-. <PERSON> Bronstein </PERSON>, who was an attorney for <ORGANIZATION> SNCC </ORGANIZATION> members during the civil rights movement, said he was issuing `` a personal plea to the mayor ... do n't send this youngster back without the kinds of guarantees that will ensure us that he wo n't be killed in jail, that he will be treated in a decent fashion and that he wo n't face the death penalty.'' If <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> refuses to make such guarantees, then <PERSON> Bronstein </PERSON> said the district should release the youth, because there are no other outstanding charges against him. O.M.'s attorneys contend he can not get a fair trial from the white authorities of <LOCATION> Etowah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, because of their long-standing vendetta against his family. Both the boy's father and uncle died while in police custody. Another of the boy's uncles has been charged with murder and arson in connection with the 1988 firebombing. O.M. is charged under juvenile law as an accessory to the firebombing, and thus is not facing an immediate threat of the death penalty. But <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> authorities have refused to rule out the possiblity that he might be tried as an adult and subjected to the death penalty.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890404-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-04-89 0220EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Bush-Baseball     04-04 0376</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Baseball,360</SECOND>
<HEAD>President Mixes Diplomacy, America's Pastime</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-US-Mideast Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BALTIMORE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> scoffs at the notion that his season-opening pitch to <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION>' catcher <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Tettleton </PERSON> was a high and wide. `` He caught it before it started breaking,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> protests. With guest Egyptian President <PERSON> Hosni </PERSON> <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> and a sellout Memorial Stadium crowd of 52,161 watching, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> tossed the first ball in Monday's American League opener between <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sox </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, captain of the 1948 <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> baseball team and an enthusistic lifetime fan, threw the ball lefthanded from the mound. Standing in his shirtsleeves with his jacket removed and a glove on his right hand, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> hurled the ball without benefit of a windup. <PERSON> Tettleton </PERSON>, who had moved several feet in front of home plate for the presidential pitch, gloved the curve ball with a long reach over his right shoulder. Over hot dogs, hamburgers and soft drinks, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> discussed that pitch _ his first game-opener as president _ with <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> and other guests and reporters in his glass-enclosed box over third base, voicing mock dismay over a reporter's suggestion that it was `` high and outside.'' Turning to baseball great <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, a longtime <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> friend, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said: `` Here's an objective judge. What did you think, sir?'' After a pause, <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said: `` High, hard, fast ball.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> then asked `` another objective visitor,'' baseball commissioner <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bartlett </PERSON> <PERSON> Giamatti </PERSON>. `` Superb,'' <PERSON> Giamatti </PERSON> said, adding he had n't seen the pitch but had heard about it from Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, who `` said it was wonderful.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Muburak </PERSON> left after the fifth inning, when <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> led 1-0, missing most of the action. The final score was <ORGANIZATION> Baltimore </ORGANIZATION> 5, <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sox </ORGANIZATION> 4 in 11 innings. <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON>, putting on an <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION> hat for photogrpahers, said he was enjoying both his hot dog lunch and his first live baseball game, calling <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> `` a very good teacher.'' `` He was the captain of the biggest team in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> said. `` That's what I told him,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> interjected. At <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION>, first baseman <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was known more for his fielding than his hitting. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was asked if Monday's game brought back memories from his youth. `` This was fun, yeah,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890404-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-04-89 0222EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ScotusRdp     04-04 0803</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus Rdp,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Upholds Use of Drug Courier `Profiles'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES H. RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Law enforcement officials are armed with new support from the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> to fight drug smuggling by air travelers. The justices on Monday made it easier for authorities to stop, question and search airline passengers who fit so-called `` profiles'' of possible drug couriers. By a 7-2 vote, the court ordered the reinstatement of a drug possession conviction of a man carrying 1,000 grams of cocaine when he was stopped by authorities at the <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> airport. `` We're pleased and happy that we've been upheld by the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>,'' said <PERSON> Cornelius </PERSON> <PERSON> Dougherty </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. The justices upheld the <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION>'s case against <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Sokolow </PERSON>, who was stopped because his behavior and dress matched a `` profile'' the agency uses to identify suspected drug couriers. Chief Justice <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rehnquist </PERSON>, writing for the court, said there were sufficient factors to lead agents to reasonably suspect <PERSON> Sokolow </PERSON> was engaged in criminal activity. `` The fact that these factors may be set forth in a ` profile' does not somehow detract from their evidentiary significance as seen by a trained agent,'' <PERSON> Rehnquist </PERSON> said In a dissenting opinion, Justice <PERSON> Thurgood </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> said the ruling likely will lead to questioning and detaining innocent people. `` Reflexive reliance on a profile of drug courier characteristics runs a far greater risk than does ordinary, case-by-case police work of subjecting innocent individuals to unawarranted police harassment and detention,'' he said. <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> was joined by Justice <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON>. Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> hailed the ruling, saying it `` validates an effective practice ... to crack down on drug trafficking.'' `` Without this tool, our anti-drug effort could be significantly hampered,'' <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said in a statement. `` By upholding the ` profile' practice, the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> has struck a strong blow in support of law enforcement's war on drugs.'' <PERSON> Sokolow </PERSON> was stopped by <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> agents on July 25, 1984, as he returned to <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> from a trip to <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. Authorities said he aroused their suspicions three days earlier when he and a female companion departed from <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> airport for <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. They said <PERSON> Sokolow </PERSON>, who appeared to be in his mid-20s, bought his plane tickets with $ 2,100 in cash taken from a roll of money that appeared to contain more than $ 4,000. He was wearing a black jumpsuit and a great deal of gold jewelry, appeared nervous, and he and the woman with him carried four handbags on the plane without checking any luggage. The agents also suspected he was using an alias because the name he gave the ticket agent was not the same as the name listed for the telephone number he gave the agent. Such behavior, dress and demeanor fit the profile of a drug courier, narcotics agents said. <PERSON> Sokolow </PERSON> pleaded guilty to possession of cocaine with intent to distribute and was sentenced to five years in prison. He appealed the conviction on grounds the cocaine should have been suppressed as evidence because authorities violated his constitutional rights against unlawful search and seizure when they stopped him in <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION>. The 9th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> threw out the conviction, ruling that suspicion of a crime `` can not be intuited from a hodgepodge assembly of factors about individual character.'' But the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> said the accumulated factors weighed by the agents were enough to permit them to question <PERSON> Sokolow </PERSON> and detain him. They subsequently obtained a search warrant after a police dog indicated a handbag contained narcotics. `` Any one of these factors is not by itself proof of any illegal conduct and is quite consistent with innocent travel,'' <PERSON> Rehnquist </PERSON> said. `` But we think taken together they amount to reasonable suspicion.'' For example, <PERSON> Rehnquist </PERSON> said, traveling from <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> may not be suspicious. But, he said, `` Surely few residents of <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> travel from that city for 20 hours to spend 48 hours in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> during the month of July.'' The use of drug courier profiles has survived previous high court scrutiny. Monday's ruling may give authorities a freer hand to use them. In other action, the court: _ Ruled in a case from <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> that there is no `` generalized right of social association'' and allowed communities to protect young teen-agers by banning anyone over 18 from some dance halls _ Ruled, by a 6-3 vote in a <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> case, that state courts lack the authority to approve adoptions of Indian babies by non-Indians even when the natural parents leave the reservation to give up the children Sending the case back to a tribal court for more study, the justices said tribal rights and Indian culture take precedence over individual rights in such circumstances. _ Agreed to decide whether a <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> woman may be jailed for refusing to reveal the whereabouts of her young son, who authorities fear may be dead
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890404-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-04-89 0223EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites SUB a0418 04-04 0157</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites, SUB, a0418,0162</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS first item to DELETE INCORRECT reference to first official
nut</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SALEM, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The hazelnut rolled past the giant chinquapin on the way to becoming the official state nut. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Operations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elections </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Monday passed the hazelnut on to the full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> for consideration. The only person to testify in favor of the giant chinquapin, a cousin of the chestnut, was <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Pope </PERSON>, a Salem seed company owner and nature lover who admitted that legislators might consider his favored nut `` squirrel food.'' He was no match against 10 members of the <ORGANIZATION> Slick </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chick </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Camp </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> from <ORGANIZATION> Clackamas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> and lobbyists for the $ 20 million hazelnut industry. `` Indians and pioneers ate hazelnuts,'' said troop member <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Stitt </PERSON>. Only one committee member voted against the hazelnut, also known as filberts. `` I'm not convinced this was an issue we need to address,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Springer </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890404-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-04-89 0225EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-EducationSpending     04-04 0623</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Education Spending,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>For release 9:30 a.m. EDT; time set by source</HEAD>
<HEAD>Teachers' Union Says $10 Billion More Needed For School Programs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JILL LAWRENCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nation's largest teachers union today called for $ 10 billion in new federal spending to counter `` a shocking erosion'' in education programs for the disadvantaged and handicapped. `` These programs reach only a fraction of the young people they were meant to serve,'' <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Futrell </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said in issuing a report called `` Federal Education Funding: Present Realities and Future Needs.'' `` In state after state, the numbers in our new report clearly demonstrate a shocking erosion of federal support for these essential programs,'' <PERSON> Futrell </PERSON> said in a statement. `` Nothing could be more impractical for our nation than continuing this systematic underfunding.'' <PERSON> Futrell </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> NEA </ORGANIZATION> report contains the first estimates of what it would cost to serve all students currently eligible for help under four of the most important federal education programs. NEA has more than 1.9 million members across the country. Its report comes as <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> prepares to tackle the fiscal 1990 budget. The report looks specifically at Chapter 1, grants to bolster basic skills among disadvantaged youngsters; the Education for All Handicapped Act, which helps states educate disabled youngsters; bilingual education, grants to make sure students with native languages other than English succeed in school; and <PERSON> Pell </PERSON> grants for college students from low-income families. The most serious erosion appears to have occurred in Chapter 1. The <ORGANIZATION> NEA </ORGANIZATION> report said the number of students served dropped from 7 million in 1980-81 to 5.7 million in 1988-89. At the same time the number of children in poverty swelled, so while the program reached 65 percent of eligible students in 1980-81, it reached only 40 percent by 1986. For fiscal 1989, the group said, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> provided $ 4.6 billion for Chapter 1 _ enough to serve 47 percent of eligible students. To serve the estimated 8.5 million who will qualify next year, would cost about $ 6.9 billion _ a $ 2.3 billion increase over current levels. The authors of the 1974 handicapped act intended that the federal government would ultimately pay 40 percent of its cost to local school districts. But the federal share started at 12 percent and stayed there until 1980, and by fiscal 1989 had dropped to 7 percent, <ORGANIZATION> NEA </ORGANIZATION> said. To reach the 40 percent target would cost $ 8.4 billion, a $ 6.5 billion hike over current levels, the report said. And though funding has doubled since 1980, merely restoring the federal share to 12 percent would cost an extra $ 700 million. The bilingual education program currently serves one in 18 of students who need help in English language skills, <ORGANIZATION> NEA </ORGANIZATION> said. An increase of more than $ 1 billion would be needed to serve the 1.6 million students states report as eligible, the group said. While funds for <PERSON> Pell </PERSON> grants have increased slightly when adjusted for inflation, the increases have not come near matching the soaring costs of postsecondary education, <ORGANIZATION> NEA </ORGANIZATION> said. It also said <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has `` fallen far short'' of meeting its own authorized funding level for the individual grants. Another $ 600 million would be needed to fully fund the maximum $ 2,900 Pell grants permitted in fiscal 1990, the teacher union said. Higher academic standards and a greater emphasis on analysis and problem-solving are `` doomed to failure unless schools and communities can maintain programs to help all students meet those standards,'' the report said. It says the solution, given state and local economic constraints, is to fully restore the federal share of support for public education. The <ORGANIZATION> NEA </ORGANIZATION> report was based on charts provided by <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Planning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, an independent statistical analysis firm.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890404-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-04-89 0225EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Budget     04-04 0502</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Budget,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Seeks $2.2 Billion in New 1989 Spending, $829 Million in Cuts</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A group that lobbies for poor people says President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s proposal to immediately slash $ 829 million in domestic spending would fall heavily on the needy. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is asking <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to make the reductions to help pay for $ 2.2 billion in new 1989 spending he is seeking in other areas, including funds for veterans and for foster care. The Center on Budget and Policy Priorities, an advocacy group for the needy, said that based on its analysis of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s proposal, $ 270 million in cuts would come from programs that provide education, job training, health and other assistance to the poor. `` The priorities reflected in these proposals raise questions about whether the talk of a kinder and gentler <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> largely represents a rhetorical attempt at image-making,'' said the center's director, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenstein </PERSON>, in a written statement. Under <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s plan, more than 1,000 domestic programs _ excluding those he considers top priority _ would be slashed by nearly 1.1 percent across the board. The details of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s request, made available by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appropriations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION>, did not specify which programs would be affected by the proposed cuts. But the center, saying it based its figures on data from <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION>, said $ 270 million of the proposed cuts would come from programs for the poor. The center said this would include $ 64 million in cuts in financial aid to needy students, $ 50 million for compensatory education for poor children, and $ 41 million for job training. Overall, the center said, the sharpest cuts would fall on the departments of education, $ 185 million; health and human services, $ 88 million; and agriculture, $ 80 million. The savings from the cuts <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is seeking would help finance increases the president wants in dozens of domestic programs for fiscal 1989, which ends Sept. 30. Even though most budget decisions are made before a fiscal year begins, presidents often seek additional spending in the middle of the year. Included in <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s request for new spending is about $ 850 million to pay for cost-of-living increases for veterans and their survivors and for other Department of Veterans Affairs programs. The president is also seeking $ 400 million to repay states for their foster care efforts, $ 100 million to pay for increased refugees entering this country from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>, and $ 55 million for the government's uranium program. In addition, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is asking <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to provide $ 892 million it has already committed itself to spending for the Guaranteed Student Loan program for college students. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> sent his request to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on March 24, when lawmakers were on their Easter recess. They return Tuesday. In his package, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told the lawmakers he would later submit a request for about $ 50 million in aid to the Nicaraguan Contra rebels, and $ 454 million to help bail out the nation's teetering savings and loan associations.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890404-0022 </DOCNO>
