<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890815-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-89 2336EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Nicaragua-Prisoners     08-15 0372</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nicaragua-Prisoners,0385</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Frees 29 Prisoners</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RODOLFO GARCIA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANTASMA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Sandinista government on Tuesday freed 29 peasants accused of collaborating with U.S.-backed rebels _ the first of about 1,200 prisoners <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> has promised to release. The 29 were freed from a city jail in this northern town. `` This should coincide with the beginning of the demobilization of the Contras -LRB- rebels -RRB- from <LOCATION> Honduran </LOCATION> territory and the withdrawal of those who operate in Nicaraguan territory,'' President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> said. He said there will be no mercy for rebel groups who do not disband in compliance with the peace agreement signed last week in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> by <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> and four other Central American presidents. <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> spoke at a cermony during the release of the 29 in <LOCATION> Pantasma </LOCATION>, 140 miles north of <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>. `` He who does not accept the hand we are extending should be prepared,'' he said. Under the agreement signed at the summit conference in <LOCATION> Tela </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>, the rebels are to disband by early December. An estimated 11,000 Contras and 12,000 dependents will be moved from camps along the Honduran border and resettled in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, under the accords. The government said recently there are about 2,500 Contras operating in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. In return for the disbanding of the rebels the government has pledged to hold free and fair elections in February. It would be the first free vote since the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> defeated the conservative government of President <PERSON> Anastasio </PERSON> <PERSON> Somoza </PERSON> and gained power in July 1979. <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> said the rebels `` have the opportunity to contribute to peace in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'' and `` avoid more suffering for their families.'' On Sunday, <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> agreed to a request from the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farmers </ORGANIZATION> and Cattlemen to release about 1,200 peasants accused of aiding the rebels. <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> said Tuesday that 1,515 rebels and 39 former national guardsmen in the Somoza regime are in Nicaraguan prisons. The government freed 1,897 former guardsmen on March 17. The leftis government has announced monthly cease-fires in its war against the rebels since June 1988, when a temporary truce between the two sides expired. Pantasma is located in a northern valley the rebels tried to take numerous times but failed. In October 1983, 48 peasants died in the fighting.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890815-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-89 0103EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TelevisionWriters     08-15 0303</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Television Writers,0311</SECOND>
<HEAD>AP Appoints Two New Television Writers, Expands Coverage</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Appointment of <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharbutt </PERSON> as a television writer has been announced by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, which also said it will expand its New York-based TV staff to two writers. <PERSON> Sharbutt </PERSON> will join the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> on Sept. 4. He has covered television for the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> since 1983. The second TV writer will be <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, now a national editor in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> for the news service. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> will transfer to the television beat later this year. `` This expansion of television coverage for our members is part of a general enhancement of <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s entertainment report,'' <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Ahearn </PERSON>, executive editor, said Monday. <PERSON> Ahearn </PERSON> said <PERSON> Sharbutt </PERSON> will be <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s lead television writer in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, covering all aspects of the industry. He succeeds <PERSON> Kathryn </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, who resigned to pursue a freelance writing career. <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Buck </PERSON> will continue as an <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> television writer in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Horn </PERSON> also covers TV as part of a general entertainment beat. For <PERSON> Sharbutt </PERSON>, 49, it is a return to the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s TV beat, which he covered from 1972 to 1978. He was <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s drama critic until 1983 and then joined the Times. <PERSON> Sharbutt </PERSON> joined the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> in 1966 as a newsman in its <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, bureau after working for The Ledger in <LOCATION> Lakeland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, and for The Orlando Sentinel. In subsequent years, he served as an AP newsman in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, and in <LOCATION> Saigon </LOCATION> during the Vietnam War. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, 39, has been a member of <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s national editing staff in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> since 1984. He has supervised filing of the national news report, and handled feature writing assignments. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> joined the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> in 1978 after work as a reporter for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fitchburg-Leominster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sentinel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Enterprise in <LOCATION> Fitchburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890815-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-89 0104EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APAppointment     08-15 0097</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Appointment,0099</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Correspondent Named for Rochester</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROCHESTER, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON> <PERSON> Appelman </PERSON>, a newswoman in the <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION> bureau of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, has been named AP correspondent in <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION>. The appointment was announced Monday by <PERSON> Lew </PERSON> <PERSON> Wheaton </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> chief of bureau for upstate <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Ms. <PERSON> Appelman </PERSON>, 25, joined the AP in <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION> in 1987 after graduating from <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and spending a year in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> as a Fulbright scholar. She is a native of Downers Grove, Ill. In <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION> she succeeds <PERSON> Randolph </PERSON> <PERSON> Picht </PERSON>, who recently was named <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> correspondent in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890815-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-89 0106EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Japan-Jeeps     08-15 0688</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan-Jeeps,0709</SECOND>
<HEAD>The American Jeep Is Mark of Prestige to Japanese 4WD Enthusiasts</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSAN MOFFAT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOTOSU, Japan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Japanese have gone wild over four-wheel drive vehicles and on that score they have shed their prejudices against American automobiles. The American-made Jeep is the mark of prestige. Churning up mud, bouncing over dirt moguls, mucking through boggy sinkholes, enthusiasts careen around a 5.5-acre four-wheel-drive playground in the shadow of <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fuji </LOCATION>. The equivalent of a ski resort for dirt vehicles, the pay-by-the-day <LOCATION> Motosu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Highlands </LOCATION> course is flourishing because herds of four-wheel-drive vehicles were banned from tearing up <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fuji </LOCATION> itself. But the four-wheel-drive vehicle also has become a status symbol in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>'s high-fashion <LOCATION> Harajuku </LOCATION> <LOCATION> district </LOCATION>, where urban dandies cruise around in chrome-trimmed, jacked-up, jeep-type vehicles with the tops down, festooned with macho but unused heavy-duty winches and fog lights. And in affluent residential neighborhoods, housewives load groceries into Jeep Cherokees parked next to Mercedes Benzes and Saabs. In a country eager for ever-more-stylish ways to spend new-found cash, four-wheel-drive recreational vehicles have become the ultimate Japanese yuppie vehicle _ and the American Jeep is the one to own. While other American cars are deemed mediocre by the Japanese, Jeeps evoke an image of American wide-open spaces and outdoor life that many Japanese long for, says <PERSON> Nobuyoshi </PERSON> <PERSON> Fukushima </PERSON>, editor of 4X4 Magazine. Chrysler Jeep sales have doubled in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> for three years in a row, but they still totaled only 500 in 1988. The vast majority of four-wheel-drive cars on Japanese roads are still domestic models, such as the <ORGANIZATION> Mitsubishi </ORGANIZATION> Pajero or Isuzu Big Horn. And many vehicles with the genuine Jeep insignia were built by <ORGANIZATION> Mitsubishi </ORGANIZATION>, which bought the technology from the <ORGANIZATION> Willis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Overland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> more than 20 years ago, before Jeep manufacturing was taken over in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> by <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and then <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION>. Four-wheel-drive vehicles are the fastest-growing segment of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s auto market. For the past few years jeep-type sales have grown 20 to 30 percent annually, or three times as fast as the entire car market, estimates <PERSON> Fukushima </PERSON>. One in 11 of the 6.7 million cars produced in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> last year had four-wheel drive. Recreation vehicles are part of a growing leisure industry fueled by rising incomes and longer vacations. Skiers, surfers, and scuba divers also are avid drivers of jeep-style vehicles. But 75 percent of four-wheel-drives in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> never leave city streets: their appeal is atmospheric rather than functional. Jeep-style vehicles with power steering, leather seats, stereos, adjustable suspensions and automatic transmissions sell fast, and dealers say they're getting BMW trade-ins from buyers. The top-of-the-line <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Jeep Cherokee costs about $ 35,000 in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, more than double the price of many smaller Japanese jeep-style cars. `` This is really a luxury car, for well-to-do buyers, mostly professionals in their late 30s or 40s,'' says <PERSON> Masayuki </PERSON> <PERSON> Sakamoto </PERSON>, director of marketing for <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sales </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Masaaki </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuroiwa </PERSON>, who has been selling Jeeps and Jeep parts for more than 20 years from a cluttered suburban garage, finds the fad a little ironic `` There's no need for these cars in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> nowadays,'' he said. `` There's hardly any place to really drive them. It's just a fashion, people like them with all kinds of shiny accessories stuck on. It's a way to spend money.'' <PERSON> Kuroiwa </PERSON> fell in love with Jeeps when they were the only vehicles that could get around in a devastated <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> just after World War II. As a child he admired the powerful olive-green vehicles driven by American occupation troops. After the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> occupation forces left <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, their Jeeps continued to serve as all-round vehicles, especially on rough country roads, but they nearly disappeared in the 1960s, when many were shipped to poorer countries for another lifetime of service. Now <PERSON> Kuroiwa </PERSON> and others are buying vintage <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jeeps </ORGANIZATION> as collectors items from the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, where they are still widely in use. In <PERSON> Kuroiwa </PERSON>'s lot, <PERSON> Yuichi </PERSON> <PERSON> Tanaka </PERSON>, 45, proudly pats the hood of his well-preserved Jeep, which is exactly as old as he is. `` It's won a lot of Jeep beauty contests,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890815-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-89 0111EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TillemProfile     08-15 0610</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tillem Profile,0627</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ethiopian Crash Claims Lawyer, Investor, Philanthropist</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Ethiopia-Leland</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BILL STIEG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 He was a lawyer, investment banker, professor and editor _ and only 32 when the plane he was in crashed in the mountains of <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>. But friends remember <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON> <PERSON> Tillem </PERSON> as a selfless man who overcame a poor, troubled childhood to use his wealth to help others, especially the young _ from disadvantaged children in <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> to starving children in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. `` When everyone else was talking, he was out there doing,'' said <PERSON> Neal </PERSON> <PERSON> Schnall </PERSON>, his roommate on a 1986 trip to <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Tillem </PERSON> was on the plane that crashed Aug. 7 in southwestern <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>, killing 16, including <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Leland </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Tillem, an Orthodox Jew, had worked on behalf of Ethiopians, Jewish and otherwise, since 1986, helping establish a poultry-farming enterprise. `` You ca n't save the world, but you can save one corner of it _ and in <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON>'s case, several corners,'' said <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Ribakove </PERSON> <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> on Ethiopian Jews. `` It was very typical of him, that helping <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> meant not just sitting in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and writing checks, but going there, going to visit Jewish villages, putting drops in children's eyes.'' Tillem's resume looked like that of someone twice his age: chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Financial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>; professor at <ORGANIZATION> Stern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Yeshiva </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, where he was on the board of trustees; publisher and editor of the Jewish Almanac, which he subsidized to keep it affordable. `` It's hard to believe that one guy could do all these things,'' <PERSON> Schnall </PERSON> said. `` He used to say, ` I do n't have time to sleep. I've got things I've got to do.'' Among those things were establishing a scholarship fund for poor students at <ORGANIZATION> Yeshiva </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, and a fund for retarded and disadvantaged children at <ORGANIZATION> Ohel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Children </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION>. `` He had almost an obsession to make a difference,'' said longtime friend <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Rapps </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jewish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> on Law and <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION>, where Tillem once practiced civil rights law. As <PERSON> Tillem </PERSON> wrote in his preface to the Jewish Almanac, `` hunger, despair, homelessness, blindness, deprivation, enslavement and hopelessness'' exist alongside `` tranquility, order and privilege,'' and Jews should work to improve the ratio. `` That is ` tikkun hoalam' _ repairing the world, for the world can and should be different than it is,'' he wrote. `` He listened to what others had to say and spoke quietly,'' said <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Bacon </PERSON>, dean of <ORGANIZATION> Stern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> for Women. `` But he was so imaginative in his ideas. `` And all of them were directed toward solving problems of humanity _ social problems, political problems. He had ideas for the subways, for <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>, for <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>, for everybody.'' The money for all this came from canny investments. <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Financial </ORGANIZATION>'s latest venture is <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION>, a passenger airline out of <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> `` He gave away most of his money,'' said <PERSON> Abe </PERSON> <PERSON> Bayer </PERSON>, director for international affairs for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jewish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advisory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. Tillem seldom spoke of his childhood, friends said, though it was known his parents divorced and that he lived in a series of foster homes before a rabbi in <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION> took him in as a teen-ager. He was unmarried. `` You got the sense that he had a thing for children, that what happened to him would n't happen to anyone else,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Rapps </ORGANIZATION>. `` He was a very strange and enigmatic fellow,'' <ORGANIZATION> Bayer </ORGANIZATION> said. `` I do n't want to gloss this over. He was a loner, a restless, imaginative and tortured soul. And it was shaped by a very poor and traumatic childhood.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890815-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-89 0112EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FarmHotLine     08-15 0353</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Hot Line,0361</SECOND>
<HEAD>University Ends Farm Hot Line; Farmers And Advisers Wiser</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT LEE ZIMMER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHAMPAIGN, ILL. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The farm crisis hot line is disconnected, but officials say farmers and <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> advisers who help them are wiser because of Rural Route. The unique program ended this summer after 3,500 farmers called its toll-free number seeking confidential advice about their financial problems. Rural Route, which received $ 2.2 million in state and federal funds over four years, has left both farmers and advisers better prepared for the future, said <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Bloome </PERSON>, assistant director of the university <ORGANIZATION> Cooperative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Extension </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. `` They have a vivid memory of a recent event that will make them more cautious,'' he said. Farmers also have learned that farming is a business and that they `` have a value and worth that has nothing to do with that occupation.'' Rural Route also taught university advisers to be aggressive in looking for solutions to farmers' economic problems, and preparing farmers for their future in agriculture or in some other occupation if necessary, said <PERSON> Bloome </PERSON>. `` Some wanted to pretend the men in trouble were older, poorly educated smaller farmers who were laggards at accepting technology,'' he said. `` The opposite was true. They were young, well-educated and progressive.'' The hot line was unplugged July 1, although the services remain available. `` Calls had dropped to one a day or less,'' said <PERSON> Bloome </PERSON>. `` The overall financial picture for farmers was much improved, and farmers' need for anonymity seemed to be less.'' When the first call came into Rural Route, on March 18, 1985, farm income was down, debt and operating costs were up, and many farmers felt a serious economic pinch. Bills _ and stress _ mounted. Foreclosure loomed for some. There was an increase in alcohol abuse, family discord, divorce and suicide. But many troubled farmers refused to seek help because of pride and fear of ridicule in their communities. Farmers were referred to counseling centers around the state, or advisers _ always from <LOCATION> another </LOCATION> <LOCATION> county </LOCATION> _ were dispatched to their farms.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890815-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-89 0025EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Japan-ChildMurder     08-15 0481</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Child Murder,0494</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Confesses to Murdering Three Girls in Series of Abduction Cases</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Note contents</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARI YAMAGUCHI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man arrested for kidnapping and killing a five-year-old girl confessed he killed two other girls in a series of brutal murders that have shocked <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, police said Tuesday. <PERSON> Tsutomu </PERSON> <PERSON> Miyazaki </PERSON>, who was arrested Friday for kidnapping and killing <PERSON> Ayako </PERSON> <PERSON> Nomoto </PERSON> two months ago, confessed to police that he also killed two 4-year-old girls, <PERSON> Mari </PERSON> <PERSON> Konno </PERSON> and <PERSON> Erika </PERSON> <PERSON> Namba </PERSON>. Police were also grilling the 26-year-old <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> print shop worker regarding his possible involvement in the disappearance of a fourth girl, 7-year-old <PERSON> Masami </PERSON> <PERSON> Yoshizawa </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Saitama </LOCATION> state, who vanished last October. <PERSON> Miyazaki </PERSON> was in custody after being arrested July 23 for allegedly taking nude photographs of a 6-year-old girl. He was charged with indecent assault in the case. <PERSON> Miyazaki </PERSON> was re-arrested Friday on charges of kidnapping and killing <PERSON> Nomoto </PERSON>, who he told police `` made fun of a deformity'' in his hands. Her torso was found near a public restroom in a cemetery northwest of <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> on June 11. Police discovered the girl's skull Thursday at a location <PERSON> Miyazaki </PERSON> led them to. Under Japanese law, prosecutors have a maximum of 20 days to collect evidence against him before releasing him or bringing charges. `` In the most brutal murder case in postwar crime history, <PERSON> Miyazaki </PERSON> finally confessed he killed the other two,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> reported. The new development appeared on the front pages of all the major Japanese papers. Reporters have been camping out in front of <PERSON> Miyazaki </PERSON>'s house, as well as the victims' homes. In his confession statement, <PERSON> Miyazaki </PERSON> said, `` On Aug. 22, I picked up <PERSON> Mari </PERSON>, drove her to a mountain, where I strangled her to death. I took two pictures of her in the car. I burned her with other things in the front yard at my house. I put her bones and ashes in a box and put it at the front door of <PERSON> Mari </PERSON>'s home,'' the police reported the letter said. In February, after the box was found, letters were sent to <PERSON> Konno </PERSON>'s home and the national newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Asahi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shimbun </ORGANIZATION> by a writer named `` <PERSON> Yuko </PERSON> <PERSON> Imada </PERSON>,'' claiming responsibility for her abduction and murder. Investigators later found that `` <PERSON> Yuko </PERSON> <PERSON> Imada </PERSON>'' was a name of a female detective in a comic book. <PERSON> Miyazaki </PERSON> told police he also kidnapped <PERSON> Namba </PERSON>, strangling her in his car, stripping her clothes off and throwing her in the woods, police said. <PERSON> Mitsuyoshi </PERSON> <PERSON> Maniwa </PERSON>, a psychology professor at <ORGANIZATION> Shizuoka </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Miyazaki </PERSON> could not distinguish between reality and the fictional world largely due to his fascination with horror and animation videos. <PERSON> Susumu </PERSON> <PERSON> Oda </PERSON>, a mental health expert at <ORGANIZATION> Tsukuba </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> described the series of abductions as `` murder for pleasure.'' `` This case involved abnormal sexual desires, especially toward little girls, sadism, obsession for dead bodies and objects,'' <PERSON> Oda </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890815-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-89 0113EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Hungary-Haven     08-15 0740</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hungary-Haven,0765</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hungary a Haven for East Europeans</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE JAHN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BUDAPEST, Hungary (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 This communist land of comparative plenty, long a magnet for Soviet bloc citizens seeking consumer goods and comfortable vacations, also is becoming an escape route to the West. On Sunday night, a dozen young East Germans who spent the weekend outside the West German consulate in hopes of reaching the West crawled into their sleeping bags for another night on the sidewalk. Police drove by now and then, but did not disturb them. Across the <LOCATION> Danube </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, a new <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> committee was examining requests for refugee status from 10 applicants: a Soviet citizen, a Czechoslovak and eight stranded Somalis. Three refugee camps for 1,400 people are being built outside <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION>. They are primarily intended for ethnic Hungarians from <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>, but officials say the camps will be open to all Europeans who can prove they face persecution at home. One of the young East Germans said: `` We still do n't know whether we'll make it, but the way West is a lot easier from <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> than from <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>.'' <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> began welcoming Romanian refugees in January 1988, breaking an agreement with the communist ally to return its citizens who sought asylum. About 17,000 Romanians, most of them ethnic Hungarians, have fled to <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> in the first instance of one <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact country giving sanctuary to citizens of another on grounds of persecution. <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s decision to take in refugees from <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> put a further burden on the already strained relations between the two allies. <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> has long maintained the estimated 1.7 million-member ethnic Hungarian minority in <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> is subject to discriminatory policies. <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> also has expressed concern over a Romanian plan to demolish villages and resettle the population. <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> fears that this could destroy ethnic culture and traditions. <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> rejects the charges as interference in its internal affairs. Hungarian officials said in recent interviews the country will not change its new border and refugee policies just to avoid tensions with allies. In May, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> began dismantling barbed wire and other barriers on its border with <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>. Since then, at least 1,500 East Germans with few chances of travel to <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> have tried to cross into <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> illegally through <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. Hundreds succeeded and have gone on to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. Other hundreds who failed have gone underground in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> or sought asylum on West German diplomatic property. Police Col. <PERSON> Karoly </PERSON> <PERSON> Nagy </PERSON> urged all people who are in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> illegally to leave, but also told reporters none would be `` forcibly deported.'' A government official said privately: `` Because this decision expands the possibility for the East Germans to go to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> illegally, it's clear that this decision is not among those that the East Germans are happy about.'' The new refugee policy, which could provide asylum to any East European who proved persecution, is likely to disturb <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s East European allies even more. On March 14, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> became the first Soviet bloc country to join the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> on the Rights of Refugees, which took effect June 12. It commits authorities not to return anyone to a country where his `` life or freedom would be threatened on account of his race, religion, nationality ... or political opinion.'' Some Western countries have applied the convention broadly, giving asylum to most citizens of Soviet bloc countries. The <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> insists <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> does not want to become a conduit to the West, but officials formulating new laws to conform with the convention say all cases will be heard. `` If an individual meets the criteria of the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> convention, then we will definitely grant him refugee status, because if we decided to accept something we have to carry it through,'' said <PERSON> Laszlo </PERSON> <PERSON> Albrecht </PERSON>, deputy head of the ministry's refugee section. `` I can not speak for the Czechoslovak or East German governments, but in case they disapprove, what can we do?'' Under new laws taking effect in October, each applicant will be heard by a refugee camp panel, <PERSON> Albrecht </PERSON> said. A refugee who is rejected may appeal to an <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> committee, then demand a court hearing. <PERSON> Albrecht </PERSON> said other countries of permanent residence would be sought for most refugees other than ethnic Hungarians, indicating most would come from the East and go West. `` It's clear that not too many Swiss citizens are going to ask for refugee status from us,'' he said, and smiled.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890815-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-89 0115EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Afghanistan     08-15 0881</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Afghanistan,0909</SECOND>
<HEAD>Six Months After Soviets: Najib Still in Power, Guerrillas Feuding</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EDITH M. LEDERER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KABUL, Afghanistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Six months after the Soviet military withdrawal, President <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> remains in power, the U.S.-backed guerrillas who oppose him are feuding and both superpowers are increasing arms deliveries. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> have said they want a political settlement of the 11-year-old civil war, but talks in <LOCATION> Stockholm </LOCATION> two weeks ago produced no breakthrough and summer fighting has continued. When the last Soviet troops crossed the <LOCATION> Oxus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> border Feb. 15, journalists in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> awaited the imminent arrival of the Moslem guerrillas, as predicted by Western diplomats who had closed their embassies and left. Six months later, with <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> in office and his communist government denying rumors of an attempted coup in July, there is no expectation of guerrillas capturing <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> or any key provincial capital. Western embassies remain closed, however. Soviet bloc and Asian diplomats in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> say that is more indicative of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> opposition to reaching a deal with <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> than to fear of the rockets that fall on the city almost daily. <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Nabi </PERSON> <PERSON> Amani </PERSON> said Monday that <PERSON> Najib </PERSON>, who uses only one name, has proved his government can defend itself and is not the kind of Soviet `` puppet'' the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> expected to fall. <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> has offered to hold elections, under <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> supervision, for a broad-based coalition government but insists his party participate. The guerrillas reject that participation. `` We want a political settlement,'' <PERSON> Amani </PERSON> said. `` War brings nothing but the killing of innocent civilians and further destruction of our country. The war option can not solve anything.'' Rockets are a daily threat in this mile-high capital ringed by mountains. Some unofficial estimates say they hit civilian targets 98 percent of the time and military targets only 2 percent. <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> sources said 281 people were killed and 745 wounded, nearly all civilians, by rockets and a car bombing between June 25 and Aug. 1. Residents generally blame the rockets on the guerrillas and on the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, which pays for them, but more and more they also are holding the government and Soviets responsible. `` Both sides buy rockets and we hate both of them,'' said <PERSON> Salah </PERSON>, an 18-year-old student, as he walked through rubble that had been a friend's home. `` I think now it's time the great powers, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, must accept some type of solution for Afghanistann'' said <PERSON> Esmatee </PERSON> <PERSON> Wardak </PERSON>, president of the Women's <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> agreed to act as guarantors of the U.N.-mediated accords of April 1988 between <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and neighboring <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, which provided for withdrawal of Soviet soldiers and an end to outside involvement. Moslem guerrillas began fighting after a communist coup in April 1978 and Soviet forces entered the country in December 1979. Each side has accused the other of interfering. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> says the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is shipping arms to <PERSON> Najib </PERSON>'s government at the rate of $ 2.5 billion to $ 3 billion a year, nearly double the figure before the withdrawal. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has promised the guerrillas new weapons with which to disable airport runways and counter high-altitude bombing by the Afghan air force. Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Abdul </PERSON> <PERSON> Haq </PERSON> <PERSON> Ulumi </PERSON> of the Afghan <ORGANIZATION> supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> council </ORGANIZATION> said last week the Soviets were supplying with new MiG-29 fighters and the latest Sukhoi-27 ground attack jets to defend against a possible Pakistani attack. At least 3 million Afghans have fled to <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s eastern neighbor, which <PERSON> Najib </PERSON>'s government accuses of direct involvement in the war Guerrillas use border cities and refugee camps as bases and supply points. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Tomsen </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> envoy to the guerrillas appointed by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, predicted a major guerrilla offensive during the fighting season, which lasts until November, but it has not materialiized. `` The end is clear,'' he told a congressional committee last month. `` Resistance will prevail.'' <PERSON> Tomsen </PERSON> said little of the guerrillas' failure to capture the provincial capital of <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION> after months of siege, and an attack July 9 by one of the seven guerrilla groups based in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> on another. Members of the <PERSON> Gulbuddin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hekmatyar </PERSON>'s group <ORGANIZATION> Hezb-i-Islami </ORGANIZATION>, which has received the most <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid, were reported to have killed 30 field commanders and fighters of the rival <ORGANIZATION> Jamiat-i-Islami </ORGANIZATION>. Compounding the effections of factionalism has been the reluctance of some field commanders to fight. Some say they resent not being included in the exile government formed earlier this year and are unwilling to risk their men for it. <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> has emphasized national reconciliation, offering autonomy to local commanders who make peace will him. On Monday, he met with 60 former guerrillas who came over to the government and said: `` Those who were fighting come together, just like two brothers beside each other.'' The government has yet to win over any major guerrilla commanders. <PERSON> Amani </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, said Monday the security belt around <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> was being extended to prevent long-range rockets from reaching the city. He said the zone, now about 20 miles, would be enlarged to between 25 miles and 40 miles, depending on terrain. <PERSON> Amani </PERSON> said the government expected the guerrillas to start using long-rante rockets. Those now in use have ranges of 20 miles or less.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890815-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-89 0115EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-OkeechobeeMonster 1stLd-Writethru a0413 08-15 0398</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Okeechobee Monster, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0413,0406</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report of 18-Foot Gator Fuels Start of Hunting Season</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 13th graf to CORRECT length of gator to feet sted inches;
picks up 14th graf, ``That was ...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CLEWISTON, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A giant, 18-foot-long alligator is living in <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Okeechobee </LOCATION>, boaters and fishermen claim, but a state wildlife expert says he doubts it. `` It looks monstrous, bigger than our boat, and we have a 19-footer,'' <PERSON> Rebecca </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>, who has been fishing on the lake with her fishing-guide husband since 1966, said recently. `` We see it all the time,'' said <PERSON> Mrs. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>, who said she believes the alligator is a female. `` She throws her food up in the air, way up, then catches and eats it, mostly fish and birds.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON> has named the alligator <PERSON> Hendrietta </PERSON>, for <LOCATION> Hendry </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, one of five counties surrounding <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Okeechobee </LOCATION>, which is about 100 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> and at 700 square miles is <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s largest lake Bass fisherman <PERSON> Sonny </PERSON> <PERSON> Pease </PERSON> said he saw the creature sunning itself on shore with its tail curled around itself like <PERSON> Lady </PERSON> <PERSON> Godiva </PERSON>'s hair. <PERSON> Pease </PERSON> said that when he took his boat closer to the gator, he kept repeating, `` Oh, my God, that alligator is long. Nobody's going to believe this.'' When he got within about 200 yards of the big reptile, it started swimming toward his 18-foot boat. It `` was all of my boat's size,'' <PERSON> Pease </PERSON> recalled. An 18-foot alligator would break <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s longest alligator record by nearly 4 feet. However, wildlife biologist <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> of the state Game and <ORGANIZATION> Fresh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Water </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Gainesville </LOCATION> said an 18-foot-long alligator would be highly improbable. The longest gator caught since records were first kept in 1977 measured just over 14 feet and weighed 714 pounds, and was trapped last month in the <LOCATION> Apalachicola </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> southwest of <LOCATION> Tallahassee </LOCATION>. Trappers estimated it was 100 years old. The heaviest gator, caught in April near <LOCATION> Gainesville </LOCATION>, weighed 1,043 pounds and was 13 feet long. It took a tow truck to lift it and three scales to weigh it. `` That was a very healthy gator,'' <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> said. `` I would've questioned it, if I had n't seen it myself. The giant gator's real length may be determined after Sept. 1, when <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s monthlong alligator season starts. `` Every hunter who has a permit will be going for him,'' said <PERSON> Pease </PERSON>'s 22-year-old son, <PERSON> Keith </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890815-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-89 0044EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-BRF--NightStalker     08-15 0150</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Night Stalker,0153</SECOND>
<HEAD>Juror in Night Stalker Case Shot and Killed</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A member of the `` Night Stalker'' trial jury was shot and killed Monday in what officials said appeared to be a domestic dispute. <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> Singletary </PERSON>, 30, of suburban <PERSON> Carson </PERSON>, was found inside her apartment and her live-in boyfriend was being sought for questioning, said <PERSON> Sheriff </PERSON>'s spokesman <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Wehner </PERSON>. She had been shot repeatedly, he said. It was n't known how the murder would affect deliberations in the serial slayings trial of <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON>. The 12-member panel first began deliberating on July 26, after hearing 165 witnesses during testimony that lasted six months. <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON>, a 29-year-old drifter from <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, is charged with 13 counts of murder and 30 other felony charges. Prosecutors alleged that <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON> is the devil-worshipping `` Night Stalker'' who raped, robbed and murdered victims in a 1985 rampage that terrorized <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890815-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-89 0129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r s PM-BKC--Valvano     08-15 0293</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BKC--Valvano,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Valvano Still Mum On Book</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHARLOTTE, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> basketball coach <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Valvano </PERSON> spent more time dodging questions than answering them at a Tournament of Champions basketball doubleheader news conference. The four representatives of the tournament teams _ <ORGANIZATION> N.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION> _ gave brief speeches Monday to start the news conference. When it was his turn to take the podium, <PERSON> Valvano </PERSON> immediately made reference to the ongoing saga at his school. `` I can now say no comment in seven different languages,'' he joked. <PERSON> Valvano </PERSON> had kept his public appearances to a minimum since the release of `` Personal Fouls,'' a book authored by <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Golenbock </PERSON>, which contains allegations of wrongdoing in the <ORGANIZATION> N.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> basketball program. On Monday, he coined a phrase which ended up being his only answer to questions on the subject. `` I will comment on that at the appropriate time,'' he said. A few minutes later, however, a determined reporter asked another question involving the controversies surrounding the university. `` You really want to talk about this do n't you,'' asked <PERSON> Valvano </PERSON>. `` Unless you think the ` appropriate time' was in seven minutes, that's still the answer.'' <PERSON> Valvano </PERSON> has denied the charges against him, but the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> System </ORGANIZATION> formed a commission that conducted an investigation into <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> State's athletic program. Details of the report are to be released Aug. 25 at a meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> UNC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Governors </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Chapel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. Despite the occasional testiness, <PERSON> Valvano </PERSON> did joke some. `` Humor is so much a part of my makeup, I'm not sure that can ever change,'' he said. `` When I get around basketball coaches who are friends as these gentlemen are, the mood is strictly on hoops and I s
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890815-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-89 0049EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Panama     08-15 0261</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama,0267</SECOND>
<HEAD>Opposition, Government Hold Third Round of Talks</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RAFAEL CANDANEDO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The opposition and government held a third round of talks Monday on the country's political crisis in an attempt to resolve the impasse over whether Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> will step down and who will govern the country after Sept. 1. The opposition is demanding that its victory in the May 7 presidential elections be recognized so it can take power when the current terms of acting President <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON> and the legislature expire at the end of August. It also wants <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> to relinquish his post as chief of the Panamanian <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>, which makes him the country's de facto leader. International observers said <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> had the election annulled when it became apparent the opposition was winning. He has resisted more than a year of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and opposition pressure for his ouster, ever since he was indicted on drug trafficking charges in 1988 in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. The opposition on Monday however refused a government proposal that the two sides join in demanding an end to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military maneuvers along the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Romulo </PERSON> <PERSON> Escobar </PERSON> <PERSON> Bethancourt </PERSON>, head of the government delegation to the talks. No reason for the opposition refusal was given. Last week there were at least 10 incidents between <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops near the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION>. An Organization of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> mission that is mediating the talks is to present another progress report on Aug. 23. The last meeting between the two sides was last Friday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890815-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-89 0129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Child'sMurder     08-15 0670</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Child's Murder,0690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Emporia Police Charge Father in Murder of Infant Boy Nine Years Ago</HEAD>
<DATELINE>EMPORIA, Kan. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A police detective haunted for years by the supposedly accidental death of a 17-month-old boy is resting easier since his reopening of the case led to the arrest of the boy's stepfather for murder The suspicious death of <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> <PERSON> Walford </PERSON> nine years ago was particularly troubling to Lt. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> because <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> was virtually the same age as his own son, <PERSON> David </PERSON>. `` I guess over the years I've always thought about <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> <PERSON> Walford </PERSON> never getting a chance to grow up and do the things <PERSON> David </PERSON> has done,'' said <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, a 16-year veteran of the police force in the eastern <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Emporia </LOCATION>. On Aug. 19, 1980, <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> <PERSON> Walford </PERSON> died of severe head injuries suffered at his home. Despite indications of abuse, the death was ruled an accident. A new investigation started by <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> led to the arrest Saturday of the boy's stepfather, <PERSON> Gurney </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Bartley </PERSON>. The 38-year-old truck driver posted $ 25,000 bond and was released on a charge of second-degree murder. <PERSON> Bartley </PERSON> is scheduled to appear Wednesday in <LOCATION> Lyon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Court </LOCATION>. Nine years ago, then-Sgt. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> was one of two detectives assigned to investigate the child's death. <PERSON> Bartley </PERSON> told detectives he was in the house with <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> when he heard a thud. He said the boy had fallen off a 3 -LCB- - inch step in a doorway between two rooms After <PERSON> Bartley </PERSON> telephoned for help, the boy was taken to a <LOCATION> Wichita </LOCATION> hospital where he died three days later. Just a few days before, <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> had been taken to an <LOCATION> Emporia </LOCATION> hospital emergency room for an ankle injury. He also had numerous bruises, <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said. Police, a doctor and relatives all suspected the boy's injuries were not an accident. But <LOCATION> Sedgwick </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> forensics pathologist Dr. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Eckert </PERSON> somehow had been given a wrong description of <PERSON> Bartley </PERSON>'s story. When he performed the autopsy, he ruled that <PERSON> Adam </PERSON>'s injuries probably were caused by the type of accident he believed <PERSON> Bartley </PERSON> had described. The county attorney decided there was n't enough evidence to prosecute and the case was closed. Authorities would not say what description the pathologist was given because prosecutors plan to use it as evidence in the trial. In 1986, <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> received permission to reopen the investigation. He reinterviewed dozens of people, including the boy's grandparents and mother, who was at work when the injury occurred. The mother, <PERSON> Stephanie </PERSON> <PERSON> Craver </PERSON>, subsequently divorced <PERSON> Bartley </PERSON> and remarried and now lives in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>. `` The entire family suspected abuse from the very beginning. I think that's what led to the divorce,'' <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Craver </PERSON> has been `` very supportive and felt something had happened to her son, and did want the investigation open,'' he said. Investigators also uncovered a new witness _ a longtime friend of <PERSON> Bartley </PERSON> who told officers that <PERSON> Bartley </PERSON> told her he was disciplining <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> when the injury occurred. Finally, <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Lyon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Rod </PERSON> <PERSON> Symmonds </PERSON> decided to view the boy's autopsy, which had been videotaped as a training exercise. It was something <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> had avoided doing the first time around. `` I just did not want to see a 17-month-old cut up,'' he said. `` I should have done it, though. That was my job.'' The viewing proved crucial, showing that <PERSON> Eckert </PERSON> had been given wrong information. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> contacted <PERSON> Eckert </PERSON>, and after reviewing the evidence the pathologist changed his mind. His new report blamed the boy's fatal injuries on an `` assaultive scenario.'' `` I ca n't explain the feeling I got inside of me when he called it a homicide,'' <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said. `` All these years, I knew it was a homicide, and now I had an expert forensic pathologist calling it a homicide.'' Armed with that report, confirmation from two other pathologists and the new witness, the county attorney decided to prosecute <PERSON> Bartley </PERSON> for second-degree murder. `` I'm just ready to put it to sleep and let <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> <PERSON> Walford </PERSON> rest,'' <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said. `` I can just put this file someplace and not have to look at it again.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890815-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-89 0148EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AIDS-Minorities Bjt   08-15 0638</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS-Minorities, Bjt,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Minorities Under-Represented in AIDS Treatments, Doctors Say</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Many minorities infected with the AIDS virus are not seeking new life-prolonging treatments because of a lack of information and distrust of the medical establishment, doctors and social workers say. Poor blacks and Hispanics are under-represented in AIDS clinical trials where experimental therapies are tested, and they often do n't seek treatment until they are sick enough to qualify for free medical care, said AIDS caseworkers attending a government conference on AIDS and minorities `` They're not as well-educated about prevention and they do n't have a cousin who is a doctor who can tell them about the latest drug that's being tested in a clinical trial in their area,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Gina </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, an assistant attending physician in obstetrics and gynecology at <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> Also, the poor are often suspicious of attempts to get them into medical research, she said. Many hear only that the treatments, like AZT, make patients sick and do n't understand that the drug can cripple the AIDS virus, said <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, also a clinical instructor at <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Presbyterian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. One way to include more minorities in clinical trials would be to move the trials out of the academic medical centers and into the neighborhoods, many conference participants said Monday. Because much of the research on new drugs is being conducted at universities, clinical trials are often set up in a way that excludes poor people, said <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Cylar </PERSON>, a clinical social worker and activist with the <ORGANIZATION> AIDS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> to </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unleash </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION>, known as ACT UP. Often, services like transportation and day care are not considered, he said. `` Do n't put the trials on Madison Avenue or at <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, put them in <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION>,'' he said. As of a month ago, 7,096 people with AIDS were participating in clinical trials sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> on Allergy and Infectious Diseases, the chief AIDS research institute at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION>. Among them were 557 blacks, 731 Hispanics and 427 women. AIDS activists helped start the move to community-based testing, and the federal government is preparing to distribute $ 6 million in the fall to groups that want to expand or begin such programs. <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Clay </PERSON> <PERSON> Stephens </PERSON>, an AIDS services worker from <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> attending the conference, dismissed the often-heard reasons researchers give for excluding women and intravenous drug users, the fastest growing segment of AIDS cases, from clinical trials: They are unreliable because they do n't always show up for treatments. `` Well, are they not coming in because they're at their methadone clinic? That's a very valid place for them to be,'' she said. `` Did the woman not come in because her child was sick? `` Those concepts of non-compliance are often covers for our poor design based on having dealt with other middle-class people who can plan ahead and are in control of their lives in terms of scheduling and resources,'' she said. <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>, whose department is sponsoring the conference, told the opening session that the government and local communities must do a better job targeting AIDS prevention messages to minorities. He said the messages must be `` culturally relevant and sensitive,'' but he added that `` community standards must be respected'' in educating about the disease that is often transmitted through sexual contact. As of July 31, the total number of Americans diagnosed with AIDS reached 102,621, of whom 59,391 have died since July 1, 1981, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION>. Blacks, who comprise 12 of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> population, represent 26 percent of adult AIDS cases in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and 53 percent of pediatric cases, he said. Hispanics, who make up 7 percent of the nation's population, represent 15 percent of adult cases and 23 percent of pediatric cases.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890815-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-89 0148EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BRF--WaterfallDeath     08-15 0148</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Waterfall Death,0153</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Plunges to Death at Yosemite Waterfall</HEAD>
<DATELINE>YOSEMITE NATIONAL PARK, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man sliding down a granite riverbed plunged over a waterfall and 1,400 feet to his death, a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> official said Monday. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Ofner </PERSON>, 20, of <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barbara </LOCATION>, was sliding in the water near the <LOCATION> Upper </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yosemite </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION> on Sunday morning, <ORGANIZATION> NPS </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Mallory </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. Witnesses said <PERSON> Ofner </PERSON> did not shout or appear to realize what was happening when he went over, Ms. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. Warning signs advising visitors to stay out of the water were posted at the time of the accident, she said. Ofner and two friends had hiked to the top of the falls on Saturday and camped there overnight, Ms. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. The Upper Yosemite Falls forms part of a 2,405-foot waterfall descent that includes a set of cascades and Lower Yosemite Falls.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890815-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-89 0149EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HammerPardoned Bjt   08-15 0394</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hammer Pardoned, Bjt,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Pardons Oilman Armand Hammer</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Industrialist Armand Hammer, pardoned by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for making illegal campaign contributions to <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s 1972 campaign, says the president's action reinforces his faith in the American legal system. White House spokesman <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> confirmed Monday night that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had pardoned the 91-year-old Hammer and nine other people whose names were not released. The White House usually does not announce its action on pardons. Hammer, who pleaded guilty to the charges in 1976, released news of his pardon in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. `` Having spent my lifetime fighting injustice, this vindication reinforces my abiding faith in the American system of justice,'' he said in a statement issued Monday through his <ORGANIZATION> Occidental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> `` I deeply appreciate President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s action in clearing my name.'' Hammer spent several years seeking a pardon, and there had been speculation that President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> would grant one in his last days in office. Hammer originally pleaded guilty in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to a criminal information filed by the Watergate special prosecutor to three misdemeanor charges of making $ 54,000 in illegal contributions to the <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> campaign. But the judge threw out the plea after <PERSON> Hammer </PERSON> wrote a 20-page letter to his probation officer blaming former <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Babcock </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> Occidental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> vice president, for the contributions. <PERSON> Babcock </PERSON> was convicted of concealing that Hammer was the true source of the money. In 1976, <PERSON> Hammer </PERSON> left a hospital bed in a wheelchair and hooked to a cardiac monitor to enter another plea in a <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> court. `` I'm pleading because I'm guilty,'' he told the judge at the time. Hammer was sentenced to a year's probation and fined $ 3,000. The judge said he spared Hammer a prison sentence because of his precarious health. Hammer was a self-made millionaire by the time he graduated from <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> at 23, having taken over his father's pharmaceutical business four years earlier. After graduation, <PERSON> Hammer </PERSON> went to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> to negotiate a business deal, and wound up with a concession for an asbestos mine and a pencil factory. Proud of having met every Soviet leader since <PERSON> Lenin </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hammer </PERSON> has devoted much of his fortune to collecting great art, research on cancer and promoting world peace. Hammer's money sent <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> physicians to treat victims of the <LOCATION> Chernobyl </LOCATION> nuclear disaster in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> in 1986.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890815-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-89 0154EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     08-15 0963</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,960</SECOND>
<HEAD>Farm Machinery Sales Up</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Better times on the farm are boosting sales of new tractors and other machinery, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says. Another reason for the increased sales is the relative scarcity of good used machines. For years, because of tight finances, farmers had to do with what they had. Thus, says the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, many farmers who might be in the used market are turning to new models. `` Sales in all categories of new farm machinery are expected to expand in 1989,'' the agency said in a report. `` Farmers appear to be continuing a trend toward using larger tractors.'' Analysts said sales of four-wheel-drive tractors are expected to grow the most this year, up 65 percent from 1988, followed by a 23 percent increase for the larger two-wheel-drive models, those of more than 139 horsepower. Sales of combine harvesters and hay balers are also expected to gain about 22 percent each this year. Overall, farmers are forecast to spend $ 6.2 billion to $ 6.7 billion on machinery this year, the third consecutive annual increase, report said. Last year's expenditures rose to $ 6.03 billion from less than $ 5.8 billion in 1987 and $ 4.6 billion in 1986. Machinery sales rose to a record of almost $ 12 billion in 1979 before sliding seven consecutive years to the 1986 level. `` Weather conditions weakened sales growth in 1988, but are not expected to play a significant role this year,'' the report said. `` Higher net cash income, lower real interest rates, and reductions in outstanding debt began boosting farm machinery expenditures in 1987 and will continue to increase sales through 1989.'' Rising land values also are improving farmers' financial standings, enabling them to replace aging farm machinery. Another factor this year is a larger planted acreage, triggered in part by last year's drought-reduced harvests and rising market prices of some of the major commodities. `` An expansion in planted acres increases the return a farmer receives from the machine, because it is used on more acres,'' the report said. `` Furthermore, greater planted acreage makes machine down time more costly because more acres must be worked within the same time frame.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A defensive war against Africanized honeybees has helped slow the northward march of the insects across <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says. Popularly called `` killer bees'' by some, including movie writers, the migrating bees were expected to reach the southern <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1987 or 1988. Then, maybe 1989 or 1990. But department officials now say the bees wo n't reach the <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> of southern <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> `` for another 18 months or later.'' <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Glosser </PERSON>, administrator of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Animal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inspection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, said Monday that a joint project with <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> has delayed the bees' arrival and `` should give researchers and beekeepers enough time to study the bee and learn how to manage it.'' The Africanized honeybee is the hybrid offspring of European honeybees and pure African queen bees brought to <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> in 1956 for research. The African queens escaped and began interbreeding with native honeybees. Africanized bees have been migrating northward since then and were found in southern <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> in 1986. Today, they are about 400 miles south of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> border near <LOCATION> Tecolutla </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Veracruz </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. Although the venom of Africanized bees is no more potent than that of the European bees that are common throughout the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the hybrids can be more dangerous because of their aggressiveness and the likelihood of them stinging in greater numbers. Besides the notoriety as a fierce pest around humans and animals, the Africanized honeybee also is feared by many commercial beekeepers for what it might do to their industry. <PERSON> Glosser </PERSON> said his agency began working with the <LOCATION> Mexican </LOCATION> government two years ago in a cooperative program to control the Africanized bees. The program includes the detection and tracking of the bees as they near the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> border; trapping and destruction of swarms to reduce their numbers; and efforts to alter the bees genetically to they pose less of a threat. `` Program personnel in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> have hung almost 60,000 traps in the last 18 months and have caught more than 11,000 swarms of Africanized bees,'' <PERSON> Glosser </PERSON> said. `` That's millions of Africanized bees that will never reach the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' The project in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> also uses `` requeening'' to reduce the transfer of Africanized traits to regular honeybee colonies. Beekeepers are encouraged to select queens from desirable genetic stock and mark them with a bright paint so that it's easy to tell if they are in the hive. If an unmarked queen is noted, that female is replaced with a marked queen known to be of good genetic stock.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A quarterly report by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says the number of workers employed by farmers showed a seasonal increase in July, but dropped slightly from a year ago. The hired work force on farms was estimated at 1,197,000 during the week of July 9-15, up from 830,000 in April. In July 1988, the work force was 1,200,000. That did not include 351,000 `` agricultural service'' workers provided by crew chiefs and labor contractors. In April, those totaled 198,000 workers, and in July 1988 they were estimated at 303,000. Average pay for all workers hired directly by farmers was $ 5.23 per hour, up from $ 4.90 per hour a year earlier but below the average of $ 5.35 in April, the report said. For workers hired by contractors, there was no national wage rate available. However, workers in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> were reported at $ 5.80 per hour, compared with $ 6.45 in April and $ 5.74 a year earlier in July 1988. <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> workers averaged $ 5.55 per hour, compared with $ 6.24 in April and $ 5.19 a year earlier.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890815-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-89 0154EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Eastern     08-15 0414</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Eastern,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eastern Agrees to $75,000 Fine on Consumer Charges</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> officials say they are changing some of their business procedures after agreeing to pay a $ 75,000 fine for alleged federal consumer violations. The <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> said Monday that the financially hobbled carrier agreed to pay the civil penalty `` to avoid costly litigation,'' but was not conceding guilt. The alleged violations occurred in 1986 and 1987. It could take the government years to pocket the funds, however, because <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> has been under the protection of federal bankruptcy laws since March 9, five days after the strike against the carrier began. When a bankruptcy judge approves a schedule for repaying creditors, the payments might take years. The DOT charged the airline with taking more than the required seven days to issue credit-card refunds to customers. It also accused Eastern of not informing some consumers that flights listed by the carrier were operated by independent commuter airlines with agreements with <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>. Eastern officials said little about the settlement. But spokeswoman <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceremsak </PERSON> said the company had `` changed our procedures to better comply with DOT regulations.'' DOT officials said <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> uses an express delivery service to speed the shipment of refund claims to its <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> headquarters. <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> agreed to pay a $ 325,000 fine in November 1987, the largest ever. <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> _ like <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> a subsidiary of <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> _ agreed to pay a $ 250,000 penalty for similar charges in June 1987. Eastern filed a reorganization plan with the federal bankruptcy court July 21. Its goal is to emerge from reorganization by the end of this year. Under the agreement with the <ORGANIZATION> DOT </ORGANIZATION>, the government would receive its payment after all creditors have been repaid but before <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s debts to <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> are repaid. If the agreement is n't approved by the court by Nov. 30, it would be voided and the government would have to renew its efforts to press its case against <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Podberesky </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> DOT </ORGANIZATION> assistant general counsel, said the fine could be repaid in the next few months or could be delayed until sometime in the 1990s. Typically, he said, fines levied against financially healthy airlines are paid within anywhere from 15 days to two years. Claims against carriers in bankruptcy can take years, he said. Eastern, which operated 1,100 flights daily before the strike, operated 350 flights Monday and planned to increase that to 390 Tuesday, <PERSON> Ceremsak </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890815-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-89 0158EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Leland-Hunger 490   08-15 0499</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Leland-Hunger, 490</SECOND>
<HEAD>No Obvious Successor to Leland Legacy</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Leland-US</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DIANE DUSTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rep. <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Leland </PERSON>'s crusade against hunger will live on despite his death, says <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, but there appears to be no obvious successor to carry the torch. `` There will be a determination on the part of members of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to work for those goals that <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Leland </PERSON> sought to achieve _ the alleviation of hunger and suffering here and in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and elsewhere in the world,'' <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> said Monday. However, <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, D-Wash., did n't say who would become chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Select </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Hunger, the panel <PERSON> Leland </PERSON> founded in 1984 <PERSON> Leland </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Democrat, died in a plane crash last week while on a fact-finding mission in <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> aide <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Biggs </PERSON> said a new committee chairman was not expected to be named until next month when <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> returns from a month-long recess. <PERSON> Leland </PERSON>'s efforts were credited with getting $ 800 million in relief for victims of famine in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. `` Whenever a member wanted to do something -LRB- on hunger -RRB- they would go to him,'' <PERSON> Miranda </PERSON> <PERSON> Katsoyannis </PERSON>, chief of staff of the hunger committee, said Monday. `` This committee served as a focus. The <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> became more sensitive as a result.'' <PERSON> Leland </PERSON> parceled out responsibilities and several members of the committee were leaders in specific areas, <PERSON> Katsoyannis </PERSON> said. The senior member is Rep. <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, who shared <PERSON> Leland </PERSON>'s concern for hunger in the Third World Rep. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ackerman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, another committee member, was one of <PERSON> Leland </PERSON>'s closest associates and among the first to go to <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> to strengthen search efforts last week. Rep. <PERSON> Byron </PERSON> <PERSON> Dorgan </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.D. </LOCATION>, is known for his work with the hungry of <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, while Rep. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Espy </PERSON>, D-Miss., has been a leader in nutrition efforts among the rural poor of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Bustamante </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, is known for his work on hunger problems among the Hispanic poor. Seniority rules do n't apply to select committee chairmanships which, like standing committees, are made by the speaker. Select committees do n't act on legislation, but do initiate studies, hold hearings and influence other committees to make changes or additions to the federal statutes. `` Select committees at their best, offer us a flexibility and a sense of focus that we may otherwise not find in our standing committees,'' House Republican Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> said during debate in February on whether to continue the committees. <PERSON> Leland </PERSON> said during the same debate that his committee's work was extensive during the 100th <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. `` Thirty-two hearings, nine basic human needs seminars and numerous briefings were held; nine reports were published and monthly status reports on international and domestic hunger were issued and widely distributed,'' he said. The House Select Committee on Hunger was instrumental in setting up the Child Survival Fund, part of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> foreign assistance program. It also provided impetus to expanded research into the effects of vitamin A on child mortality.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890815-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-89 0159EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Exports     08-15 0480</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Exports,470</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congressmen Seek to Curb Pentagon in Rulings on Exports</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CARL HARTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Several members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> are making a new bid to curb the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s power to stop exports of high-technology goods, but defense officials say the limits are needed to keep equipment out of communist hands. Rep. <PERSON> Les </PERSON> <PERSON> AuCoin </PERSON>, D-Ore., and others say the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> should oversee shipments of goods with both military and civilian uses, as long as the goods are not being sold to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> or other Communist-ruled countries `` I think it makes sense,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Gejdenson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Conn </LOCATION>., who heads the subcommittee on international trade in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> `` I ca n't commit myself now, but I ` ll be glad to look at a proposal.'' Supporters of the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> on the issue include Sens. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Heinz </PERSON>, R-Pa., and <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, D-Ill., and Rep. <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Bereuter </PERSON>, Members interested in changing the trade rules worry that the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is overzealous in blocking exports. They see <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> business losing sales to foreign competitors when more sales are needed to reduce the trade deficit. At the current rate, the trade deficit will be $ 111 billion this year. The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, however, has told the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> its work on export licenses has `` resulted in denial of license application to known diverters in <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Basin </LOCATION> countries, at an estimated value of approximately $ 200 million.'' Sensitive goods shipped to allies have sometimes reached Soviet hands. The Japanese government found that <ORGANIZATION> Toshiba </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Machine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> had sold the Soviets sophisticated machinery capable of silencing submarine propellers. At one point, some members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> showed their anger by destroying a <ORGANIZATION> Toshiba </ORGANIZATION> radio with hammers on the Capitol lawn. When <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> returns from vacation next month, <PERSON> AuCoin </PERSON> and other advocates of the change will sound out opinion in both Houses. <PERSON> AuCoin </PERSON> represents a district where there are many high-technology companies. The new effort in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> would not keep the Pentagon out of decisions on exports that go directly to communist-ruled countries, or on exports of purely military goods. The countries on which the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> would continue to have its say include <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mongolia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Laos </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> voted last year to let the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> oversee exports to non-communist countries of technology with non-military uses, but the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> would not go along. Commerce Secretary <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON> won a decision from President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> against the Pentagon last month on a similar issue, enabling American manufacturers to ship higher-powered computers to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> as well as to other countries _ despite public opposition from <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON>. `` We did have a difference inside the administration on this question,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told reporters at the time. `` This will not endanger the legitimate national security needs of this country.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890815-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-89 0203EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-PLO     08-15 0615</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-PLO,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Gives Assurances to PLO in a New Round of Talks</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, pledging to keep talking to the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> despite deep policy differences, says it aims for a <LOCATION> Mideast </LOCATION> agreement with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> that promotes Palestinian political rights. A conciliatory statement issued Monday in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tunisia </LOCATION> sought to repair the recent rift between the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration and <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s group while also urging the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> to approve an <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> election plan. The statement by <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Pelletreau </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> seeks a settlement based on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> giving up territory in exchange for peace. Also listed as `` firm principles'' in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> statement were `` security and recognition for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> political rights.'' The statement did not say how those rights would be expressed. `` Our immediate task ... is to find a practical means to translate these principles into political reality,'' it said. The <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> demands a state on the Israeli-held <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy opposes statehood, and would have <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and Palestinians negotiate an arrangement acceptable to both sides. `` The Palestinians should have a chance to determine their own future in negotiations with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> as well as to run their daily affairs,'' said a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official who demanded anonymity. Meanwhile, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, pledged the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would keep talking to the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> to try to get negotiations started. `` We do n't expect a breakthrough in each particular meeting,'' <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON> said in announcing that the talks begun last December had resumed in <LOCATION> Tunisia </LOCATION>. `` It's an ongoing process.'' The department last month accused the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> of attaching unacceptable conditions to its provisional approval of an <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> proposal for elections on the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>. One was the demand for statehood. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration supports the <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> proposal to choose elected <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> representatives for negotiations as the best way to get talks started. The <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>, however, has denounced the proposal as a ploy to block Palestinian statehood. Last week, the department again criticized <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s organization. Spokeswoman <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON> said a statement adopted by <ORGANIZATION> Fatah </ORGANIZATION>, the main <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> faction, raised questions about the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s `` commitment to accommodation, understanding and peace.'' Delegates to a <ORGANIZATION> Fatah </ORGANIZATION> meeting in <LOCATION> Tunis </LOCATION>, where the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> maintains its headquarters, had approved a resolution calling for `` intensification of the armed struggle and all other forms of battle to put an end to the Israeli occupation of Palestinian territories.'' On Monday, the department took a different approach through both spokesman <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON> and envoy <PERSON> Pelletreau </PERSON>. <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON> said <PERSON> Pelletreau </PERSON> had met in <LOCATION> Tunisia </LOCATION> with a <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> delegation headed by <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Abd-Rabboo </PERSON> and again sought `` a positive Palestinian response'' to the Israeli election proposal. `` We continue to believe that through an Israeli-Palestinian dialogue progress can be achieved in moving the process forward to elections and peace negotiations,'' he said. <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>, while disapproving of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> talks with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>, proposed elections to select Palestinians who would negotiate temporary and limited self-rule with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. After five years, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> would negotiate an overall settlement of the <LOCATION> Arab-Israeli </LOCATION> dispute. The lengthy statement by <PERSON> Pelletreau </PERSON> called Monday's session `` serious and probing'' while offering assurances to the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> that the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration seeks to foster political rights for Palestinians. `` There is a road to peace in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>,'' it said. `` We are suggesting that the next, but not the last, milestone on that road is an election in the occupied territories.'' In <LOCATION> Tunis </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Abd-Rabboo </PERSON> said he expected the discussions to continue in `` the near future'' and said an international peace conference was `` the best introduction to establish an effective peace.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890815-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-89 0204EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SovietMissile 530   08-15 0538</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet Missile, 530</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Distressed Soviets Didn't Heed Appeals on Missile Test</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration is upset that the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> ignored two high-level <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> appeals to change its plans to test a long-range missile that passed near the Hawaiian islands. `` There was no danger, but there is always a risk, however slight,'' a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official said Monday after Friday's 8,000-mile flight of an unarmed intercontinental ballistic missile was disclosed. The missile did n't pass over land while flying over the island chain, but a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official said the point of the complaint was that `` it was too close for comfort.'' The missile was launched from the Tyuratam installation deep in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and splashed down some 1,250 miles south of <LOCATION> Oahu </LOCATION>, officials said. Two <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> the missile had passed over waters between two tiny Hawaiian islands, <PERSON> Neckar </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Nihoa </LOCATION>. A third official confirmed that the Soviets conducted the test Friday despite <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> appeals that it posed potential political and safety problems. The Soviets announced Aug. 7 that they intended to conduct a test between Aug. 11 and Aug. 21, but neither of the two private <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> appeals to Deputy Ambassador <PERSON> Serge </PERSON> <PERSON> Chetverikov </PERSON> nor the test itself were made public. `` It's somewhat disturbing the Soviets did n't take our concerns into account,'' a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official said Monday. `` There was no danger, but there is always a risk, however slight, it might be that something would go awry. That is why we felt it was inappropriate.'' Assistant Secretary of State <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Seitz </PERSON> and his deputy, <PERSON> Curtis </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kamman </PERSON>, held separate meetings last Monday and Tuesday with <PERSON> Chetverikov </PERSON> to complain that the missile was likely to pass over the <LOCATION> Hawaiian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> chain before splashing down in the ocean. <PERSON> Seitz </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kamman </PERSON> are the senior officers in the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> and Canadian Affairs. `` The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government expressed its deep concern to the Soviets over the planned test and asked that it be modified,'' a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official said. <PERSON> Chetverikov </PERSON> returned to the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday to say the test would be conducted strictly over water, not over any <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> territory. He said it would involve only international airspace and water. `` We did not find that response persuasive or sufficient, because the Soviet missile test would pass over the <LOCATION> Hawaiian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> chain,'' said the official, who spoke on condition of anonymity. `` It is not a legal issue but an issue of political and safety considerations. Once again, we strongly urged the Soviets to reconsider their plans.'' Two years ago, in a similar situation, the Soviets revised a missile test near <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> when the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration objected. In the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> appeals to the Soviets, the planned test was described as a `` provocation,'' said another <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official, who also requested anonymity. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> relations with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> have been on the upsurge on most fronts, although there have been recent disagreements over <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> assistance to rebels in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and Soviet overtures to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> and Soviet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> will meet in <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> next month to plan a summit between President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890815-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-89 0208EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-China     08-15 0450</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-China,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chinese Envoy Bids Adieu With Round of Parties</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GENE KRAMER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
