<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890816-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-89 2329EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-UN-Namibia     08-16 0373</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-UN-Namibia,0386</SECOND>
<HEAD>African Nations Say South Africa Endangers Namibia's Elections</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER JAMES SPIELMANN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNITED NATIONS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 African nations on Wednesday appealed to the <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> to foil alleged attempts by <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> to rig the outcome of <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>'s pre-independence elections in November. The African nations told a special council meeting that <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> was trying to stop the <ORGANIZATION> South-West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Africa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, known as <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION>, from taking power <LOCATION> Ghana </LOCATION>'s ambassador, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gbeho </PERSON>, called on the <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> to adopt a new resolution giving the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> interim control over <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>, rather than the South African administrator-general for <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>. But South African <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> representative, <PERSON> Jeremy </PERSON> <PERSON> Shearar </PERSON>, said <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> was the real threat to Namibian independence. In response to criticism of the continued South African presence in <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> said Tuesday it was confining former members of a feared police unit to base for retraining. But <PERSON> Gbeho </PERSON> said it was not good enough to place former members of the <LOCATION> Koevoet </LOCATION> police under <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> supervision. He said the veterans, who have been integrated into the South African-led Namibian police, should be fired. <LOCATION> Ghana </LOCATION>'s ambassador also said the proposed election laws are unfair because they allow white South Africans who worked or were born in <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> to register to vote there. <PERSON> Gbeho </PERSON> also objected to proposed Namibian laws that disqualify those convicted of crimes, including treason and sedition, from voting or being candidates for the constituent assembly. He said these provisions would bar many <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> leaders from running for assembly seats, and prevent <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> activists from voting. <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> has accused <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> of trying to manipulate November's pre-independence elections, which it is expected to win <PERSON> Shearar </PERSON> said it was a `` great pity'' the <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> had been convened by the Africans. He said fewer than 2,300 South Africans with Namibian citizenship had registered to vote so far. Up to 700,000 people are expected to vote. <PERSON> Shearar </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> poses the true threat to Namibian independence. He said that 1,900 armed <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> guerrillas entered <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> the day the U.N.-backed peace plan went into effect on April 1. Hundreds of guerrillas and dozens of soldiers and police died in subsequent fighting between <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> and the South African-led security forces.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890816-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-89 0006EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Anchorwoman-Fan 1stLd-Writethru a0767 08-16 0320</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Anchorwoman-Fan, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0767,0326</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fan Pleads Innocent To Threatening TV Anchorwoman</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 3rd graf to fix typo in `precious'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man who allegedly told a co-worker he was `` bored with life'' and that he was going to <LOCATION> Burbank </LOCATION> to shoot <ORGANIZATION> KNBC-TV </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> news </ORGANIZATION> anchorwoman <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> <PERSON> Lange </PERSON> pleaded innocent Tuesday to a terrorism charge. <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Sevy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON>, 57, was ordered held on $ 50,000 bail after he pleaded innocent to one felony count of making a terrorist threat, said Deputy District Attorney <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON> was arrested Friday after a co-worker at the downtown precious metals exchange where he worked reported hearing him threaten to kill Ms. <PERSON> Lange </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON> said. He told the co-worker that he was `` bored with life and that he was going to <LOCATION> Burbank </LOCATION> to shoot <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> <PERSON> Lange </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON> allegedly made the threat Wednesday, the day before he was fired from his job. <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON> wrote letters, made telephone calls and sent gifts to Ms. <PERSON> Lange </PERSON> for the last five years, <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON> said. The gifts were returned and she never met or spoke to <LOCATION> Hudson </LOCATION>, the prosecutor said. `` He was despondent. He felt she did n't understand him,'' <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON> said. `` He apparently had this love affair with her in his mind for several years.'' The case is the latest in a recent series of attacks or harassment of celebrities by fans. Among them was the slaying last month of actress <PERSON> Rebecca </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaeffer </PERSON>, allegedly killed by an <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> man described by police as an obsessed fan. A <ORGANIZATION> KNBC </ORGANIZATION> executive contacted the district attorney's office Thursday to report the threat, prompting police to locate <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON> and make the arrest the following day, authorities said. A .38 - caliber pistol and ammunition were found in the motel room where <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON> was arrested, police Ms. <PERSON> Lange </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> KNBC </ORGANIZATION> officials declined to comment on the case. A preliminary hearing for <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON> was scheduled for Aug. 25.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890816-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-89 2355EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Japan-US     08-16 0182</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-US,0188</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kaifu to Meet with Bush in September</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prime Minister <PERSON> Toshiki </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON> will travel to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to meet with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> next month, the Japanese government announced Thursday. An official in the <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON> will meet with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> on Sept. 1. The government has not yet confirmed details of the trip. Foreign Minister <PERSON> Taro </PERSON> <PERSON> Nakayama </PERSON> will accompany <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON>, said the official, who spoke on condition of anonymity. At the meeting, <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON> will reaffirm his government's commitment to maintaining good relations with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the official said. This will be the first time for the two leaders to meet and also <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON>'s first meeting with a foreign leader since becoming prime minister on Aug. 9. The 58-year-old <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON> took <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s highest office after Sousuke Uno stepped down to take responsibility for the governing <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>' crushing setback in parliamentary elections last month. A <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> official, speaking on condition of anonymity, said President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will interrupt a holiday at his home in <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, to meet with <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890816-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-89 0012EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TourismBust     08-16 0497</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tourism Bust,0512</SECOND>
<HEAD>State Says Ad To Make Chicago Tourism Boom Shows Too Much Bust</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM LITKE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It may be art, but <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> tourism officials could n't believe their eyes when an ad featuring an <PERSON> Alberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Vargas </PERSON> watercolor of a nude woman fondling her breasts beckoned Europeans to visit <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. Portrayed on the other side of the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> as home to seamy politics, bluesy music and gangsters, the city has long been viewed as a wide-open town. But this time, city and state officials concurred, someone went too far. `` We think there are a lot greater things that portray <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> better than a nude lady,'' said <PERSON> Avis </PERSON> <PERSON> LaVelle </PERSON>, spokeswoman for Mayor <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Daley </PERSON>. `` I'm sorry it happened,'' Gov. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said, `` but it was n't our fault.'' Developed for the <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> by the <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION>, Italy-based STZ agency, the ad featuring `` Legacy Nude No. 1'' was part of a 13-week campaign running in the European editions of Newsweek and Time. The campaign touts the city's world-class architecture, museums and business institutions, the <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> shoreline, its varied sports and vibrant nightlife. The Vargas painting was used in an ad promoting the city's magazine publishing community and was accompanied by copy inviting Europeans to `` Come to the city where Life was created -LRB- And Playboy, too. -RRB-'' and proclaiming `` A city once famous for its hogs gives birth to a bunny.'' <PERSON> Vargas </PERSON>' famous `` Varga Girl'' paintings appeared in <ORGANIZATION> Esquire </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- which also got its start in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> -RRB- and later <ORGANIZATION> Playboy </ORGANIZATION> from the 1930s through the 1960s. His works also are held by a number of private collectors. State officials recognized the <PERSON> Vargas </PERSON> painting was art, but they also knew they did n't like it as advertising. `` I do n't like to censor anything, and it was a picture done by a world-famous <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> artist of another time,'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said. `` But I thought the ad would be controversial and I did n't want folks talking about the ad. I wanted them talking about <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, so I said no, we are not going to run that.'' State officials subsequently contacted both magazines and directed them not to publish the ad. But a production assistant at Time inadvertently picked up the wrong copy and some 400,000 readers of the magazine's European edition received the unauthorized invitation, according to <PERSON> Marianne </PERSON> <PERSON> Floriano </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the state <ORGANIZATION> commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> department </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said Time officials apologized and agreed not to charge the state for the ad. But <ORGANIZATION> Playboy </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Tomcisin </PERSON> suggested the flap was much ado about nothing. `` We started here, we are the best-selling men's magazine in the world and <PERSON> Vargas </PERSON>' association with <ORGANIZATION> Playboy </ORGANIZATION> goes back a long way,'' she said. `` I think this whole thing just highlights the discrepancy between what Americans and Europeans find acceptable. `` We sell 5 -LCB- million copies worldwide, and over in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> without controversy. In fact,'' she added, `` we're considered kind of tame over there.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890816-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-89 0015EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PTLTrial     08-16 0864</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-PTL Trial,0889</SECOND>
<HEAD>After Revelations, Investigations, PTL Founder Bakker Goes On Trial</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL NOWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHARLOTTE, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After two years of revelations _ and a last-minute prosecution surprise _ <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> founder <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> faces trial on charges of using TV, telephones and the mail to defraud supporters out of millions of dollars. Jury selection in his fraud and conspiracy trial is set for Monday. Opening arguments are to begin one week later and the trial is expected to last at least six weeks, with dozens of witnesses and thousands of documents. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>, whose multimillion-dollar evangelical empire crumbled after word leaked about his sexual tryst with a church secretary, is charged in a 24-count indictment with diverting millions in <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> money to support a lavish lifestyle. If convicted on all counts, he could be sentenced to 120 years in prison and ordered to pay more than $ 5 million in fines. The case against <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> resulted from a 16-month federal grand jury investigation into <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>, which once boasted $ 129 million in revenue under his leadership. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Dortch </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>'s former top aide at the now-bankrupt television ministry and former co-defendant, agreed on Aug. 8 to plead guilty to four counts and to testify against <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>. <PERSON> Dortch </PERSON> pleaded guilty to one count of mail fraud, one count of wire fraud by telephone, one count of wire fraud by television and one count of conspiracy. `` It's got to have some effect -LRB- on the approach taken at trial -RRB-,'' one of <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>'s attorneys, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, said of <PERSON> Dortch </PERSON>'s testimony. `` But these kind of people who make these kinds of pleas are not always considered as credible as they might be.'' The <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> trial follows the tax evasion convictions of two former <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> aides, brothers <PERSON> David </PERSON> and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Taggart </PERSON>, in the same federal courtroom. The Taggarts' attorney, <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Cotten </PERSON>, said his clients would consider testifying against <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Taggart </PERSON>, who was <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>'s personal aide, and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Taggart </PERSON>, his former interior designer, are scheduled to be sentenced on Aug. 25 _ three days opening arguments in <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>'s trial. The Taggarts each face 25 years in prison and more than $ 1 million in fines when they are sentenced by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Potter </PERSON>, who also will preside over the upcoming <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> trial. They were convicted July 25. It's been more than two years since <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> stepped down as chairman of <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>, following revelations about his sexual encounter with secretary <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON> and hush money paid to her by <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>. The story broke in March 1987. Disclosures about <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>'s extravagant spending habits on homes, cards and jewelry, <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>'s bankruptcy proceedings, and charges of homosexuality by former <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> associates touched off an unprecedented `` holy war'' among some of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s most prominent televangelists, including <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Falwell </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON>. The federal grand jury heard testimony from more than 100 witnesses, reviewed thousands of documents and watched tapes of old `` <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>'' shows. Its Dec. 5 indictment came almost eight years to the day after <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> and Ms. <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON> had sex in a <LOCATION> Clearwater </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, hotel room _ Dec. 6, 1980. <PERSON> Dortch </PERSON> was accused of giving her $ 265,000 in <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> money in exchange for her silence. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> is charged with eight counts of mail fraud, 15 counts of wire fraud, and conspiracy to commit mail and wire fraud. Specifically, he is accused of pocketing some of the $ 158 million that poured into <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> from 1984 to 1987 under various `` lifetime partnership'' programs. In eight of the 11 programs, contributors were promised free lodging at the ministry's <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> retreat near <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION> in exchange for a one-time donation of $ 1,000 or more. Instead of using all of the money to build hotels and other facilities at <LOCATION> Heritage </LOCATION> <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION>, the indictment said, <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> executives spent more than $ 4 million on themselves and used some of it for operating expenses. All the while, <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> was suffering from severe cash-flow problems as <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> received nearly $ 3.5 million in bonuses from 1984 through 1987 and <PERSON> Dortch </PERSON> got $ 550,000 in bonuses. At the same time, they withheld informaton about <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>'s worsening financial problems from its board of directors, the indictment charged. <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> was not charged. Prosecutors <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, who works in the fraud section of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>, and Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> have declined to discuss details of the upcoming trial. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> and his defense attorneys also are mum, saying they believe it will be impossible to get a fair trial in <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION> because of extensive pretrial publicity, particularly in The Charlotte Observer. The newspaper won a Pulitizer Prize last year for its investigative stories about <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> under <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>'s leadership. He resigned when the Observer's editors told him they were prepared to go to print with a story spelling out the details of the sex-and-money scandal. Defense attorneys failed in their attempts to move the trial out of <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>'s lawyer, said the judge has said he believes it's possible to select a fair jury `` And if that's true, I ca n't think of anything we're more anxious to do than to go to trial,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890816-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-89 0016EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PTLChronology     08-16 0612</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-PTL Chronology,0638</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-PTL Trial</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a chronology of the major events involving <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> since his resignation as head of the Fort Mill, S.C.-based ministry and its <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> theme park:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>1987</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 March 19 _ <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> resigns amid sex and money scandal involving former <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> church secretary <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON>. The Rev. <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Falwell </PERSON> takes over as chairman of the board and <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Dortch </PERSON> becomes president of <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>. May 6 _ Assemblies of God leaders defrock <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dortch </PERSON>. June 12 _ <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> files for protection from creditors under Chapter 11 of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Bankruptcy Code. Oct. 8 _ <PERSON> Falwell </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> board of directors, the co-hosts of the `` PTL Show'' and other top executives resign from <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> during a dispute over bankruptcy reorganization plan and fears that <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> will be allowed to return. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> executive, becomes trustee. Dec. 22 _ <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Bankruptcy Judge <PERSON> Rufus </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> approves the ministry's bankruptcy plan, which divides <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> into separate ministerial and for-profit entities and involves a schedule for repaying creditors.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>1988</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Jan. 31 _ <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> sues <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> and his chief aide, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Taggart </PERSON>, for $ 52 million for recovery of unwarranted compensation and funds lost through mismanagement. April 22 _ The <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> revokes <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>'s tax-exempt status. May 20 _ <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> resigns as <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> trustee to become president of <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministries </ORGANIZATION>, the non-profit ministerial entity. Former <LOCATION> Winston-Salem </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, Mayor M.C. <PERSON> Benton </PERSON> becomes the new trustee. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> later resigns as president of <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministries </ORGANIZATION>. June 7 _ <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> return from <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, open an office for <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Ministries </PERSON> and move into a condominium paid for by supporters. Aug. 31 _ <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> and <PERSON> Benton </PERSON> agree on terms for <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> to buy <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION>, paving the way for <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>'s return as leader of <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>. Sept. 9 _ <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> misses deadline for $ 3 million deposit. <PERSON> Benton </PERSON> says he will no longer negotiate with <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>. Nov. 3 _ <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> notifies the <ORGANIZATION> Bakkers </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Taggart </PERSON> they are subjects of a grand jury investigation. Nov. 10 _ Reynolds rules that the <ORGANIZATION> Bakkers </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Taggart </PERSON> must pay $ 7.6 million in damages to <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>. Dec. 5 _ Federal grand jury hands up indictments of <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dortch </PERSON> on charges of mail fraud and wire fraud. They also are accused of conspiring to defraud ministry contributors to support extravagant lifestyles and of diverting more than $ 4 million in <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> money for their personal benefit. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> aides <PERSON> James </PERSON> and <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Taggert </PERSON> are charged with evading taxes, conspiring to impede the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> in tax collection, and using more than $ 1.1 million in <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> money for personal expenditures. Dec. 13 _ <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION> real estate magnate <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Mernick </PERSON>, an Orthodox Jew, buys the assets of <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> for $ 65 million at a hearing before Judge Reynolds.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>1989</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 January _ The <ORGANIZATION> Bakkers </ORGANIZATION> begin broadcasting `` The Jim and <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> Show'' from their leased home in <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>. Feb. 13 _ <PERSON> Mernick </PERSON> assumes joint management of the <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> property with a bankruptcy trustee but title questions delay the sale's closing. March 29 _ <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> arrives at a <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> retreat for ministers, but continues to tape his program. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> had to cease his broadcasts from his <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION> home since they violated zoning ordinances. May 8 _ The <ORGANIZATION> Bakkers </ORGANIZATION> broadcast `` The <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> Show'' live from their new studio in a boarded-up department store in a nearly abandoned mall in southwest <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>. July 25 _ The <PERSON> Taggart </PERSON> brothers are convicted of tax evasion charges Aug. 8 _ <PERSON> Dortch </PERSON> agrees to plead guilty four counts _ mail fraud, wire fraud by telephone, wire fraud by television and conspiracy _ and testify against <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890816-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-89 0017EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-QuebecIndependence     08-16 0791</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quebec Independence,0813</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quebec Separatist Issue Back in Canadian Politics</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SOLL SUSSMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MONTREAL (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A public opinion poll has thrust the issue of Quebec independence back into the Canadian political arena, although Quebeckers rejected separatism in a referendum nearly a decade ago. The Gallup poll indicated that 28 percent of Canadians believe French-speaking <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION> should become an independent country. According to Gallup, it was the strongest support for separatism nationally since the company's pollsters first asked the question more than 20 years ago. Perhaps the most startling finding of the poll of 1,034 Canadians was that 27 percent of English-speaking Canadians and 36 percent of French-speaking Canadians favored <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION>'s becoming a separate nation. There long has been resentment in parts of English-speaking <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, especially in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>, of what is perceived as favoritism or special treatment for Quebec. But the percentage of those who would just as soon see it separate from <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> had not been perceived to be as high as the poll indicated. Prime Minister <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON>, a native of <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION>, brushed the poll findings aside. `` The heartbeat of the nation is strong, it's vigorous and it's resolved to even greater unity,'' he said `` It's kind of silly to ask Canadians whether they want to divide their country or to strip their country. The answer, when you strip away the varnish, is absolutely ` no.''' <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> conceded that some linguistic tensions exist in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> but said that always has been the case. Indeed, a focus in the Canadian news media on the national unity issue may be as much a result of a languid summer without much else attracting attention as to any concrete developments in <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION>. Premier <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Bourassa </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION>, who opposes separatism, appears virtually certain to win the election expected in early fall, possibly with an even greater margin of victory for his provincial <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> than in 1985 when it won 99 of 122 seats in the <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION> legislature. The <LOCATION> Parti </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Quebecois </LOCATION>, which found success with its separatist message in the 1970s, has fallen on hard times, and the economic prosperity that has lasted in <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION> along with most of <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> for seven years makes this an unlikely time for a comeback. Quebec, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>'s largest and second most populous province with 6.5 million people, is 81 percent French-speaking. No one is predicting a new surge of the separatist movement. The poll results were a reminder of how intractable the French-English issues are in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and the difficulties of running a country in which nine provinces are majority English-speaking and one French-speaking. Among those expessing unease, however, was <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, the retiring leader of the naional <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, which sits in opposition to <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON>'s Progressive Conservatives. `` I have, during the course of the last six or nine months, experienced and felt a deterioration in the mood of the country,'' <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> said. `` I believe all those who share with me the view of a tolerant, bilingual federation working in equilibrium should be concerned.'' Quebec barely surfaced as an issue in the national election this past November when the big issue was the free trade agreement with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON>'s victory allowed the pact to take effect as scheduled Jan. 1, and <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION> was a center of support for the agreement and its native son. <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON>'s Progressive Conservatives do not run in <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION>'s provincial elections. But the <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION> government's refusal last winter to remove its restrictions on bilingual signs despite a <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canada </ORGANIZATION> decision touched off resentment among the province's English minority and in English-speaking provinces. French is required throughout <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION> as the only language on most outdoor signs. There also has been growing realization that the <ORGANIZATION> Meech </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lake </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accord </ORGANIZATION>, a constitutional agreement recognizing <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION> as a `` distinct society,'' may not make its deadline on June 23 for ratification by all 10 provinces. The <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> coast province of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Brunswick </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Manitoba </LOCATION> in the West have yet to ratify the agreement, and threats have been made to reconsider ratification elsewhere before the deadline. The Meech Lake Accord developed because <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION> had refused to join the nine other provinces in signing the national constitution at the outset of the decade. The constitution still applies to <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION> even without its signature, but the impasse makes it more difficult for changes to be made on such national issues as native rights and the way the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> operates. <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION> voters rejected sovereignty in a 1980 referendum after a dizzying decade in which power shifted from the English minority to the French majority. The <LOCATION> Parti </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Quebecois </LOCATION> governed the province from 1976 to 1985 but lost its spirit after 60 percent of <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION>'s voters in the 1980 referendum rejected separation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890816-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-89 0019EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Lebanon-Life     08-16 1184</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lebanon-Life,1225</SECOND>
<HEAD>Life Has Become a Nightmare in Beirut's Ruins</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Once-bustling <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, emptied of most of its population, is now filled with despair. Those who remain can do little but wait for the end. Here is a report on how they survive under a constant rain of shells.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By RODEINA KENAAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIRUT, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After five months of day and night shelling by <PERSON> Christian </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Syrian </LOCATION> forces, <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> has been abandoned by 90 percent of its people. It is a living hell for those who still huddle in its ruins. `` We're living like rats underground, hiding in fear in shelters for endless days and nights,'' lamented <PERSON> Salwa </PERSON> <PERSON> Ashkar </PERSON>, a 22-year-old <ORGANIZATION> Maronite </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> woman who runs a beauty parlor in Christian east <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. `` We ca n't take much more.'' Across the capital's dividing <ORGANIZATION> Green </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Line </ORGANIZATION>, a moonscape of devastated apartment blocks infested by snipers, life is as desperate for the Moslems as well as the Christians. `` We're going down the drain,'' said <PERSON> Mahmoud </PERSON> <PERSON> Shami </PERSON>, an engineering graduate from the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION> who has no job and no future. `` I'm trying to get out. Anywhere. I'll go to any country that will give me a visa,'' said <PERSON> Shami </PERSON>, 24. Hospitals are running out of medicine. There's no electricity or water. The presidential palace atop a hill overlooking <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> in the Christian suburb of <LOCATION> Baabda </LOCATION>, like most buildings, has been blasted into rubble. Packs of stray dogs, their ribs poking through their sides, scavenge through the piles of fly-infested garbage in the streets. Rats, some as big as cats, scamper through the stinking mounds that lie feastering in the summer heat on nearly every alley corner. Beneath the rubble-strewn streets, where power cables cut by shrapnel dangle from splintered wooden poles, the estimated 150,000 Beirutis who cling to what is left of their lives cower for days on end in underground bunkers or basement parking lots from the bombardment. Apartment building tenants crowd ground-floor entrances to cook whatever they have on makeshift stoves. Housewives hand out the meager fare. The men venture out when they can to forage wood or anything that will burn. There is nothing but despair. After 14 years of civil war, an <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> invasion and murderous street battles between rival militias, surviving one day to the next is all Beirutis can expect. The capital's radio stations cut into programs to report which areas are being hit _ in between commercial breaks with bouncy jingles advertising scotch or hairsprays that seem grotesquely out of place. The police, who long ago lost all hope of maintaining law and order in a country that seemed bent on self-destruction, chronicle <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s daily disasters with painstaking dedication. They estimate that more than 1.3 million of the 1.5 million people who lived in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> before the latest spasm of fighting between the Christians and the Syrians broke out March 8 have fled the city. Every day in Moslem west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, when the shelling eases, people emerge from the bunkers, load up cars and pickups with whatever they can carry, and head south. Some find shelter with relatives. But tens of thousands have to camp out along the coastal highway as they did when they fled the Israeli siege of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> in 1982. They sleep in their cars or under plastic sheets. For miles along the highway, these refugees in their own land squat beside the road, listening to the rumble of shellfire to the north ripping their city apart. In east <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, the Christians are not so lucky. Their 310-square-mile enclave, shrunken after years of defeats in the civil war, is ringed to the north, south and east by the Syrians and their allies. The only way out is by sea, past a Syrian blockade on ships bound for <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>. Not everyone makes it. A Christian couple lost their two daughters a few nights ago when Syrian shellfire hit the speedboat ferrying them to a Norwegian-owned hydrofoil, the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Maria </LOCATION>, that sneaks in at night. The parents were separated when they were pulled from the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> by the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Maria </LOCATION>'s crew. Both thought the other had the children. It was n't until they reached the <LOCATION> Cypriot </LOCATION> port of <LOCATION> Larnaca </LOCATION> hours later that they bumped into each other and learned their children had been killed. Many Christians had fled to the comparative safety of ski resorts of <LOCATION> Faraya </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Harajel </PERSON> and Ashkout in the pine-studded central mountains. But it it expensive: A two-room apartment rents for about $ 1,800 a month. Some Beirutis have stuck it out. Some have nowhere to go. Some have no money to get out. Some have just given up and wait for the end. <PERSON> Gaby </PERSON>, the Armenian who has had a barber shop in the basement of the Commodore Hotel for 15 years, is still there. He used to have hundreds of customers a month, sipping scotch as he clipped their hair. Now he's lucky if he gets a dozen. His best customers in the ruined hotel, once headquarters for the foreign press, are the 30 Syrian soldiers billeted there. If he's lucky, they sometimes leave a tip `` Mostly they do n't bother paying,'' he said. `` What can I do? There's nowhere for me to go anymore.'' The Christians, paralyzed by a fuel shortage because of the blockade, line up at gas stations. Gas canisters for cooking cost about $ 21. In more peaceful times they cost $ 1. In the Moslem sector, fuel is more plentiful, although still scarce. Oil and gas are brought in from <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>, but even that's becoming risky because the Christians are shelling the mountain roads used by Syrian convoys <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s cafes and restaurants, once the haunt of high-rolling Arab sheiks and their bejeweled women, are closed: no customers, no power, no water. A few bistros open briefly during lulls along rubble-strewn <LOCATION> Hamra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION>, the main commercial thoroughfare that once bustled with life. But few risk sitting down for a coffee when a shell could blow them away at any minute. Along west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s corniche, the Syrians have set up artillery guns that shell the Christian side across the bay. They have become a favorite target for Christian gunners, which makes for dangerous living in the apartment blocks lining the corniche. Government offices, banks, businesses are closed. What was left of the government system after years of fighting has ceased to function. No one is being paid. Schools have been closed for months. Parents teach children at home, often in the shelters during shelling. Central Bank Governor <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON> <PERSON> Naim </PERSON> lives in the building's underground bunker and refuses to answer the telephone _ even when it is functioning _ because the bank is n't operating Christian leader Gen. <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> huddles in his bunker two floors below the presidential palace, which has been demolished by Syrian shellfire. <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> <PERSON> Khoury </PERSON>, <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>'s spokesman, said the two-story, 35-room complex has been hit by 10 240mm mortar rounds, designed to knock out army bunkers, and scores of 180mm shells. `` They try every day to blow us away, but we're still here,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890816-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-89 0021EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Lebanon-Forces     08-16 0769</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lebanon-Forces,0792</SECOND>
<HEAD>Brief Sketches of Various Factions in Lebanon</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Lebanon</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a rundown of the main military forces and militia factions involved in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s civil war:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> AMAL </ORGANIZATION> _ Arabic for <PERSON> Hope </PERSON>, is the mainstream Shiite Moslem faction that controls most of southern <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. It was founded in 1974 as a social movement seeking better living standards for the million-strong Shiites, <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s largest single faction. Its leader is French-educated lawyer <PERSON> Nabih </PERSON> <PERSON> Berri </PERSON>. Although a close ally of <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Amal </ORGANIZATION>'s 6,500 fighters have stayed out of the latest confrontation between Syrian forces and <LOCATION> Lebanese </LOCATION> army christian units.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 THE PROGRESSIVE SOCIALIST PARTY _ The militia force of the Druse, an offshoot of Islam based in the <LOCATION> Chouf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> mountains </LOCATION> <LOCATION> east </LOCATION> and southeast of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. The party is led by <PERSON> Walid </PERSON> <PERSON> Jumblatt </PERSON> who is from the largest clan among the 200,000-strong Druse community. The Progressive Socialists have about 100 Soviet-made tanks and 4,000 hardcore fighters but can field up to 12,000. The party has been fighting alongside the Syrians.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 HEZBOLLAH _ The <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> God </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> is </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Amal </ORGANIZATION>'s main Shiite rival and seeks an Iranian-style Islamic republic in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. It controls <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s southern slums. The Iranian-backed party, formed in 1982, has some 3,500 fighters. <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> is believed to be the umbrella group for extremist <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> factions holding most of the 16 foreign hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. It has declared support for the Syrian units in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> but has not joined the battle.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 THE MOURABITOUN _ The main militia force of the Sunni Moslems before it was smashed by <ORGANIZATION> Amal </ORGANIZATION>, aided by the <ORGANIZATION> Progressive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialists </ORGANIZATION>, in April 1985. It has gone underground since then, leaving the <LOCATION> Sunnis </LOCATION> without any significant militia force.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 THE LEBANESE ARMY _ It has been fractured along sectarian lines. The mainly Christian units, with an estimated 20,000 men, are led by army commander Gen. <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Maronite </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION>. His three combat brigades are <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trained and equipped with U.S.-built tanks and artillery. They are the main force defending the Christian areas around <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. The Moslem military forces, with an estimated 22,000 soldiers, are commanded by Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Sami </PERSON> <PERSON> Khatib </PERSON>. These brigades, made up of Druse, <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> and Sunni troops, have stayed out of the latest fighting.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 THE LEBANESE FORCES _ Led by former medical student <PERSON> Samir </PERSON> <PERSON> Geagea </PERSON>, it is the Christians' main militia. The right-wing force has some 6,000 fighters and thousands more reservists. The force has pro-Israeli leanings and is well armed with tanks and artillery. In the past year it has received an estimated 120 tanks plus armored personnel carriers and 155mm artillery from <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>'s main Arab foe. The Lebanese Forces are <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>'s only backers.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 THE <ORGANIZATION> PALESTINE </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> LIBERATION </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> ORGANIZATION </ORGANIZATION> _ Comprised of about 5,000 guerrillas and thousands of reservists based in camps in southern <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s loyalists, who make up the bulk of the force, have stayed out of the current fighting but pro-Syrian dissidents have joined forces with <PERSON> Jumblatt </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Progressive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. They include some 1,000 fighters from the <ORGANIZATION> Popular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> for the <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palestine-General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>, headed by former Syrian army Capt. <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> Jibril </PERSON>, and Col. <PERSON> Saeed </PERSON> <PERSON> Mousa </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Fatah-Uprising </ORGANIZATION>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 SYRIAN TROOPS _ They first entered <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> in 1976 as part of an Arab League peacekeeping force. The non-Syrian units soon pulled out. The Syrians initially sought to curb Moslem factions, but wound up fighting the Christians in later years. The Syrians, with more than two divisions _ about 40,000 troops with hundreds of tanks and heavy artillery _ in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, control about 70 percent of Lebanese territory. They are blocking all land exits from the 310-square-mile Christian heartland.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 THE <LOCATION> SOUTH </LOCATION> <LOCATION> LEBANON </LOCATION> ARMY _ Supported by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, the army is mainly Christian and holds a salient around the mountain town of <LOCATION> Marjayoun </LOCATION> in south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. Its estimated 2,500 fighters also patrol <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s self-declared `` security zone,'' an occupied border strip running from the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hermon </LOCATION> The army often engages Moslem and leftist militia groups in clashes in south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> but has no force close to the battle lines in and around <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> ISRAEL </LOCATION> _ It maintains about 1,000 troops, with armor and artillery, in the buffer zone carved out when the Israelis withdrew the bulk of their army from <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> in 1985, three years after it invaded that country.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> IRAN </LOCATION> _ It has some 2,000 men from the <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> in the Syrian-controlled <LOCATION> Bekaa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> in east <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. They moved in to fight the invading Israelis in 1982. They have not been involved in the latest fighting, although <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> has declared support for <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890816-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-89 0617EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--WomanJustice     08-16 0170</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Woman Justice,0174</SECOND>
<HEAD>Don't Tell Women's Caucus, But Montana Court Appointment is a First</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HELENA, Mont. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>'s first female <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> justice was named to the bench just this week, no matter what the National Women's Political Caucus directory says. The organization listed Chief Justice <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Turnage </PERSON> as one of the women holding top elective offices around the country, in its National Directory of Women Elected Officials. Trouble is, <PERSON> Turnage </PERSON> is a man. His first name, French for <PERSON> John </PERSON>, has been Anglicized. <PERSON> Turnage </PERSON> said his name has n't caused him problems in recent years, but he recalled receiving written invitations to join sororities when he was in college. `` I once knew a guy named <PERSON> Pearl </PERSON>, but I never knew a boy called Sue,'' he joked Monday. The women's caucus will be able to cite one female justice on the state's <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in its next directory, though. Gov. <PERSON> Stan </PERSON> <PERSON> Stephens </PERSON> on Monday appointed <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Barz </PERSON>, a state district judge in Billings, to fill a vacancy on the bench.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890816-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-89 0034EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ElvisVigil 1stLd-Writethru a0744 08-16 0461</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Elvis Vigil, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0744,0465</SECOND>
<HEAD>Elvis Fans Stream Past His Grave in Annual Vigil</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Eds: LEADS with 9 grafs to UPDATE with vigil. Picks up 12th graf
pvs, `Graceland and...' ^By WOODY BAIRD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEMPHIS, Tenn.(AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hundreds of <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> <PERSON> Presley </PERSON> faithful walked with candles up a winding quarter-mile driveway to his former mansion Tuesday night to pass the singer's grave and mark the 12th anniversary of his death. The crowd walked single file and carried candles lit from an eternal flame at the mansion, called Graceland. Many left single roses at Presley's graveside beside the swimming pool. The rock' n' roll pioneer died Aug. 16, 1977 `` He just had everything,'' said <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> <PERSON> Cousins </PERSON>, who waited on a sidewalk for 13 hours to be first in line for the procession. `` He had looks. He had charisma. He had everything.'' The candlelight vigil, expected to draw more than 4,000 participants through the night, is the largest single event of a nine-day lineup of concerts, memorials, trivia contests, film festivals and souvenir fairs that make up Elvis International Tribute Week. The 7-year-old Tribute Week is organized and promoted by managers of <PERSON> Presley </PERSON>'s former residence, Graceland, which draws 650,000 visitors a year, including some 40,000 over the anniversary celebration, said <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Soden </PERSON>, executive director of the Graceland division of <ORGANIZATION> Elvis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Presley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprises </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc </ORGANIZATION>. The vigil was begun 11 years ago by the <ORGANIZATION> Elvis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Country </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, one of more than 250 Presley fan clubs around the world. <PERSON> Georgann </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, president of the Elvis Country club, said her group has more than 1,200 members worldwide, many of whom are too young to have been Presley fans when he was alive. She said she expects the annual graveside vigils to continue for years to come. `` One reason for a fan club is to pass the torch, to keep the candle burning,'' she said. Ms. Cousins, 38, of <LOCATION> Winnipeg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, said her daylong wait to be first in line was worth it. It was the third year in a row that she and her friend-in-Elvis <PERSON> Sheryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Fordin </PERSON>, 38, of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, have been at the front of the procession. Graceland and its 36,000-square-foot souvenir shopping center take in about $ 12 million a year. The complex is run for the financial benefit of Presley's only child, <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Marie </PERSON>. Tickets to tour the house, two of <PERSON> Presley </PERSON>'s former airplanes and a museum of his cars and motorcycles cost $ 15.95 each for adults and $ 10.25 for children. A tour of the house alone is $ 7.50. Presley bought the three-story, white-columned residence in 1957 when his rock' n' roll career began to blossom, and he called <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> home for most of his professional life. Presley died at age 42 of heart disease.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890816-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-89 0038EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PreschoolMolest     08-16 0824</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Preschool Molest,0847</SECOND>
<HEAD>Marathon Trial Is `Cottage Industry Event' in Bloated Justice System</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LINDA DEUTSCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A defense attorney sees the McMartin preschool molestation trial as `` a cottage industry event'' and legal experts say its protracted length is symptomatic of a bloated, unworkable justice system. With the trial in its third year and the charges against <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckey </PERSON> and his mother 6 years old, the <PERSON> McMartin </PERSON> case has set records in criminal law. And it's not over yet. In April, the trial became the longest in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> history, surpassing the two-year record of the Hillside Strangler case. Its cost was estimated recently at $ 15 million and climbing. `` This trial has become a cottage industry event,'' said <PERSON> Buckey </PERSON>'s attorney <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> `` It made experts out of people who testified. It became an annuity for attorneys. It has regularly been a ratings focus for television. ... Lots of carpet baggers glom on and make hay.'' The chief prosecutor, Deputy District Attorney <PERSON> Lael </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON>, says that although <PERSON> McMartin </PERSON> is the longest trial it's not that unusual. `` I would say that in many respects the <PERSON> McMartin </PERSON> case is like other cases that take much too long to go through the system and come to a conclusion,'' she said. Ms. <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> blames the defense for the trial's length, citing interminable cross-examinations. She says 80 percent of the 14 months she spent presenting her case was taken up by defense inquiries. The defense blames the prosecution. `` <PERSON> McMartin </PERSON> is a case that may have been doomed to excesses,'' <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> says. `` It started in excess. Its core defect was numbers _ numbers of counts, numbers of defendants, numbers of children. Whatever you think of guilt or innocence, there was no necessity to bring such a large case.'' It began with <PERSON> Buckey </PERSON>'s arrest in 1983 and escalated to include six other teachers at the prestigious McMartin Pre-school in the seaside community of <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>. Prosecutors alleged that <PERSON> Buckey </PERSON>, his mother, sister, grandmother and three other women teachers had molested hundreds of tots at the school over five years. But after an 18-month preliminary hearing, District Attorney <PERSON> Ira </PERSON> <PERSON> Reiner </PERSON> dropped charges against five of the defendants, saying there was insufficient evidence to prosecute them. <PERSON> Buckey </PERSON>, now 31, and his mother, <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> McMartin </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckey </PERSON>, 62, were left to face trial on 64 counts of molestation and a shared count of conspiracy involving alleged molestation of 11 children. Since the trial began in April 1987, the jury of 12 with a backup panel of six alternates has been dwindling due to illness and employment problems. With only one alternate left, <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Pounders </PERSON> worries that the case will be aborted if more jurors are lost. A jury of 12 is required to decide a criminal case. `` It is a probability this case will end in a mistrial,'' <PERSON> Pounders </PERSON> said recently, vowing to do everything he can to avert that. He has limited defense witnesses and lengthened the trial day to six hours. Attorneys hope to submit the case to jurors this year. `` The system ca n't survive too many more McMartins because it's so long and expensive,'' says <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Aranella </PERSON>, professor of criminal law at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <PERSON> Aranella </PERSON> suggests that the time and money consumed by such a case reduces the chance for other defendants to receive trials. In order to work, he said, the system must rely on plea bargaining to dispose of 80 percent to 90 percent of criminal prosecutions. `` The adversarial trial system is too time consuming, cumbersome and expensive to provide to every criminal defendant,'' he said. `` That's a fact of life that every actor in the criminal justice system understands.'' `` The irony,'' <PERSON> Aranella </PERSON> says, `` is that as long as the system can rely on plea bargaining to settle the majority of criminal prosecutions, we can go on for a long time with these occasional show trials.'' The national trend is toward longer and longer trials, says <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Alschuler </PERSON>, professor of law at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> who calls the length of the <PERSON> McMartin </PERSON> case `` incomprehensible.'' `` American trials are just ridiculously too long with the result that we do n't give them to everyone,'' he said. `` We pressure almost all defendants into plea bargains.'' <PERSON> Alschuler </PERSON>, citing legal history, says trials have been growing in length for the last century. `` I think it was the late 18th century when the first criminal trial lasted longer than a day,'' he said. `` ... It's been a gradual process of increasing trial complexity.'' Ms. <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> thinks that <PERSON> McMartin </PERSON> will lead to reforms with legislators moving to limit the length of jury selection and preliminary hearings. But <PERSON> Alschuler </PERSON> sees little chance for reform. `` This is a great system for lawyers, and lawyers control the criminal justice system,'' <PERSON> Alschuler </PERSON> said. `` It's not a great system for defendants and taxpayers. But, by <PERSON> God </PERSON>, it's a great system for lawyers.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890816-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-89 0039EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Vatican-Jews     08-16 0886</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Vatican-Jews,0912</SECOND>
<HEAD>Disputes Over Auschwitz, Covenant Hurt Jewish-Catholic Relations</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEPHEN R. WILSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Relations between Roman Catholics and Jews have suffered new setbacks that threaten long-term efforts aimed at mending centuries of mistrust and misunderstanding. Officials on both sides are appealing for moderation to deal with the disputes involving a Roman Catholic convent at <LOCATION> Auschwitz </LOCATION> and Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>'s recent remarks about God's covenant with the Jews, in which he said history showed <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> had not always been faithful to God's law. While expressing anger and disappointment, Jewish leaders in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> said relations with the church have improved substantially since the 1962-65 Second Vatican Council, and they want to continue the interfaith dialogue. `` Our relations have to overcome 2,000 years of misunderstanding,'' said Rabbi <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Klenicki </PERSON>, director of interfaith affairs of the Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and the group's liaison representative to the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION>. `` You ca n't do it in 20 years What is crucial is to continue the dialogue and the relationship.'' It has been a bumpy relationship during the 10 -LCB- - year papacy of <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> Rabbi <PERSON> Marc </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tanenbaum </PERSON>, former chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jewish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interreligious </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Consultations </ORGANIZATION>, said relations have gone `` two steps forward, one step backward.'' The steps forward included <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>'s visit to <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>'s main synagogue in 1986, the first recorded visit by a pope to a Jewish shrine, and his talks with a delegation of American Jews in 1987. A step backward was the pope's meeting at the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> in 1982 with <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>. Then came the pope's audience in 1987 with Austrian President <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON> <PERSON> Waldheim </PERSON>, accused of complicity in Nazi war crimes. The Holocaust has been a particular source of friction. Jews and others have questioned whether <PERSON> Pope </PERSON> <PERSON> Pius </PERSON> <PERSON> XII </PERSON> did enough during World War II to stop <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>'s campaign to exterminate the Jews. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> was criticized for not mentioning Jewish victims during his 1988 visit to the <LOCATION> Mauthausen </LOCATION> concentration camp in <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>, although a few weeks later he spoke of the `` particular measure of extermination'' suffered by Jews. In a 1987 papal letter released in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> said Christians `` approach with fearsome respect the terrifying experience of the extermination ... suffered by the Jews'' during the war. Still, some Jewish groups say the pope has not gone far enough and that he treats the Holocaust as not exclusively a Jewish tragedy. Nobel laureate <PERSON> Elie </PERSON> <PERSON> Wiesel </PERSON>, a Holocaust survivor and author, recently accused <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> of trying to `` de-Judaize'' the Holocaust by ignoring Jewish suffering in speeches and comments about that era. The Holocaust is at the root of the latest dispute, which involves a Carmelite convent at <LOCATION> Oswiecim </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, a few feet from the fence surrounding the <LOCATION> Auschwitz </LOCATION> concentration camp. Jewish groups say the convent and its Christian symbols, such as a 23-foot cross, offend the memory of the 2.5 million Jews who died there. Under an accord signed by <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Jewish </PERSON> leaders in 1987, the nuns were supposed to have moved by Feb. 22 to a prayer center to be built several thousand yards away. The deadline passed, and the center has yet to be built. Jewish groups accused the Polish church of reneging. `` What was supposed to be and should have been a discreet and loving gesture of conciliation and reconciliation, because of delays has become a stumbling block on the path of Jewish-Catholic relations,'' said <PERSON> Tullia </PERSON> <PERSON> Zevi </PERSON>, president of the Union of Italian Jewish Communities and a signatory to the 1987 accord. After a series of demonstrations at the convent by American Jewish activists, Cardinal <PERSON> Franciszek </PERSON> <PERSON> Macharski </PERSON> announced Aug. 10 he was suspending the agreement to move the nuns. He blamed Western Jewish groups for launching `` a violent campaign of accusations and slanders'' and creating an `` atmosphere of aggressive demands.'' Many Jews want the pope to intervene. The pope himself sparked a controversy with his remarks during two recent general audiences about God's covenant with <PERSON> Moses </PERSON> on <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sinai </LOCATION>. On Aug. 2, the <PERSON> pope </PERSON> said God selected Jews as the chosen people `` on condition that they remained faithful to his law.'' `` But the history of the Old Testament shows many instances of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s infidelity to God,'' he said. `` Hence God sent the Prophets as his messengers to call the people to conversion, to warn them of their hardness of heart and to foretell a new covenant still to come.'' The Anti-Defamation League of B'Nai B'rith protested, expressing `` profound concern'' at the comments and said it hoped the `` clock of Catholic-Jewish relations has not been tragically set back.'' The group said the <PERSON> pope </PERSON>'s remarks suggested the new covenant with Christianity had replaced and superseded the alliance with Jews, who believe that God's covenant with them is everlasting. Jewish leaders said the <PERSON> pope </PERSON>'s remarks contradicted the <ORGANIZATION> Second </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vatican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>'s 1965 document Nostra Aetate -LRB- In Our Times -RRB-, which officially rescinded the accusation that the Jews killed Christ. That document is considered a turning point in Catholic-Jewish relations. The Rev. Pier <PERSON> Francesco </PERSON> <PERSON> Fumagalli </PERSON>, an official of the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION>'s office for relations with Jews, confirmed he received the Anti-Defamation League's letter of protest and said it would be studied Otherwise, the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> has not commented publicly on the issue.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890816-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-89 0041EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-LynnFire     08-16 0169</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Lynn Fire,0173</SECOND>
<HEAD>Investigators Uncover Fourth Body from Amid Charred Rooming House
Rubble</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LYNN, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Investigators uncovered a fourth body Tuesday from the rubble at a charred rooming house, the site of a fatal fire officials believe was triggered by an arsonist. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connell </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Essex </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> Attorney <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Burke </PERSON>, said authorities located the body on the <LOCATION> Ben </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crest </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plaza </LOCATION>'s top floor about 3:30 p.m. `` What happened is in the course of re-interviewing witnesses the detectives determined they should go back to the building and search a particular area. On doing so, the body was found,'' <PERSON> O'Connell </PERSON> said. The victim was not immediately identified, but forensics experts were were being consulted, <PERSON> O'Connell </PERSON> said. He said so far no suspects had been linked with the fire, which burned out of control for three hours a week ago and killed at least three other people. Authorities said the building had several safety violations. Investigators were still tracking down leads in the case, <PERSON> O'Connell </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890816-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-89 0051EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-LibelSuit     08-16 0348</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Libel Suit,0356</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Exec Files $80 Million Libel Suit Against Business Week</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOINA CHIACU</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CONCORD, N.H. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The former chief executive for <ORGANIZATION> Allegheny </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> has filed an $ 80 million libel suit against <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Week </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> magazine </ORGANIZATION>, claiming a defamatory cover story cost him his job and reputation. The lawsuit filed in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> said false statements about <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON>'s business dealings and professional competency were made in the Aug. 11, 1986, issue of the magazine published by <ORGANIZATION> McGraw-Hill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> `` He was the featured cover article in a national publication, he was held up to ridicule and scorn, he was accused falsely of ruining the company and he lost his position at the company as a direct result of this and follow-up articles,'' <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON>'s lawyer, <PERSON> Dort </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bigg </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Manchester </LOCATION>, said Tuesday. The suit also cites a July 3, 1989, article that mentions <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON> in another cover story on corporate directors under the heading `` Horror Stories.'' <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON> was fired as <PERSON> Allegheny </PERSON>'s chief executive officer shortly after the 1986 article hit the newsstands and the Pittsburgh-based appliance manufacturer later went bankrupt. <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON> has been unemployed since then, <PERSON> Bigg </PERSON> said. `` He has found it virtually impossible to pursue the type of business dealings it was his experience and his pleasure to pursue,'' <PERSON> Bigg </PERSON> said. `` He has been seriously damaged economically and in the national and world business community.'' <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON>'s son, <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON>, currently has a lawsuit pending against the publishing house in federal court in <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, claiming he was defamed in the 1986 story. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON> initially filed his libel suit in a <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> court in 1986, but dropped it after <ORGANIZATION> McGraw-Hill </ORGANIZATION> moved the state court action to federal court, <PERSON> McGraw </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> attorney <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Vittor </PERSON> said. `` We feel it has no merit. We stand by our story,'' said <PERSON> Betsy </PERSON> <PERSON> Russo </PERSON>, director of public affairs for <ORGANIZATION> McGraw-Hill </ORGANIZATION>. `` The story was exhaustively researched and we intend to vigorously defend it.'' <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON> filed his suit in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> on July 28, only days before the state's three-year statute of limitations ran out, <PERSON> Bigg </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890816-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-89 0106EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     08-16 0921</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0957</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gen. <PERSON> Colin </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> said goodbye to <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>'s business and government leaders at a reception commemorating his short stint as commander-in-chief for Forces Command at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> McPherson </LOCATION> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>, who was nominated last week to serve as chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chiefs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Staff </ORGANIZATION>, said he enjoyed his four-month stint at the <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> post. `` I leave here loaded with Southern hospitality,'' he said Tuesday. <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Atlanta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>, presented a picture of the symbol of <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> Rising, inscribed to <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>, `` who was in our midst the shortest time of any Forscom Commander but will leave the longest shadow.'' Mayor <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> praised <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> for his work as former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s national security adviser, saying he was `` the last person the president talked to before he made a decision and he made some very good decisions on your watch.'' `` We really hate to see you go,'' <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said, `` but we could n't find anybody better to entrust our military to.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former `` Charlie's Angels'' TV star <PERSON> Kate </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> underwent cancer surgery in which doctors removed a malignant part of her breast, a spokeswoman said. Miss <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, 40, was resting comfortably at an undisclosed <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles-area </LOCATION> hospital and `` her prognosis is excellent,'' publicist <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Kasteler </PERSON> said Tuesday. Surgeons performed a modified mastectomy and reconstructive plastic surgery, <PERSON> Kasteler </PERSON> said. `` I'm making this disclosure public in order to help other women facing this difficult situation, encourage early detection of breast disease through mammography and to save inquiring minds 50 cents,'' Miss <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said in a statement. The actress, who starred in the movie `` Making Love'' and the short-lived 1989 television series `` Baby Boom'' on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, will return to work Sept. 6 in a still-untitled television movie for <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, her publicist said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Candy </PERSON> loves his wisecracking roles in comedy films, but he regards viewing his own movies as a horror. `` I do n't watch my movies,'' the hefty actor said. `` I just get too critical of myself.'' Candy, who got his start in television with `` SCTV,'' said he watches daily prints during shooting and often views rough-cut versions. But he wo n't go further in fear of second-guessing his performances and editing room decisions. `` You get frustrated thinking, ` I would do this and I would do that,''' he said. `` Instead of putting myself through that, I do n't even bother with it anymore. Candy plays an irresponsible bachelor baby-sitting his brother's children in `` Uncle Buck. The film, scheduled for release this week, is his third collaboration with moviemaker <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Jill </PERSON> <PERSON> Ireland </PERSON>, whose battle with cancer was described in two best-selling books, is `` pretty much stable, looking good and feeling good,'' her publicist said. `` The cancer has not recurred in her neck and shoulder,'' publicist <PERSON> Lori </PERSON> <PERSON> Jonas </PERSON> said Tuesday. `` She is undergoing chemotherapy and still has the catheter in her chest. But she is doing very well.'' The English-born actress, wife of movie star <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Bronson </PERSON>, first underwent surgery for removal of a cancerous right breast and eight lymph nodes under her arm in 1984. She wrote about the ordeal in `` Life Wish.'' In April 1988, <LOCATION> Miss </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> began feeling pain in her shoulder and was diagnosed with cancer that had spread to her lungs, hip, femur and thyroid. The 53-year-old actress underwent a drastic form of treatment in <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, called hypothermia that involved injecting 9-inch metal skewers into her shoulder and heating them to 160 degrees in an attempt to burn the tumors.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Kitty </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelley </PERSON>, the biographer whose unauthorized life stories of <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Onassis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON> set their subjects seething, is a target of a $ 50 million lawsuit from syndicated gossip columnist <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Feld </PERSON>. In the suit filed Tuesday in <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Feld </PERSON> alleged that <PERSON> Kelley </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Time </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> photographer <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Tretick </PERSON> tried to drive her out of business by threatening to file a lawsuit of their own. The action allegedly resulted in <PERSON> Feld </PERSON> losing her syndicated column at The <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Times. In June, <PERSON> Feld </PERSON> wrote a column saying <PERSON> Kelley </PERSON> appeared at the funeral of the daughter of former <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> aide <PERSON> Lyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> `` disguised as one of the bereaved.'' The article speculated that <PERSON> Kelley </PERSON>, who is writing a biography of <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, attended only to get access to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> insiders. <PERSON> Kelley </PERSON> told Washingtonian Magazine she had been invited by the Nofzigers, who confirmed the invitation, and threatened to sue <PERSON> Feld </PERSON>. That suit was never filed. <PERSON> Feld </PERSON>'s publicist, <ORGANIZATION> Samantha </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Samantha </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Feld </PERSON> stands by her column. <PERSON> Kelley </PERSON> did not return a telephone call seeking comment.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>COLORADO SPRINGS, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Film stars <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Redford </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Weaver </PERSON> and <PERSON> Goldie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawn </PERSON> have been invited to the first Environmental Film Festival, scheduled for April 27-29 in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>. Between 35 and 40 feature films, shorts and documentaries are expected to be shown at the festival, which will coincide with the 20th anniversary of Earth Day. <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Pikes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, which is organizing the event with the <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION>, said the sponsors hope to encourage filmmakers to pursue environmental subjects in future films. Organizers also hope to attract environmental scientists, politicians and technical experts to discuss ecological issues. Also invited are author <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON>; actress <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> Morris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Animal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>; actor <PERSON> Dom </PERSON> <PERSON> DeLuise </PERSON>, and environmental artist <PERSON> Christo </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890816-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-89 0113EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WoodstockRevisited     08-16 0451</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Woodstock Revisited,0461</SECOND>
<HEAD>Spirit Willing, Crowd Weak for Woodstock Anniversary</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto AB1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BAUDER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BETHEL, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The crowd was smaller, the musicians amateur and Saabs replaced sandals as the favored form of transportation, but hundreds of people donned tie-dyed shirts to conjure the spirit of <LOCATION> Woodstock </LOCATION> anyway. Twenty years after <PERSON> Richie </PERSON> <PERSON> Havens </PERSON> opened the <LOCATION> Woodstock </LOCATION> festival before 400,000 people, the late <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Yasgur </PERSON>'s old farm filled with revelers Tuesday to celebrate one of rock' n' roll's most sacred anniversaries. `` It was a deeply spiritual experience and certainly people would want to come back,'' said comedian <PERSON> Wavy </PERSON> <PERSON> Gravy </PERSON>, the only one of <LOCATION> Woodstock </LOCATION>'s original performers. Gravy, wearing a beanie with a propeller and carrying a walking stick topped with a pig's snout, waved to festival veterans before being ushered into a forest of satellite dishes for one of dozens of interviews. More free enterprise than free love was evident at the upstate <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> meadow as tourists could choose between T-shirts emblazoned with `` I survived the Woodstock Reunion'' and `` Was I Late?'' `` I really honor the people whose spread this is for allowing this to take place,'' <PERSON> Gravy </PERSON> said. `` It's very folksy.'' It was n't without a price. A man who said he was a relative of the field's new owners, <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicky </PERSON> and <PERSON> June </PERSON> <PERSON> Gelish </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, asked a $ 5 `` field restoration'' donation from each carload. Police said the owners squabbled with merchants who tried to sell their wares. True to the spirit of the original <LOCATION> Woodstock </LOCATION>, when fans swarmed over fences to transform it into a free concert, some motorists just waited until the landlord looked the other way and snuck their vehicles onto the field. Police were on hand to make sure traffic kept moving. There were no arrests, said Sgt. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Kulick </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Sullivan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriff </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. He estimated the crowd at about 600, the largest of a celebration that had been building for a week. The most tension came when television reporters, nervously approaching 6 p.m. deadlines, competed for space near the commemorative plaque that is the only permanent fixture on the alfalfa field. `` I did n't really know what to expect,'' said <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Corwin </PERSON>, a resident of upstate <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> who said he attended the original show and has returned every year since. `` I'm just thankful that they let us go back. The numbers have fallen down but the spirit has n't died. On the same corner where <PERSON> Jimi </PERSON> <PERSON> Hendrix </PERSON>, the Who, the <ORGANIZATION> Jefferson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airplane </ORGANIZATION> and the Grateful Dead performed 20 years earlier, a makeshift stage was built for stray amateur guitarists. One singer replaced Country <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON>'s infamous `` Gim me an ` F''' cheer with the more modest L-O-V-E spellalong.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890816-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-89 0148EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-UnwantedBuffalo     08-16 0375</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Unwanted Buffalo,0387</SECOND>
<HEAD>Herd Eating Chippewa Tribe's Budget</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BELCOURT, N.D. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An Indian reservation sounded like a good home for a buffalo herd, but the <LOCATION> Chippewa </LOCATION> tribe wishes someone would take them away. `` We do n't want a herd of buffalo,'' said <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> `` </PERSON> <PERSON> Fritz </PERSON><PERSON> '' </PERSON> <PERSON> Monette </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Chippewa </LOCATION> tribal councilman. `` Unfortunately, we got stuck with a herd of buffalo, and we do n't know what to do with them.'' Feeding the herd is costing the tribe about $ 100 a week and will become more expensive come winter, he said Monday. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> gave the herd to the Turtle Mountain Indian Reservation under a program that distributes surplus animals to reservations. The herd has grown from nine head in 1984 to 29. <PERSON> Louise </PERSON> <PERSON> Crosby </PERSON> claims the tribe is trying to cut expenses by starving the buffalo. `` To see them starve like that is a horrible thing,'' she said. <PERSON> Crosby </PERSON>, who ran a game farm before selling her animals to the <ORGANIZATION> Minot </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zoo </ORGANIZATION>, said she offered to buy the buffalo to show the tribe how extreme she thinks the situation is. But she said she does n't really want them because she too is daunted by feed costs. <PERSON> Monette </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Tribal </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Twila </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin-Kekahbah </PERSON> deny the buffalo are starving. `` They cost some money to the tribe, which we really ca n't afford,'' <PERSON> Martin-Kekahbah </PERSON> said `` However, the buffalo are not starving. Some believe the buffalo are better taken care of than the membership.'' <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Peltier </PERSON>, caretaker for the buffalo, said the animals usually are fed between 15 gallons to 30 gallons of ground barley a day. The tribe also buys 80 to 90 bales of hay a year for the herd, he said, and provides a barrel of canned food supplement and a salt block. The herd also has a large spring-fed water hole, he said. `` I think they are fed better than a lot of places,'' <PERSON> Peltier </PERSON> said. Complaints from people like <PERSON> Crosby </PERSON> may stem from a misunderstanding about how buffalo should look, he said. `` A person has to get pretty close to them to see what shape they are in,'' he said. <PERSON> Monette </PERSON> said the tribe is asking for suggestions on how it might reduce the herd to a manageable size, possibly by auctioning or donating animals.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890816-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-89 0144EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Hills-Savings Bjt   08-16 0629</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hills-Savings, Bjt,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Administration Considering Tax Benefits for Savers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Economics Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration, seeking ways to boost the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> savings rate to cure a variety of economic ills, appears to be inching closer to recommending increased tax incentives for thrifty Americans. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Trade Representative <PERSON> Carla </PERSON> <PERSON> Hills </PERSON> added her support to the idea Tuesday, saying that expanding Individual Retirement Accounts would make her job of reducing <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s huge trade deficits easier. Millions of American savers could benefit through expanded IRAs, which enjoyed great popularity earlier in the decade, but it could cost the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> billions of dollars in lost tax revenue. <PERSON> Hills </PERSON>, in an interview with reporters, stressed that she was not signaling an imminent administration announcement on IRAs. However, other officials said a proposed increase in tax incentives for IRAs is high on the list of options being studied by the administration. Americans' personal savings rate _ savings as a percentage of after-tax income _ fell to a 40-year low of 3.2 percent in 1987 and increased only slightly to 4.2 percent last year. By contrast, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, the country with the world's largest trade surplus, had a savings rate of 16.5 percent in 1987. Administration officials said they are planning a fall campaign, to be led by <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>, focusing on the country's chronic low savings rate and proposing ways to correct the problem. The huge cost of IRAs was one reason they were greatly scaled back by the 1986 Tax Reform Act. As a result, the number of tax returns claiming <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> deductions fell from 15.5 million in 1987 to 7.4 million last year. In endorsing increased tax incentives for IRAs, <PERSON> Hills </PERSON> said it would `` highlight the great need for private savings to go up. It sends up a flag saying, this is very important, not only to your nation, but to your own future and to your children.'' A key reason advanced for <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s high trade deficits is the fact that Americans consume more than the country can produce domestically. Economists argue that if Americans can be persuaded to cut back consumption and save more, it would limit the need for foreign goods. A higher savings rate would expand the pool of available funds in this country and lower the cost of borrowing by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> businesses, making them more competitive internationally. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration is negotiating with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> demands for the Japanese to lower trade barriers erected against foreign goods. <PERSON> Hills </PERSON> said cutting the federal budget deficit, which drains away savings, and efforts to boost personal savings would counter Japanese arguments that <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> is not doing enough at home to fix its trading problems. In recent weeks, Budget Director <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON> have issued their own warnings about the need to increase the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> savings rate. <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> attacked <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s `` cultural now-now-ism,'' which he defined as an unrestrained appetite for satisfying immediate wants at the expense of long-term goals. <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON>, testifying before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> earlier in the month, called raising the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> savings rate `` the crucial issue for the long-term economic outlook of the country.'' <PERSON> Hills </PERSON> is holding negotiations with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> in an effort to get those nations to lower trade barriers cited by the administration in May in a `` hit list'' of the most harmful impediments to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade. The administration is holding separate talks with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> on so-called structural impediments that keep foreign companies from doing business in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, such as the Japanese distribution system. However, she warned that despite the administration's best efforts, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade deficit is likely to widen `` a little'' in the next 18 months because the dollar has increased in value, making <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> goods less competitive on overseas markets.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890816-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-89 0206EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Poland Bjt   08-16 0682</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Poland, Bjt,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Poland's Governmental Problems an `Internal Affair,' US Officials
Say</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
