<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890925-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-25-89 2344EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Dyson     09-25 0321</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Dyson,0328</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congressman Says Former Aide Improperly Pocketed Funds</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN ROLL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAMBRIDGE, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rep. <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON> said Monday he has made `` mistakes in judgment'' while in office and that his former top aide who committed suicide had improperly pocketed campaign funds. The five-term Democrat from <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> also said he was returning $ 18,000 in campaign contributions made by officials connected to a defense contractor. <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON> said his former top aide and campaign manager, <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Pappas </PERSON>, improperly pocketed nearly $ 7,300 in campaign funds. <PERSON> Pappas </PERSON> wrote $ 7,275 in checks to other <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON> staff members and told them to give him the cash, <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON> said. `` I must accept ultimate responsibility for these errors in judgment because <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Pappas </PERSON> was my campaign manager,'' <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON> said. `` I was not aware that <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> was writing checks to staff members and asking them to cash those checks and return the cash to him.'' <PERSON> Pappas </PERSON> committed suicide in May 1988 by jumping from a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> hotel following newspaper reports that were highly critical of his management of <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON>'s congressional office. The apparent violations will be reported to the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elections </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON> also said he would return $ 18,000 in campaign contributions received from officials connected to <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, one of several defense contractors under investigation by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> for suspected violations of contract procurement regulations. He said was returning the money because individual guilty pleas entered as a result of the investigation `` point to a systematic attempt on the part of <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION> to circumvent the federal laws governing campaign contributions,'' said <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON>, who sits on a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee with repsonsibility for approving the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> budget. `` Mistakes were made by my staff. I have made mistakes of judgment,'' <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON> added. `` I regret the controversy these matters have caused, but I want the people of <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> to know that these were mistakes of the head, not of the heart.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890925-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-25-89 2346EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-ChemicalWeaponsStocks 1stLd-Writethru   09-25 0784</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Chemical Weapons Stocks, 1st Ld - Writethru,a0663,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Up to 12 Nations May be Capable of Making Chemical Weapons</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 4th graf: ``Bush said,'' to note Bush estimate and discrepancy
with experts</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Bush, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> are the only two nations to acknowledge having chemical weapons, although up to a dozen, including <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, are thought to have the grisly substances or the ability to make them, experts said Monday. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, addressing the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>, proclaimed his readiness to destroy 80 percent of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> chemical weapon stores if <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> agrees to the same stockpile level, and urged other nations to sign a multilateral pact to ban them entirely. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, however, did not suspend production of new <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> chemical weapons, and his offer did not appear to go beyond legislation passed by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> requiring the government to destroy old chemical weapons stocks by 1997. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said more than 20 nations have these weapons or the ability to mkake them. There was no immediate explanation of why his estimate was higher than those offered by the experts. The president's proposal `` might focus international attention on chemical weapons and lead to a multilateral treaty,'' said <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Feinstein </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Arms </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, a disarmament lobby in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. But it may instead produce a U.S.-Soviet deal on chemical weapons and divert attention from production by other countries, he said. Private analysts believe the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has 30,000 tons of chemical weapons. The Soviets have said they have `` no more than'' 50,000. Delegates to the 40-nation Conference on Disarmament ended their most recent meeting in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> last month without any clear idea of when it would be possible to conclude a global ban on chemical weapons. The conference, which meets again in November, is stalled on the issue of how to monitor the production of chemical weapons, which experts say can be made in factories similar to those that make fertilizer or other compounds. `` The problem we have is that nobody has determined how to -LRB- monitor -RRB- it in an effectively verifiable way, because chemical weapons can be made in just about any kind of chemical plant,'' Gen. <PERSON> Colin </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> said earlier this year, before he was nominated chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chiefs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Staff </ORGANIZATION>. Also in dispute are the size of chemical weapons stockpiles, and even the number of countries that have them. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence officials have said that <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> is building the world's largest chemical weapons plant at <LOCATION> Rabta </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Moammar </PERSON> <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> has said the factory is designed to produce pharmaceuticals. In 1984, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> concluded that <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> had used lethal chemical agents against Kurds along the <LOCATION> Iran-Iraq </LOCATION> border, although <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> has not admitted it. Other nations thought able to make their own chemical weapons are <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> and probably <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Elisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, a scholar who closely tracks the issue at the <ORGANIZATION> Brookings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. The size of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet stockpiles is not publicly known, although those two governments last weekend signed an agreement to exchange and verify data on their chemical arsenals, including the right to on-sight inspection. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has disclosed what type of weapons it has and where they are stored, but not the size of the stockpiles. The <ORGANIZATION> Arms </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> estimated the size of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> stock at about 30,000 tons. In 1987, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government, after an 18-year moratorium, began to manufacture a new generation of `` binary'' chemical weapons, which consist of two toxic substances that become lethal when mixed together. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> also has ordered the destruction by 1997 of 90 percent of stockpiles of older <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> chemical weapons, stored at 11 sites in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. Work began on Aug. 31 at the <ORGANIZATION> Toole </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Depot </ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> desert to destroy 42 percent of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> stockpile, consisting of nerve and mustard gas, blistering agents that were used in World War I. Similar facilities were being studied at other storage sites to destroy the remainder. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> stockpile also consists of the nerve agents Sarin and VX, and other substances, according to the government. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> suspended chemical weapon production on Dec. 26, 1987, seven months after the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> resumed production. Kremlin spokesmen, giving the first-ever Soviet figures on chemical weapon stockpiles, said they contained `` no more than 50,000 tons of chemical warfare agents.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> estimates of Soviet stockpiles have ranged from 30,000 to 50,000 tons. In October 1987, the Soviets announced that their stockpile consisted of the nerve agents Sarion, <PERSON> Soman </PERSON>, VX, two mustard blistering agents and one irritant.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890925-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-25-89 0001EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-LaserPhoto CORRECTIVE   09-25 0072</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-LaserPhoto, CORRECTIVE,0072</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: Members who used LaserPhotos NY34 of Sept. 21 and NY10 of Sept.
22 are asked to use the following.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two Associated Press LaserPhotos, on Sept. 21 and Sept. 22, erroneously identified a man as <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION> pilot <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>. The photos do not show <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, the pilot whose plane crashed Wednesday at <LOCATION> LaGuardia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>. The photos show an unidentified pilot at the crash scene.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890925-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-25-89 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r e PM-APonTV--Chung     09-25 0683</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP on TV--Chung,0702</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Connie Chung Series Good Drama, Little Journalism</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAY SHARBUTT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 If the premiere of `` Saturday Night With Connie Chung'' is typical of things to come, it might be wise for <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> to turn it into a docudrama anthology series and let <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION> produce it. The show spent half its opening hour Saturday dramatizing the life of a fiery early civil rights pioneer in <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, the Rev. <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> <PERSON> Johns </PERSON>, played by <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>. That half was a fairly good docudrama. But this is supposed to be a news series, even though this one's closing credits cited a `` soloist'' _ jazzman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanborn </PERSON>, who played the show's bluesy theme music It is not a good sign for a journalism show to have a news & amp; blues saxaphonist. But this effort's first 30 minutes were not a good sign, either. They made one fear that this series, produced by <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Lack </PERSON>, producer of the departed `` West 57th'' series, may prove just a training ground for TV news producers who hope to someday make TV movies. Entitled `` God's Bad Boy,'' Saturday's debut dramatization, set in 1949, featured seven actors; a group of black townsfolk as extras in <PERSON> Johns </PERSON>' church, the <ORGANIZATION> Dexter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Avenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baptist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, and white extras as hostile policemen. By <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, the `` re-creation'' sporadically included brief interviews _ in the manner of the movie `` Reds'' _ with seven people who knew the late minister. They included his daughter, <PERSON> Toni </PERSON> <PERSON> Johns </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, and <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>. There was an eighth interviewee, historian <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> <PERSON> Branch </PERSON>. The first chapter of his Pulitzer Prize-winning book on the civil rights movement, `` Parting the Waters,'' was the basis for the dramatization. The dramatization, in which <PERSON> Johns </PERSON> strongly and loudly spoke out against murder of blacks by whites and urged his middle-class congregation to stand up for black civil rights, was woefully weak in journalistic basics. Even <PERSON> Chung </PERSON>, who has a reputation as a good reporter, exhibited this flaw in her non-acting role as anchor. She prefaced one scene by saying how `` a series of brutal murders of blacks by the police'' in the spring of 1949 led <PERSON> Johns </PERSON> to preach a sermon that `` would threaten the uneasy calm'' between the races in <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION>. But she cited no examples of any murders by police. She only said that a white man got up off his front porch and shot and killed a black man who was running by. The killer's explanation, she said, was this: `` ` If he was running, he must have done something.''' She did n't say if the white man was charged with anything, let alone tried. In the docudrama, <PERSON> Johns </PERSON>, in saying that `` a lot of people doing the killing'' of blacks are the police, at least cited two cases. They were found to be, he scornfully noted, `` justifiable homicide.'' But he named only one policemen while naming all the victims. It made you wonder if any of the names were real. In another scene, he was called `` boy'' by a white man identified only as a `` commonwealth's attorney'' in <LOCATION> Mongtomery </LOCATION>. No name was given. Another white official in a succeeding scene is identified only as `` Judge <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>.'' In yet another scene, <PERSON> John </PERSON>'s daughter, in an off-camera interview excerpt that accompanied the on-screen drama, said that `` as I recall, a black girl had been raped. I think it was by six policemen.'' You'd think there be might be a question at this shocking point whether what she said actually happened, and whether any policemen were charged. But there was no question. On the bright side, the show's second half was an interesting panel discussion where sparks occasionally flew between the Rev. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and Montgomery Mayor <PERSON> Emory </PERSON> <PERSON> Folmar </PERSON>, the latter a white man. For the record, <PERSON> Chung </PERSON> told viewers that next Saturday will bring `` <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON>, talking for the first time on television, about her separation from <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON> and about her newest roles, both on-screen and off.'' It can be assumed that <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON> will play herself.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890925-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-25-89 0021EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SAfrica-Activist     09-25 0200</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SAfrica-Activist,0204</SECOND>
<HEAD>Activist Freed But Restricted After 28-Day Hunger Strike</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAPE TOWN, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police have imposed severe restrictions on a white anti-apartheid activist who won his freedom from detention by staging a 28-day hunger strike. <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hofmeyr </PERSON>, 35, was detained without charge Aug. 26 while participating in a protest against <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>, sponsors of an international rugby series that many activists viewed as a violation of the sports boycott imposed on <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> because of its segregationist policies. <PERSON> Hofmeyr </PERSON>, a lawyer, drank only fruit juice during his detention, and relatives said he was on the verge of suffering permanent damage when the government agreed to free him Friday. He remained in <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Town </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Groote </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Schuur </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> on Sunday, and his family said he was not likely to leave until midweek. According to his lawyers, <PERSON> Hofmeyr </PERSON> has been issued a restriction order which bars him from working with anti-apartheid organizations, prohibits him from giving interviews or publishing articles and requires him to be indoors from 8 p.m. to 6 a.m. He also is barred from attending any anti-government meetings. <PERSON> Hofmeyr </PERSON>'s release followed a 90-minute meeting Thursday between his father and Law and Order Minister <PERSON> Adriaan </PERSON> <PERSON> Vlok </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890925-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-25-89 0027EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Drive-InOpera     09-25 0570</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drive-In Opera,0586</SECOND>
<BYLINE>Norwegians Come on Foot to `World's First' Drive-In Opera ^By DOUG
MELLGREN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OSLO, Norway (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Norwegian National Opera tried to bring 19th century arias to the masses this weekend with a drive-in performance. Many viewers, mostly on foot, found opera loud but hard to see. A 225-square-foot movie screen dangled from a crane above <LOCATION> Oslo </LOCATION>'s Youngstorget marketplace for what was billed as the world's first drive-in opera Broadcast images of the opera's live Saturday night performance from its regular theater were dim, but stacks of loudspeakers blasted the normally quiet city center with crisp arias. `` It started as a crazy notion but we went ahead anyway,'' said state opera spokesman <PERSON> Terje </PERSON> <PERSON> Baskerud </PERSON>. It was inspired by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> drive-in movies, which are unknown in <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>, he said. `` We want people to know that opera can be fun,'' <PERSON> Baskerud </PERSON> said of choosing one act from the 19th century comedy `` The Barber of <LOCATION> Seville </LOCATION>'' for the experiment. The opera hoped 1950s Americana will help it shed a high-brow image and appeal to a broader public through the free, one night drive-in. Sponsors paid the $ 28,000 cost. Several operas in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and elsewhere asked to be kept informed of the results, <PERSON> Baskerud </PERSON> said. Drive-in movie theaters are as foreign to most Norwegians as opera. Police estimated there was room for 250 cars in the closed-off marketplace. About 70 cars parked, many facing away from screen. Unsure of drive-in etiquette, `` one lady asked if she was allowed to get out of her car,'' said <PERSON> Baskerud </PERSON>. Most of the roughly 1,300 people who passed through the square came on foot, often leading dogs or carrying children. A core of about 300 stayed through the 90-minute first act, politely applauding the screen. Some sat in chairs lined up on a truck's cargo bed. Nearby, limousine passengers sipped champagne. The second act proved too dark for television and plans to have waitresses on rollerskates serve hamburgers also proved impossible, <PERSON> Baskerud </PERSON> said. `` It's wonderful,'' said <PERSON> Lillian </PERSON> <PERSON> Ingerbretsen </PERSON>, 48, an opera fan. `` The screen was dark ... but now people will buy tickets to a performance just to see what it is really like,'' she said. <PERSON> Baskerud </PERSON> admitted picture problems but said `` sound was perfect and that's what counts ... Next time, we will have a performance lighted for television.'' <PERSON> Morten </PERSON> <PERSON> Kristoffersen </PERSON>, 16, who paused, looked and walked on, said, `` Great idea but it's hard to see ... I do n't think I'll be going to the opera anytime soon.'' But <PERSON> Baskerud </PERSON> said ticket sales to regular performances boomed during the drive-in. The opera, founded in 1957, already averages 90 percent bookings for 200 shows a year in its home, a cramped former movie theater, he said. The 1,119-tickets for the premiere had been sold out, yet when the curtain rose in the opera house many seats were empty. `` More than a third of the ticket holders stayed outside to watch the drive-in, then came in for the second act,'' he said. The Italian-language performance of <PERSON> Rossini </PERSON>'s `` Barber of <LOCATION> Seville </LOCATION>'', first performed in 1816, was directed by <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Hampe </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Cologne </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Opera </LOCATION>, and conducted by Italian <PERSON> Carlo </PERSON> <PERSON> Felice </PERSON> <PERSON> Cillareo </PERSON>. <PERSON> Iziar </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> <PERSON> Galdos </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> resident of <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>, sang the female lead <PERSON> Rosina </PERSON>, the Scottish opera's <PERSON> Neill </PERSON> <PERSON> Archer </PERSON> sang Count <LOCATION> Almaviva </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Trond </PERSON> <PERSON> Halstein </PERSON> <PERSON> Moe </PERSON> performed <PERSON> Figaro </PERSON>, with support from the opera's other 26 singers, 42-member chorus and 75-piece orchestra.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890925-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-25-89 0032EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Education-Choice     09-25 1034</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Education-Choice,1063</SECOND>
<HEAD>In East Harlem School District, Choice Triumphs, But Money Still
Talks</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report. Education summit is Sept. 27-28.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE MITGANG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Outside the battered metal doors of Intermediate School 117 in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION>, crack vials litter the pavement and row after row of tenements stand empty and graffiti-scarred. But inside is what President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has called `` the single most promising idea'' in education _ an idea certain to be high on the agenda at the education summit this week between <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and the nation's governors in <LOCATION> Charlottesville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va </LOCATION>. The idea is `` choice'': the belief, as espoused by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and others, that if parents are allowed to choose the best public schools for their children, the resulting competition would compel schools everywhere to improve. <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> have already adopted `` open enrollment'' plans permitting parents to choose among schools throughout those states. Many other states offer more limited choice options aimed at gifted students or youngsters with academic problems that only certain districts can handle. Scores of local districts have offered magnet and alternative programs for years. A Gallup education survey in August found Americans support the principle of school choice by a 60-31 margin, with 9 percent saying they were n't sure. <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>'s plan, voluntary for two years, became mandatory this fall for districts with at least 1,000 students. In <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, a law signed this year gives students the right to apply to any school in the state. They must stick with their choice for at least four years. <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> this year passed a comprehensive open enrollment law permitting students aged 5 through 18 to choose schools across district lines as long as there is room and as long as it does n't upset desegregation efforts But advocates say no place offers better proof than <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION> that choice's benefits can extend even to urban <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s neediest. In 1972, District 4 ranked last among <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s 32 school districts in reading and math achievement. Only 15 percent read at or above grade level. With federal and private funds, then-superintendent <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Alvarado </PERSON> gradually broke up or replaced existing schools in the district with magnet schools and alternative `` schools within schools,'' small enough to give students individual attention and academically attractive enough to draw pupils from all over the city. Some are selective, like the gifted programs or the school for the performing arts. Others take nearly all comers. The district has weathered some recent problems. Last December, superintendent <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Medina </PERSON> was suspended on allegations he and fellow board members funneled district money into a secret bank account and used it for trips, food, liquor and improper loans. And citywide school budget cuts may force reductions this year in some of the district's innovative magnet programs, said assistant superintendent <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Falco </PERSON>. Still, everyone agrees the district has been transformed for the better by the bracing effects of competition. Even <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Geiger </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, which has given only qualified support to the idea of choice, calls District 4 `` choice at its very best.'' Today, reading scores of District 4's 14,000 pupils rank 16th in the city, and 65 percent read at grade level or higher. Pupils can choose among 23 alternative schools specializing in such areas as science and humanities, performing arts and environmental science. Choice has also meant that poor programs which no longer attract students do n't last. A school specializing in maritime science was closed about three years ago, <PERSON> Falco </PERSON> said. It reopened recently with a new director. I.S. 117 was once a failing, impersonal middle school bulging with more than 2,000 students. It now houses four academies, or schools within schools, each occupying one floor and each with only about 200 pupils. There is a gifted and talented program; the `` Harbor School'' for the performing arts; the `` Career Academy,'' which helps poorly prepared students take a seemingly outlandish goal such as becoming a lawyer and plan how to attain it; and the `` Key School'' with classes of no more than 18 students and intensive instruction for youngsters with emotional difficulties. Most pupils come from <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION>. But the magnet schools are so appealing that this once-downtrodden district is drawing students of all races and economic circumstances from every corner of the city. Nearly 200 children from around the city applied for 70 places in the entering class of the <ORGANIZATION> Harbor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> this year, says assistant director <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Roth </PERSON>. Fourth-grader <PERSON> Chenoa </PERSON> <PERSON> Rommereim </PERSON> takes a car pool each day from the <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> to attend I.S. 117's gifted program. She is one of the estimated 15-25 percent non-minority students in District 4 magnet programs, <PERSON> Falco </PERSON> said. Even staunch supporters of choice note its limitations. District 4 has shunned choice for elementary schools, <PERSON> Falco </PERSON> said, because at that early age it's more important for parents and children to maintain neighborhood ties. <PERSON> Sy </PERSON> <PERSON> Fliegel </PERSON>, an early architect of choice in District 4, recently wrote that choice worked in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION> because it came gradually, one school at a time. And successful programs were kept small. It's far better to have parents clamoring for a few excellent programs than to offer lots of poor choices `` When I hear about a school district deciding to become a complete choice system in one blow, I worry,'' <PERSON> Fliegel </PERSON> wrote. And as the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> education summit approaches, educators here greet their fame with a mix of pride and frustration. Some worry that District 4's accomplishments are being used to demonstrate that choice alone, without additional money, will fix the nation's schools. Few here believe that choice is an educational cure-all. `` In the final analysis the folks in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> seem to be saying: ` Federal dollars are n't necessary. What's needed is to have more schools like THAT one,''' said <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Batton </PERSON>, a computer and Spanish teacher who has been at I.S. 117 for 24 years. `` I have two feelings,'' said <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonet </PERSON>, director of <ORGANIZATION> Northview </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tech </ORGANIZATION>, a magnet school on East 116th Street specializing in computers and writing. `` It's very positive that people are noticing us. Let them notice. But send us more money.''
</TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890925-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-25-89 0035EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--UniformsOut     09-25 0133</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Uniforms Out,0134</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ethiopian Officials to Shed Uniforms</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ADDIS ABABA, Ethiopia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It may not spark a revolution in men's wear in <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>, but for the first time in years government officials are being allowed to shed their uniforms. A senior official said Sunday that government employees have been told they may dispense with their khaki uniforms in favor of civilian garb in their offices and at ceremonial occasions. The two-piece uniforms had been mandatory for employees of the military government, the ruling party and government-owned industries since 1985. Ethiopian television viewers were surprised to see members of the government delegation to recent talks with Eritrean rebels in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> dressed in suits and ties, a fashion long frowned on by the military men who seized control of the country in 1974.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890925-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-25-89 0037EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-OneGermany     09-25 1121</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-One Germany,1155</SECOND>
<HEAD>German Reunification Again Under Discussion as Changes Sweep Europe</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN COSTELLOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FRANKFURT, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three decades ago, a West German politician said German reunification was a `` sleeping lioness'' that would awake one day with a mighty roar. Now, there is growing speculation the awakening may be at hand to create a giant political and economic machine that could dominate <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. `` Reunification is coming closer, but I ca n't say whether it will take 10, 15 or 20 years,'' says West German conservative lawmaker <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> Lintner </PERSON>. `` We have the impression that things are much more concrete than we could have imagined five years ago.'' The daily sight of thousands of refugees fleeing East German leader <PERSON> Erich </PERSON> <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON>'s hard-line <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> rule for the capitalist West has revived international interest in the debate. Once dismissed as a nostalgic daydream, the idea of German reunification has gotten a public nod from President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and something short of a categorical `` no'' from President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. The idea makes East German leaders virtually apopletic. `` If there were a free choice under the present circumstances in the <LOCATION> German </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Democratic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> -RRB-, certainly 80 percent to 90 percent would vote for national reunification with the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>,'' added the 44-year-old <PERSON> Lintner </PERSON> in an <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> interview. The West German constitution calls for a united <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, but it has not been a paramount concern of the West Germans in the years since the ruins of <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> were divided into East and West at the end of World War II. Full national reunification would completey rework the postwar European order mapped out by the conquering Allies. It is a prospect that creates unease in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, and in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc. <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s prestigious Sunday Times on Sept. 10 mapped out a possible scenario that includes massive troop reductions in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON>'s death and further Westernization of <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. `` <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> unilaterally abolishes the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact after guarantees from <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> they will not join other alliances,'' the Times' futuristic view continued. `` <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> withdraws from <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>; and a referendum in both East and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> votes for reunification and neutrality.'' That sort of talk is being heard more and more as <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> loosens its hold on the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc and countries like the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> explore democratic reforms. The implications of pulling down the Berlin Wall and other barriers to link the two German states are enormous and, for many, ominous. As much of <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> heads towards its own unification in 1992, the economic center of gravity would be shifted even further to the German side with a powerhouse of nearly 80 million people _ 61.1 million West Germans and 16.6 million East Germans. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> is already <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s largest exporting nation, and despite its many flaws <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s economy is the envy of many Soviet bloc neighbors. A unified <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> could become the political focal point of a continent already in flux, as democratic movements sweep parts of the Soviet bloc. Older generations recall eerie echoes of <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> dictator <PERSON> Adolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>'s boasting that he had brought about `` the unity of the German nation.'' <PERSON> Eva </PERSON> <PERSON> Kulesza </PERSON>, head of research for the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> French </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION>, says she believes that `` as far as public opinion there is new sort of mistrust toward <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. `` This new fear of <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> is linked to German economic trends. <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> is much stronger, much more dynamic than <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>,'' she added. Since <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> are at the front lines of two competing alliances, any signs for eventual reunification would have to come from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. During a news conference last week in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said that reunification is a `` matter for the Germans to decide.'' But he added: `` If that -LRB- reunification -RRB- was worked out between the Germanys, I do not think we should view that as bad for Western interests.'' For his part, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> evaded the issue during a news conference in <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> in June, saying only, `` the situation in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> today was determined by historical realities.'' Outside <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, political leaders and commentators have been sharply divided on the issue. `` In thinking about the German Question, we ought not to be governed by old prejudices and out-of-date assumptions,'' wrote commentator <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s The Independent. `` The Cold War was conducted in the name of freedom and, today, if the coming of freedom to <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> brings a desire for unity which finds its echo in the Federal Republic, we ought not to be opposed.'' <PERSON> Willy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brandt </PERSON>, the Social Democrat who sought greater ties to the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> as chancellor in the 1970s, said <LOCATION> German </LOCATION> unity does n't necessarily mean a single state although he called reunification a `` hypothesis that can not be excluded. As talk grows in the West, the positions against reunification almost seem to harden in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, as people leave the country in near-record numbers. More than 100,000 East Germans are expected to resettle in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> this year, leaving a gaping hole in the Communist nation's work force. Little is likely to change in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> as long as the 77-year-old <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> and his aging comrades stay in power. During a September 1987 visit to <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> called respect for <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s present borders a basic condition of peace. `` Socialism and capitalism ca n't be any more united than fire and water,'' <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> added on the issue of reunification. There are virtually no indications that <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON>'s successors will be inclined to democratic reforms, let alone joining the capitalist West. The calls for reunification have already found a sympathetic ear among some leaders of the Polish Solidarity movement, in the country that suffered some of the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION>' most brutal savagery. `` After all, the abnormal situation of the German nation overshadows the whole of Polish-German relations,'' member of Parliament <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> <PERSON> Michnik </PERSON> wrote on Monday in the pro-Solidarity daily newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Gazeta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wyborcza </ORGANIZATION>, which he edits. The renewed talk of reunification is recalling the nearly prophetic words of <PERSON> Reinhold </PERSON> <PERSON> Maier </PERSON>, a prominent West German state governor who later went on to head the centrist <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. `` Reunification is resting in our midst like a sleeping lioness. Tired and weak, indecisive people in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> are trying not to disturb her sleep,'' <PERSON> Maier </PERSON> predicted in 1955. `` The lioness will one day wake up, blink, snap her her tail and start to roar.'' Still, many in both East and West still agree with the 1967 quip by Nobel Prize-winning French author <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mauriac </PERSON>: `` I love <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> so much, I'm delighted that there are two of them.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890925-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-25-89 0038EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Hazelwood     09-25 0666</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hazelwood,0686</SECOND>
<HEAD>Captain Of Exxon Valdez Prepares Defense For Alaska Oil Spill Case</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAT MILTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HUNTINGTON, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The man who was captain of the tanker Exxon Valdez when it caused the nation's worst oil spill now divides his time between lobstering on <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sound </LOCATION> and meeting with lawyers preparing his defense. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> has refused interviews since the accident but his attorneys agreed to talk to The Associated Press and describe the captain's life as he awaits trial in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. The trial is scheduled for Oct. 30. `` <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> feels terrible about the tragic accident,'' said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Chalos </PERSON>, a prominent admiralty attorney who represents <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON>, 42, was fired by <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> a few days after his tanker struck a reef in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON> on March 24, ripping its hull and releasing nearly 11 millions gallons of crude oil. <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> is saddened, <PERSON> Chalos </PERSON> says, by the environmental damage, the harm to wildlife and the hardship it caused fishermen and others. `` He loves <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>,'' and had seriously considered two job offers there before the accident, according to <PERSON> Chalos </PERSON>. <PERSON> Chalos </PERSON> and another <LOCATION> Hazelwood </LOCATION> attorney, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Russo </PERSON>, outlined their client's account of the accident. They contend the accident was the result of the failure of third mate <ORGANIZATION> Gregory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cousins </ORGANIZATION> or helmsman <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kagan </PERSON>, or both, to properly carry out <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON>'s orders. They assert that <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> was not drunk when the accident occurred, and said not one witness testified at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> hearings that <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> was intoxicated. His blood alcohol level was tested about 10 hours after the grounding and found to be 0.061 percent, 50 percent higher than the legal limit for a seaman operating a vessel. He has had a history of alcohol abuse and has lost driver's licenses in two states because of intoxication. The attorneys said <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> had moved his ship out of shipping lanes to maneuver around ice. They said he told Cousins to bring the tanker back into the lanes and went to his cabin to do paper work, but the return to the shipping lanes was delayed and Cousins' directions to set the rudder to clear the reef were not carried out <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> now faces up to 12 years in prison and $ 150,000 fines if convicted of the criminal charges of reckless conduct which resulted in the spill. `` He has a very positive outlook on life although he is apprehensive about the upcoming trial,'' said <PERSON> Chalos </PERSON>, a schoolmate of <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON>'s at <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maritime </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Schuyler </LOCATION>. `` He hopes the people of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> have n't prejudged him on the inaccurate reports they've read in the newspapers and seen on television,'' he said. In the meantime, <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> has faded into a quiet life at home in the tree-lined community of <LOCATION> Huntington </LOCATION>, on the north shore of <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> about 50 miles from <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>. He, his wife, <PERSON> Suzanne </PERSON>, and their 13-year-old daughter, <PERSON> Alison </PERSON>, have kept pretty much to themselves, occasionally inviting friends and family over for a barbecue. His spirits are good. He has received hundreds of letters from <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> and around the world, many of them from children; the letters have become more supportive in recent months. To relax, he enjoys sailing his 16-foot catamaran. He also is an avid reader and history buff, devouring any book on the sea. He is said to be an expert on a famous seafarer, Capt. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Cook </PERSON>, who explored the <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> coast in the late 1770s. The sailing master for <PERSON> Cook </PERSON>'s voyage was Lt. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bligh </PERSON>; it was <LOCATION> Bligh </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Reef </LOCATION> that the Exxon Valdez struck. <PERSON> Bligh </PERSON> was later promoted to captain. The crew of his ship, the <LOCATION> Bounty </LOCATION>, mutinied in 1789 and set him adrift. He survived, returned to <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> and, in 1791, resumed his naval career. Like <PERSON> Bligh </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> wants to return to the ocean. `` Right now, he is eager to get back to the profession he knows and loves: His work as a captain at sea,'' <PERSON> Chalos </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890925-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-25-89 0039EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Bush-Networks     09-25 0079</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Networks,0081</SECOND>
<HEAD>Network Coverage of President Bush's UN Speech</HEAD>
<UNK>With PM-Bush</UNK>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Four major networks planned live coverage of President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s speech to the General Assembly of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> today. <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> was beginning its live coverage at 11:30 a.m., while <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> planned to interrupt regularly scheduled programming at approximately 11:45 a.m. CBS planned to interrupt its programming to broadcast the speech at approximately at 11:50 a.m. All times are Eastern Daylight Time.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890925-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-25-89 0043EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     09-25 0573</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0604</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DECATUR, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Estella </PERSON> <PERSON> Gill </PERSON> got a special present for her 102nd birthday _ the chance to add another `` great'' to her name. Just hours before her birthday party at Oak Manor Nursing Home, her great-great granddaughter <PERSON> Leandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawson </PERSON> gave birth to a daughter. The 6-pound, 12-ounce girl, Mrs. <PERSON> Gill </PERSON>'s great-great-great-granddaughter, was named <PERSON> Ashley </PERSON> <PERSON> Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawson </PERSON> Family and friends helped celebrate the double birthday Saturday with a large cake, cookies and punch at the nursing home. `` We had two candles on the table,'' said <PERSON> Charlene </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, 62, a daughter from <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>. `` And we sang ` Happy Birthday.''' She said her mother was in good spirits, and just as lively as she was on her 101st birthday and at a big Mother's Day party attended by about 100 people. Mrs. <PERSON> Gill </PERSON> was born Sept. 23, 1887, near <LOCATION> Waco </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Some family members contend she may actually be one year older, but birth records back then were sketchy. Before the arrival of <PERSON> Ashley </PERSON> <PERSON> Marie </PERSON>, the family included five daughters, seven grandchildren, 19 great-grandchildren and 25-great-great-grandchildren.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>TWIN LAKES, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 There were only a few true Texans on hand, but the tomato-throwing troops representing the Lone Star state conquered <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>'s partisans in the annual Colorado-Texas Tomato War. About 6,000 pounds of overripe tomatoes were tossed Saturday in the contest, a sort of statement by longtime residents against outsider-driven development at the nearby resort of <LOCATION> Aspen </LOCATION>. `` I used to own a hotel in the area and one day a woman from <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> looked out over the mountains and said, ` Sure is pretty out there _ too bad someone ai n't done nothing with it,''' explained <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, originator of the event. <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> Vestring </PERSON>, one of the few true Texans in this year's battle, found the fun wore a bit thin `` It is really lonely,'' she said. `` I offered some of them my Lone Star beer but no one would drink it.'' This year's contest came complete with anti-war protesters, a chanting group calling itself the Society for the Protection of Overripe Tomatoes and led by <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Zimmerman </PERSON>. `` We try to rescue wounded tomatoes and do the best we can while they are in the dying throes,'' <PERSON> Zimmerman </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MILWAUKEE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 There's really nothing new under the collar, despite what may have been written about the `` latest'' in necktie knots. <PERSON> Delos </PERSON> <PERSON> Hinze </PERSON> says he was surprised to read a newspaper story that touted as innovation the idea of tying a <LOCATION> Windsor </LOCATION> knot by starting with the cravat inside-out. The Shelby knot has caught the eye of the national press since being praised by a <ORGANIZATION> Milwaukee </ORGANIZATION> television newsman. `` I've been tying it that way for 35 years,'' <PERSON> Hinze </PERSON> said. `` It just bothered me.'' The novelty was supposed to have been proven by its absence from a reference guide from the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Neckwear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> called `` Getting Knotted _ 188 Knots for Necks.'' But <PERSON> Hinze </PERSON> dug up a booklet he got from a <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION> clothing store in the 1950s, and there it was, on Page 6. The booklet from <ORGANIZATION> Johnnie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Walkers </ORGANIZATION> clothing calls it a reverse half-Windsor. The store's still around, but the present staff is n't interested in laying claim to the knot. `` I do n't think people care too much about how they tie a tie,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Kodner </PERSON>, <PERSON> Johnnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Walkers </PERSON> vice president. `` I'm left handed,'' said his store manager, <PERSON> Argil </PERSON> <PERSON> Zirbel </PERSON>, `` so I've always tied it this way.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890925-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-25-89 0044EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Teen-AgeKiller     09-25 0391</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Teen-Age Killer,0401</SECOND>
<HEAD>Community Weighs Sentence of Juvenile Killer</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT W. TROTT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WARWICK, R.I. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fifteen-year-old <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON> is in reform school after confessing to killing four neighbors. Those connected with the case hope he gets help there _ fast _ because he'll be released by the time he turns 21. The stocky, barrel-chested youth was sentenced to six years in the <ORGANIZATION> Rhode </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Training </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> after pleading guilty Thursday to the Labor Day weekend murders of a mother and her two young daughters, and the 1987 killing of a woman who lived two doors from him. Before he was taken away, <PERSON> Price </PERSON> told his friends outside the <LOCATION> Kent </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Courthouse: `` Later. When I get out I'm going to smoke a bomber.'' While justice moved swiftly in the Sept. 1 killings _ Price was arrested two weeks after the slayings and pleaded guilty four days later _ some are not convinced the punishment that will allow him to be freed by age 21 fits the crime. State Attorney General <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neil </PERSON>, who pushed unsuccessfully for legislation to allow prosecutors to try juveniles under age 16 who face capital charges as adults, expressed frustration that the sentence was the maximum allowed under state law. `` It's a crying shame that it takes a tragedy to wake ... a community up,'' <PERSON> O'Neil </PERSON> said. Police Capt. <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> said Price told investigators he broke into a home two blocks away Sept. 1 to steal whatever he could, and killed three people because he was afraid they would identify him. <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Heaton </PERSON>, 39, and her two daughters, <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON>, 10, and <PERSON> Melissa </PERSON>, 8, had been severely beaten and stabbed. Several of Ms. <PERSON> Heaton </PERSON>'s ribs were broken, and <PERSON> Melissa </PERSON>'s skull was fractured. <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> said the viciousness of the crimes led police to link the killings with that of <PERSON> Rebecca </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON>, 27, was stabbed 58 times the night before she was to move from the neighborhood. Investigators said the 240-pound Price, who was repeating the ninth grade, never showed any remorse for the killings. `` Iron Man,'' as the football-playing Price was known at school, had a history of run-ins with the law. He had been placed on probation for assaulting his sister two days before the Heatons were killed, and he was put on probation last fall for burglary.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890925-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-25-89 0023EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Colombia 3rdLd-Writethru a0798 09-25 0838</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Colombia, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0798,0861</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judges Threaten Strike For Better Protection</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Eds: LEADS with 10 grafs to CLARIFY that information on judicial
employees killed comes from same organization that is threatening to strike.
Picks up 11th pvs, `The judges ...' DELETES last grafs of Brazil violence
to TRIM. ^By TOM WELLS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOGOTA, Colombia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s 4,600 judges, facing persistent death threats from drug traffickers, said Sunday they would strike if the government does n't give them better protection. Also Sunday, the army said it had captured a suspected drug trafficker wanted by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for extradition. <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON> <PERSON> Zapata </PERSON> is not on the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s list of 12 most wanted drug traffickers. The son of a crusading newspaper editor killed by drug traffickers said Sunday that <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s congress is cowardly and corrupt in the government's fight against drug traffickers. Three bombs exploded late Sunday in <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>, the capital city of 6 million, heavily damaging offices of three savings and loans companies but causing no injuries, national police said. Late Saturday, bombs exploded in a theater, a city bus company's garage and at a neighborhood headquarters of the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> party </ORGANIZATION>, injuring two people, police said In the last month, 103 bombs have killed six people and wounded 130. <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s judges, fearing for their lives, said in a statement issued through their labor union, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judicial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION>, that they will go on strike if immediate action is not taken to address the dangers they face. Since 1981, about 50 judges and 170 judicial employees have been killed. According to the union, at least 1,600 of <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s 5,000 judges have been threatened with death in the last 12 months. Union officials were to meet Monday with acting Justice Minister <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Lemos </PERSON> <PERSON> Simmonds </PERSON>. `` We do n't see any will on the part of the government to increase security for our lives,'' union president <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON> <PERSON> Nino </PERSON> said in the communique. The judges repeated previous demands for bulletproof cars and vests, guards with metal detectors at their offices and other security measures. Judges in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> earn about $ 400 a month. In interviews last month many said they were forced to take buses to work because they could n't afford cars. A compact car here costs $ 20,000. <PERSON> Monica </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Greiff </PERSON>, who resigned as justice minister last week after being threatened by drug traffickers, said she was promised $ 19 million in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid earlier this month for the purpose of protecting judges. But the union said it has heard nothing since about the aid. <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s army said Sunday it had captured a suspected drug trafficker wanted by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for extradition. The army's 2nd Brigade, in the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> coast town of <LOCATION> Barranquilla </LOCATION>, said it had captured <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON>. It said <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON> has been wanted on drug trafficking charges in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> since 1985. Last month, Colombian government security forces claimed to have arrested two Colombians wanted by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for extradition. The two were released after the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said it had no charges pending against them. <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> McNamara </PERSON> and other embassy employees have refused to comment on extraditions. The anti-drug crusading newapaper <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Espectador </ORGANIZATION>, in a column by its editor, <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cano </PERSON>, accused <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s congress Sunday of being cowardly and corrupt. `` It is not a very admirable congress. Better yet, it is cowardly ...,'' <PERSON> Cano </PERSON> said in a signed column in the <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION> daily. His father, <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cano </PERSON>, was killed by drug traffickers in 1987 after the newspaper called on the government to crack down on the traffickers. `` We have finally hit bottom,'' the column said Sunday, in the harshest criticism of the congress ever published in a newspaper. Colombian newspapers have said 25 Colombian congressmen have been denied visas to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> because of links to drug traffickers. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> has denied comment, but the reports have caused a furor in the congress. One of the country's biggest drug trafficking suspects, <PERSON> Pablo </PERSON> <PERSON> Escobar </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaviria </PERSON>, was an alternate member of <ORGANIZATION> congress </ORGANIZATION> from 1982 until 1986. An alternate member votes during the absence of a congressman, which happens frequently in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>. Four years ago a federal senator was accused of receiving drug traffickers' money for his campaigns, but an investigation was dropped when a bank microfilm supposedly showing receipt of the funds disappeared. <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Espectador </LOCATION> has remained in the forefront of the war on drugs. On Sept. 2, a 500-pound car bomb exploded near the paper's plant, seriously damaging its press and other equipment. In <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, a retired army officer wanted in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> in connection with the training of drug-cartel militias claimed Sunday that an Israeli Embassy official offered to smuggle him from <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION> for $ 10,000. Retired Lt. <PERSON> Col </PERSON> <PERSON> Yair </PERSON> <PERSON> Klein </PERSON> said <PERSON> Yossi </PERSON> <PERSON> Biran </PERSON>, the security chief at <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s embassy in <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>, offered to smuggle him out of <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> in April after threats on <PERSON> Klein </PERSON>'s life were reported in the <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> media. A spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> said the claim was `` totally unfounded'' and that <PERSON> Biran </PERSON> would remain at his post.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890925-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-25-89 0048EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Pope-Galileo     09-25 0530</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pope-Galileo,0547</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pope `Rehabilitates' Astronomer in His Hometown</HEAD>
<HEAD>By STEPHEN R. WILSON</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PISA, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 450 years after the church tried <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Galilei </ORGANIZATION> for heresy, Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> came to the astronomer's hometown and pronounced the words many Pisans have longed to hear: <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION> was right and the church was wrong. The pope had previously said the Inquisition erred in condemning <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION> for teaching that the earth revolves around the sun. But his statements during a weekend trip to this Tuscan city were viewed by its citizens as <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION>'s official rehabilitation. Speaking Sunday at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pisa </ORGANIZATION>, where <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION> studied and taught in the late 1500s, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> said he wanted to recall some of the school's illustrious alumni _ `` above all the very great Galileo.'' Shortly after his arrival in <LOCATION> Pisa </LOCATION> on Friday night, the <PERSON> pope </PERSON> stood on a bridge over the <LOCATION> Arno </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, illuminated by flickering candles, and declared: `` How can one not recall the name of that great man who was born here and from here took the first steps toward immortal fame? `` <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Galilei </ORGANIZATION>, whose scientific work, imprudently opposed at the beginning, is now recognized by all as an essential step in the methodology of research and, in general, on the path toward the knowledge of the world of nature.'' Born in 1564, <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION> originally aroused antagonism when, as a professor at the university from 1589 to 1592, he initiated experiments on the laws of bodies in motion which contradicted the accepted teachings of <PERSON> Aristotle </PERSON>. But he was most widely known for his support of the Copernicus system, which taught that the sun is the central body and the earth and the other planets revolve around it. That defied the church-held belief that the earth was the center of the universe. In 1616, the church denounced the Copernicus system as dangerous to faith, summoned <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION> to <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> and warned him not to uphold or teach it. But he published a book supporting the theory in 1632. The next year he was summoned to <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, tried by the Inquisition and forced to abjure his beliefs. <PERSON> Galileo </PERSON> was sentenced to life imprisonment, which was later changed to house arrest. He died in 1642 near <LOCATION> Florence </LOCATION>. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> has often spoken out on <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION>'s behalf. In 1979, less than a year after his election as <PERSON> pope </PERSON>, he urged the international scientific community to examine the <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION> case, saying he hoped it would help remove the `` diffidence that still prevents fruitful harmony between science and faith, and between the church and the world.'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> appointed a <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> commission in 1979 to study the case. Five years later, the <ORGANIZATION> Pontifical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> issued documents from secret <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> archives, including details of the Inquisition proceedings, which uphold <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION>. In his speech at the university on Sunday, the pope did not address the Galileo case specifically. But he noted that religious faith and science have often been at odds throughout the centuries. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> warned of potential moral and ethical abuses of modern science but said faith and research are not incompatible. `` The church trusts, promotes and encourages your task,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890925-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-25-89 0105EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-VietnamTribute     09-25 0486</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Vietnam Tribute,0500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vietnam Correspondents Honored in Solemn Ceremony</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto XLIB1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE ESPER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JEFFERSONVILLE, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The roll call of six combat photographers who died in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> evoked painful memories and tears at a memorial honoring them and 57 other journalists who were killed covering that war. _ <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Burrows </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Magazine </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Henri </PERSON> <PERSON> Huet </PERSON>, The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> <PERSON> Potter </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>, killed in 1971 when the helicopter in which they were flying was shot down while they were covering a South Vietnamese offensive in <LOCATION> Laos </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Laurent </PERSON>, Pulitzer Prize-winning photographer, <ORGANIZATION> Gamma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Photo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, killed in an ambush two days before the war ended in 1975; he was the last western journalist killed _ <PERSON> Kyoichi </PERSON> <PERSON> Sawada </PERSON>, Pulitzer Prize-winning photographer, <ORGANIZATION> UPI </ORGANIZATION>, killed in an ambush in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> in 1970 _ <PERSON> Huynh </PERSON> <PERSON> Thanh </PERSON> <PERSON> My </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> photographer, killed in a battle in the <ORGANIZATION> Mekong </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> in 1965 After My was killed, his brother, <PERSON> Huynh </PERSON> <PERSON> Cong </PERSON> `` Nick'' Ut, then only 17, took his place with the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>. Eight years later, <ORGANIZATION> Ut </ORGANIZATION> won a Pulitzer Prize for his photo of a horrified <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> girl running naked down a highway after a napalm strike by <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vietnamese </LOCATION> bombers seared her body. Ut, now based in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, was among the more than 200 photographers, staff members and guests at the second-annual <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> workshop who honored the journalists Sunday in this year of the 150th anniversary of photography. `` I wish my mother and brothers and sisters -LRB- still in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> -RRB- would have been here to share this unforgettable moment and place where our fallen comrades including my beloved brother are posthumously being commemorated,'' <ORGANIZATION> Ut </ORGANIZATION> said in prepared remarks. `` I am at this very minute feeling very humble and very proud of the achievements and sacrifices sustained by our fallen colleagues including my brother.'' Ut was so choked with emotion that he was unable to speak and asked a colleague to read his remarks. `` I saw my brother's name and I could not speak,'' <ORGANIZATION> Ut </ORGANIZATION> said afterward. The <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> also paid tribute to the fallen journalists. `` They made the ultimate sacrifice in recording history for people of all countries throughout the world,'' Commandant <PERSON> A.M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> said in a message delivered by a staff member. `` Our nation owes these journalists and photographers its honor, gratitude and respect.'' The ceremony was the idea of <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> Pulitzer-Prize winner himself. It was held on a hilltop on his workshop-farm in the Catskills around a slate table inscribed with the first names of the six photographers who were his best friends. Six small blue spruce trees were planted around the table, one for each of the photographers. A seventh tree was planted in honor of the other journalists killed in the war. Then, the men and women who had gathered, some who were only toddlers during the Vietnam War, some with tears in their eyes, lifted their champagne-filled glasses and toasted the fallen.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890925-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-25-89 0117EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Pierce-LegalStrategy Bjt   09-25 0774</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pierce-Legal Strategy, Bjt,770</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pierce Faces Legal and Public Relations Challenge in HUD Testimony</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD CARELLI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> faces a daunting legal and public relations challenge when he appears Tuesday before a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee investigating his old agency, say lawyers who have helped many witnesses cope with sometimes-hostile congressional inquiries. Potential pitfalls, even for the most blameless witness, range from bad publicity to a perjury indictment. `` It's a very difficult forum,'' said <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> lawyer <PERSON> Abbe </PERSON> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowell </PERSON>. `` There are fewer rules to protect witnesses than in a court or even a grand jury. The power structure is very one-sided.'' <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> has been subpoenaed by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Government Operations subcommittee to testify about alleged influence-peddling and mismanagement at the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>, an agency he ran for eight years. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Perito </PERSON>, one of <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s lawyers, has questioned the subcommittee's fairness and complained that there is not enough time to prepare <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> to testify. While not disclosing specific strategies, <PERSON> Perito </PERSON> said, `` I assure you, I am not going to let my client get kicked around.'' <PERSON> Perito </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> panel `` seems to have made up its mind that my client was involved in some wrongdoing despite the fact there is not a shred of evidence to support such a finding.'' `` In light of this, I must consider every viable and reasonable professional option,'' <PERSON> Perito </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> asked expert lawyers what advice they would give to <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>. Their advice: _ Listen to the questions and limit any answer to what you know to be the facts Do not be afraid of qualifying any answer. _ Anticipate what might be asked, and focus on the facts known about those issues _ Be prepared to tell your story in a clear, concise and consistent way _ Be aware of potential criminal charges, and of your right to invoke the Fifth Amendment privilege against self-incrimination _ Be aware of the news media attention your appearance will generate The subcommittee is expected to question <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> about his role in a number of controversial agency decisions to provide funding for projects supported by well-connected Republicans. `` To some degree, it's like preparing for any testimony,'' said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> lawyer who 16 years ago served as assistant chief counsel of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> committee investigating the Watergate scandal. `` But there are peculiarities of the forum with which you must deal.'' <PERSON> Justin </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, another <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> lawyer who has represented congressional witnesses, noted that <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s legal team already has laid a foundation for the former <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> officer's refusal to cooperate with the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> panel. `` Only in rare circumstances would it be advisable for an individual who has potential criminal exposure to testify,'' he said. `` By maintaining that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is not allowing enough time to determine whether their client has a criminal problem, it becomes very reasonable for a witness to rely on his Fifth Amendment right even if convinced he did nothing wrong,'' <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> said. If <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> invokes his right not to answer the panel's questions, <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> added, `` He has to bite the bullet and take the adverse publicity. It may raise the specter, although in theory it should not, that the guy has something to hide.'' Late Friday, <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> exercised his right under <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> rules for any subpoenaed witness to have all news media cameras and microphones banned from the hearing room. <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> said that if he were advising <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, he, too, would have advocated that move. Another option is testifying in executive session, with the public excluded, but that tack is subject to the subcommittee's discretion `` It's important for a witness' lawyer to know the rules of the particular committee,'' said <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>. `` For example, can the witness make an opening statement?'' <PERSON> Lowell </PERSON> said the paucity of ground rules forces a witness' lawyer to be more aggressive. Attorneys like <PERSON> Brendan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>, who was often combative when representing <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> during testimony before a congressional committee about the Iran-Contra affair, `` often have to depend on the strength of their will to protect their clients,'' <PERSON> Lowell </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> agreed, noting that in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, unlike in court, `` there are very few restrictions on what are viewed as relevant questions _ almost anything is relevant in this forum.'' The experts said <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, if he chooses to testify, faces a thorny problem _ the threat of being accused of perjury _ if his memory fails him or he falls into what <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> called the common trap of `` remembering things in a way that reflects favorably on you.'' `` And if his testimony disagrees with that of another witness, it's a matter of who is believed,'' <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890925-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-25-89 0120EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Contras Bjt   09-25 0617</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Contras, Bjt,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shift Leaves Some Contras Out in the Cold</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s shifting political landscape has produced a more tolerant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attitude toward <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s leftist government and deepening hostility toward some Contra rebels who once enjoyed red-carpet access here, according to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and rebel sources The changed attitude toward the Sandinista government has been subtle compared with the mutual recriminations and finger-pointing that now characterize the relationship between the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and some elements of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s exiled opposition. By de-emphasizing military pressure against the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> government, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has moved away from the confrontational policies of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration and is now pursuing peaceful but guarded coexistence. The shift has embittered some Contras. `` No one in the resistance trusts the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>,'' says <PERSON> Bosco </PERSON> <PERSON> Matamoros </PERSON>, a rebel spokesman who is closely allied with veteran Contra leader <PERSON> Adolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Calero </PERSON>. <PERSON> Calero </PERSON> was once a regular visitor to the White House and the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> years but nowadays is treated almost as an outcast by the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration. <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION> maintains that the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has refused even to answer rebel correspondence while abandoning the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration policy of avoiding all substantive contact with Sandinista leaders. When a congressional delegation met recently with President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>, a top <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official participated. Amid the ongoing debate over when the Contras should disband, <ORGANIZATION> Matamoros </ORGANIZATION> said the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> `` seems more interested than the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> in demobilizing the resistance.'' One continuing source of concern for the administration is Soviet bloc military aid for the <LOCATION> Sandinistas </LOCATION>, estimated at $ 350 million for the first eight months of this year. The administration view is that the <ORGANIZATION> Contra </ORGANIZATION> leadership mantle has passed from Miami-based civilians to battle-hardened <LOCATION> Contra </LOCATION> field commanders who have risen through the ranks and are far more qualified to represent the armed opposition to the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION>. Officials talk disdainfully of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> taxpayer-financed Contra bureaucracy which has operated for years in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. Matamoros accused <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials of grossly exaggerating the size of the Contras' paid staff. By turning its back on <LOCATION> Contra </LOCATION> civilian leaders who have refused to return to the region and by favoring the emerging military commanders within the resistance, <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION> says the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration is tacitly advocating a military coup despite its stated preference for civilian supremacy. The administration's twin objectives for <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> are to support the internal opposition there as the country gears up for national elections and to keep the armed resistance intact until after the Feb. 25 balloting. The bulk of the rebel force is based at camps along the Honduran border, living off U.S.-supplied humanitarian assistance. Central American presidents have called for the demobilization of the rebels by Dec. 5 but the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration regards that deadline as irrelevant because the presidents also said that any such process must be voluntary. The administration believes that the presence of rebel forces along the border serves as an incentive for the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> to fulfill their promise of a free and fair election. At the same time, the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration is trying to devise a way to assist <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s fledgling democratic process without providing direct support to the campaign of the principal opposition candidate, <PERSON> Violeta </PERSON> <PERSON> Chamorro </PERSON>. Meanwhile, the administration seems willing to live with a <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> victory provided the process is reasonably honest. <PERSON> Calero </PERSON> likens the more permissive <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attitude toward the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> to the appeasement policies that led to World War II. `` Rather than pressing for military assistance, Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> joked about relocating the Contras to his <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> ranch,'' <PERSON> Calero </PERSON> has written. Such an attitude, he said, could deprive <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> of democracy while damaging <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> security interests in region.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890925-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-25-89 0129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CongressRdp     09-25 0651</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress Rdp,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Complaints, Not Agreement, Emerge From Talks on Strategic Weapons</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONNA CASSATA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Lawmakers thrashing out a fiscal 1990 defense plan are looking toward <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> action on a military spending bill to help break the impasse over President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s budget request for strategic weapons. House and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> conferees, meeting behind closed doors on authorization legislation, have made no progress on resolving their differences over funding levels for <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wars </ORGANIZATION>, land-based nuclear missiles and the B-2 stealth bomber. Complaints, rather than agreement, have emerged after three weeks of negotiations. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> still has n't learned to do math,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Colo </LOCATION>., one of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> conferees `` They want everything and take it off somebody else's budget.'' `` The thing is going nowhere,'' Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kasich </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ohio </LOCATION>, another <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> conferee, said Friday. Sen. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Exon </PERSON>, D-Neb., said the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> came to the negotiations with a series of votes that were `` all over the lot They both accepted and rejected every strategic program. `` This is one of the most difficult ones -LRB- conferences -RRB- I've ever been in,'' he added. Initially, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> were far apart on the major strategic programs. _ On Star Wars, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approved $ 4.5 billion, a slight cut in <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s request of $ 4.9 billion The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> adopted a budget of $ 3.1 billion for the missile shield. _ On the multiple-warhead, rail-garrison MX missile, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> endorsed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s request of $ 1.1 billion for the MX and $ 100 million for the Midgetman The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> cut $ 502 million from the MX program and eliminated all money for the Midgetman. _ The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> made a modest cut of $ 300 million in <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s $ 4.7 billion proposal for the stealth bomber, the bat-winged aircraft that at a cost of $ 530 million a copy has caused sticker shock The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> limited production of the radar-evading plane to four over the next two years _ half of what the administration requested. Last week, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> presented a revised proposal that restored the MX money, left out the Midgetman and called for the chamber's lower funding total on Star Wars, according to congressional sources The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> rejected the plan. A counterproposal that left the original <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> bill relatively intact was quickly turned down by the House. Setting the tone for future <ORGANIZATION> House-Senate </ORGANIZATION> negotiations on strategic weapons will be <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> action, scheduled to get under way today, on a $ 288.2 billion military spending bill. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appropriations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> approved about $ 3.7 billion for the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s Star Wars program, which amounts to last year's level plus inflation. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republicans are expected to introduce amendments to raise the funding level for Star Wars, formally known as the Strategic Defense Initiative, to at least something closer to the authorization total. But their efforts may have been hurt by a statement from the administration released Friday. The Office of Management and Budget complained about the restrictive language the <ORGANIZATION> Appropriations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> put into the bill which requires that $ 820 million of the $ 3.7 billion be used for research on laser and particle beams. Sen. <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>, D-La., sponsor of the amendment, expressed concerns that the administration will sacrifice long-term research on directed energy weapons in favor of a quick deployment along the lines of the so-called `` Brilliant Pebbles'' scheme favored by many in the administration In its statement, the administration `` urged restoration of the requested funding levels.. and removal of the restrictive SDI language,'' but unlike a previous statement on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> appropriations legislation, there was no veto threat `` That will be a key test vote,'' <PERSON> Exon </PERSON> said. `` Once the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> speaks on that issue it puts into cement what the figure would be.'' And the hope, according to <PERSON> Exon </PERSON>, is that a decision on <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wars </ORGANIZATION> will trigger a chain reaction of agreement on the other strategic programs. `` Once the SDI number is resolved others will not easily fall in place but likely will,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890925-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-25-89 0140EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-AfghanFighting Bjt   09-25 0862</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Afghan Fighting, Bjt,0896</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mujahedeen Torment Afghan Army, But Win No Major Victories</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NEIL MacFARQUHAR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SHINDAND, Afghanistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The commander of the local army garrison knows the guerrillas will be back. They have attacked this mud-brick town a few miles from a major air base three times this year but have not taken it. After each foray they evaporate into the hills or surrounding villages. It is a tactic repeated throughout most of the country. `` They are not so near as they were before, but I do n't know exactly where they are,'' Col. <PERSON> Mobine </PERSON> <PERSON> Nurzi </PERSON> told reporters flown to <LOCATION> Shindand </LOCATION> this month to refute guerrilla claims of capturing it. He said at least 100 guerrillas were killed in the latest, weeklong assault on <LOCATION> Shindand </LOCATION>, about 425 miles southwest of the capital city of <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> and about 90 miles east of the border with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, where some guerrillas are based. But one soldier told reporters, `` They really pounded us before withdrawing. How do we know how many were killed?'' After the Soviets withdrew their troops in February, the U.S.-backed guerrillas were predicting their easy capture of provincial centers like <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION>, if not <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> itself. Now seven months later, their military campaigns remain primarily the hit-and-run attacks that successfully drove the Soviets out. But guerrilla tactics are not going to win the guerrillas a civil war against the <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> government or even much leverage at the bargaining table. And the fatigue with the war rampant in the civilian population after 10 years of fighting and 1 million deaths is also infecting the mujahedeen guerrillas, or Islamic holy warriors. `` The mujahedeen have the capacity to harass the <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> government, but they are not going to win the war,'' said an <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> diplomat, speaking on condition on anonymity. `` The average commander, the average fighter is tired,'' said one <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> official. `` There is battle fatigue, there is no doubt.'' Yet the war wears on and the mujahedeen control most of the countryside. Pilots on the runway in the southern city of <LOCATION> Kandahar </LOCATION>, fearing guerrilla rockets, taxi at 100 mph. Troops at the last checkpoint in north <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> before the <LOCATION> Salang </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Highway </LOCATION>, the supply lifeline from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, report it was recently closed by guerrilla attacks for a few hours on several occassions. There is constant low-level combat that occasionally flares into full-scale battles. At the daily press briefings, the government spokesman reports a litany of `` sweeping and mopping up operations'' throughout the provinces bordering <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, where most of the mujahedeen are headquartered. The repetition indicates the mujahedeen can not be swept away but that the government is confident they can be kept at bay for the most part. `` Despite the attempts of the extremists, the situation in the country is by and large calm,'' President <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> recently told a group of foreign visitors. He referred with bravado to the massive supply convoy that just arrived in <LOCATION> Kandahar </LOCATION>: `` Such a convoy rarely could exist even in the presence of the Soviet troops.'' But weeks of conflicting reports about when the 1,000 or so vehicles would arrive indicated it had run into trouble. <PERSON> Mahmoud </PERSON> <PERSON> Baryalai </PERSON>, the first deputy prime minister in charge of supplies, said earlier that the group of trucks was bogged down by guerrilla rocket fire on the last 90 miles before <LOCATION> Kandahar </LOCATION>. It was not constant, he said, but prevented moving ahead. The mujahedeen claimed to have knocked out 110 trucks, while the government said it lost three trucks and a tank. It said a year's supply of ammunition got through The convoy apparently veered off hundreds of miles into the desert to avoid the attacks, eventually taking more than three weeks to cover the 360 miles from the town of <LOCATION> Torgundi </LOCATION> on the Soviet border. While sporadic attacks can interrupt supply routes, the guerrillas have been unable to take a major town. A concerted attack on <LOCATION> Khost </LOCATION>, about 24 miles from the <LOCATION> Pakistani </LOCATION> border, threatened the city briefly late last month. But diplomats said the mujahedeen lacked the sustained supply routes needed to overcome government forces surrounded by dense minefields and tanks. `` It is difficult for the mujahedeen to capture anything,'' said another <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> diplomat in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. `` They were trained as a guerrilla force and they are trained to make conventional attacks. They lack heavy artillery, air support.'' The government uses both heavily. Dawn in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> is punctuated by outgoing Scud and other missiles. Spotting Scud trails at night is a favorite activity at diplomatic parties. The Scuds, with a range of 180 miles are used against mujahedeen positions along the border. To knock out guerrilla positions around <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, Frog-7 missiles with a range of about 48 miles were deployed late last month. The Continental Hotel, where most foreigners stay, shakes daily from a nearby missile battery. The mujahedeen leaders in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> have so far refused negotiations. But there are only six weeks left before winter weather sets in and most military activity stops because mountain trails are impassable. Said one ambassador, quoting a visiting Englishman during the wars of the last century: `` the only time the Afghans are at peace is when they are fighting.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890925-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-25-89 0147EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     09-25 0951</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,950</SECOND>
<HEAD>Entomologists' Group Marks 100th Anniversary</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
