<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890327-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-27-89 2354EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Iraq-Compensation 2ndLd-Writethru a0634 03-27 0411</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Iraq-Compensation, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0634,380</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Delegation Nears Agreement on Compensation Agreement</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDs: retransmitting a0402 to eliminate garble at end</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> have reached agreement in principle for <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> to pay compensation for the 37 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sailors killed aboard the frigate Stark in a May, 1987 Iraqi missile attack in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>, sources said Monday. The compensation package still needs the formal approval of both governments, said the sources, speaking on condition of anonymity. Progress on the stalled claim request was made when a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> delegation, led by <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> legal adviser <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Sofaer </PERSON>, went to <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> last week. The talks ended Monday and <PERSON> Sofaer </PERSON> was headed back to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON> said. In their talks, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> teams apparently `` are reaching the final stages of achieving a substantial settlement on the claims,'' Ms. <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON> said. She said she did not know when the actual agreement would be concluded and could not divulge details of its content. At the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, defense sources said an agreement had been reached but they described the accord as `` tentative _ subject to review back here in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.'' The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> presented <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> with a $ 29.6 million claim for the families of 37 crewmembers who died on the guided missile frigate Stark when an Iraqi jet fighter fired two French-made Exocet missiles at the ship. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> claimed the missile attack was a mistake born of the tensions of the Iran-Iraq war. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> claim was presented 11 months ago but <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> rejected the amount, which includes $ 800,000 for each of the families. The defense sources, who insisted on anonymity, said they could not discuss the dollar amount in the agreement or how it might be divided among the families of those who were killed; the sailors who were injured; and as settlement toward the cost of repairing the Stark. `` But apparently our negotiators are recommending we settle for a bit less than we were originally asking with the goal of ending further delays in settling the issue,'' one source said. In addition to the $ 29.6 million sought for the families of the 37 dead sailors, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> has asked <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> to pay $ 82.9 million to cover the cost of repairing the Stark and returning it to active duty with the fleet. <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials have refused to say how much they asked <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> to pay to sailors who suffered injuries but survived the attack.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890327-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-27-89 2355EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-EasternRdp 2ndLd-Writethru a0716 03-27 0840</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Eastern Rdp, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0716,0864</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Orders Hearing on Pilots Strike; Carlucci Possible Bankruptcy
Examiner</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 13 grafs to UPDATE with comment from spokesmen for
Eastern, Texas Air, Ueberroth, no-comment from Kerkorian, union; picks
up 9th graf, ``Ueberroth met ...' A version also moving on the financial
wire.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD COLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Outgoing baseball Commissioner <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ueberroth </PERSON> is discussing a purchase of strikebound <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> learned Monday. Meanwhile, a judge ordered a hearing on <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s attempts to force its pilots back to work, and sources said former <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> is among those being considered to head the carrier's reorganization. An offer from <PERSON> Ueberroth </PERSON> may be presented to <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> parent <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>'s board of directors within the next few days, airline industry and baseball sources said on condition of anonymity. Eastern spokesman <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Matell </PERSON>, contacted for comment at his <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> home, said, `` I've heard about it. But we just do n't comment on rumors.'' <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> said his company would have no comment on the matter. `` There are a lot of those rumors going around,'' <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> said. `` If and when any agreement is reached to sell Eastern I'm sure all the parties involved will issue a statement.'' <PERSON> Ueberroth </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, contacted in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, said the commissioner did not wish to comment on the matter. A source said the deal would involve <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerkorian </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> businessman who is a friend of <PERSON> Ueberroth </PERSON>'s and is majority owner of <ORGANIZATION> MGM-UA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Ueberroth </PERSON>, who headed the host committee for the 1984 <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> Olympics, is to step down as baseball commissioner on Saturday A call to <PERSON> Kerkorian </PERSON>'s office seeking comment Monday night was not answered. <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION>'s board is holding a regularly scheduled meeting Tuesday and Wednesday, said a source close to the company. <PERSON> Ueberroth </PERSON> was approached last fall by officials of <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s unions to consider taking over the troubled airline, which filed for bankruptcy protection March 9, five days after the start of the Machinists' strike supported by airline pilots The Machinists and pilots unions have said they would make concessions if <PERSON> Ueberroth </PERSON> took over, possibly in return for ownership of part of the airline. A call to the Machinists local in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> was not answered Monday night. <PERSON> Ueberroth </PERSON> met with Eastern officials during baseball's winter meetings in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> last December, then traveled to <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> for further talks, a baseball source said. In addition, <PERSON> Ueberroth </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kerkorian </PERSON> have discussed a possible buyout with <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON>. In <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> set a hearing Thursday on a key issue tossed back to him by an appeals court. The appellate court said <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> must decide if the pilots are merely honoring <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION> union picket lines legally, or if they are trying to advance their own cause with their walkout, which could violate the National Railway Labor Act. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Line </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pilots </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> has backed the full hearing, denying their strike is illegal. In refusing to cross the picket line, <ORGANIZATION> ALPA </ORGANIZATION> `` certainly considered our parallel interests to strengthen our position to obtain our own collective bargaining interests,'' said pilots' attorney <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Linsey </PERSON> `` There is nothing wrong with that.'' Eastern proceeded on another front against the pilots Monday, inaugurating its first six-week training class to replace pilots who walked out with Machinists on March 4. While the carrier had planned to begin training up to 50 replacement pilots Monday, the class size ended up smaller than that. `` We cut back to 35,'' said company spokesman <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Matell </PERSON>, adding that all the new hires had impressive qualifications. The carrier said many are pilots from other carriers hoping to bump up their seniority by jumping to Eastern. Meanwhile, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Bankruptcy Trustee <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, who is administering <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s Chapter 11 bankruptcy reorginization in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, said Monday he is considering about a dozen candidates for examiner in the complex case. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, who declined to name names, said the ideal examiner would be `` someone who can play the role of statesman.'' Sources who spoke under condition of anonymity told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> that the list includes <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> and top securities fraud lawyer <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Silverman </PERSON>. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said he hopes to decide by late this week or early nex week, and will recommend that person to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Bankruptcy Court Judge <PERSON> Burton </PERSON> <PERSON> Lifland </PERSON>. <PERSON> Lifland </PERSON> has said he would appoint an examiner with sweeping powers to try to mediate the bitter dispute between <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> and its unions. The examiner also will review financial transactions between <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> and sister carrier <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Silverman </PERSON>, a Washington-based securities lawyer who represented some claimants in <ORGANIZATION> Manville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>'s Chapter 11 proceeding starting in August 1982, also is one of the lead defense attorneys for imprisoned insider trader <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boesky </PERSON>. <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> is now vice chairman and managing director of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carlyle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, an investment banking firm in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <PERSON> D.C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON>'s secretary said he was unavailable to comment. <PERSON> Silverman </PERSON> said he was n't aware he was on the list.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890327-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-27-89 0018EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Oscars-SocialWhirl     03-27 0511</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Oscars-Social Whirl,0524</SECOND>
<HEAD>Glamour Stressed for Oscars and Post-Ceremony Partying</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF WILSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's Academy Awards time again, the glamour, the glitz and the ballyhoo. But Oscar can easily be upstaged by the <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> sideshows sharing the bill. Who's wearing what and with whom _ the evening's Five Ws _ have been known to steal the show from the golden statuettes that come later, as arriving celebrities ritualistically alight from their black limos. On the party scene, the Academy's official Governor's Ball is generally a staid affair and Oscar winners usually make only obligatory appearances before heading to private parties. But this year, many stars will party while watching the awards on television. `` It is very fashionable this year to say, ` I'm not going to the Oscars,''' said celebrity insider <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON>, who is also a public relations consultant for <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> hair stylist <PERSON> Umberto </PERSON>. Superagent <PERSON> Irving </PERSON> `` Swifty'' <PERSON> Lazar </PERSON> will throw his annual Oscar soiree at the posh eatery <ORGANIZATION> Spago </ORGANIZATION>, with dozens of celebrities expected to gather there to watch the awards on television. Those expected include <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Bridges </PERSON>, <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Close </PERSON>, <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON>. The city's No. 1 celebrity of late, former President <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, turned down an invitation to <PERSON> Lazar </PERSON>'s party to watch the awards with wife, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON>, at their <LOCATION> Bel-Air </LOCATION> home, said spokesman <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinberg </PERSON>. Actress <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> will hold a private get-together to watch the Oscars show, and <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tova </PERSON> <PERSON> Borgnine </PERSON> will cast mock ballots with friends during a private party in their <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> home. Other mockers will gather at the Palace club in <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>, the scene of the <ORGANIZATION> Golden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Raspberry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>'s annual Oscar spoof ceremony, which this year will be held simultaneously with the Academy Awards. Guests will dine on a potluck dinner while viewing the real Oscar show on a large-screen TV. Presentation of the plastic `` Razzie'' trophies, which honor the worst in entertainment, will be made during commercial breaks. The Oscars ceremony may not be the only game in town Wednesday, but it could be the most expensive. A complete Academy Awards evening can range from $ 1,800 to $ 15,000 per person. A seat at the Shrine Auditorium ceremony costs $ 150, the Governor's Ball runs $ 450, it's $ 500 for a stretch-limousine, tuxedo rental is about $ 70 and designer gowns range from $ 1,200 to $ 12,000. Producer <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> Carr </PERSON>, who hired designers <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Klausen </PERSON> and <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayman </PERSON> to spiff up the Oscar show, said the awards will be big, glitzy and nostalgic, more like a Broadway play than the annual parade to the podium. `` The trend this year will be drop-dead chic entrance gowns,'' said <PERSON> Hayman </PERSON>. `` The idea this year is a return to great glamour, the Hollywood of the past. The public looks to <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> for glamour.'' He promised `` a lot of wonderful beading'' on the gowns. Two celebrities can particularly be expected to have the drop-dead look. <PERSON> Cher </PERSON> can usually be counted on to expose her navel, and actress-model <PERSON> Edy </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> habitually steps out of a limousine wearing not much of anything.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890327-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-27-89 0045EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AssaultRifles Bjt   03-27 1127</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Assault Rifles, Bjt,1100</SECOND>
<HEAD>NRA Loads Up as Gun Issue Heats Up</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rifle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, traditional heart, soul and bankroll of the nation's gun lobby, is digging in for a test of its vaunted political power amid rising pressure to curb sales of assault weapons. `` When less than half the convicted felons ever spend a day in jail, why should we be taking firearms away from law-abiding people?'' declares <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, federal affairs director for the 118-year old <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>. Demands for restrictions on military-style, semiautomatic firearms are escalating, however, in the aftermath of the <LOCATION> Stockton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, schoolyard tragedy Jan. 17 in which a deranged gunman with an assault rifle left five youngsters dead and 30 other persons injured. So intense is the clamor that, as often as the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> has crushed or blunted gun control bills in the past, many doubt that it can prevail this time with its strategy of blaming the murder wave sweeping cocaine-ridden communities not on firearms but `` our crumbling criminal justice system.'' `` We're certainly going to try,'' says lobbyist <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>. Even Rep. <PERSON> Barney </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, D-Mass., who urged Democrats to softpedal the gun issue after the 1988 election, says public opinion is ripe for action on semiautomatics `` I think the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> is stubbing its toe here,'' he says. `` The appearance of being unwilling to deal with assault rifles has hurt them.'' From its modern headquarters on <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION> in downtown <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, a few blocks from the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> deploys lobbyists to <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> and statehouses across the nation, provides generous campaign contributions to its political friends and generates tons of literature to fill the mailboxes of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s gun enthusiasts With annual revenues of $ 70 million and a staff of 365 employees, including 65 in its lobbying department, the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> is well equipped to fight its political battles. It also has powerful friends. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is a member. And its roots go deep in the fabric of American life. Founded in 1871 by <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> officers, the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> has long counted many military men and policemen among its members. It holds firearms courses for police, private security firms and private citizens. It is recognized by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Olympic Committee as the national governing body of shooting sports in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and maintains a junior program for youngsters. It also provides self-defense courses for women and maintains a 1,100-piece gun museum within its headquarters as well as a special, `` Muzzleloaders'' division within its membership for history buffs. Last year, the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> got the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to shelve a proposed seven-day waiting period for would-be gun buyers. Failure of the bill named for former presidential spokesman <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>, brain damaged in the 1981 attempt on President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, spurred <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>'s wife to urge readers in full-page magazine ads to help `` break the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>'s death grip on <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>.'' The real secret of the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>'s power has long been its ability to mobilize hundreds of thousands of gun owners across the nation to write and telephone lawmakers. `` Please open immediately. Legislative alert,'' trumpets a mailing that went to <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> gun owners in February. It warns of an impending bill in <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION> in which `` the anti-gunners ... have launched an all-out attack on semiautomatic firearms in line with their goal of banning all firearms.'' `` Your immediate action is needed to defeat this dangerous bill,'' it says. But the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> nevertheless approved the measure calling for a background check of would-be gun buyers. <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> lawmakers are expected to pass a more stringent measure and bills are pending in <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. A number of cities, including <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>, also have approved restrictions on semiautomatic weapons. And on Sunday, the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chiefs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> announced its opposition to the public sale and distribution of the guns. The chain reaction has led to a further question of <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> power. `` The <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> is being forced increasingly to the fringes of this debate,'' says Dr. <PERSON> Garen </PERSON> <PERSON> Wintemute </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, who treated AK-47 assault rifle wounds as a doctor in a <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> jungle hospital in 1981. On coming home, he was shocked to find the same AK-47 wounds in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` More and more people are willing to come out and say, the emperor has no clothes, meaning the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>,'' says the doctor, who has become an outspoken critic of assault-rifle sales. Others are more skeptical about the alleged erosion of <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> power. `` The <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> members have n't lost anything with me,'' declares Rep. <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Volkmer </PERSON>, D-Mo. Few if any <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members take a dimmer view of gun control. Pending bills aimed at military-style assault weapons also would `` take away my Browning shotgun and my thirty-ought-six deer rifle,'' says <PERSON> Volkmer </PERSON>. `` I think we can kill that up here. I think we can beat it.'' What happens in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> will depend heavily on the view from the hustings. Democrats say a blizzard of <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> mailings against 1988 presidential nominee <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> were probably not decisive. But they hurt, especially in states where gun owners are plentiful. <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> political consultant <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Christian </PERSON> says the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> stand in favor of toughened gun control `` was n't the No. 1 issue'' in his state `` but as part of a package of issues that subjected him to attack from the other side, it played a very important role. `` The Republicans used gun control advertising very heavily, so obviously their polling showed that it was an important issue,'' he says. But on Capitol Hill, a stream of gun-control bills is flowing into the hopper, sponsored by Rep. <PERSON> Fortney </PERSON> -LRB- Pete -RRB- Stark, <LOCATION> D-Calif </LOCATION>., and an array of other Californians The most heavily spotlighted bill, however, is being offered by Sen. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>. It would place certain semiautomatics, such as the AK-47 and the Israeli-made Uzi, in the same restricted-sales category with fully automatic machine guns. It also would allow the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to put additional semiautomatics in the same class. Private citizens may own machine guns but only if they are fingerprinted, pay a $ 200 fee, undergo an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> background check and get permission from their local law enforcement officials. This has not deterred all firearms fans. <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> <PERSON> Stapleton </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> NRA member, declares that he would hate to part with the .50 - caliber machine gun that is the centerpiece of his Why does he want it? `` What does anyone pay $ 150,000 for a Ferrari? Why does anyone want a Matisse?'' <PERSON> Stapleton </PERSON> muses. His company makes a sinister-looking round-drummed, semiautomatic shotgun called the Striker, which pumps out 12 rounds of 12-gauge shot in three seconds. The weapon, designed by a Rhodesian farmer to chase off rebels, is precisely what <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON> wants to outlaw.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890327-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-27-89 0046EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Refugees'Voices Bjt   03-27 0796</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Refugees' Voices, Bjt,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>14 Million Refugees, But They Speak in One Voice</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Note contents 11th graf</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE FEINSILBER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Whether they're from <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, they all seem to speak the same language: the language of the refugee. The voice and the picture of the world's 14 million political refugees _ of whom it has been calculated that only three of every 100 ever return to their homeland _ is brought home in a newly published photo book. The book, `` Forced Out,'' represents an unusual collaboration by four publishing houses and a foundation in an attempt to inspire a global movement on behalf of the human rights of refugees, often unwanted guests in unwelcoming camps. It consists largely of accounts by refugees of the sometimes bewildering, frightening or hopeless twists their lives took once they were forced from their homelands. To a world inured to political disaster, the voices sound familiar. A Salvadoran, describing how the National Guard conscripts boys from a sleeping village: `` No one could run that night, maybe because the boys were still half asleep. ` They are only going for a year,' the members of the patrol would say to make us feel better, ` and they'll be more civilized when we send them back. In the barracks they learn to read and mind their manners,' they went on, without looking at anyone, addressing the stones that were us. The year was up but they never came back. No one comes back.'' An Ethiopian, resettled in <LOCATION> Somalia </LOCATION>: `` Arriving in the area of settlement we were scared to death. You feel lost. ... Never had we seen such thick forest, inhabited only by wild animals, snakes and big, biting flies. Homeland was a beautiful place, full of grazing cattle. My dreams are still bound to my homeland.'' An Afghan looking for a new home: `` We were deported from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> on March 29. They next day <ORGANIZATION> Korean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> took us to <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> and then to <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> refused us and sent us back to <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. The Koreans then sent us to <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION> and told the Sri Lankan authorities that we should be sent on to <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. The Sri Lankan government refused to accept us ... so <ORGANIZATION> Korean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> took us to <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>.'' A Salvadoran: `` If we speak out, they kill us. If we're suspected of speaking out, they disappear us And if we keep our mouths shut, they think we're hiding something. So they kill us for that too.'' In one painful paragraph, a famous <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> doctor, <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rusk </PERSON>, describes how the body starves: `` Nature becomes kinder to the starving at this juncture, kinder than the politicians arguing about boundaries and power. A great overpowering lethargy develops, and a kind and wise nature offers large doses of sleep to ease the pain of slow death. In the meantime the body proteins have been depleted, the water and electrolyte balance destroyed. The abdomen becomes distended with fluids, the extremities swollen with water, and now the degeneration of the vital organs such as the liver and the kidneys starts in earnest ...'' A Vietnamese boat person describes the desperation of the starving: `` Our food and water ran out. No ship rescued us. ` Please wait until tomorrow. I'll die. Then you'll eat me,' said <PERSON> Dao </PERSON> <PERSON> Huo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuong </PERSON>. Three of us pulled <PERSON> Cuong </PERSON> out of the cabin and held his head in water. Then one of us butchered him. Four others helped. We cooked the meat in boiling water. I remember we prayed to the Lord before we killed Mr. <PERSON> Cuong </PERSON>.'' Principal author <PERSON> Carole </PERSON> <PERSON> Kismaric </PERSON> says political rather than natural disasters create most refugees and most are forced from their homes by their own governments, either for supporting rival factions or so that their land can be seized. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Frelick </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Refugees </ORGANIZATION>, in an essay on how countries accept or reject refugees, writes, `` Refugees are inconvenient. Their concern is not for order, systems or bureaucracies, nor for the general welfare. Their concern, rather, is for survival _ their own and that of their families. `` Governments, on the other hand, have competing concerns: the sovereignty of borders, relations with neighboring countries, controlling immigration, promoting ruling ideologies, placating public opinion. If offering asylum to a refugee is consonant with those concerns, a government might come to his aid.'' `` Forced Out,'' a collection of photographs and first-person accounts refugees, was commissioned by the <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaplan </PERSON> <PERSON> Fund </PERSON>, supporter of <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Watch </ORGANIZATION>, which monitors the conditions of refugees. It was published in a collaboration by <ORGANIZATION> Random </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> W.W. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Norton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> William </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Morrow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Penguin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Books </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>, with profits earmarked for the Human Rights Fund.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890327-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-27-89 0046EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CondorEgg     03-27 0267</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Condor Egg,0276</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rare Condor Egg Found at Zoo on Easter Morning</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A tiny, pale aqua egg was found in the nest box of a pair of nearly extinct <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> condors at the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> Zoo. The egg, measuring 5 inches long, 3 inches in circumference and weighing about 10 ounces, was spotted early Easter Sunday morning. Zoo workers took the egg to an incubator while the parents, <LOCATION> Cuyama </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Cachuma </PERSON>, a pair of 6-year-olds, were away from the nest. `` What an Easter egg!,'' said zoo spokeswoman <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollack </PERSON>. `` If fertile, God willing, it will hatch in 54 to 58 days.'' The pair had an egg last month that proved to be infertile. Zoo officials also took that egg away for artificial incubation in hopes that <PERSON> Cachuma </PERSON> would `` double clutch'' or lay a second egg. `` We have high hopes for this egg because since the time of the last one they have definitely improved their -LRB- mating -RRB- technique,'' Ms. <PERSON> Pollack </PERSON> said. `` It's a big egg, a nice egg. It looks good but we wo n't know for sure for another week.'' She added that there were no cracks in the shell. In the wild, the massive birds with a 9 -LCB- - foot wing span would normally lay one egg every other year, Ms. <PERSON> Pollack </PERSON> said <PERSON> Molloko </PERSON> is the only <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> condor chick conceived in captivity. The bird was born last April and stays in the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> Wild Animal Park. There are only 28 <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> condors left in the world. Fourteen of them are in the Wild Animal Park and 14 at the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> Zoo.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890327-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-27-89 0048EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-RefugeeCrisis Bjt   03-27 0946</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Refugee Crisis, Bjt,980</SECOND>
<HEAD>United States Overwhelmed By Glasnost's Flood Of Emigrants</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RUTH SINAI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For years, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has urged, threatened and cajoled the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> to allow free emigration from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. But now that thousands of Soviets are being let out, many are finding the doors to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> closed. Some 19,000 Soviets are waiting to be interviewed at the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> for permission to enter the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> as refugees; another 7,000 are waiting in temporary quarters near <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, according to <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> figures. The steadily growing backlog appears to result from several factors: poor planning by the administration, severe budget restraints and a change in the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s refugee policy. `` Now that the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has chosen to let these people go, we must not fail them,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Berman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Calif </LOCATION>., who has sponsored one of several proposed funding bills to ease the emergency Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kasten </PERSON>, R-Wis., co-sponsor of another emergency funding proposal, warned that `` <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s policies could change overnight We have to take advantage of this moment.'' Soviet applicants have been told their processing could take as long as two years and have been advised not to quit jobs or tell landlords they plan to leave for fear of finding themselves without work or housing. Last fall the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> asked Soviet authorities to withhold exit permits until some of the backlog can be cleared, Jewish community officials say. At the current rate of Soviet applications _ about 4,000 a month _ the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will run out of allocated refugee slots by April or May. In January, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> shifted 7,000 unused slots meant for Vietnamese refugees to accommodate the Soviet overflow. Revised estimates project some 40,000 Soviet applicants this year, about 20,000 more than was budgeted for by the administration. The crisis has been compounded by a change in <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> policy, which no longer grants automatic refugee status to every person seeking to leave the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. In the past, all Soviet Jews, who account for the majority of Soviet emigres, were presumed to have a `` well founded fear of persecution'' and therefore were considered refugees. Jews were subjected to government-backed anti-Semitism, prevented from studying Hebrew or practicing their religion and denied permission to leave. In 1984, the low point of Jewish emigration, only 896 Jews were let out. A directive issued last summer by former Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> ordered the <ORGANIZATION> Immigration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> to determine refugee status for Soviets on a case-by-case basis rather than as a group, in keeping with the way <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> laws are applied for other refugee applicants. This has resulted in denials for as many as 70 percent of <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> applicants for refugee status, according to a just-released report by the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, the investigative arm of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The report found a 50 percent reversal rate on appeal by those denied, evidence of `` uneven standards and inconsistencies among INS officers.'' The report faulted <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> inspectors for, in many cases, not speaking Russian and not knowing about life in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. In some cases, <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> processors were brought to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> from duty along the U.S.-Mexican border and applied the same standards to Soviet applicants as to Mexicans, the report said. Those denied refugee status are being offered parolee status, which does not provide government funding nor does it allow the recipients to eventually apply for citizenship. `` This sends a message to the Soviet government that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> no longer views Jews and other minorities as persecuted people,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> representative of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jewish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> which lobbies for Soviet Jewish immigration. `` It's a strange political statement as a time when the administration has decided to keep up its pressure on <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to comply with international human rights standards,'' he said. The administration, caught in a squeeze, is scrambling to respond. The White House is preparing an emergency request to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for $ 100 million to help process and resettle the flood of emigrants. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has prepared legislation that would allow as many as 30,000 people to enter the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> annually if the president declares it in the best foreign policy interests of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Unlike refugees, though, these people would not be given government funding. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is conducting an internal review of the problem in preparation for consultations with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on increasing the number of refugees allowed into the country. Meanwhile, more <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> officers are being sent to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to help hasten the processing, said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Refugee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Programs </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> told a congressional hearing that the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> could not have foreseen the surge of Soviet applicants when it budgeted last year for this fiscal year. But members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and Jewish community groups are accusing the administration of deliberately misleading them. `` The administration's refugee program is phony,'' said Rep. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Obey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Wis </LOCATION>., head of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on foreign operations `` This was not unpredictable in light of last year's growing emigration trends,'' he told <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> Obey accused the administration of presenting deliberately low predictions in order to stay within the limits of the budget, knowing it could obtain emergency funding later on to respond to the humanitarian crisis. Jewish groups contend the low figures are part of an administration attempt to shift the funding for refugee programs increasingly to private groups. Currently, the American Jewish community provides about $ 2 to $ 3 for every government dollar spent on refugee admissions and resettlement and it has launched a $ 75 million fund-raising campaign to provide for the flood of emigres.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890327-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-27-89 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-IMF-WorldBank Bjt   03-27 0968</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-IMF-World Bank, Bjt,950</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two World Bodies Clash Over Scope</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CARL HARTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A feud is smoldering between two world institutions based in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> with billions of dollars to lend and the power to make deeply indebted countries tighten their belts. The disagreement between the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monetary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION> centers around the division of work between them. Which should be telling governments to devalue their currencies? Which should require cuts in government spending? Which should look at long-term problems? How long is long-term? The 151 governments that own the bank and the <ORGANIZATION> IMF </ORGANIZATION>, which get together every spring and fall, start meetings in the coming week. Their ministers of finance and central bankers will have a lot to say about the debt of Third World countries, now over $ 1.2 trillion. What the two organizations can do about it depends on clearing up just what their roles should be, or even whether they should be merged. Treasury Secretary <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> has put out some new ideas on how to reduce the debt, but critics are saying they may be too little and too late. Other governments are expected to suggest doing more. Before the meetings open, President <PERSON> Barber </PERSON> <PERSON> Conable </PERSON> of the bank, a former congressman from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, and Managing Director <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Camdessus </PERSON> of the fund, a Frenchman, are trying to agree on how to cooperate. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and nine other leading governments have asked <PERSON> Lamberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Dini </PERSON>, the No. 2 at the Italian government's central bank, to report on improving the relations between the twin institutions `` If they do n't get their act together, there's going to be more pressure to merge them,'' said <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Bergsten </PERSON>, who heads the private <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economics </ORGANIZATION>. `` That would be a mistake, because they would only have to be separated again after a few years.'' <PERSON> Bergsten </PERSON> used to be in charge of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> relations with them as assistant secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> for international affairs. Both organizations are linked to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, but they have something it lacks: teeth. By giving or holding back loans and by the conditions they set, they can sometimes make or break governments. Their conditions can lead to violence. Most recently, a reduction in government subsidies, urged by the fund, brought an increase in bus fares that touched off riots last month in <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION>. At least 300 people were killed. Both the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> IMF </ORGANIZATION> were set up at a meeting in <LOCATION> Bretton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Woods </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.H. </LOCATION>, as World War II came to an end. Western leaders were hoping to nip in the bud the economic problems that had twice helped to plunge the world into bloody conflict. The bank, officially the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reconstruction </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>, was to help the countries devastated by the war to recover a decent standard of living. As they did, the bank turned to the Third World, making easy, long-term loans for schools, hospitals, farms, roads, ports _ the basic needs of poor countries. <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> were among the biggest borrowers. The fund's job was to keep currencies stable. Big shifts in currency values upset world trade, and bad trade relations can lead to bad political relations. As recently as the 1970s it was helping <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> with such problems. In time the fund too found itself working mostly in the Third World, where high values for local currencies wre making trade difficult. Often the exchange rates were only part of a country's problem The fund offered big loans and mobilized more from private banks. To get the loans, borrowing governments had to promise changes in their policies _ austerity programs, often including devaluations, to put the debtors in better shape to keep up with their debts. Billions went to <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and other major debtors. In 1985 <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, then secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>, said the way out of the debt problem was more loans and more policy changes by the borrowers. The <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> plan called on the bank to map out longer-term programs for them, since their problems went too deep to be solved in a few years and the bank was used to taking the long view. It had always made some `` policy-based'' loans. Now it started making more. So bank and fund, with headquarters facing one another in downtown <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, found their jobs overlapping more and more. They approached problems from different viewpoints. <PERSON> Lord </PERSON> <PERSON> Keynes </PERSON>, the British economist who helped set them up, was quoted as saying that the bank is a fund and the fund is a bank. Funds are usually concerned with improving people's living standards; banks worry more about finance. But some of the <ORGANIZATION> IMF </ORGANIZATION>'s staff of 1,600 have seen the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> as a collection of 6,000 soft-minded do-gooders Many in the bank thought the fund too preoccupied with the world's financial system and insensitive to people's needs. Neither bank nor fund officials want to be quoted about their differences, except to say that they try hard to work together. But some acknowledge privately that they have occasionally given countries contradictory advice. Last October the bank offered $ 700 million worth of loans to <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>. The fund had been negotiating with <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> for years, but could not get the government of President <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON> to meet its conditions. The bank's offer raised a lot of eyebrows: in the past, the bank had waited for the fund's approval of a country's policies before going ahead with its own lending In February, after disbursing $ 150 million, the bank decided <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> was not meeting its own conditions and refused to disburse another $ 350 million. There were some quiet `` I-told-you-sos'' from sympathizers with the fund, but officials said the bank's action showed that the two institutions were closer to seeing eye-to-eye.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890327-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-27-89 0053EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     03-27 0889</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,910</SECOND>
<HEAD>Farmers Advised to be Wary of Easier Credit</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An improving economy and a surge of federal relief measures have put easy credit back within reach of farmers, but an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> economist says yielding to temptation could be hazardous to the financial health of some of them. `` Farmers have reasons to be optimistic,'' says <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Gajewski </PERSON> of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. `` The burdensome grain stocks are dropping and commodity prices are strong in the face of rising domestic and foreign demand.'' <PERSON> Gajewski </PERSON> cites rising land values after years of declines `` and bankers' willingness to lend'' as reflections of farmers' improved outlook. `` But the current optimism is tempered by the knowledge that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and foreign farmers still have the capacity to produce large crops and large volumes of livestock products that could exert downward pressure on agricultural prices and land values,'' he added. The <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> analyst, writing in the April issue of Agricultural Outlook magazine, said that when the drought hit last summer many farmers needed more credit to cover expenses and gear up for the next season. `` Bankers are often accused of deserting farmers when times get tough, but this apparently did not happen during and after the drought,'' <PERSON> Gajewski </PERSON> said. In 1987, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> provided up to $ 4 billion to rescue the ailing Farm Credit System, the national cooperative network of land banks, production credit associations and other units that serve farmers. Drought relief last year added an additional $ 3.9 billion package. Huge outlays for government commodity support programs have pumped billions of dollars into the farm economy, reaching a record $ 25.8 billion just three years ago. `` When combined with rebounding farmland values, the recent rescue of the <ORGANIZATION> FCS </ORGANIZATION>, and other changes in the farm credit delivery system -LRB- including an overhaul of <ORGANIZATION> Farmers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> loan policies -RRB-, the good news about credit availability raises questions about how much credit farmers should use,'' <PERSON> Gajewski </PERSON> said. Some financial analysts, he said, are concerned that the recent rise in farmland values may not be supported by future returns. The boom of the 1970s was followed by a collapse in land values. `` During the early and mid-1980s, all of the inflation adjusted gains to farmers from the 1970s land price runup were lost,'' <PERSON> Gajewski </PERSON> said. Agricultural banks in the severe drought areas began 1988 in a stronger position and made relatively more loans through the drought's summer peak than banks did in other areas, he said. For example, loan volume in the drought areas grew by 4.7 percent to 7 percent from the end of 1987 to mid-1988, compared with a 2.9 percent growth at agricultural banks elsewhere. More than half of the nation's roughly 4,500 agricultural banks _ commercial banks that specialize in farm finance _ are located in counties hit hardest by last year's drought. <PERSON> Gajewski </PERSON> said the picture for the Farm Credit System is less clear. Most of the drought damage was in FCS multi-state districts having headquarters in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paul </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>; and <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>, Neb. Performing loans _ those without late payments or collateral problems _ grew in volume by 2.6 percent in the three districts during the first half of 1988, compared with a 4.7 percent growth systemwide. `` In general, lenders are willing and able to make new loans to farmers when they believe agricultural prospects look good,'' he said. `` Lower wheat and -LRB- soybean -RRB- stocks, and the consequent runup in commodity prices, have given farmers and their lenders reason for optimism.'' A recent survey of a agricultural bankers in the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> showed that farmland value rose an average of 11.5 percent in 1988, up a fifth from the depressed level of 1986, he said. And a <ORGANIZATION> Minneapolis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> survey in December showed cropland values up 5.7 percent from a year earlier. `` Farms in both the <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION> districts were hit hard by the drought,'' <PERSON> Gajewski </PERSON> said. `` Apparently, the drought did not markedly weaken the already rebounding land market. In part, this is because land values reflect expectations about the land's future earning power, not just current earning power. Another factor in making farm credit cheaper and easier to deliver is the new <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mortgage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corporation </ORGANIZATION>, or <ORGANIZATION> Farmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mac </ORGANIZATION>, which is a secondary market for agricultural real estate loans and rural housing. <PERSON> Gajewski </PERSON> said <PERSON> Farmer </PERSON> <PERSON> Mac </PERSON> will allow lenders to originate and service fixed-rate and flexible-rate long-term mortgages without keeping the loans on their books. By selling mortgages in the secondary market, lenders will be able to pass on much of the risks while keeping the origination and servicing fees. The Farmer Mac loan sales are ultimately guaranteed by the federal government, although lenders selling loans will have to maintain or contribute to a small reserve against future losses, he said. `` Farmer Mac can benefit farmers, but the loan standards it sets will determine its effectiveness,'' <PERSON> Gajewski </PERSON> said. If the standards are too tight, only the lowest-risk loans will be sold, and the new market will not have much effect. If they're too loose, lenders will be able to pass high-risk farm loans on to non-farm investors, with federal backing `` This would encourage farmers to take on more debt, leaving them more vulnerable to the vicissitudes of weather, the general economy and international markets,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890327-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-27-89 0053EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-PhilippinesFarms     03-27 0512</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Philippines Farms,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Small Third World Farmers Report Gains from Export Crops</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CARL HARTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When 448 farm households on the Philippine island of <LOCATION> Mindanao </LOCATION> switched to raising sugar for sale to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, their earnings per acre grew to nearly double those of their neighbors. The cash crop brought the equivalent of just over $ 100 an acre in a year, compared with about $ 52 an acre for the corn grown by neighboring families. These were poor families, with farms that averaged only about 10 acres. In a country where the average citizen earns about $ 660 a year, the difference was huge. `` Contrary to conventional wisdom, farmers who produce crops for export have more income and are better fed than subsistence farmers who produce only basic food crops for home consumption,'' said the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Policy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, an independent study organization. The institute project was run by <PERSON> Joachim </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Braun </PERSON>, a West Germam farm economist, with a grant from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government's <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> The study found at least one bad effect from the contracts offered by the <ORGANIZATION> Bukidnon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sugar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>: some corn farmers sold their land or gave up leases and took jobs on sugar farms, creating a new group of landless farm workers. <PERSON> Von </PERSON> <PERSON> Braun </PERSON> suggested that the <LOCATION> Philippine </LOCATION> government should have gotten the mill to make contracts for sugar with the tenant farmers, as well as with those who owned land. The government could also have taken measures to improve the production of small farms that stayed with growing corn, making credit, fertilizer and new varieties available, he said. Contrary to some people's belief, the researchers saw no damage to child health _ but little improvement either _ from the change to cash crops. While better income from the sugar provided more food for the family, it did little to solve the problem of badly nourished children. Better health and sanitation measures are needed as well, the report said. <PERSON> Von </PERSON> <PERSON> Braun </PERSON> said that as farmers' income rose, the proportion they spent on traditional foods went down. Spending on meat, housing, transport and education rose sharply among the most prosperous farmers in the Philippine group. <PERSON> Von </PERSON> <PERSON> Braun </PERSON> studied farmers not only in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, but also in the east African republic of <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> who made a similar switch, and Guatemalans who tried vegetables instead of corn. There were also groups in two more African countries who switched to farming for the market rather than for home consumption. In central African Rwanda they planted potatoes and tea instead of corn. In <LOCATION> Gambia </LOCATION>, on the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> coast, the shift was from swamp rice to peanuts and to rice under irrigation. The researchers found that when small farmers switched to cash crops, they often kept some of their land in traditional food crops as a kind of insurance. The study said that makes sense, because the income from cash crops is not always certain. Sugar prices have dropped from the levels that first made the switch attractive in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, for example.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890327-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-27-89 0052EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     03-27 0636</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0664</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Kristy </PERSON> <PERSON> McNichol </PERSON> refused to continue working on the movie `` Just the Way You Are'' in 1982 and rumors flew that she was a drug addict, an alcoholic or a manic depressive. She denies the rumors, telling this week's People magazine that it was an emotional breakdown that caused her to leave the set. `` I was totally out of control,'' said <PERSON> McNichol </PERSON>, 26. `` I wanted to please everybody all the time. ... I was making my mom happy. And then I found out later that was n't making me happy,'' she said. A friend took her to a psychiatrist who advised her not to go on with the movie, her eighth in six years. She finished the movie a year later. Once a star on the TV series `` Family,'' <PERSON> McNichol </PERSON> is back in prime time starring in <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Empty Nest.'' She said she finally is in control of her life. `` Now I feel like I'm this mountain of strength,'' she said. `` Now I think, ` This is the time for me.'''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitley </PERSON> says he does n't remember when he wanted to be anything but a country singer. `` I grew up listening to my mother's collection of <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> and <PERSON> Marty </PERSON> <PERSON> Robbins </PERSON> records,'' said the <LOCATION> Sandyhook </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, native. <PERSON> Whitley </PERSON> was 13 when he met another aspiring <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> bluegrass musician, <PERSON> Ricky </PERSON> <PERSON> Skaggs </PERSON>, at a fiddlers' convention in <LOCATION> Ezell </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Skaggs </PERSON> joined <PERSON> Whitley </PERSON>'s band, the <ORGANIZATION> East </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kentucky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mountain </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boys </ORGANIZATION> `` I laid my country music aside for quite a while ... because bluegrass audiences did n't care to hear it. But it just kept haunting me,'' <PERSON> Whitley </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Whitley </PERSON> in 1972 formed the New Tradition, later known as the Country Store. In 1978, he teamed with <PERSON> J.D </PERSON>. <PERSON> Crowe </PERSON> and the New South. <PERSON> Whitley </PERSON>'s hit list includes `` Do n't Close Your Eyes,'' `` Homecoming'63,'' `` Ten Feet Away,'' and `` I'm No Stranger to the Rain.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CHARLESTON, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican National Chairman <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> let fly some barbs of his own following a roast by <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republicans </ORGANIZATION>. `` Mama always told me do n't attack unarmed people _ especially in a battle of wits,'' he told the more than 1,000 people at Saturday night's event. <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> also poked fun at himself. He said he was glad to be back in <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, noting he spent the first five years of his life there. `` I learned from <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> that the more places you call home, the more votes you get,'' he said. Gov. <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> said, `` I often wondered what <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> would be when he grew up. I'm still wondering.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CHARLESTON, W.Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> Gaston </PERSON> <PERSON> Caperton </PERSON> says he could n't read a comic book when he was growing up because he suffered from dyslexia, a disability that jumbles letters and numbers in a person's mind `` I was smart enough that I was able to fool my way through for a while,'' <PERSON> Caperton </PERSON> said in an interview. `` I remembered when all the other kids in the neighborhood would read the funny books and I could n't. I just sort of looked at the pictures.'' Eventually, his parents caught on and began an extensive catch-up program for him. By the time he reached high school, the problem was under control, he said. <PERSON> Caperton </PERSON>, 49, is an avid reader who loves history books and fiction. He's also a strong backer of remedial education. `` It's so important to fund those programs in the early years. If we can catch it then, the kids will have a chance later on,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Opera singer <PERSON> Placido </PERSON> <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON> helped brighten Easter for children hospitalized with cancer. Toting Easter candy, the 48-year-old international star visited children and their families Sunday in the cancer ward at Children's Hospital in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890327-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-27-89 0054EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Drought     03-27 0754</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drought,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wheat-Growing Regions Still Dry</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hope for a wetter summer is blossoming in the wake of recent coastal rains, but drought continues in several sections of the nation. Wheat-growing areas of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> and adjacent <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> remain particularly dry, and area legislators have already begun to complain about lack of concern in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. In the Northeast, meanwhile, a dry winter left reservoirs low, threatening water supplies in parts of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> and other parts of the <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> basin. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> declared a drought emergency and imposed strict water-use limits last week, citing low reservoir levels that have not been replenished by winter snowfalls, though recent rains may help some. Recalling low river flows that restricted shipping in the nation's midsection last year, the navigation season on the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> is being shortened by five weeks to allow water to be held in reserve at reservoirs, which are only about 60 percent full. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Miskus </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atmospheric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Climate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Analysis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> reports that storms along the Gulf and <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> coasts have helped ease the dryness there somewhat in recent days, and more moisture is expected in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> states. Incoming storms could also bring some needed moisture to the middle of the nation this week, <PERSON> Miskus </PERSON> said. The long-term outlook through mid-April calls for above normal precipitation in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lakes </LOCATION> and the Northeast. But that projection also indicates below normal rain in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and adjacent states and in a large area including <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and northern <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>. Some of those areas are badly in need of moisture. Over the winter, fierce winds eroded nearly 4.7 million acres of land in the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION>, one of the most extensive losses on record, according to an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> survey. `` Much of this damage is due to the drought,'' said <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> Scaling, chief of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Soil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. `` We went into the wind erosion season with poor cover in much of the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION> because of the drought. Then this winter, we've had a combination of no snow cover and high-velocity winds in many areas.'' In addition to the land damaged during the four-month period, Scaling said more than 22.5 million acres were `` in condition to blow'' as of March 1, the most in 32 years. Highest on the list are <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, he said. Farm state lawmakers, meanwhile, say the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> is mishandling last year's emergency drought relief and ignoring this year's arid, potentially disastrous conditions on the High Plains. Rep. <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, R-Kan., said the central part of the country is `` blowing away'' but help is not forthcoming from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> because of the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's slow pace in filling key policy jobs at <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> As of Feb. 28, more than 558,000 producers have received disaster payments and emergency feed assistance amounting to more than $ 2.7 billion, responded <PERSON> Milton </PERSON> <PERSON> Hertz </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. On the other hand, along a wide belt from <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>, moisture has been excessive in recent months, said <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> meteorologist <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> LeComte </PERSON>. Despite some flooding, that moisture was badly needed in a region that has suffered drought for several years, <PERSON> LeComte </PERSON> said. He said the northern plains are in much better shape than last year, with snow and rain providing beneficial wetness for <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Dakotas </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lakes </LOCATION> region this winter _ although some subsoils remain dry. Good snow and rains have also wetted down the <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> and western portions of the corn belt, said <PERSON> LeComte </PERSON>. `` The main spring planting areas were off to a pretty good start.'' <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, especially <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, remains dry, said <PERSON> LeComte </PERSON>. He said moisture also remains a problem for the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION>. Things are looking better, but the area still has a lot of rain to make up following three dry winters. <PERSON> Miskus </PERSON> reports that despite recent improvements, <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> received less than half of the normal amount of rainfall between Dec. 1 and March 18. Other regions with less than half of normal wetness for the winter include most of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> and eastern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> state; parts of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, the Gulf Coast, southern <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, northern <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and parts of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>; northern <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>; southern <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>; most of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> and parts of north <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, northern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and western <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890327-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-27-89 0057EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CFCSubstitutes     03-27 0751</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-CFC Substitutes,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>EPA Defends `Voluntary' Approach to Ozone-Damaging Chemicals</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> says the hunt to find substitutes for ozone-depleting chemicals will go much quicker without strict government regulation of the chemical industry. <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> said the agency's policy is voluntary cooperation _ instead of strong government control _ because <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> has received `` excellent cooperation'' from the industry. <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> was reacting to a recent <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> report that concluded the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s policy is failing to ensure the safe testing of chemicals that will take the place of chlorofluorocarbons, or <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION>'s. By not starting the lengthy regulation process now, <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> will find itself unable to quickly restrict use of many substitutes shown to endanger human health and the environment, the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' investigative agency, said <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> should use its powers to demand unpublished test results and quickly slap controls on substitutes believed to endanger the environment or humans. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the 12-nation European Community have pledged to ban chlorofluorocarbons by 1999 _ surpassing the goals of the 1987 Montreal Protocol which requires they be halved by the end of the century. <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION>'s, and related chemicals called halons, are stable and non-toxic when released into the atmosphere, but 10 to 100 years later, when they rise 15-20 miles to the stratosphere, their chemical bonds are broken apart. Scientists say their chlorine atoms destroy ozone, allowing more of the sun's ultraviolet rays to reach <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>, causing more skin cancer and eye cataracts, and suppressing human immune systems. The recent <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> report called the decision to rely on voluntary cooperation a course that would allow eventual production of <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION> alternatives `` by anyone, in any amount, and for any use, without prior notification ... or an <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> safety review.'' But the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> countered, `` We feel using that cooperative relationship is going to obtain the information we need on a much quicker track. `` We have very great concern over toxicity testing'' <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> said, adding that <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> has `` not ruled out'' using its full authority to regulate the industry `` if we're not getting the cooperation we need.'' `` It's a question of how you do it as quickly as possible while everyone is clamoring for new compounds as quickly as possible,'' said <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fay </PERSON>, of the Alliance For Responsible CFC Policy, representing <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION> producers and users. `` The concern is you've got some policy makers in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> saying we've got to go faster, and you have regulatory structures that would slow it down,'' he said, comparing the dilemma to sitting at an intersection with both red and green lights. The Toxic Substances Control Act allows <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> not only to demand industry's test results, but to order advance notice from any company planning to convert chemicals designed for other use into CFC substitutes. `` Given the importance of the safety issue, we believe that <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s approach to assessing the safety of CFC ... chemical substitutes should include the use of -LRB- the -RRB- two TSCA authorities,'' the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said in a report requested by the chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>, D-Mich. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said dependence on voluntary cooperation is a mistake because, `` <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s previous attempt to gather testing information'' from <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION> producers in December 1987 `` resulted in incomplete data.'' By ordering the test results, <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> officials could determine if a chemical presented `` an unreasonable health or environmental risk'' and if so, could require testing to determine the specific risks. If necessary, the agency could take actions ranging from labeling requirements to a complete ban. Advance notice of new uses for chemicals would let <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> `` review the safety of these new uses and quickly control'' any substances posing a danger. If EPA determined the information was inadequate to ensure the safety of the new use, the agency could require more testing and prevent the new use while data is gathered. <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION>'s are used as coolants in refrigerators and freezers in home, office and automobile air conditioners; propellants in aerosols; blowing agents for plastic foam products and insulation; cleaning agents for metals and electronic equipment; fast-food cartons, and sterilizing agents for medical instruments. Related chemicals, halons are used in fire extinguishers where foam or water treatment would not work: ships, planes, military vehicles, computer facilities, telephone switching centers and libraries. Substitutes for <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION>'s will be tested for at least two more years before commercial production could begin, <PERSON> Fay </PERSON> said. No substitutes have yet been found for halons.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890327-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-27-89 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Sudan-Famine     03-27 0695</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sudan-Famine,0719</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.N. Relief Effort Faces Daunting Problems in Sudan</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY20 of March 26</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DALIA BALIGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MUGLAD, Sudan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Starvation and disease, abduction and slavery are some of the atrocities that six years of civil war have inflicted on millions of people of southern <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>. Consider <PERSON> Akwa </PERSON> <PERSON> Karfath </PERSON> <PERSON> Kawal </PERSON>, a woman of <LOCATION> African </LOCATION> descent who fled hunger in her hometown of <LOCATION> Aweil </LOCATION> and ended up in a squalid refugee area just outside <LOCATION> Muglad </LOCATION> in western <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>. Armed Arabs abducted her five sons en route, she says, forcing them into slavery as cattle herders. Another woman, <PERSON> Miriyal </PERSON> <PERSON> Mayowin </PERSON>, lost two toddlers to starvation and one to the Arabs during the trek out of the south. `` There is nothing in <LOCATION> Aweil </LOCATION> but destruction and we were hungry, so we left,'' she said. `` We ate shrubs as we walked ... but there was no water. `` So many died.'' More than 12,000 refugees in this maze of huts made of sticks and plastic sheets tell similar tales. Dressed in rags, these Dinka tribesmen and their brethren in other camps have been changed by the war from cultivators and cattle breeders to paupers dependent on relief. The Dinka, largest of <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>'s 115 tribes, form the backbone of the rebel army. They are Christians and animists. Rebels began fighting in 1983 for more autonomy from the government, which is dominated by the Moslem Arab majority in the north. On Sunday, a new broad-based Cabinet met for the first time in <LOCATION> Khartoum </LOCATION> and endorsed a peace plan to end the war. And in April, the world will try to assuage the suffering of <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>'s people with an ambitious emergency relief program coordinated by the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>. Relief workers for both Western donor governments and private organizations say the $ 132 million program will save the lives of some of the hundreds of thousands of southern Sudanese who face starvation. But they say the outside world has neglected the war and its ruin for so long that a logistical nightmare will further complicate the already precarious security situation. They doubt the logjams can be sufficiently overcome to prevent another disaster like last summer, when at least 250,000 people died after monsoon rains isolated them without food. Everyone agrees the need is real and urgent, even the rebel <ORGANIZATION> Sudan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. Though the rebels have refused a call by the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> for a one-month truce to let the food pass, they have pledged not to attack supply convoys in certain protected corridors. The plan is to stockpile 100,000 tons of food, medicine and other supplies in places accessible to 2.25 million southerners in both government and rebel-held areas. The supplies are to be in place before the rainy season starts in May and paralyzes transportation. `` It's an enormous quantity and a short period of time,'' said one relief worker. `` Above all, this is <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>.'' Relief and government officials agreed to the plan for bringing in supplies by train, plane, <LOCATION> Nile </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> barge and truck convoy. The government also promised to undo complicated bureaucratic procedures for the relief organizations. For their part, Western relief workers offer endless stories about bureaucratic inefficiency, generally on condition they not be identified. A British-based organization says it had to wait a year before four jeeps were cleared through Sudanese customs. A Dutch diplomat says he tried to transfer $ 4 million in aid to the emergency operation. He was handed forms to fill out and told that the transfer would probably take weeks. Much of the food must be transported to government-held southern areas on Nile barges or trains. However, the barges and trains have made no more than one trip in the past year because of security problems and nervous railway workers. The government says of <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>'s 22 million people, 4 million are southerners. It says half have been displaced by the war to camps in <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> or northern <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>, and half still need relief in the south. Southerners, however, claim they are 6 million. Western relief workers suspect that the discrepancy _ 2 million people _ represents the number who died as a result of the war.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890327-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-27-89 0112EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TradeDangers     03-27 0813</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Trade Dangers,820</SECOND>
<HEAD>For release 10 a.m. EST; time set by source</HEAD>
<HEAD>U.S. Economy Faces Trouble Without Trade Changes</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Economics Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Improvements in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade deficit will stall out next year without major policy changes on the part of the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration, posing grave economic dangers for <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, a research institute warned today. The <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economics </ORGANIZATION> issued a report forecasting that <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s trade deficit will begin rising again in 1990 and will hit $ 150 billion by 1992, very near the all-time record imbalance of $ 154 billion set in 1987. The projections are based on the current account, the broadest measure of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade. It includes not only trade in merchandise but also trade in services, primarily investment flows between countries. In 1988, the current account deficit narrowed to $ 135 billion, reflecting a surge in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> merchandise exports. The current account, also known as the country's balance of payments, shows how much foreign investment will be needed to finance <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s trade deficit. Unless something is done to jump-start <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s stalled trade improvement, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, already the world's largest debtor country, will see that debt top $ 1 trillion by 1992, the report predicted. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> net debtor status means that American assets have been traded to foreigners to pay for imported items such as cars and television sets. Because of this, foreigners now own more <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> investments than Americans hold overseas. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Cline </PERSON>, a senior fellow at the institute and the author of the report, blamed the worsening trade picture on continuing high domestic demand in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, which attracts imports and deflects American production away from export markets. To correct the situation, <PERSON> Cline </PERSON> said it is essential that the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration reach agreement with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on a credible program to meet the targets in the Gramm-Rudman deficit-reduction law. The law calls for the deficit to be cut by $ 40 billion annually until the budget is in balance by 1993. <PERSON> Cline </PERSON> said the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration also needs to abandon the exchange rate policy <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> has been pursuing since February 1987, which has aimed at stabilizing the value of the dollar. Instead, he said, the new administration needs to convince its major trading partners, in particular <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, that further devaluation of the dollar is needed to boost <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s competitiveness by making <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> exports cheaper on overseas markets <PERSON> Cline </PERSON> said the dollar needs to drop by 25 percent in value against the Japanese yen and by 20 percent in value against the West German mark. Such actions would put the trade deficit back on a declining path, reducing it to an annual rate of around $ 50 billion by 1992. <PERSON> Cline </PERSON> said trying to eliminate the entire trade deficit is not really feasible. `` To go all the way to a zero trade deficit would meet very stiff resistance'' from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trading partners, <PERSON> Cline </PERSON> said in an interview. `` I think it will be a major challenge just to get it down from $ 150 billion to $ 50 billion annually.'' <PERSON> Cline </PERSON> warns, as have other economists, that higher and higher levels of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> foreign debt will ultimately lower <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s living standard as more and more resources are transferred to foreigners to pay interest payments on the debt. Such high levels of foreign borrowing also leave the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economy vulnerable to foreign investors, who could suddenly decide they no longer want to hold <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> investments, the study said. The growing debt burdens run the risk of a `` collapse of confidence in the dollar, triggering a further surge of inflation and interest rates _ and possibly a recession,'' the report said. `` At a minimum, they would weaken <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s future growth by requiring persistently high <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> interest rates to attract the needed foreign funds.'' The Cline study was based on computer models which simulated global trade flows based on various economic scenarios. Among the report's conclusions: _ Every percentage point boost in growth in the economies of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s major trading partners will result in a decline of $ 9 billion to $ 13 billion in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> current account deficit by 1992 _ Every percentage point drop in the dollar's exchange value against other currencies produces a trade improvement of between $ 8 billion and $ 10 billion by 1992 as <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> goods are made more competitive on overseas markets _ Each percentage point drop in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s economic growth rate produces $ 15 billion in improvements in the deficit by lowering the demand for imports <PERSON> Cline </PERSON>'s study argues that major reductions in the federal budget deficit would dampen the growth of domestic demand, thus cutting <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s appetite for foreign goods. The study said that if the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> act quickly to implement the budget cuts, it will allow the necessary shift from a consumption-driven economy to an export-driven economy without a recession. The institute is a non-profit research organization which analyzes international economic issues.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890327-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-27-89 0115EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Paraguay     03-27 0518</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Paraguay,0532</SECOND>
<HEAD>Paraguan Opposition Party Picks Candidate</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELIZABETH LOVE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ASUNCION, Paraguay (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The country's chief opposition leader was picked at a weekend convention to run for president in May 1 elections, but his party vowed to boycott a new government in the event of election fraud. <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON> <PERSON> Laino </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Authentic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, accepted his party's nomination Sunday night and vowed in his speech to defend <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION>'s peasants and adopt economic policies to meet their needs. `` We will work with the clean hands and moral strength of the people,'' said <PERSON> Laino </PERSON>, 53, an economist and former university professor. He was exiled for seven years by the recently deposed government of Gen. <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>. <PERSON> Laino </PERSON> was expelled by <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>'s government in 1981 after writing a book about the business activities of Nicaraguan dictator <PERSON> Anastasio </PERSON> <PERSON> Somoza </PERSON>. The Nicaraguan, a friend of <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>, was granted asylum in <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION> after his ouster in 1979. He was assassinated a year later on an <LOCATION> Asuncion </LOCATION> street. `` Who is to say that on May 1, there will not be a new government composed of the glorious <ORGANIZATION> Authentic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>?'' said <PERSON> Laino </PERSON>. He was the only candidate proposed for the presidency at the convention. <PERSON> Laino </PERSON> was carried from the convention hall on the shoulders of supporters following his acceptance speech. Delegates also approved candidates for the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputies </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. The May 1 elections will pick a president to fill the four years remaining in the five-year term of <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>, who was ousted Feb. 3 by Gen. <PERSON> Andres </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>. The coup leader, who had served as an aide to <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>, declared himself provisional president, dissolved <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, and called for new elections. The <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, the country's largest and best-organized party, has governed since 1947. It is expected to ratify <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> as its presidential candidate at a convention set for April 1. `` We know that many sectors of the government harbor hidden intentions of legitimizing the current de facto government,'' said <PERSON> Laino </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputies </ORGANIZATION> from 1967 to 1977. In recent weeks, the party has repeatedly criticized what it views as irregularities in voter registration, and it has suggested the <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> government might be trying to steal the election. <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>, who had led <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION> since a 1954 coup, was elected to an eighth consecutive term in February 1988 elections widely regarded as fraudulent. A plan adopted by <PERSON> Laino </PERSON>'s party calls for rejecting any seats won in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> if it deems the May 1 balloting to be fraudulent. Even if the elections are viewed as fair, the party still would withdraw from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> if electoral law reforms and changes in voter registration lists are not made before municipal elections scheduled for October 1990. The party claims voter lists are inflated in favor of the <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. It also conditioned its participation in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on revocation of a law which allows a president to serve an unlimited number of terms. It also demands repeal of two laws frequently used under <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> to crack down on dissidents and a ban on soldiers belonging to political parties.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890327-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-27-89 0115EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-YellowstoneInterpretation Bjt   03-27 0610</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Yellowstone Interpretation, Bjt,0624</SECOND>
<HEAD>Computer Games, Interpretive Exhibits Explain Yellowstone Fires</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KURT J. REPANSHEK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>YELLOWSTONE NATIONAL PARK, Wyo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
