<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890501-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-01-89 2336EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0744 05-01 0359</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0744,0369</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: ADDS Malley; Separates moved as a0681 on Ackerman and a0695
on Boyd.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Anne Ackerman</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NORTH MIAMI BEACH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Annie </PERSON> <PERSON> Ackerman </PERSON>, 75, the powerful political activist whose support was courted by candidates ranging from condominum board members to a president, died Monday of cancer. Ms. <PERSON> Ackerman </PERSON> political activism included volunteer work for the campaigns of the late Mayor <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and accelerated when she moved to a waterfront <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> condominium in 1969. Ms. <PERSON> Ackerman </PERSON> successfully roused retirees from political apathy and mobilized them into powerful voting blocs. Famed for turnouts ranging past 90 percent, they were dubbed `` condo commandos.'' Her political friends included President <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, fellow Democrats <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, and nearly every well-known Democratic politician in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>John Boyd</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyd </PERSON>, who fought off leftists to lead the powerful British union of engineering workers, died Sunday. He was 71. A cause of death was not available. <PERSON> Boyd </PERSON> started his career as an engineering worker but began work as a trade union organizer in 1946. He stepped up to the presidency of the <ORGANIZATION> Confederation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shipbuilding </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineering </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unions </ORGANIZATION> in 1964. <PERSON> Boyd </PERSON> spent years fighting communists and left-wing elements for control of the 1.5 million-member <ORGANIZATION> Amalgamated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineering </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION>. From 1975 to 1982, he served as general secretary of the union, which is one of the largest in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. From 1967 to 1975, <PERSON> Boyd </PERSON> sat on the general council of the <ORGANIZATION> Trades </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, the national organization of unions. <PERSON> Boyd </PERSON> was a director of the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> from 1981-86. A chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in 1967, he was knighted in 1979.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>William Malley</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WEST SENECA, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Malley </PERSON> a deputy managing editor at The Buffalo News was killed Sunday after his car spun out of control. He was 49. <PERSON> Malley </PERSON> joined The News as a copy editor in 1966 and was promoted to assistant news editor in 1969 and then Sunday magazine editor in 1977. He was named assistant managing editor in 1980 and deputy managing editor in 1987.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890501-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-01-89 2348EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-IllinoisDeathPenalty 1stLd-Writethru a0712 05-01 0539</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Illinois Death Penalty, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0712,0552</SECOND>
<HEAD>Federal Judge Rules Illinois Death Penalty Unconstitutional</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 7 grafs after 6th graf, `Judge threw ...,' to UPDATE
with reaction; picks up 7th graf, `Baker's ruling ...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DOWLING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SPRINGFIELD, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal judge Monday struck down <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION>' death penalty law, raising doubts about the fate of 121 prisoners on the state's Death Row, including serial killer <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gacy </PERSON>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> ruled that the 1977 law gives prosecutors too much discretion in deciding when to seek the death penalty, violating <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> directives that capital punishment not be imposed in an `` arbitrary and capricious'' manner. If sustained on appeal, the decision would invalidate the sentences of the 121 men currently facing the death penalty in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>. They include <PERSON> Gacy </PERSON>, convicted in 1980 of killing 33 young men and boys in the worst multiple-killing case in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> history. Prosecutors said they were confident the ruling would be overturned by the 7th <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. No one has been executed under the state's death penalty law, which was upheld by the state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in 1979. Judges threw out three earlier death sentences that emerged through the appeals process in federal court, but Monday's ruling was the first to address the constitutionality of the law. `` I think we knew that in some case, a -LRB- federal -RRB- judge would rule specifically on the statute,'' said <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> Gottfried </PERSON>, head of the state appellate defender's office, which handles appeals for death row inmates. `` We did n't know which case it would be.'' First Assistant Attorney General <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Ficaro </PERSON> defended the death penalty law. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> has dealt with that issue over 60 times,'' <PERSON> Ficaro </PERSON> said. `` We believe the statute is constitutional.'' <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, director of the state's <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> chapter, said, `` We're delighted with any decision that finds any death penalty law unconstitutional. `` We think they're all unconstitutional,'' <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said. `` I do n't think there's any way to write a death penalty law that's constitutional. Legal experts agreed a ruling by the <ORGANIZATION> federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> appelate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> court </ORGANIZATION> is virtually a certainty. Should the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decline to review that ruling, it would in effect become the last word on the law's validity. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>'s ruling came in the case of a double killer, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Silagy </PERSON>, who demanded the death penalty after being convicted in 1980 of a double killing in <LOCATION> Vermilion </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Silagy </PERSON>, who has been on death row since August 1980, had his sentence appealed twice to the state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> and once to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, but was unsuccessful until his case reached <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> in one of the last stages of the death-penalty appeals process. The state's capital punishment law allows a trial court to consider a death sentence in certain circumstances, such as a multiple killing, when requested by the prosecution. The state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> upheld the law in 4-3 ruling in 1979. Dissenting Justice <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON>, whose opinion was cited by <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, wrote: `` Our statute contains no directions or guidelines to minimize the risk of wholly arbitrary and capricious action by the prosecutor in either requesting or in not requesting a -LRB- death sentence -RRB- hearing.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890501-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-01-89 2349EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Germany-Missiles 3rdLd-Writethru a0661 05-01 0711</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Germany-Missiles, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0661,0730</SECOND>
<HEAD>West Germans Step Up Campaign For Missile Talks</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS two grafs after 3rd pvs `Both the...' to UPDATE with
newspaper report of emerging compromise; pickup 4th graf pvs `In Washington...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERRENCE PETTY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BONN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government began a new effort Monday to rally <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> allies behind its proposal for superpower talks on reducing short-range nuclear weapons, which has caused a dispute with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. Foreign Minister <PERSON> Hans-Dietrich </PERSON> <PERSON> Genscher </PERSON> was quoted as saying <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s argument must have `` special weight'' because it is the alliance's front line, and a war with such battlefield-range weapons would be fought on its territory. Both the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> say the negotiations proposed by Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> might endanger Western security. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported Tuesday that the elements of a compromise have begun to emerge with a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> proposal submitted to <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> headquarters in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION>. Quoting unidentified diplomats from several nations, the newspaper said <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> proposed Wednesday that the alliance decide to upgrade the weapons and then announce unilateral reductions. <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> would then challenge the Soviets to make cuts to the lower levels. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said Monday that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> remains committed to a mixture of <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> conventional and nuclear forces, called flexible response, as a deterrent to attack. `` The West German position demonstrates the special strength that <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> has,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. `` Our allies can debate quite vigorously these issues, yet maintain the basic strength of our unity. `` Our position remains that keeping the peace requires a strong <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> alliance and a policy of flexible response.'' <PERSON> Genscher </PERSON>'s remarks were the first official West German comment since a meeting Sunday in which Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> tried, but failed, to change <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>'s mind on the issue. In pursuit of support for the West German position, <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> plans to visit <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> on Tuesday and <PERSON> Genscher </PERSON> will go to <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> has said it agrees with <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> that negotiations on the short-range weapons should begin, but <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> has not made its position clear. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> claims the support of seven of the 16 <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orgnization </ORGANIZATION> members. In an interview with the <PERSON> Frankfurter </PERSON> <PERSON> Rundschau </PERSON>, <PERSON> Genscher </PERSON> was quoted as saying: `` This is not a new demand that has only now been made by us and other alliance partners. This concerns putting into effect an intention which has already been stated in two alliance decisions.'' His ministry made copies of the interview available to other news organizations before publication in the paper's Tuesday editions. <PERSON> Genscher </PERSON> has noted previously the <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> decision at summits in 1987 and 1988 that negotiations on short-range nuclear weapons should be held at some point. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> say this is not the time. `` Naturally the German view must have a special weight because the Lance rockets are on our soil and because our army represents the largest conventional contribution -LRB- in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> -RRB- to the common Western security,'' <PERSON> Genscher </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s army has about 500,000 soldiers. Most of the alliance's short-range Lance rockets are on its territory and would be used there in a war. <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> and <PERSON> Genscher </PERSON> say <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> should not pass up opportunities to negotiate in important areas of disarmament, and they insist the time is right for taking up the battlefield-range weapons. The chancellor has said he wants the talks to begin `` soon,'' but has not proposed a timetable. A West German government official said privately Monday the chancellor was `` optimistic'' about a compromise. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> officials say starting negotiations now could lead to elimination of the short-range weapons and increase the threat from the Soviet bloc's superior conventional forces. After the meeting with Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> on Sunday, <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> said he does not favor pulling the Lance missiles out of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> `` under the present circumstances.'' Gen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Galvin </PERSON>, the American who commands <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> forces in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, was quoted as saying he did not believe there was disagreement on strategy within the alliance. In an interview for publication Tuesday, the newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Die </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Welt </ORGANIZATION> quoted <PERSON> Galvin </PERSON> as saying: `` Recent statements make it very clear that there are no differences in the grand strategy. The importance of nuclear deterrence is recognized.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890501-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-01-89 0001EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-CustomsandPolitics     05-01 0945</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Customs and Politics,0975</SECOND>
<HEAD>Political Aide's Suicide Spotlights Japan's Money Politics</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSAN MOFFAT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When the prime minister's political secretary committed suicide, many saw him as a victim of the money politics entwined with Japanese culture and tradition. Beside such Western-style institutions as a parliament and free elections, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> has customs that demand exchanges of gifts and favors and lingering ideals of absolute loyalty. Japanese politicians spend campaign money in a very personal manner. Voters expect their representatives not only to bring pork-barrel projects to the district, but to help their children find jobs in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, attend weddings and send donations to funerals. Political secretaries spend much of their time going to family ceremonies and delivering obligatory gifts. Results of a survey published in the newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Asahi </ORGANIZATION> said a legislator or his representative attends, on average, 26.5 funerals a month. <PERSON> Ihei </PERSON> <PERSON> Aoki </PERSON>, for three decades Prime Minister <PERSON> Noboru </PERSON> <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>'s closest aide, may have killed himself Wednesday because more than $ 1 million in donations and loans he received from the <ORGANIZATION> Recruit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> helped bring down his boss, who had announced the day before he would resign `` The tragic case of <PERSON> Aoki </PERSON>'s suicide pathetically calls for a drastic reform of the money-oriented structure of politics,'' the daily <ORGANIZATION> Yomiuri </ORGANIZATION> said in an editorial. <PERSON> Asahi </PERSON> said political aides `` function as ` cloaks' that cover up foul play.'' Of 13 politicians linked to the Recruit scandal, it noted, six took donations in aides' names rather than their own. Political secretaries, who would be called legislative assistants in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, carry a burden imposed by the money-driven election system. Most spend hardly any time drafting legislation, a job generally handled by bureaucrats. <PERSON> Aoki </PERSON>'s main task as secretary to a top leader was `` to raise money from big business and distribute it to legislators,'' said <PERSON> Kotaru </PERSON> <PERSON> Nogami </PERSON>, chief political editor of the <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. Secretaries of legislators, in turn, pass some of the largesse on to their districts. `` Basically, a secretary does everything and anything he is told to do and he has to carry out any order to perfection, even though specific guidelines are not given,'' said <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Redl </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>, a political secretary to a legislator of the governing <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. When he began working in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Redl </PERSON> said, he was surprised to see aides in funny costumes dancing to entertain constituents at a local festival. He said he was exhausted by the dawn-to-2-a.m. schedule of courtesy calls and parties with supporters in the Hokkaido district of his legislator, <PERSON> Shizuo </PERSON> <PERSON> Sato </PERSON>. `` I talked to another secretary who had to do this all the time,'' the American said. `` He told me, ` It's like the old days. You have to be ready to die for your shogun.''' When <PERSON> Aoki </PERSON> killed himself, many people were reminded of the suicide in 1976 of former Prime Minister <PERSON> Kakuei </PERSON> <PERSON> Tanaka </PERSON>'s driver, who had carried payoff money in the <ORGANIZATION> Lockheed </ORGANIZATION> scandal. <PERSON> Tanaka </PERSON> eventually was convicted on a bribery charge. `` After the <ORGANIZATION> Lockheed </ORGANIZATION> scandal there was a lot of discussion of political reform, but it was never carried out,'' <PERSON> Nogami </PERSON> said. A partial reform limited donations, but the Recruit case revealed ways around it: buying many tickets to fund-raising parties and selling shares at bargain prices before offering them for public sale. Recruit was limited to contributing $ 115,000 a year to all politicians. In three years, however, <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> alone got more than $ 1.5 million from the company in donations, stock-sale profits, loans and proceeds from ticket purchases. All of it went through <PERSON> Aoki </PERSON>'s hands. Such huge sums of money are needed, in part, because taxes cover only a fraction of what it costs to run the parliament. `` The Recruit scandal was born of the system,'' said <PERSON> Sato </PERSON>, 47, the young American's boss. He is a member of the governing party's cmmittee on reform and wants more government funds so legislators will be less dependent on contributions In the tiny office the government provides, he told an interviewer: `` The budget from the government allows for only two aides. I have 15.'' His monthly travel allowance of $ 500 covers just a quarter of what he spends visiting his constituency. <PERSON> Sato </PERSON> depends on a patron, former Prime Minister <PERSON> Yasuhiro </PERSON> <PERSON> Nakasone </PERSON>, for political funds, and in return backs <PERSON> Nakasone </PERSON> in intra-party maneuvers. Patrons like <PERSON> Nakasone </PERSON> or <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> lead <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> factions that operate almost as separate parties, particularly in raising money. Explaining how Japanese politicians spend campaign funds in their districts, <PERSON> Sato </PERSON> said: `` It's different from <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. A simple television ad wo n't get votes. It's a matter of obligation and human feelings.'' Americans might see the exchanges of favors and money as graft or vote-buying, but in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> they generally are considered social custom. Contributions by Recruit were at the top level of an interlocking system of gifts and obligations stretching down to ordinary citizens. Some Japanese say they do n't mind politicians collecting large amounts of money because they usually recirculate it rather than enriching themselves. Giving gift envelopes of cash at weddings, funerals and bon voyage parties, even between parents and children at the New Year, is a matter of etiquette in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. A parliamentary survey indicated young legislators spent an average of $ 274,000 a year on cash gifts for funerals, weddings, community festivals and local clubs. `` When a politician gives money at a funeral, it's not because he's a politician but because it's a matter of Japanese custom,'' <PERSON> Sato </PERSON> said. `` Now it may be necessary for us to distance ourselves from Japanese habits.'' Among reforms an advisory group suggested to <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> last week was prohibiting parliament members from giving money at weddings and funerals.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890501-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-01-89 0037EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-Obit-Denton     05-01 0204</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Denton,210</SECOND>
<HEAD>Washington Post Reporter, Editor Herbert Denton, Jr., Dead at 45</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Denton </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> correspondent in <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION> and the newspaper's former editor for <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, died of pneumonia at a hospital in <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Denton </PERSON>, 45, had AIDS. A native of <LOCATION> Muncie </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, and a graduate of <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Denton </PERSON> joined the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> in April 1966 but later was drafted into the Army. During service with the 1st Cavalry in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> as a public information specialist, he received the Bronze Star. After returing to the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Denton </PERSON> served as <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> editor, District of <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> editor and correspondent in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. His career at the newspaper spanned more than 20 years, and in an op-ed article in Monday's edition of the newspaper, fellow reporter <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> wrote: `` There are all kinds of ways to deal with being a black man in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. My friend and mentor <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Denton </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, who died here Saturday, never shouted a mouthful of rhetoric or spent time pointing fingers at whites. He did not condemn the futility of black anger. What he did was to build a potent legacy _ a generation of <PERSON> black </PERSON> journalists at The Washington Post.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890501-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-01-89 0024EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-NIreland'sWeek Bjt   05-01 0736</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-NIreland's Week, Bjt,0761</SECOND>
<HEAD>No One Killed, Several Hurt In A Quiet Week of the `Troubles'</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BARR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BELFAST, Northern Ireland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It was quiet last week in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, by the standards of a province in its 20th year of `` the troubles.'' A few children and elderly people were terrified by a mortar attack on a police station, and police shot up a car, but there were no additions to the 2,000-plus deaths caused by sectarian violence since 1969. There were several attacks on police stations. Charges were filed against alleged members of the <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, which is largely Roman Catholic and fighting to unite <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, and the <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Volunteer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, which is Protestant and wants to keep the province British. These are the stories of a quiet week: SUNDAY: Masked gunmen crash a house party in <LOCATION> Londonderry </LOCATION> at 2:30 a.m. and fire four shots. Police say the homeowner was held with one gun in his mouth and another to his head while being interrogated about a guest who already had left. No one is injured and no group claims responsibility. A 36-year-old woman is hit in the head as automatic gunfire sprayed the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Constabulary </ORGANIZATION>'s station at <LOCATION> Clogher </LOCATION> in the western part of the province. She survives and there are no injuries to police, who attribute the late-night attack to the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION>. MONDAY: <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> commandos fire three mortar rounds at the <LOCATION> Ballynafeigh </LOCATION> police station in south <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> as children walk to school. Elderly residents are evacuated from their homes, past a can in which a bomb explodes minutes later. No one is injured. A van used in the attack is stolen from <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> McCusker </PERSON>, who is held captive by gunmen, along with his wife, <PERSON> Maureen </PERSON>, and two children, for three hours during the attack. TUESDAY: A funeral is held for taxi driver <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, 26, who was shot to death the previous Friday night. The <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> claims <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> had been involved in sectarian killings. In <LOCATION> Armagh </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dermot </PERSON> <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON>, 26, and <PERSON> Niall </PERSON> <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON>, 22, are charged with setting off a homemade 50-pound bomb the previous Friday while a <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> patrol was nearby. An 18-year-old man from west <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> is shot in both ankles and knees. Police say it appears to be a punishment shooting, the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION>'s way of dealing with people in the <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> community whom it considers criminals The chief constable of the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Constabulary </ORGANIZATION> agrees to pay a `` four-figure'' settlement to a <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> councilman from <LOCATION> Londonderry </LOCATION> who claimed he was repeatedly assaulted while detained in 1977. WEDNESDAY: Bombs explode at the <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION> police station and <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Street </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> post </ORGANIZATION>, and shots are fired at security force patrols in three other areas of <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION>. No casualties are reported. <PERSON> Alex </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwood </PERSON>, a member of the <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> city council from the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, the largest <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> political party, says army tactics are creating tension in west <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION>. `` People talking to neighbors or passing the time of day on their own doorstep have been treated with contempt by some patrol members and subjected to verbal abuse.'' An army spokesman promises an investigation. The McCuskers are charged with withholding information about their stolen van. THURSDAY: The McCuskers are released on bail. FRIDAY: Police fire 30 shots at a stolen car that allegedly is driven through a checkpoint in west <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> at 1 a.m. Two occupants are seriously injured. Councilor <PERSON> Alex </PERSON> <PERSON> Attwood </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> SDLP </ORGANIZATION> says he fears the incident reflects `` this hostility where people shoot first and ask questions afterwards.'' <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernadette </PERSON> <PERSON> Cavanagh </PERSON>, 29, of <LOCATION> Londonderry </LOCATION>, appears in court on charges of attempted murder of a police officer and possession of grenades, guns and explosives. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Branagh </PERSON>, 45, of <LOCATION> Ardoyne </LOCATION>, is sentenced to five years in prison after being convicted of membership in the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> and possessing a nail bomb and documents useful to terrorists. Prosecutors say <PERSON> Branagh </PERSON> would leave his back door unlocked, knowing the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> was using his home to store weapons. A 25-year-old man is shot in a knee and both ankles in <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION>. SATURDAY: Police seize a suspected <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> arms cache, including a Soviet-made flame thrower, in a woodland west of <LOCATION> Londonderry </LOCATION>. A 14-year-old east <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> girl appears in court on charges of stealing a semiautomatic Beretta shotgun and 174 cartridges. A detective says the girl claimed, `` I only did it because I was under threat.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890501-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-01-89 0046EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     05-01 0907</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0943</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 First lady <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has puppy love written all over her face. Puppy love times six, that is. That's how many puppies first dog <PERSON> Millie </PERSON> gave birth to about a month ago. `` I have not named the puppies,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> writes in a cover story in this month's Life magazine. `` I know them intimately, but I do n't want to give them names and get attached because I want everyone who gets one to name his or her puppy.'' The English springer spaniel is a dog without bad habits, the first lady notes. `` I never had a girl dog before. I had boy dogs all my married life. <PERSON> George </PERSON> loves <PERSON> Millie </PERSON>, but she is attached to me,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says. `` She gets White House table scraps when the president slips them to her. He gives her showers _ how else do you wash your dog? Every week or two, we climb right in the shower with our dog.'' Clean or not, there wo n't be any more puppies during the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> tenure at 1600 <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ave. </LOCATION> `` She wo n't have any more puppies, not because of her age -LRB- she's only 3 -RRB-, but because I think you can ask a household to do this only once I would like more if I lived privately,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CHATTANOOGA, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Bacon </PERSON> knew as a child he wanted to be an actor, and says he used to go to the movies and then dress up as one of the characters once he got home. <PERSON> Bacon </PERSON>, who stars in the movie `` Criminal Law,'' said his mother, who was a nursery school teacher, encouraged him to be creative. `` I fantasized, enjoyed dressing up in costumes. My favorite toy was a big box of old clothes my mother saved for me,'' he said in Sunday's <ORGANIZATION> Chattanooga </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News-Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. `` Every day I would be someone else,'' he said. `` I went to the movies as a kid and enjoyed the movies, but could n't wait to get out and get dressed as the character and act it out _ <PERSON> Davy </PERSON> <PERSON> Crockett </PERSON> or <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hood </PERSON>,'' he said. `` It was n't enough for me to sit and watch it. I think I wanted to be the center of attention.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The smell of marijuana wafted through the air, and plenty of iced beer was on hand as about 2,000 people lined up to buy tickets for The Who's reunion concert. During the weekend, some of the fans huddled under small tents, braved rain and chilly temperatures outside Radio City Music Hall for a shot at the tickets, priced from $ 75 to $ 2,000. <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> <PERSON> Yankowitz </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> legal secretary, claimed the first spot in line by getting there Friday night. She slept through rain showers, chased scalpers away from her spot and then learned that the tickets were going to be issued by lottery. Promoters allowed those in line to draw a bracelet from a box. The bracelets, numbered from one to 500, allowed the bearer to return this morning and claim a place in line according to the number drawn. Each person is limited to two tickets. The British rock band will be performing its rock opera `` Tommy'' in its entirety for the first time in 17 years. `` Is it worth it? Yeah, I worship this band!'' said <PERSON> Yankowitz </PERSON>, who saw The Who perform at Shea Stadium in the group's farewell tour in 1982.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON>, who plays <PERSON> Roseanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Barr </PERSON>'s hefty husband in the TV series `` Roseanne,'' and his real-life sweetheart were among the celebrities in the audience at the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orleans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jazz </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Festival </ORGANIZATION> `` This is my third <ORGANIZATION> Jazz </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fest </ORGANIZATION>,'' said <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON>, who attended Saturday with his fiancee, <PERSON> Annabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartzog </PERSON>. Most celebrities try to attend the festival without being recognized, said <PERSON> Anna </PERSON> <PERSON> Zimmerman </PERSON> of the festival staff. `` The ones we make arrangements for do n't want us to talk about it,'' she said. `` They just want to come in and enjoy it with everyone else. The people at the T-shirt tent always seem to recognize them. They must all go there to get T-shirts.'' `` It gives us a chance to see a lot of acts as well as perform,'' singer <PERSON> Rita </PERSON> <PERSON> Coolidge </PERSON> said. `` You always see other performers in the audience.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ronnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Milsap </PERSON>, who has been successful with pop and country audiences, says he's not afraid to return to his country roots in his latest album. `` Most folks are afraid, I think, after you've had some pop and rock success, to turn around and cut a country album again, but I'm not ashamed to do that because I love country music so much anyway,'' <PERSON> Milsap </PERSON> said recently The <LOCATION> Robbinsville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, native, who has been blind since birth, said he was exposed to classical music at a <LOCATION> Raleigh </LOCATION> school. `` I was taught to play and to listen to and to observe all kinds of things _ then I came to <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> and they say you can only be one thing,'' he said. `` There's all kinds of albums that I see in my future if we're able to make them happen. The new album, `` Stranger Things Have Happened,'' has already yielded two hits, including `` Do n't You Ever Get Tired of Hurting Me,'' and `` <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> Solution.'' <PERSON> Milsap </PERSON>'s other hits include `` Stranger In My House'' and `` I'm a Stand By My Woman Man.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890501-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-01-89 0121EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FirstThanksgiving 1stLd-Writethru a0420 05-01 0469</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-First Thanksgiving, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0420,0475</SECOND>
<HEAD>First Thanksgiving Re-enacted on the Rio Grande</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS last graf with two grafs to restore first reference to
Chamizal National Memorial and include crowd estimate.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HOLDEN LEWIS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>EL PASO, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Horsemen in armor, monks in brown robes and four musketeers gathered near the <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION> to commemorate what they say was the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' first Thanksgiving celebration, in 1598. The group took a step Sunday toward revising history with a re-enactment of the fiesta held April 30, 1598 _ 23 years before the Pilgrims celebrated in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. While the 400 settlers led by Spanish aristocrat <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Onate </PERSON> were celebrating, the Pilgrims were still in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, dreaming of a place where they could worship freely. The <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paso </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trail </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> sponsored the re-enactment. In addition to the armored horsemen, Franciscan monks and musketeers, it included a dozen sheep, a goat and a donkey to represent the 7,000 head of livestock the original settlers brought with them. No one is asking to move Thanksgiving from the fourth Thursday in November to April 30, but organizers want people to know about the 1598 feast. `` We do n't want to fight against any tradition,'' said <PERSON> Ricardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Marti-Fluxa </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>'s consul general in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>. `` But we feel it was a deprivation not to acknowledge the full history of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>.'' Mission Trail president <PERSON> Sheldon </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> said he wants the re-enactment to become an annual event in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION>. The 130 men and 270 women and children in <PERSON> Onate </PERSON>'s party started out from central <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> in early 1598 to settle along the <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION>, according to the group's chronicler, Capt. <PERSON> Gaspar </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Villagra </PERSON>. While crossing the vast Chihuahuan desert of northern <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, the group ran out of water. Five days later and near death by thirst, they reached the river April 20. According to the <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Villagra </PERSON>, the settlers rested for 10 days before holding a thanksgiving feast a few miles east of present-day <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION>. `` We built a great bonfire and roasted the meat and fish, and then all sat down to a repast the like of which we had never enjoyed before,'' <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Villagra </PERSON> wrote. <PERSON> Onate </PERSON> then took formal possession of the <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION> <LOCATION> basin </LOCATION> in the name of King <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> _ an action called the `` toma'' _ and his party eventually settled near present-day <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fe </LOCATION>, N.M. During the re-enactment, the `` settlers,'' led by the horsemen, wandered around the grassy slopes of Chamizal National Memorial near downtown <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION> and spied the river. <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> rules prevented a re-enactment of the feast, but the actors recreated <PERSON> Onate </PERSON>'s toma, a solemn Mass led by the Franciscan monks and a celebratory dance. About 1,000 people watched the pageant.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890501-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-01-89 0120EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Jordan-Peace Bjt   05-01 0705</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jordan-Peace, Bjt,0728</SECOND>
<HEAD>Riots Distance Jordan From Israeli Hopes</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN RICE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>AMMAN, Jordan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The riots that shook the kingdom have turned <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>'s focus toward internal problems and made the country less of a factor in the Israel-Palestinian controversy over the future of the occupied territories. It has become increasingly clear that King <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> was serious last year when he vowed never to negotiate on behalf of the <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION>, saying it is a matter between <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION> themselves. The king was bowing to the obvious: The Palestinian uprising on the Israeli-occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> of the <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, which he ruled until 1967, showed he had little remaining loyalty there. It had shifted to the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>. Even the idea of a confederation between <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> and a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> state _ a proposal to make <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> independence palatable to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> _ seems only remotely possible these days. <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> for months has said he will consider a confederation only after a Palestinian state is created, and only if Palestinians there and <LOCATION> Jordanians </LOCATION> in his country vote for it. Many old-line Jordanians, or East Bankers, oppose a confederation because it could give <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION> a larger say in <LOCATION> Jordanian </LOCATION> affairs. Palestinians already make up half of <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>'s 3 million people. Palestinians were almost nowhere to be seen in the four days of rioting that began on April 18 and rocked more than a dozen towns and villages in southern <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>, the bedrock of support for <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>. The rioting, in which at least nine people were killed, was sparked by government-imposed price increases but contained a cry by East Bankers that <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> pay attention to their problems and give them a greater voice in running the country. Some have resented the prosperity and political prominence of <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION>, who were granted full citizenship when <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> merged with the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> in 1950. Some also hold a grudge from 1969 and 1970, when <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> guerrillas began to set up a state within a state in <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>, often harassing East Bankers at guerrilla roadblocks. <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>'s selection Thursday of Field Marshal <PERSON> Zeid </PERSON> <PERSON> Bin </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaker </PERSON>, the former army commander, as prime minister partly answered that plea. <PERSON> Bin </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaker </PERSON>, a man of Bedouin stock, commands wide loyalty in the armed forces, which are still a favored occupation for Bedouin youth. He also was prominent in crushing the guerrilla movement in 1970. He replaces <PERSON> Zaid </PERSON> <PERSON> Rifai </PERSON>, whose Jordanian birth was not enough in the eyes of many <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> eyes to compensate for his father's Palestinian origins <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> will not renounce the Palestinians in <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> itself. He has woven them into the fabric of his society, along with smaller immigrant groups such as Armenians and Circassians. But the king has demanded they act as Jordanians and his security forces watch closely for any expressions of domestic Palestinian nationalism. Israeli leaders still speak often of turning part of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> back to <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> or putting it under the control of Jordanian security forces. But hard-line Israelis refuse to give up any of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> or consider any form of <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> entity. They say there already is a <LOCATION> Palestine </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>. However, some of the resentments that led to the recent rioting demonstrate that <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> is not a Palestinian state. No amount of introspection will keep <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> from being an essential player in <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> peace maneuvering. It shares <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s longest border and is permanently threatened by a conflict that has twice swamped <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> with refugees. The king has vowed to maintain his support of the Palestinians in the occupied lands and has been an important moderating force on the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s negotiating demands. His abandonment of claims to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> helped push the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> to focus its attention on ending Israeli occupation there. And the Palestinian organization followed <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>'s longstanding appeal that it formally endorse <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s right to exist. That led the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to open a dialogue with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> in December and turn its gaze away from <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> as the answer to the 41-year conflict. <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> is urging Israelis to do the same.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 EDITOR'S NOTE: <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Rice </PERSON>, correspondent for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Amman </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>, has covered the <LOCATION> Arab-Israeli </LOCATION> conflict since 1984.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890501-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-01-89 0135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WoodyGuthrie     05-01 0484</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Woody Guthrie,0499</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woody Guthrie Receives Homecoming After All These Years</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRETT J. BLACKLEDGE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OKEMAH, Okla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For years, residents of this rural community wanted nothing to do with native son <PERSON> Woody </PERSON> <PERSON> Guthrie </PERSON>, citing his writings in a Communist newspaper and his support for the post-Depression labor movement. But detractors were nowhere to be found Saturday as more than 750 fans waited in line hours to see his son, <PERSON> Arlo </PERSON>, perform at a benefit concert to commemorate the author of songs such as `` Bound for Glory'' and `` This Land Is Your Land.'' `` Thank you for being here,'' <PERSON> Arlo </PERSON> <PERSON> Guthrie </PERSON> told the more than 750 people present. `` And I know that my dad thanks you also, very much, for this night. God bless you all.'' The concert, <PERSON> Guthrie </PERSON>'s first in his late father's hometown, was a benefit performance to raise money for scholarships. For <PERSON> Arlo </PERSON> <PERSON> Guthrie </PERSON>, the concert was a homecoming of sorts to a place he's visited many times but perhaps never really appreciated. `` I've been walking around the whole town feeling kind of strange,'' he said. `` I have other folks here. My grandfather and a lot of his folks grew up here, spent their lives here. I feel like I have encountered my own roots and I'm real happy about that.'' He spent much of his two-hour performance talking to the audience and, at one point, took a moment to joke about the controversy that has surrounded the memory of his father. `` I think a lot of good things are happening for my dad ... now that he does n't need it so much,'' <PERSON> Guthrie </PERSON> said. The younger <PERSON> Guthrie </PERSON>, known for songs such as `` Alice's Restaurant'' and `` City of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>,'' told the audience how he asked his father to teach him the words to `` This Land Is Your Land'' when classmates teased him for not knowing them `` I remember he sat me down and he taught me some verses that were n't in the schoolbook version. I did n't just go back to school, I went back armed,'' he said. `` It never occurred to me in sixth grade that other people would know that stuff. I thought that just went on in our house.'' The celebration was an emotional experience for <PERSON> Guthrie </PERSON>, who said many of his memories of his father are of the years before his death when he had grown weak from a nervous disorder. `` I wish my folks were alive, especially my mom,'' he said. `` But at any rate, where they are now I know that they are looking down and having a ball, laughing hysterically that this could possibly go on here tonight.'' Eighty-year-old <PERSON> Ramona </PERSON> <PERSON> Davidson </PERSON> attended the concert and said she was happy her hometown honored <PERSON> Guthrie </PERSON>. `` It's about time all this has come to pass. Woody has come home. It's just too bad <PERSON> Woody </PERSON> was n't here to see all of this,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890501-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-01-89 0148EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ChildVictims     05-01 0577</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Child Victims,0596</SECOND>
<HEAD>Outpouring of Love for Two Young Victims of Violence</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER McNULTY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three days and 2,000 miles apart, two little girls became victims of violence so shocking that disbelief was the first response of many. Then came love. Two-year-old <PERSON> Carmina </PERSON> <PERSON> Salcido </PERSON> was found April 15 in a remote county dump in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s scenic wine country with her throat slashed. Beside her lay the bodies of her two young sisters who died of similar wounds inflicted the day before. Despite her wound, <PERSON> Carmina </PERSON> told a detective, `` Daddy cut me.'' On April 17 in <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION>, 5-year-old <PERSON> Erin </PERSON> <PERSON> Bower </PERSON>'s hand was blown off when she reached for a tube of toothpaste while shopping with her parents and 1-year-old sister at a K mart store. A pipe bomb hidden in the pump-style container exploded. <PERSON> Erin </PERSON> was the victim of a random attack, while <PERSON> Carmina </PERSON> allegedly suffered at the hand of her father. Yet the two girls are united by an outpouring of love from strangers across the country. <PERSON> Carmina </PERSON>'s hospital room was filled with gifts wheeled in on a brand new, shiny red wagon when loved ones gathered April 24 to celebrate her third birthday. The hospital was deluged with more than 500 toys. Clothing, balloon bouquets and other gifts are piled so high in offices that officials recently began urging well-wishers to contribute instead to one of several trust funds established for <PERSON> Carmina </PERSON>. Her 28-year-old father, <PERSON> Ramon </PERSON> <PERSON> Salcido </PERSON>, is in jail awaiting trial on murder charges in the deaths of her two sisters, mother, grandmother and the grandmother's two young daughters, and a co-worker of her father. In <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION>, about 20 federal and local investigators are still trying to find the person who planted the bomb. <PERSON> Erin </PERSON> lost four fingers and half of her left hand in the explosion, and the remainder of her hand was amputated the following day. Although doctors removed the lens of her left eye April 25, they are optimistic she will regain at least partial sight in the eye. She was released from the hospital Friday. <ORGANIZATION> Methodist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Richards </PERSON> said so many gifts and letters arrived for <PERSON> Erin </PERSON> that he could n't even guess a number. `` She's become such a sort of touching and sad news event that all the staff follow it carefully,'' <PERSON> Richards </PERSON> said. `` I've heard many expressions of condolences.'' Unlike <PERSON> Carmina </PERSON>, <PERSON> Erin </PERSON>'s family remains intact. `` I'm just glad we have our little girl,'' <PERSON> Erin </PERSON>'s mother, <PERSON> Maureen </PERSON> <PERSON> Bower </PERSON>, told reporters. `` She does n't have a hand, but she's ours and she's got her same personality back She's going to be fine.'' By contrast, the public barely knows <PERSON> Carmina </PERSON>. Family survivors remain in seclusion, and the spunky little girl whose mother always dressed her in beautiful party clothes remains under 24-hour guard in the hospital to protect her privacy. The only available photo of <PERSON> Carmina </PERSON> is a small snapshot of her sitting with her two sisters. Doctors believe <PERSON> Carmina </PERSON> will remain hospitalized for five more weeks, but adoption offers have already poured in from across the country, according to <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Frost </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for <LOCATION> Petaluma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in the northern <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Petaluma </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Carmina </PERSON>'s grandfather, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Richards </PERSON>, was the sole family member to escape the attacks unharmed, and county officials report that he has begun the formal process of asking to become <PERSON> Carmina </PERSON>'s guardian They are hopeful that her permanent home will be selected soon after her release from the hospital.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890501-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-01-89 0205EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AIDS-Schools     05-01 0865</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS-Schools,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>Book Shows Different Local Responses to AIDS-Infected Children</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JILL LAWRENCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirp </PERSON> says he saw <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> at its best _ and its worst _ in the two years he spent studying the way different communities reacted to children with AIDS. In his book `` Learning by Heart,'' <PERSON> Kirp </PERSON> offers a wrenching account of the paths taken by nine communities forced to wrestle with the dilemma of AIDS-infected children in school. From <LOCATION> Kokomo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Ocilla </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, which banished students in a frenzy of irrational fears, to <LOCATION> Swansea </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, and a Hispanic neighborhood in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, where understanding and reason triumphed, `` Learning By Heart'' is a mirror on humanity _ and sometimes inhumanity. `` AIDS is a very powerful light on us,'' <PERSON> Kirp </PERSON> said in an interview. `` How do we deal with a crisis that directly touches our lives? Most of the time we do n't get to make moral decisions.'' His book, <PERSON> Kirp </PERSON> said, `` is really about <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> at its absolute best and absolute most mean-spirited,'' A newspaper columnist, magazine writer and professor of public policy at <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Kirp </PERSON> said he `` had a fantasy I could write this like politics and policy'' _ a dry treatise on how communities behave. Instead, he found himself repeatedly on the verge of tears or anger as he interviewed families and school administrators and government officials. He even dreamed about one young AIDS victim after a particularly affecting encounter. `` I did n't know what would lie ahead of me along the way,'' <PERSON> Kirp </PERSON> said. `` But for all the sad moments when terrible things are happening to good people, you find people who are behaving with amazing nobility. They are really ordinary heroes.'' <PERSON> Kirp </PERSON> did several drafts of the book, moving away from a judgmental stance. Doctors can tell parents over and over that AIDS is transmitted only through blood and semen, that classroom contact is virtually risk-free, yet fear persists. Among the most trying tales was that of <LOCATION> Ocilla </LOCATION>, where white administrators barred from school three black children with AIDS-stricken relatives. Tests showed that none of the children carried the virus, but the superintendent insisted there were no absolutes in dealing with AIDS. `` You want an absolute, I'll give you one,'' Dr. <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON>, a local health officer, shot back in frustration. `` You ca n't get AIDS from someone who does n't have it.'' Teen-ager <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>'s protracted fight to attend <LOCATION> Kokomo </LOCATION> schools was one of the first involving an AIDS victim and one of the most widely publicized. `` I tried not to add to the chorus of condemnation,'' <PERSON> Kirp </PERSON> said. `` In 1984, when the story was breaking, the unknowns were so great, the ifs and the fears. My real unhappiness about the <LOCATION> Kokomo </LOCATION> story is that they got stuck there -LRB- opposing <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON>'s return -RRB- and could never get dislodged.'' The Whites eventually moved away from <LOCATION> Kokomo </LOCATION> to a less hostile setting. <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> told his mother, `` I did n't want to die there.'' The <LOCATION> Swansea </LOCATION> story was equally poignant but altogether different. There, a popular teen-ager with a passion for baseball was welcomed back by school administrators, health officials, schoolmates and their parents after he contracted AIDS. `` They were better than they had to be,'' wrote <PERSON> Kirp </PERSON>. The boy, <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoyle </PERSON>, 13, eventually died _ but not before he `` returned to school, read ` Macbeth' in English class, learned how to bake a yellow cake in cooking class, and won the science fair with an exhibit on the wonders of the human eye.'' <PERSON> Kirp </PERSON> found some common threads in communities that reacted nobly: well-informed school authorities and involved local doctors, who held lots of meetings to educate parents and let them vent their fears, and who talked about the ill child as `` one of us as opposed to one of them.'' The most spectacular example of tactics that backfired was in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, where authorities let parents know exactly 48 hours in advance that a second-grade AIDS victim would be attending school somewhere in the vast anonymous metropolis. The result was furious parents, a massive boycott and a court case ultimately decided in favor of the city. At one point in his book, <PERSON> Kirp </PERSON> comments that `` it seems strange that a question as basic as the rights of children with AIDS should be decided locally.'' He concludes with criticism of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, accusing the former president of a silence that set cities and towns adrift as they tried to cope. `` The historians will wonder how it was that the nation's president through much of the decade ... could have been mute on AIDS for so long; and when he finally spoke out, could have been so inarticulate,'' <PERSON> Kirp </PERSON> wrote `` The right words from the president, at the right moment, could have made all the difference.'' <PERSON> Kirp </PERSON> recalled what happened to the three AIDS-stricken Ray boys of <LOCATION> Arcadia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>. Their home was burned to the ground in 1987 after their parents had fought to enroll them in school `` I just got furious thinking of that,'' <PERSON> Kirp </PERSON> said. `` What happened in places like <LOCATION> Arcadia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kokomo </LOCATION> made no sense. Powerful signals from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> could have changed attitudes. But there was nobody in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> communicating any sort of moral message.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890501-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-01-89 0212EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     05-01 0891</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tropical Oil Use Down in US Food Products</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The use of so-called tropical oils by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> food manufacturers has fallen considerably in recent years, but the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says it wo n't make much difference economically. Imported products such as palm oil, palm kernel oil and coconut oil have been attacked vigorously by many <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> farm and consumer interests because of their high levels of saturated fats and possible effects on health. The department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> says the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> used about 14.5 billion pounds of fats and oils in food products in the last year but that only 550 million pounds, or 4 percent, were tropical oils. Soybean oil accounted for more than 10 billion pounds; corn oil, 950 million pounds; and cottonseed oil, 800 million. Animal fats _ lard and tallow _ totaled about 1.1 billion pounds. Other sources of vegetable oil include sunflower seed and rapeseed. Major edible uses of fats and oils are salad and cooking oils; baking and frying fats; and margarine. Economists <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Cummings </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaub </PERSON> said that use of tropical oils in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> may average about 1.84 billion pounds since 1985, but the portion used in food products is expected to average only about 650 million pounds a year, down from the record 1.6 billion pounds in the mid-1970s. In 1986, the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Soybean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, after watching palm oil and other tropical oils nudge into the lucrative <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> market, launched a campaign highlighting the health benefits of soybean oil's relatively low saturated fat content. <PERSON> Cummings </PERSON> and <PERSON> Schaub </PERSON>, writing in the May issue of Agricultural Outlook magazine, said the soybean people were joined by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Heart </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, which began promoting the use of oils low in saturated fats. Tropical oil interests deny adverse health effects, and the <ORGANIZATION> Malaysian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Growers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> has mounted an information campaign and has underwritten medical studies to support its case. But <PERSON> Cummings </PERSON> and <PERSON> Schaub </PERSON> said saturated fats `` have been linked with high blood cholesterol levels and heart disease,'' citing last year's report by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> surgeon general recommending reduced intake of dietary fats, especially saturated fats. Several major food companies have eliminated tropical oils in all or most of their products, and others plan to follow. `` If edible use of tropical oils were cut 50 percent, the effect on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> fats and oils markets would be marginal, because these oils are only a small portion of total use,'' the economists said in their report. `` Substitute oils would capture some of the small market share held by tropical oils.'' The report added: `` Prices also would be little affected. Those manufacturers using large quantities of relatively low-priced palm oil would experience the largest impact. Consumers would hardly be affected, because tropical oils account for only a small part of the price of finished food products.'' <PERSON> Cummings </PERSON> and <PERSON> Schaub </PERSON> also said that a 50 percent reduction in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> food use of tropical oils would have little effect on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> imports and world trade, and the effect on suppliers such as <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION> would likewise be minor.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A final order is expected to be issued soon by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> clearing the way for a watermelon checkoff plan to finance a national research and promotion program. The department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marketing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said the next steps after the formal order is to hold meetings and solicit nominations for a 29-member board that will oversee the program. Those nominations are expected to be submitted by the end of July. After a board is selected, a proposed spending budget will be drawn up and submitted for review. The agency says it may be fall or later before everything is wrapped up. In any case, the watermelon assessments _ which are mandatory but can be refunded _ are expected to be ready for 1990 production. The assessments and the program were authorized by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in the 1985 farm law. A referendum was held in February in which approximately 52 percent of the growers and 56 percent of the handlers approved the plan. Agency officials said an estimated 7,000 watermelon producers and handlers would be covered by the checkoff program. The assessment, to be recommended by the board and then set by <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>, can be levied at rate of up to two cents per 100 pounds of watermelons sold by producers and two cents per 100 pounds for handlers. All producers of watermelons having five acres or more and first handlers are required to pay the assessment. A grower of five acres or more who also handles watermelons would have to pay both assessments.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sales of cut flowers, potted plants, greenery and other commercially grown floriculture crops in 1988, a time of severe drought in much of the nation, dropped 2 percent to an estimated $ 2.24 billion, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. An annual survey of 28 crops showed that wholesale values of cut flowers increased 3 percent from 1987 to about $ 452 million, while the value of potted flowering plants declined 3 percent to $ 494 million. Sales of foliage, including hanging baskets and potted foliage, declined 7 percent to $ 477 million. The wholesale value of plants used for bedding and gardens declined 2 percent to $ 724 million last year, the report said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890501-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-01-89 0215EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--HoffmanMemorial     05-01 0175</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Hoffman Memorial,0179</SECOND>
<HEAD>Whoopi Goldberg, Timothy Leary Lead Tribute To Late Abbie Hoffman</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Whoopi </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> and LSD guru <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Leary </PERSON> led a tribute to 1960s radical <PERSON> Abbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON>, remembering him as a tireless activist whose outrageous style helped turn public opinion against the Vietnam War. <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON>, 52, committed suicide April 12 at his <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> home, coroner's officials said. More than 1,000 people gathered at the <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unitarian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> for Sunday's memorial. Others in attendance included singer <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> <PERSON> Browne </PERSON>, `` Platoon'' director <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Papers </ORGANIZATION> figure <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellsberg </PERSON>. Miss <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON>, who is often associated with social activism, said <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> taught her `` I can be part of the revolution without having to hate, without having to hurt people and maim them.'' `` God bless him,'' Miss <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> said. `` I'm going to keep him alive in my heart.'' <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> founded the radical Yippie movement in the 1960s and was a defendant in the <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> Seven trial, following violent clashes between protesters and police outside the 1968 Democratic National Convention.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890501-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-01-89 0215EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SpottedOwl Bjt   05-01 0835</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Spotted Owl, Bjt,820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fight Over Owl Most Acrimonious Since Snail Darter</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LES BLUMENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Not since the 1970s, when the snail darter took a run at a dam on the <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, has the Endangered Species Act been the focus of a dispute as acrimonious as that surrounding the northern spotted owl. The Tellico Dam was eventually completed, but only after a lengthy and bruising battle over the darter _ a tiny fish _ that reached the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the Carter White House. At stake in the spotted owl showdown is the fate of some of the oldest forests on earth and the role of logging, so rich a part of the heritage of the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION>, in the economic future of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and northern <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. A medium-sized, mostly nocturnal bird, the spotted owl is fiercely territorial and nests almost exclusively in the cathedral-like ancient forests of the Northwest. The trees in these stands average 500 years in age with some of the giants up to 1,000 years old. When the first settlers arrived in the early 1800s, more than 20 million acres of old-growth forest dominated the landscape. No one is quite sure how much remains with estimates ranging from 2 million acres to 6 million acres. But if current levels of logging continue over the next half-century, the only suitable spotted owl habitat remaining may be in wilderness areas and the national parks. Environmentalists have used the owl as part of a campaign aimed at halting logging of these virgin stands of timber, the bulk of which are on federal land. Old-growth timber is among the most coveted by the industry and dozens of one-mill towns in the <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION> are economically dependent on logs cut in federal forests. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Products </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> claims that protection of the owl could result in the elimination of 280,000 direct and indirect jobs in the Northwest. Conservationists say those estimates are `` hysterical'' and peg the job loss at about 2,300. They also insist that if all the remaining spotted owl habitat is protected the timber harvest on federal lands would be reduced no more than 25 percent over the next 50 years. The <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Fish and <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, reversing a <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration decision that congressional investigators found was based more on politics than biology, proposed last week that the owl be protected as a threatened species under the Endangered Species Act. The agency found that about 1,500 breeding pair of owls remain and that without protection their numbers could be cut in half by the year 2050. A species is considered threatened if it is `` likely to become an endangered species in the foreseeable future throughout all or a significant portion of its range.'' The agency now has up to two years to decide whether to actually list the owl. But once the recommendation is published in the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Register </ORGANIZATION> in the next few weeks, federal agencies will be required to consult with the Fish and <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> before taking any action that would affect spotted owl habitat. Such actions could presumably include timber sales in the national forests and logging of billions of board feet of timber already under contract. Some have already suggested that the Endangered Species Act be amended to exclude the spotted owl from listing, though few lawmakers find the prospect politically palatable. Similar suggestions were made when the battle over the snail darter was raging. Interior Secretary <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Lujan </PERSON>, in a comment that sent shock waves through the environmental community, suggested the act might be changed to take into account the economic impact of listing a species. The Fish and <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> is now allowed to consider only `` biological factors'' when deciding whether to list a species. The congressional <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> found that top Interior officials had pressured the Fish and <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>'s regional director in <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, to reject a petition to list the owl 16 months ago This time, a spokesman for <PERSON> Lujan </PERSON> said, the decision was strictly up to regional director <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Plenert </PERSON>. `` No one beat on me,'' <PERSON> Plenert </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldstein </PERSON>, <PERSON> Lujan </PERSON>'s spokesman, said that in such a `` highly charged atmosphere it would have been inappropriate for us to do anything but let the regional director make the decision.'' However, he said, future decisions affecting the owl could possibly be reviewed at a `` higher level.'' Although they are pleased by the listing, conservationists are still reserving judgment on the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's claim to environmental respectability. `` From a political point of view this was inevitable,'' said <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Frampton </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Wilderness </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>. `` Based on the scientific evidence they had no choice. There would have been an uproar if they had n't.'' <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Pissot </PERSON>, a wildlife specialist with the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Audubon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>, said there are indications that the regional director's decision `` raised a few eyebrows'' within the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> `` But biologists and legal staff insisted this was their only course of action,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890501-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-01-89 0220EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Germany-Missiles 1stLd-Writethru a0428 05-01 0678</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Germany-Missiles, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0428,0696</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kohl, Thatcher Remain Far Apart On Disarmament Dispute</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: CORRECTS spelling of `Britain' in lede, `adamant' in 3rd to
last graf.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERRENCE PETTY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DEIDESHEIM, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After discussing <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s demand for early talks on cuts in short-range nuclear weapons, Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> and Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> remained firmly divided on what has become a major <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> dispute Both leaders reported making little progress during an afternoon of talks Sunday on an issue that has split the alliance, describing their talks as frank and intensive. <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> assured Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> of his country's firm allegiance to <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>, whose leaders meet in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> at the end of the month for a summit. The West German leader's call last week for prompt superpower negotiations on short-range nuclear weapons has placed him in a battle of wills with Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> and President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` We still have quite a lot of work to do,'' <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> told reporters during a joint news conference with Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> after Sunday's talks in this village west of the <LOCATION> Rhine </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> city of <LOCATION> Mannheim </LOCATION> However, <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> said he thought the issue could be worked out before the <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> summit. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> also expressed optimism, but stressed that all <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> nations </ORGANIZATION> need to agree on a common position. The British leader said any suggestion of eliminating short-range nuclear weapons in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> is unacceptable and dangerous. At one point, she appeared to question <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>'s position on the issue. `` I'm sure Mr. <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> will correct me if I have misunderstood him on this issue,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>. <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> responded by having his interpreter read a line from his speech to <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> last week in which he rejected the total elimination of the tactical nuclear weapons under the present balance of military forces in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> say talks on reducing short-range nuclear arsenals should not begin as long as the Soviet-led <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pact </ORGANIZATION> has a superiority in conventional forces. They also argue that it would be hard to stop talks from ending in the total elimination of short-range forces that Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> advocates. The West Germans say superpower arms talks should be attempted on a broad scale in light of the current disarmament climate in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. They remind their allies that most of <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>'s short-range nuclear weapons are based in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and would be used exclusively on German soil in the event of war. Critics of the West German position say it divides and weakens the alliance at a time <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> must show unity on defense. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> said elimination of short-term weapons would mean the `` <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> will have achieved its objective of getting land-based nuclear weapons out of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. This I believe would be disastrous.'' Throughout the 40-minute news conference, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> repeatedly returned to the topic of flexible response and the necessity of upgrading <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>'s aging tactical weapons arsenal. `` Flexible response is not just something you mouth,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> said. `` Strength must continue not only in words; strength has to be translated into weaponry.'' She added that the missiles must be upgraded `` because obsolete weapons do not deter.'' Under the flexible response policy, the allies could respond to a Soviet bloc attack with either conventional or nuclear weapons. <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>, faced with uncertain election prospects next year, wants to delay until at least 1992 a decision on modernization and deployment of the Lance short-range nuclear rockets. Recent polls show that the majority of West Germans no longer believe the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> to be a military threat. <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>, while reaffirming his commitment to <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>'s flexible response strategy, was also adamant that the West German position on missile talks be acknowledged. He said he hoped a `` joint document which takes our special situation into account'' could be prepared at the <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> summit. `` And that has nothing at all to do with the Germans having become unreliable or anything like that,'' <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> said, referring to suggestions that <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> is no longer following agreed upon <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> doctrine.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890501-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-01-89 0220EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     05-01 0026</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0025</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Up In Tokyo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 33,793.17, up 79.82 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Monday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890501-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-01-89 0226EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Gingrich Bjt   05-01 0787</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gingrich, Bjt,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Gingrich Finds Transition to Statesman Isn't Easy</HEAD>
<HEAD>Laserphoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Newt </PERSON> <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> seems to be taking out his frustrations on the pavement as he sets off on a 6 a.m. walk down <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s Mall. The morning newspaper includes a poll showing that two-thirds of Americans are n't paying much attention to the ethics problems of House Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> and just 37 percent know that he's a Democrat. <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>, the newly elected No. 2 leader of <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Republicans, is annoyed. `` My party is simply not an aggressive, tough competitor compared to the Democrats,'' he says, in full stride in hiking boots and a sweatsuit as the sun begins to rise on the dogwoods and azaleas on the Capitol lawn. `` Given a comparable problem at any given moment, Republicans are slower and softer and vaguer. We are not in the habit of going out and being tough. We're in the habit of being a minority.'' What should the Republicans be doing in the case of <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, who has been charged by the ethics committee with 69 violations of House rules? `` Here's a chance to say over and over again, ` It's sad, but you can understand after 35 consecutive years of being in power why the Democrats are having a hard time,''' <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> says, making his favorite link between power and corruption. `` Republicans have a chance to communicate what's wrong with the way the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> is currently run. We're not using it. It's as though somebody filled up a theater for us, and our side decided not to perform.'' <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>, the strident conservative whose complaint last year launched the ethics case against <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, seems to be having some trouble making the transition from gadfly to statesman. The <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> lawmaker has had some early successes in his new job as <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> whip, lining up an organization that includes not only his supporters but also some old-line moderates. And he demonstrated vote-counting skills last week when he was one of the few to foresee a chance to win a key budget vote on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor. But it has been difficult for him to follow the advice of senior Republicans who have told him to sit out the <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> affair. `` Everybody pretty much agrees that for right now it does n't serve anyone's interests to have <PERSON> Newt </PERSON> as the spokesman,'' says Rep. <PERSON> Vin </PERSON> <PERSON> Weber </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Minn </LOCATION>., a close <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> `` It's very delicate right now. Members of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> may be asked to act as jurors. It's very hard for him to play any kind of a role in that environment The country should not see Republican members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> as a hanging jury.'' Part of <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>'s problem has been his inability to sell the notion that there is a clear link between a politician's ideology and his ethics. He has been striving to make that case in recent weeks, pointing to big-city <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> political machines as evidence that the party's ethical problems extend beyond <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` Ethics is in the long run a devastating issue if you're on the wrong side of it,'' he says. An occasional jogger slows to stare at this prematurely gray former history professor who is bustling along the Mall, keeping up a steady patter of politics before breakfast. `` Those Democrats who want to gamble that <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s little problems will disappear are welcome to do it. But it's both historically and morally wrong, and they're going to find that politically it's a disaster.'' `` Disaster'' seems to be one of <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>'s favorite words, along with `` profound,'' `` fundamental'' and the phrase, `` corrupt liberal welfare state.'' When pressed, <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> concedes that the Republicans have had their own ethics problems _ Watergate, and more recently <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> and <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> _ which have been costly. But without elaborating, he insists those have been less `` systematic'' than the moral shortcomings of the other party. And he does n't mention his own book promotion deal, which is being brought to the ethics committee's attention by <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Democrats. `` It's almost impossible to convince the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people that one party is the clean party and the other is the corrupt party,'' <PERSON> Weber </PERSON> says. `` They tend to view us all as the same. ... There is no clear partisan advantage.'' Despite his beliefs, <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> has been trying lately to suppress his instinct to batter <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> publicly. And at a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> speech last week he wore a button that said, `` Moderates make a difference.'' `` I obviously am more cautious now that I'm whip because I do n't just speak for <PERSON> Newt </PERSON> <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>,'' he said `` I speak for 174 other Republicans in the House.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Drinkard </PERSON> covers <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890501-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-01-89 0233EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BabyDeath-Cases     05-01 0437</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Baby Death-Cases,0450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Courts Produce Conflicting Results When Parents End Lives of Doomed
Children</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Baby Death, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRENDA C. COLEMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The case of a father accused of killing his comatose son by disconnecting him from a respirator is going to court, and two past cases fared very differently in the nation's courtrooms <PERSON> Rudy </PERSON> <PERSON> Linares </PERSON>, a 23-year-old house painter from west suburban <PERSON> Cicero </PERSON>, is charged with first-degree murder in the death of his severely brain-damaged son, <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON>, at Rush-Presbyterian-St. <PERSON> Luke </PERSON>'s Medical Police say <PERSON> Linares </PERSON> kept nurses in the pediatric intensive-care unit at bay with a handgun while he disconnected the 16-month-old boy's respirator Wednesday and cradled him until he was sure the baby was dead. `` I think he was definitely in a state of irreversible vegetative coma,'' said the boy's physician, Dr. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldman </PERSON>, director of the pediatric intensive care unit. `` My opinion was that recovery was not possible.'' Yet the hospital refused the family's request that the respirator be turned off, contending that <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> law prohibits withdrawing life-support unless the patient is already legally dead. Three years ago, a 25-year-old <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> father was sentenced to life in prison for killing his comatose 3-year-old daughter, whom he shot with a pistol as she lay in her hospital crib, eight months after she had been injured in an accident. An <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> case that began six years ago has a vastly different history. In that case, charges against a <PERSON> Beecher </PERSON> veterinarian who admitted crushing the head of his severely deformed newborn son were dismissed by a judge after two juries failed to reach a verdict. In both instances, the legal battles are dragging on. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Leroy </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> is appealing his sentence, which carries a mandatory 25-year term, in the hope of obtaining a new trial in the shooting of his daughter, Joy. He never denied the act. The girl had been in a coma for eight months after her head got caught between the foot rest and the seat of a recliner chair, cutting off her air supply. `` I could n't stop her from suffering,'' <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON> told the judge, explaining his motive for ending his daughter's life. `` There was nothing I could do. It drove me crazy ... at least she's not suffering any more.'' In <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cook </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> prosecutors are hoping to get a murder charge reinstated against <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>, who pleaded temporary insanity after slamming his newborn son to the floor of the delivery room at <ORGANIZATION> Ingalls </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Harvey </LOCATION>. Circuit Judge <PERSON> Will </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gierach </PERSON> dropped the charges after two juries failed to reach a verdict.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890501-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-01-89 0234EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-MarilynQuayle Bjt   05-01 0618</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Marilyn Quayle, Bjt,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Marilyn Quayle Following Own Agenda During Pacific Trip</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JAKARTA, Indonesia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> is keeping an independent schedule and pursuing a separate agenda as she tours the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> with her husband, Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>. In <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Quayles </ORGANIZATION>' first stop on their 12-day trip, Mrs. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> frequently went her own way. While <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> visited a pub, she toured a children's hospital; while he met with Australian Prime Minister <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawke </PERSON>, she went sightseeing at the national art gallery; while he dropped by a tennis clinic, she taught an elementary school class; and when he teed off for golf, she signed up for a tennis lesson. `` If you want to go out and see the country, go with <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said at the beginning of the trip. He called her schedule the `` more interesting'' of the two. Since <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> assumed office a little over three months ago, Mrs. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, 39, has kept a low profile, rarely granting interviews and jealously guarding her family's privacy. An attorney by training, Mrs. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> has not practiced her profession in over a decade, though she told a group of school children in <LOCATION> Melbourne </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, that she would n't mind returning to law. `` In my original job, I was a lawyer, but since my husband became vice president, I've had a lot of duties to perform for him,'' she said. `` So, I'm not sure I can practice law, although I would like to.'' Having apparently ruled out that career path for now, questions have arisen over how Mrs. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> plans to define her new role. <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, for instance, used the second lady's slot as a platform to promote literacy, and <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> pushed the `` Just Say No'' program to fight drugs when she was first lady. Before the Quayles left on their trip, the vice president was asked what role his wife would adopt. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> made light of the question, responding, `` She has a very major cause, and a very major interest. ... A very complex and consuming issue with her _ and that is me.'' But on this trip, Mrs. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> made it clear she had her own interests, interests which often kept her out of her husband's way when he dealt with substantive topics such as grain exports. `` In addition to her official duties, she will also pursue her interest in disaster relief and disaster preparedness,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s office said in a statement explaining her trip schedule. In <LOCATION> Canberra </LOCATION>, Mrs. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was briefed on <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>'s national disasters organization, a group that responds to floods, cyclones and other such events. In <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>, Mrs. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> will travel from the capital to learn about coping with volcanic eruptions, and in <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION>, she'll find out about cleaning up oil spills. On her first foreign trip as the vice president's wife, Mrs. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> seems to have adapted to her new status, whether standing somberly by her husband's side at a war memorial or dancing with him at a black-tie ball. During a tree-planting ceremony, Mrs. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> referred formally to her husband, who says he likes to be called <PERSON> Dan </PERSON>, as `` the vice president,'' and she has handed out souvenirs: <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> signature key rings embossed with pictures of the vice presidential mansion in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. But she does n't seem entirely comfortable with the constant media scrutiny. `` I've done my duty,'' she told reporters aboard <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Two after chatting for about two minutes four days into the trip. In fact, Mrs. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> seems to have some ambivalence about her role. Asked by a school child whether she ever thought she would be the wife of the vice president, she replied: `` It was n't on my agenda.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890501-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-01-89 0236EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BabyDeath-Laws Bjt   05-01 0762</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Baby Death-Laws, Bjt,0786</SECOND>
