<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890829-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-29-89 2323EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Colombia 3rdLd-Writethru a0715 08-29 0958</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Colombia, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0715,0986</SECOND>
<HEAD>Father of Drug Barons Appeals for Peace; Finance Figure To Be Extradited</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 4 grafs, to UPDATE with rocket attack foiled; Picksup
3rd, `Eduardo Martinez...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto BOG1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN NOBLET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOGOTA, Colombia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The father of three purported drug barons begged the government on Tuesday to end its fierce anti-narcotics drive and negotiate peace, as <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> moved to extradite a reputed drug finance chief to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. The developments came as the city of <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> was hit by seven bombs. Police also said Tuesday night they frustrated a planned rocket attack on a state-owned distillery there. Four imported, high-powered rockets were found aimed at an alcohol storage tank outside the <LOCATION> Licores </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antioquia </LOCATION> plant in <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION>, a police spokesmen said. <PERSON> Eduardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> <PERSON> Romero </PERSON>, identified as a major financial man for the <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> cocaine cartel, was told by <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> authorities Tuesday they plan to hand him over to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for trial, Colombian television said. According to the Tuesday night report by the private syndicated news program <ORGANIZATION> Noticiero </ORGANIZATION> 24 <ORGANIZATION> Horas </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> was formally notified during the day of plans to extradite him. The <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> cartel is the world's largest cocaine trafficking organization. <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> is wanted by a federal court in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> on charges related to a $ 1.2 billion drug money-laundering operation. <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> was told he had until Tuesday to appeal the extradition, the report said. It was the first word that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> had completed extradition paperwork and made a formal request for <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>, a 35-year-old econmist. He was the first of at least four extraditable suspects to be caught up in a sweep aimed at drug traffickers. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> has said it will not comment on any extradition proceedings. The <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> case is seen as a test of <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s resolve to press its attack on drug dealers. They have cowed the courts in this <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> country through assassinations, threats and bribes. Meanwhile, <PERSON> Fabio </PERSON> <PERSON> Ochoa </PERSON> <PERSON> Restrepo </PERSON>, the father of three reputed cocaine kingpins, appealed in an open letter to President <PERSON> Virgilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> to bury the hatchet and agree to talk to the drug barons. `` Let there be dialogue, let there be peace, let's have forgiveness, let's carry out a kind of erasing and clean slate,'' <PERSON> Ochoa </PERSON> <PERSON> Restrepo </PERSON> wrote. The letter was published on Tuesday in a <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION> newspaper. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, Justice Minister <PERSON> Monica </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Greiff </PERSON> reiterated the Barco government's refusal to negotiate with drug traffickers, who are blamed for the assassination Aug. 18 of Sen. <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Galan </PERSON>, a leading presidential candidate. The slaying led to the crackdown on drug trafficking. <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s police intelligence chief said Tuesday that among the more than 11,000 people arrested in the crackdown, one has been implicated in <PERSON> Galan </PERSON>'s death. Earlier, news reports pointed to <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Majuat </PERSON>, reputedly a top financial man for drug dealers, but the reports could not be confirmed. Bombs exploded at six state liquor stores Tuesday in <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION>. The shops are a source of patronage for political leaders. A seventh bomb went off outside a tourist agency office in <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>. No one was hurt, police said. They estimated damage at $ 100,000. A man who identified himself as a spokesman for drug traffickers claimed responsibility for the bombings Tuesday and nine bombs that exploded in <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> on Sunday. The claim came in phone calls to <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> radio stations. In his emotional appeal, which was dated Saturday and appeared in the <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION> daily <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tiempo </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Ochoa </PERSON> <PERSON> Restrepo </PERSON> called on Barco to `` stop the bloodshed in our poor and dear <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>.'' `` Nobody in the world ever won a war, all that is left are orphans, widows and pained mothers,'' said <PERSON> Ochoa </PERSON> <PERSON> Restrepo </PERSON>, 65. He said traffickers should be called on `` to stop dead'' their activities, `` no more drug trafficking, no more war, no more killings, no more bombs, no more fire.'' He identified himself in the letter as `` father of three extraditables. The poor little ones, may God shelter them.'' Neither <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> nor Colombian authorities have accused <PERSON> Ochoa </PERSON> <PERSON> Restrepo </PERSON> of trafficking. But his three sons, <PERSON> Jorge </PERSON> <PERSON> Ochoa </PERSON> <PERSON> Vasquez </PERSON>, <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ochoa </PERSON> <PERSON> Vazsquez </PERSON> and <PERSON> Fabio </PERSON> <PERSON> Ochoa </PERSON> <PERSON> Vasquez </PERSON>, are alleged to be among the kingpins of the <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> cartel and are wanted by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Drug agents believe the cartel is responsible for 80 percent of the cocaine distributed in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ochoa </PERSON> <PERSON> Restrepo </PERSON> said traffickers facing extradition `` say they prefer a tomb in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> to a jail cell for life in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, which is to be dead in life, as are so many that we have there. In this I think they're right.'' He said any negotiated concessions by the traffickers would also require concessions by leftist guerrillas. The traffickers allegedly have equipped and financed right-wing paramilitary death squads that have killed hundreds of suspected leftists and provided security and assassination services for the traffickers. The <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> and also the <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, quoting a confidential report by <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> security forces, reported that at least five <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> and 11 British mercenaries helped train teams of assassins for Colombian cocaine traffickers and their right-wing allies. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said it asked <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> to investigate allegations some of its citizens were involved. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, Mrs. <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Greiff </PERSON> pledged Tuesday to continue to fight her country's drug lords despite death threats, and she appealed for more <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to protect judges. She disputed reports that she had considered resigning in the face of death threats against her, her husband and their 3-year-old son. She said she was requesting $ 19 million to purchase armored cars, bulletproof vests, metal detectors for courts and other security devices. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has approved $ 65 million to help the <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> government fight the drug cartels and $ 5 million to help protect judges.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890829-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-29-89 2350EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TravelingActivists     08-29 0999</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Traveling Activists,1025</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Activists Seek Contacts, Publicity, Equipment in West</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By THOMAS GINSBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two years ago, <PERSON> Sergei </PERSON> <PERSON> Grigoryants </PERSON> was in a Soviet labor camp, ostracized and imprisoned by his government for what it called slander. Today, he is among a new breed of globe-trotting <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> activists flocking to the West to pitch their causes, attend seminars, meet government leaders and finally shake hands with people whose stubborn support kept many of them going. Unlike Soviet tourists and emigrants, these activists also are forging new contacts with people who will support them when they return home. Along the way they are amassing an arsenal of donated computers, printers and FAX machines to open new, electronic windows on the once-closed Soviet society. The number of activists visiting the West has soared since 1986, the year after President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> launched his reforms. They range from veteran <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> dissidents who spent years in jail for their beliefs to pro-independence Baltic activists spurred by <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s programs. Nearly every top leader of the three independent `` popular front'' groups in the Baltic republics has visited <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> in the last year. Leading <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> activists such as <PERSON> Lev </PERSON> <PERSON> Timofeyev </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sergei </PERSON> <PERSON> Kovalyov </PERSON> have crossed both continents, and Nobel Peace Prize winner <PERSON> Andrei </PERSON> <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> has returned to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> twice since his first visit last year. But Soviet authorities still tightly control travel visas for personal and business trips, leaving wide speculation about the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>'s motives for allowing activists to ply their trade freely abroad. `` I'd shy away from conspiracy theories, but it obviously builds up <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reputation. He obviously believes enough in his reforms to allow this,'' said <PERSON> Ginte </PERSON> <PERSON> Damusis </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Lithuanian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. `` <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> wants to appear as a peaceful ... law-abiding figure,'' said <PERSON> Ludmilla </PERSON> <PERSON> Thorne </PERSON>, Soviet affairs director at the New York-based human rights organization <ORGANIZATION> Freedom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>. `` They do n't want bad publicity. <PERSON> Jeri </PERSON> <PERSON> Laber </PERSON>, executive director of <ORGANIZATION> Helsinki </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Watch </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, suggested the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> simply is less concerned about activists' influence `` Somebody there has realized it's not so bad when these people speak out.'' A <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> said only that <LOCATION> Kremlim </LOCATION> policy on visas for travel to the West does n't discriminate between activists and all other Soviet travelers, whose total number could reach 2 million this year. <PERSON> Vytautas </PERSON> <PERSON> Landsbergis </PERSON>, president of the Lithuanian independence movement <ORGANIZATION> Sajudis </ORGANIZATION>, said he did n't know why authorities let him visit the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, but that he had more important things on his mind. `` There is an opportunity to maintain contacts, to establish new contacts,'' the 56-year-old musicologist said through an interpreter last month in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. `` I hope that <ORGANIZATION> Sajudis </ORGANIZATION> will be known not just by name only, but as a very real movement and representative of its people, its nation.'' <PERSON> Landsbergis </PERSON>, who became an activist only in the last two years, said his trip reaffirmed <ORGANIZATION> Sajudis </ORGANIZATION>' rejection of Soviet authority, imposed on the <ORGANIZATION> Baltics </ORGANIZATION> under a 1939 pact signed by <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Adolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>. `` We're raising questions about the authority of our representatives abroad. Can we expect emigres or other governments to represent us?'' He met with <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials, congressmen, a former <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> policymaker and <PERSON> Lane </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION>, which has appointed a representative to deal with <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>'s fledgling independent labor union Just a few weeks before, the 48-year-old <PERSON> Grigoryants </PERSON> met with Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> and other officials and activists and signed an agreement with <ORGANIZATION> Freedom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to fax daily installments of his journal to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Grigoryants </PERSON>, the Georgian publisher of the journal Glasnost, was freed in 1987 after four years in a labor camp for publishing an underground journal. He formally came to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> to accept the <ORGANIZATION> Golden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Freedom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Award </ORGANIZATION> from the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journalists </ORGANIZATION>. A <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman would not comment on any of the meetings, saying only that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy is to meet with all Soviet activists. `` One of their intentions for contacts with the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> is to be so well known that if a crackdown came, they'd be well known enough to protect themselves,'' said <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Zvaners </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Latvian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` The fact that these people are coming to the West, showing their faces, gives -LRB- Westerners -RRB- a stake personally in their fate.'' The activists also are `` seeing us working and they get an idea about how they could work. They see participation in a real parliamentary democracy,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Voren </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Bukovsky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Amsterdam </LOCATION>. But ideas and contacts are n't the only things activists take home. <PERSON> Grigoryants </PERSON> handed <PERSON> Thorne </PERSON> a list of supplies, from staples to computers, for his <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> office, which was stripped by <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> agents and <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> forces last year. <PERSON> Thorne </PERSON> said she was n't sure if all his requests were filled, but that his wife, <PERSON> Tamara </PERSON>, earlier in the year had carried a personal computer back to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> after visiting the West. <PERSON> Landsbergis </PERSON> picked up a desktop publishing system with which <ORGANIZATION> Sajudis </ORGANIZATION> hopes to put out a daily newspaper from <LOCATION> Vilnius </LOCATION>, the Lithuanian capital. Baltic, Armenian and <LOCATION> Georgian </LOCATION> activists regularly use fax machines they got from the West to send dispatches to <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> activists, the recipients said. `` One fax can perform miracles,'' said <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gudava </PERSON>, executive director of the New York-based <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democracy </ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION> U.S.S.R. </ORGANIZATION> `` They can stop all this travel. ... But they can not cut all the telephone lines.'' The center receives daily dispatches from the human rights journal Express-Khronika and translates them for Western media. Such independent reporting will make <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> think twice before sending troops against protesters, <PERSON> Gudava </PERSON> said. `` It's impossible now to keep information inside the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> about such things,'' he said. Still, nothing can replace face-to-face contact, said <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Voren </PERSON>. `` They would be doing their jobs even without these trips. But it's easier to discuss things in person _ you know, they still have bugs in their offices.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890829-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-29-89 2353EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Salvador-War     08-29 0774</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Salvador-War,0799</SECOND>
<HEAD>Not Quiet on El Salvador's Northwestern Front</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS GRANT MINE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Guerrillas on the 6,000-foot volcano looming over <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>'s northwestern limits have turned the working-class neighborhood of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ramon </LOCATION> into another bullet-pocked battlefront. Contingents of leftist rebels have come down the slopes four times in nine months to attack an army post in the center of the ramshackle district of 30,000 people. The attacks are part of a year-old guerrilla campaign to bring their war against the government into the capital. The Salvadoran military says the guerrillas are making urban attacks because they've failed elsewhere. But three of the four raids were staged in daylight, illustrating the guerrillas' confidence in their ability to at least partly neutralize the government's single greatest tactical advantage: air power. `` Each time the combat is more fierce,'' said <PERSON> Marta </PERSON> <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> <PERSON> Figueroa </PERSON>, a vendor in the stall-lined market alley hard hit by the fighting. `` It will happen again, and next time it will be worse.'' She stood 10 feet from the spot where <PERSON> Santos </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrera </PERSON>, a 60-year-old mason, was killed by a bullet in the head the afternoon of Aug. 1. That raid also left a soldier dead, another wounded and two civilians _ a market-stall owner and her daughter _ wounded. Three of <PERSON> Barrera </PERSON>'s grandchildren stood on the stoop of his humble cinder-block home and told how they huddled under beds while the fighting raged for two hours. Asked if the attacks made her afraid to come to the market, 16-year-old cheese-seller <PERSON> Julieta </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> said, `` Yes. But necessity obliges us to risk our lives.'' Though residents of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ramon </LOCATION> have nothing against the soldiers manning the post, several said there is a feeling that the detachment should be withdrawn, or at least moved from the district's center. <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> <PERSON> Angel </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON>'s arm is still bandaged and in a sling from a wound he received in November during the first attack on <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ramon </LOCATION>. He had stopped to light a cigarette for a soldier when the first fusillade exploded out of the darkness. The bone in the 21-year-old bus fare-taker's upper arm was shattered, the artery severed and much of the nerve destroyed. `` They should remove the post to a more isolated place,'' he said, standing a block from the one-story house that serves as the 15-man detachment's headquarters and barracks. The house is distinguished from its neighbors by green-and-black camouflage daub and sandbag positions at its corners. `` There are too many people around here _ the market, the school, the church, people who have nothing to do with the conflict _ and things happen to them,'' <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON> said. Sgt. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Ventura </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON>, a stocky 51-year-old former paratrooper, commands the post. A 32-year army veteran, <PERSON> Ventura </PERSON> lost a lung from a wound suffered in combat with the rebels in 1982. Standing next to a patched hole in the wall where an antitank rocket struck in the previous attack, <PERSON> Ventura </PERSON> said his detachment was there `` to protect the community from these terrorist delinquents.'' He estimated that about 100 rebels took part in the attack Aug. 1. His troops were reinforced soon after it began by scores of 1st Brigade soldiers on constant patrol around the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> volcano's base. A UH-1H helicopter with two M-60 machine-guns _ one of 70 U.S.-supplied choppers in the <LOCATION> Salvadoran </LOCATION> air force _ circled about 3,000 feet above <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ramon </LOCATION> shortly after the battle began, too high for its gunfire to be effective. The helicopters are n't coming in as close as they used to because the guerrillas have acquired several hundred Soviet-designed Dragunov sniper rifles, which have a range of 800 yards, compared with about 300 yards for an ordinary assault rifle. The helicopters have been taking more hits and abandoning more missions. With government air power reduced, the rebels have been able to launch more daytime attacks than at any time in the last four years of the conflict that began nearly a decade ago. Ventura contended his post is getting ever-greater acceptance and support from the local people. `` They're tiring of seeing the way the terrorists' actions affect the civilian population,'' he said. But a dozen residents interviewed indicated little or no animosity toward the attackers. It was clear, however, they were sick of the war. `` One asks oneself whey the two sides are fighting, and one does n't find an answer,'' said a produce vendor who preferred not to give her name. Even <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON> says he has nothing against the rebel who wounded him so severely. `` It was just bad luck,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890829-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-29-89 2356EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Britain-War     08-29 0711</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-War,0732</SECOND>
<HEAD>War &amp; Remembrance: Britons Get Reminders of the Road to Battle</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARCUS ELIASON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Good evening, the headlines tonight,'' <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawley </PERSON> tells BBC-TV viewers. `` <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> has sent a warning to <PERSON> Herr </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>: we will stand by <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> whatever the consequences.'' There's an eerie quality to `` News 39,'' a weeklong series of mock newscasts that marries 50-year-old old footage to high-tech TV to recreate the last days before World War II. With her reassuringly English tones, as well as the period jewelry she bought especially for the program, this doyenne of British television seems born to the role of wartime newscaster. But at 43, Ms. <PERSON> Lawley </PERSON> was n't even born when the war ended. And computer graphics have an unsettling impact as they mingle with grainy black-and-white photos of helmeted Germans and gas-masked babies. The reporters on the 15-minute news roundups are real, like <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Sebastian </PERSON>, reporting on evacuees coming home from the Continent, or <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Wheeler </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> correspondent, now `` reporting from <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>'' and appearing in color against a backdrop of the <ORGANIZATION> Brandenburg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gate </ORGANIZATION> in black and white. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> is being deluged with memories of Sept. 1-3, 1939, when <PERSON> Adolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> invaded <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> declared war on <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. The TV schedules are saturated with documentaries and drama. Newspapers are publishing special supplements. More than 100 new books about the war are being published, from fresh histories to coffee-table volumes of photographs. The emphasis is on the small, almost forgotten details of life on the home front. `` News 39'' even claims to have unearthed a 50-year-old scoop: newly discovered footage of crowds falling over rubber balls that were strewn by an anti-war protester outside the prime minister's Downing Street residence This week `` will be a time of sadness for many. For some it will bring a nostalgic smile, a memory of a small but personal part in history,'' says <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, managing director of BBC-TV. `` For those born after the event it will be a time to learn what happened and why.'' But for some, it's too much. `` All those trench coats. All those tin hats. All those smiling cockneys with a mug of tea amid the sepia ruins of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. I ca n't face it. I'm off,'' wrote <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Pile </PERSON>, an iconoclastic Sunday Times columnist. For most Britons, the war years have taken on a burnished, nostalgic glow, where `` there is never any doubt where the division between good and evil lies, and where there will always eventually be a happy ending,'' as <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Booker </PERSON> put it in The <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION>. But although the collective memory is of a nation united, making huge sacrifices in the noblest of causes, the anniversary is also reopening old controversies. Historians once again are debating whether the pre-war British government, in seeking to appease <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>'s territorial demands in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, was abjectly craven or playing for time to rearm. There is even a debate about whether <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> should have joined the war. That argument was rekindled by <ORGANIZATION> Cambridge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> historian <PERSON> Maurice </PERSON> <PERSON> Cowling </PERSON>, who argued in The Sunday Telegraph that from a purely conservative viewpoint, a victorious <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> would have been preferable to a postwar <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> dominated by the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. By staying out of the war, he wrote, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> would have allowed <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> to destroy its natural enemy, Bolshevism, and left the British empire intact. `` It is wrong to assume that a dominant <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> would have been more intolerable to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> than the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> was to become, or that British statesmen had a duty to risk British lives to prevent <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> behaving intolerably to Germans and others,'' he wrote. Cowling conceded that `` these are harsh judgments which will be offensive to men of good will,'' and the flood of outraged responses to the Telegraph proved him right. Professor <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Allbone </PERSON>, who worked on the development of the atomic bomb, wrote that had it stayed out, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> would eventually have come under the domination of a nuclear-armed <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. Other historians said the empire already was disintegrating before the war, and <PERSON> Lord </PERSON> <PERSON> Glendevon </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Tory </ORGANIZATION> minister, wrote that the war saved civilization, `` and I am deeply thankful that I was old enough to join in.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890829-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-29-89 2357EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Afghanistan     08-29 0914</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Afghanistan,0945</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kandahar, Former Royal Capital, Left a Ruin by War</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 An AP correspondent was able to visit <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s second-largest city for 36 hours with the aid of guerrilla commanders and Afghan army officers. This is her report.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By SHARON HERBAUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KANDAHAR, Afghanistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two years of bombardment have made a ruin of this former royal city named for <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> the </PERSON> <PERSON> Great </PERSON>, who may have founded it, but flowers brighten the rubble. Roses and mimosa, jasmine and bougainvillea cover the serrated remains of buildings in <LOCATION> Kandahar </LOCATION>, which was the seat of Afghan kings two centuries ago. Block after block of mud-walled dwellings that were bombed, rocketed and shelled by Moslem guerrillas and Afghan soldiers have been transformed into ghost neighborhoods of jagged walls and collapsed archways, twisted beams and shattered wooden roofs. Other buildings are heavily damaged by bullets and shrapnel. Some are boarded up and locked. What remains, often compared to <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, is a monument to the suffering caused by 11 years of war since the communist coup of 1978, in which Soviet military forces took part for nine years. The <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> withdrew in February. Even army officers and government officials are half-hearted in trying to blame the destruction solely on the guerrillas, most of whose arms are supplied by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` Every day the Soviets were here was a disaster,'' an army officer said privately. `` All they touched turned to dust. Now that we are on our own, every day gets a little better.'' Guerrillas have tried since October 1987 to capture <LOCATION> Kandahar </LOCATION>, whose name derives from the Arabic for <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>. The conqueror's army passed through in 329 B.C. For centuries after that, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Persia </LOCATION> fought over <LOCATION> Kandahar </LOCATION>, which was strategically located on the central Asian trade routes. Since early May, the government has claimed that guerrillas _ known as the mujahedeen, or holy warriors _ and <LOCATION> Pakistani </LOCATION> soldiers were planning a new assault on the city. <LOCATION> Kandahar </LOCATION> is 70 miles from <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, where the main guerrilla groups are based. Most guerrilla commanders deny the charge, and say instead that they agreed seven months ago to stop attacks on the city and turn their rockets and mortars on army posts and on the airport 15 miles north of the city. `` For every communist killed, as many as 100 innocent people may die'' if the city is shelled, said commander <PERSON> Mulah </PERSON> <PERSON> Naqib </PERSON> of the fundamentalist <ORGANIZATION> Jamiat-i-Islami </ORGANIZATION>, or <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> of Afghansitan, considered the best-organized and most efficient fighting group. `` These are the people who helped us against the Russians,'' he said. `` These are the people who gave us food and protection at a time when we were getting no outside aid. Why should we kill or hurt them?'' <PERSON> Naqib </PERSON> commands about 4,000 of the estimated 20,000 guerrillas around <LOCATION> Kandahar </LOCATION>, which was <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s second-largest city before the war. Only one of the seven often-feuding resistance groups based in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> _ the fundamenalist <LOCATION> Hebz-i-Islami </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Islam </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- led by <PERSON> Gulbuddin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hekmatyar </PERSON> _ has refused to stop shelling the city, the field commanders said. Some said they may be forced to save some weapons and ammunition to fight <PERSON> Hekmatyar </PERSON>'s men. Government officials said the population fell from 300,000 to about 25,000 when the bombardment was at its heaviest. Residents who fled to <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> have begun returning, even though up to 30 rockets still hit the city every day. Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Nurul </PERSON> <PERSON> Haq </PERSON> <PERSON> Ulumi </PERSON>, military governor of <LOCATION> Kandahar </LOCATION> province, said: `` Seventy percent of the buildings in the city have been completely destroyed. The remaining 30 percent have been hit by at least one bullet.'' Workers have begun building playgrounds for children and repairing badly minarets on neighborhood mosques. In the battered shops of the bazaar, teen-age boys in turbans inspect Japanese-made electronics goods and women in full-length veils bargain with vendors for grapes and melons. People travel on bicycles and donkeys, on horses sometimes decorated with silver bells and brightly colored woolen balls, along paved streets chewed up by tanks. Most gasoline stations are closed for lack of supplies, so nearly all the motor traffic is military. `` Two years ago, on any day of the week at any hour of the day, you could n't leave your house,'' the army officer said, driving past rows of shattered government houses. `` This is still war, but it's just not as bad. Soldiers and guerrillas are within yards of each other in two rings around the city, but appear to be observing a comparative truce, at least for a time. `` We all want the same thing,'' <PERSON> Ulumi </PERSON> said. He is a member of the <PERSON> Durrani </PERSON> tribe, which produced the kings of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> until the monarch was overthrown in 1973. `` The government, the mujahedeen, the refugees in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and the West all want the same thing. We want to live together in peace,'' he said in an interview at his office in Governor's <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, where portraits of the former kings hang. `` We were friends before the war. We can be friends in the future.'' Guerrilla commanders feel, however, that talking with President <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> is tantamout to accepting the Soviet legacy from a war that has cost more than 1 million lives. `` We have problems with <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> and his government,'' <PERSON> Naqib </PERSON> said. `` They are still the enemy. Maybe we'll see each other and sit down and talk. God willing, one day we will. But now is n't the right time.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890829-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-29-89 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BRF--SwanKilling     08-29 0166</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Swan Killing,0171</SECOND>
<HEAD>Football Player Gets 30-Day Suspended Sentence for Killing Swan</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KALAMAZOO, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A college football player who admitted ripping the head off a swan at <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> received a 30-day suspended jail sentence Tuesday. <LOCATION> Kalamazoo </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Coyle </PERSON> also sentenced <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, 20, of <LOCATION> Rockford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, to two years probation and ordered him to pay $ 175 in restitution. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> pleaded guilty earlier this summer to killing the swan. Authorities believe <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> and teammate <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> <PERSON> Willis </PERSON>, 19, of <LOCATION> Rossville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, were drunk when they killed the swan April 18. <PERSON> Willis </PERSON> pleaded innocent, and faces a jury trial next month. University officials banned the students from the football team until Jan. 1 for destroying university property, and ordered them to undergo alcohol counseling and to perform 100 hours of community service at the <ORGANIZATION> Kellogg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bird </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sanctuary </ORGANIZATION>. Killing a protected waterfowl is a misdemeanor punishable by up to 90 days in jail and a $ 1,000 fine. Authorities estimated bird's value at $ 350
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890829-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-29-89 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-TwoForks 1stLd-Writethru a0630 08-29 0621</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Two Forks, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0630,0633</SECOND>
<HEAD>EPA Plans to Continue Veto Process for Dam, Officials Say</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 14 grafs to UPDATE with quotes and reaction from
EPA official, mayor, governor, Nebraska's senators; picks up 10th graf,
`Environmental groups....'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CARL HILLIARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DENVER (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> will press on with an effort to kill <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>'s proposed $ 500 million Two Forks dam because of the damage it would cause to the environment, an <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> official said Tuesday. The 615-foot-high dam to be built near the confluence of the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Platte </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> and its <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fork </LOCATION> would flood 30 miles of scenic river valley and canyon and the town of <LOCATION> Deckers </LOCATION> to provide drinking water for up to 360,000 new Denver-area residents. Opponents, including several environmental groups, have called the project `` the biggest ecological disaster'' in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> history. `` The Two Forks dam and reservoir project would result in the loss of a major aquatic resource which provides irreplaceable stream fishery habitat and recreational resources near the <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> metropolitan area,'' said <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> DeHihns </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> deputy regional administrator from <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> who reviewed the project for five months. <PERSON> DeHihns </PERSON> said he was recommending continuation of the veto process started by <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> administrator <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Reilly </PERSON> on March 24. The next step in the process is two months of public hearings. The final decision will be made at <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> headquarters in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, but <PERSON> DeHihns </PERSON> said vetoes are rarely overturned. `` I caution that there are still powerful forces aligned against us,'' Two Forks opponent Sen. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Exon </PERSON>, D-Neb., said in a statement released by his <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> office `` You simply ca n't leave us high and dry,'' Mayor <PERSON> Federico </PERSON> <PERSON> Pena </PERSON> said at a news conference Tuesday. `` We have not been given a fair, objective appraisal of this project.'' <PERSON> DeHihns </PERSON> said in response to <PERSON> Pena </PERSON>'s remarks: `` I'm not happy they're upset. But I'm obliged to carry out my responsibilities under the law.'' Gov. <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Romer </PERSON>, a onetime Two Forks supporter, was noncommittal about DeHihns' decision. He said he hoped the cooperation forged between <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> and its suburbs in their drive to build the project would not deteriorate. <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> officials said <PERSON> DeHihns </PERSON> had two options besides continuing the veto process _ letting the project proceed or attaching additional environmental requirements that would have to be met before the project could proceed. But after more than 160 hours of meetings with Two Forks backers and foes, DeHihns' apparently remained unconvinced the project could be built without inflicting serious environmental damage. The dam 25 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> was proposed by the <ORGANIZATION> Denver </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Water </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> and 42 area water providers. They said the dam is needed to meet <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>'s future water needs. <PERSON> DeHihns </PERSON> said metropolitan <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> appears to have adequate water supplies for now, and could put more water conservation measures in place. `` This is not just a statement to the people of <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerrey </PERSON>, D-Neb. `` We should hear this message too.'' Environmental groups said the dam would flood a premier trout stream and dry up wildlife habitat in <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> <PERSON> Orr </PERSON> opposes the project. <ORGANIZATION> Denver </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Water </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruetz </PERSON> denied the downstream habitat would dry up if the dam were built. Another board member, <PERSON> Monte </PERSON> <PERSON> Pascoe </PERSON>, said the agency would challenge DeHihns' decision and demand more <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> involvement in future <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> water decisions. <ORGANIZATION> Audubon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> A.A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Berle </PERSON> said DeHihns deserves `` the heartfelt praise and gratitude of all concerned Americans'' because of his decision. `` This recommendation brings us one step closer to a total victory for common sense and for the environment,'' said <PERSON> Melinda </PERSON> <PERSON> Kassen </PERSON> of the Environmental Defense Fund. `` There are less costly and less destructive ways to supply the <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> metropolitan area with water.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890829-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-29-89 0042EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Panama Bjt   08-29 0579</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Panama, Bjt,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>After Thursday, United States Will Have No One to Recognize in Panama</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy toward <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> enters an uncertain phase Friday when the calendar runs out on the ousted president's term, leaving the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> with nobody to recognize as legal head of the country The situation raises a number of touchy situations, such as notifying Panamanian officials when a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> naval vessel plans to search a Panamanian-flag ship suspected of carrying drugs. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s President <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> was ousted in February 1988 by forces loyal to Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration refused to recognize that ouster, and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has continued to look upon <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> as <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s legal authority even though he wields no power. But Friday is the date when <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> was supposed to step down officially as president, according to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s constitution. With that date, the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's withdraws the mantle of legitimacy it accorded to <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>. In the absence of even a paper successor, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will not have anyone it recognizes as president of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. The end of <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s term also means that his envoy in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, Ambassador <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sosa </PERSON>, will surrender control of the Panamanian Embassy here. The building will remain under the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s care until a democratically elected government taks office in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Sosa </PERSON> has found an apartment here and plans to look for a job. Officials acknowledge they do n't know what will happen in cases such as those involving the inspection of Panamanian ships. For the past 18 months, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> naval vessels encountering Panamanian-flag ships suspected of carrying illicit narcotics have secured permission from <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> before inspecting these vessels. It is normal for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to recognize whatever authority is in effective control in a foreign country, but an exception was made in the case of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> because of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s refusal to have official dealings with the Noriega-dominated government in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> The campaign against <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> began in earnest after two <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> grand juries indicted him on drug-smuggling charges in February 1988. In practical terms, the end of <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s term in office will mean little. Having spent much of the time since his ouster living in hiding in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> with only a small base of popular support, <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> has been largely irrelevant as a political factor since he was deposed. His downfall occurred when he attempted to fire <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> as commander of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s military forces. Within hours, the Noriega-controlled <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> voted to fire him as president and to replace him with <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> loyalist. After Friday, it is not clear what will happen in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. Authorities there recognize the constitutional significance of that date but there is no officially recognized successor to <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON> because the May 7 national election results were voided by the government after the anti-Noriega candidate, <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Endara </PERSON>, appeared to have won by a wide margin. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration recognizes <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> as `` president-elect'' but officials said unless there is a swearing-in accompanied by the appointment of a cabinet, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has no one to recognize. The administration had hoped the <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION> would be able to promote a democratic transfer of power in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. But that effort broke down last week, and <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> seems to have emerged with his power intact. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said afterward the administration may tighten economic sanctions which were imposed against <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> last year after <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s ouster.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890829-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-29-89 0037EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-GenericDrug Bjt   08-29 0543</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Generic Drug, Bjt,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>FDA Moves to Pull Dyazide Clone</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> is moving to withdraw from the market the second of two generic versions of a popular drug used to treat high blood pressure. However, the company that makes the drug contends that it's safe and effective. In the third such action in less than a week, the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> proposed Monday to remove <ORGANIZATION> Bolar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pharmaceutical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>'s generic version of Dyazide because of questions about its therapeutic value The Copiague, N.Y.-based company said in a statement that its product remains on the market. `` It is safe, effective and may be used with assurance of clinical effectiveness,'' <ORGANIZATION> Bolar </ORGANIZATION> said, adding that it will appeal the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> action within the 30-day limit. Dyazide and its generic competitors are among the most widely prescribed drugs in the country and the generic version is <ORGANIZATION> Bolar </ORGANIZATION>'s largest-selling product The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> said it `` has not been able to fully establish'' whether <ORGANIZATION> Bolar </ORGANIZATION>'s product has the same effect as the brand-name product made by <ORGANIZATION> SmithKline </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beecham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> PLC </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Bolar </ORGANIZATION> officials told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> in today's editions that the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> announcement is the result of confusion over a clerical error in the identification of samples used in safety testing and misinterpretation of the results of tests for safety and effectiveness conducted by the company last year. The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> said that while the proceeding to withdraw approval of the company's license to market its product is under way, it will indicate that the drug is not considered to be of proved therapeutic equivalence to the brand-name drug. If <ORGANIZATION> Bolar </ORGANIZATION>'s generic Dyazide is withdrawn, there would be no generic version on the market. Generics are copies of brand-name drugs that sell for much lower prices. The other maker of a generic Dyazide, <ORGANIZATION> Vitarine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pharmaceuticals </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gardens </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, halted distribution of its copy earlier this summer when the company said it substituted samples of the brand-name drug in tests required for <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> approval. <ORGANIZATION> Bolar </ORGANIZATION> is among 11 drug makers being investigated by the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> in the wake of allegations of fraud and corruption involving employees in the agency's generic drug division and some makers of generic drugs. The agency also is sampling 30 of the most prescribed generic drugs and their brand-name counterparts in the wake of disclosure that several generic drug companies have provided false data to the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION>. However, the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> said it found no evidence of fraud in the approval process for <ORGANIZATION> Bolar </ORGANIZATION>'s generic Dyazide. Questions about the product's equivalence to the brand-name product stem from irregularities in the batch records for lots of the product that were tested, the agency said. The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> announced last week it was proposing to withdraw approvals for three products made by Par Pharmaceuticals of <LOCATION> Spring </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, and 25 made by <ORGANIZATION> Vitarine </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION>'s action was praised by Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>, D-Mich., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> investigations subcommittee, which has been looking into the agency's generic drug division `` The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> is coming to grips with the problems in the generic drug industry,'' he said. `` I expect that after all is said and done both the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> and the generic industry will be stronger and better.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890829-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-29-89 0043EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PartyBloodbath     08-29 0343</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Party Bloodbath,0354</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Say Spurned Husband Crashes Party and Opens Fire, Killing
Four</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man burst into a birthday party and opened fire with a gun, killing his estranged wife and three other women while seriously wounding two other people, authorities said Monday. <PERSON> Raymundo </PERSON> <PERSON> Navarro </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> was arrested without resistance outside his father's apartment, authorities and witnesses said. He was held without bail for investigation of murder and of attempted murder. <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Delia </PERSON> <PERSON> Navarro </PERSON> was celebrating her 27th birthday with about 20 family members and friends late Sunday when her estranged husband burst in and began shooting a handgun, investigators said. <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> fell dead, as did <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>, 65, <PERSON> Leticia </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dipp </PERSON>, 46, and <PERSON> Francisca </PERSON> <PERSON> Arizpe </PERSON>, 62, said coroner's spokesman <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dambacher </PERSON>. `` I hid behind a cabinet when the man came in and started shooting,'' said 12-year-old <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Amazcua </PERSON>. `` I saw people fall to the floor. After he left, I ran into the bedroom and hid under the bed with two other kids.'' An unidentified woman was listed in critical condition at County-USC Medical Center with gunshot wounds to the head, and a man with a bullet wound in the abdomen was in serious condition, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff's investigators said. <PERSON> Partygoer </PERSON> <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Amezcua </PERSON> said someone telephoned <PERSON> Maria </PERSON>'s apartment about 11 p.m. Sunday to warn partygoers that <PERSON> Navarro </PERSON>, 26, was on his way. <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> telephoned the 911 emergency line and said her husband was coming to kill her, he said. The 911 operator told <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> to call back when <PERSON> Navarro </PERSON> arrived, the partygoer said. Minutes later, <PERSON> Navarro </PERSON> invaded the party carrying a gun, said <PERSON> Amezcua </PERSON>. The Sheriff's Department confirmed someone called the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> station prior to the shooting, but said it was unable to give details about the conversation until the tape is located and transcribed. `` He had a very bad temper. They used to fight a lot,'' said <PERSON> Beatrice </PERSON> <PERSON> Palacios </PERSON>, 27, a longtime friend of the couple. The couple separated for about a year and <PERSON> Navarro </PERSON> has been despondent about the breakup, friends said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890829-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-29-89 0048EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TreasuryBills     08-29 0199</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Treasury Bills,180</SECOND>
<HEAD>Six-Month Bills Highest Since June</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Interest rates on short-term <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> securities are mixed, with rates on three-month bills declining slightly while rates on six-month bills are at their highest level since mid-June. The <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> sold $ 7.2 billion in three-month bills Monday at an average discount rate of 7.94 percent, down from 7.99 percent last week. Another $ 7.2 billion was sold in six-month bills at an average discount rate of 7.88 percent, up from 7.85 percent last week. The rates on three-month bills matched the rates Aug. 7 and were the lowest since three-month bills sold for 7.65 percent on July 31. The rates on six-month bills were the highest since June 19 when they averaged 8.08 percent. The new discount rates understate the actual return to investors _ 8.21 percent for three-month bills with a $ 10,000 bill selling for $ 9,799.30 and 8.32 percent for a six-month bill selling for $ 9,601.60. In a separate report, the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> said Monday that the average yield for one-year <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> bills, the most popular index for making changes in adjustable rate mortgages, rose to 8.36 percent last week, up from 8.30 percent the previous week.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890829-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-29-89 0105EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FederalTurnover     08-29 0387</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Federal Turnover,360</SECOND>
<HEAD>Federal Job Turnover Rate is 9 Percent</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The 9 percent turnover rate among federal employees in 1987 is roughly comparable to private industry and may be about right for an employer as large as the government, says the <ORGANIZATION> Merit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. The board said Monday that it found a 5 percent turnover rate for many technical and engineering occupations such as computer specialists. That was `` contrary to conventional wisdom'' that turnover problems are more severe in those categories than other job descriptions, the board said. The board said its figures were virtually identical to those in a 1984 study by the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> and not far off the private sector turnover rates of 14 percent and 16 percent cited in two recent studies. After major differences are filtered out, `` federal employee turnover may not be as different from private sector turnover as believed by some,'' it said. One difference, for example, is that a private worker who moves from one company to another would count as a `` turnover,'' while a federal worker transfering from one department to another would not. Calling the overall government turnover rate `` relatively stable,'' the board said `` the current overall rate of turnover may be near optimal for an organization the size of the federal government.'' Of those leaving, 58 percent resigned, 25 percent retired, 5 percent were fired and 12 percent were unspecified `` other removals,'' the report said. The board based its report on an analysis of 1.4 million employee records from the 1987 fiscal year. Here are some highlights of the report: _ There was a 25 percent turnover rate among employees during their first year of service _ Only 4 percent of all employees with from 16 to 20 years of service left their jobs during the year reviewed _ Among those with more than 30 years' service, 20 percent retired in 1987 _ The average age of federal retirees, 60, is close to the average age of private sector retirees, which is about 61 to 62 _ Although they constitute only 26 percent of the work force, employees in the lowest five pay grades accounted for 55 percent of all resignations _ Turnover was highest among health-related and lower-level clerical and support occupations _ 19 percent of all practical nurses and 16 percent of all clerk-typists
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890829-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-29-89 0109EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WasteDump     08-29 0569</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Waste Dump,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Official Says Timetable For Nuclear Waste Dump Depends on Nevada</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Energy Department may be unable to set a reliable date for completing a high-level nuclear waste dump in <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> until it wins state permission to begin site studies, a senior department official says. In an interview Monday, <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Rousso </PERSON> indicated that squabbles with <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> pose a bigger obstacle than a court ruling last week against the department's proposed $ 1 billion contract award to a <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> unit to manage the waste repository. <PERSON> Rousso </PERSON>, acting director of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civilian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radioactive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Waste </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION>, said no decision has been made on whether to appeal the court ruling. Completion of the dump proposed for <LOCATION> Yucca </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION>, about 100 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>, originally was scheduled for 1998 and currently is set for 2003. The <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> state government and its congressional delegation oppose the project, in part on grounds that <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> was chosen for political reasons rather than scientific reasons. Energy Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> said earlier this summer he was reconsidering the project timetable in light of recent setbacks, and <PERSON> Rousso </PERSON> said he expects a decision in the next few months on whether the schedule will be pushed back again. `` A meaningful schedule will probably depend on agreement with the state to go forward,'' <PERSON> Rousso </PERSON> said. `` At some point _ there's no fixed point, but at some point _ we must have access'' to the site to perform the preliminary work. <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> so far has refused to grant the environmental permits needed by the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to begin drilling on the site to determine its geologic suitability. The department is obligated by a 1982 federal law to study the <LOCATION> Yucca </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> site. Gov. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> cited last week's court ruling against the contract award to <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION> as an example of the program's lack of credibility. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Claims Court Judge <PERSON> Reginald </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> ruled on Thursday that the department may award the contract to no one but <ORGANIZATION> TRW </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> TRW </ORGANIZATION> was an unsuccessful bidder which sued on grounds that the department's means of selecting <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> as manager was improper and unfair `` Over the short run, I ca n't see that that's a dramatic impact'' on the program, said <PERSON> Rousso </PERSON>, unless it forces the department to abandon its plans to put a single company _ <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION> or any other _ in charge of managing much of the project. Nuclear utilities are eager to see the repository built because some are being forced to spend millions of dollars to expand temporary waste storage facilities. Utilities customers pay $ 400 million a year into a fund for the permanent dump. <PERSON> Rousso </PERSON> also reiterated his denial of one of <ORGANIZATION> TRW </ORGANIZATION>'s main charges: that his involvement in the contract award process was a conflict of interest. <ORGANIZATION> TRW </ORGANIZATION> asserted that the award was tainted by the fact that <PERSON> Rousso </PERSON> worked for <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Applications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION> subcontractor, before joining the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Rousso </PERSON> said he worked for Science Applications for seven months before joining the department in 1986. The <LOCATION> Yucca </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> contract proposal did not exist then, he said, adding that he has no continuing ties with Science Applications. `` I hold no pension rights, no favoritism, no job promises, no thoughts to that regard, and I do n't see where any conflict of interest has been shown,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890829-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-29-89 0047EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Colombia-Governor'sSecurity     08-29 0250</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Colombia-Governor's Security,0256</SECOND>
<HEAD>Martinez Security Increased in Wake of Colombian Drug Violence</HEAD>
<HEAD>With US-Colombia, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRENT KALLESTAD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TALLAHASSEE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Security for Gov. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> has been bolstered amid threats of political violence by <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> drug lords, the governor confirmed Monday. `` There has been a general warning, a general concern of high-profile public officials on the subject of drugs,'' <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> told reporters. `` We've been rather active in dealing with the drug issue.'' The additional protection started this weekend after <ORGANIZATION> FDLE </ORGANIZATION> agents were told by federal sources that <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> drug lords threatened a political assassination in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> if any of the targeted drug dealers were extradited from <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> said. Earlier this year, <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> traveled to <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> and other Latin American countries to survey drug-fighting efforts. He also serves as the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Governors </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> lead governor on substance abuse and drug trafficking. Last Friday, the governor asked <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney General <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> to extradite 25 <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> drug fugitives should they be arrested by Colombian authorities. <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> said he believed <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> officials might be threatened because of the scheduled extradition Wednesday of a Colombian drug dealer. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> just feels a little bit more comfortable, at least in these next few days, being a little more cautious,'' the governor said. <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Ballard </PERSON>, director of operations for <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>, said the governor's public schedule, which is normally published days in advance for distribution to the press, will now be on a day-to-day basis.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890829-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-29-89 0049EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Voyager-Neptune Bjt   08-29 0713</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Voyager-Neptune, Bjt,0735</SECOND>
<HEAD>Last-Minute Adjustments Saved Voyager's Photos of Icy Triton</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: News briefing 12:30 p.m. EDT; top prospects uncertain.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE SIEGEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PASADENA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Voyager's pictures of <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION>'s moon <ORGANIZATION> Triton </ORGANIZATION> _ which revealed a unique world of icy volcanoes _ might have been washed out if not for last-minute adjustments to the spacecraft's cameras, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> says. `` It would n't have wiped out the mission, but would have made a lot of photographs embarrassingly overexposed,'' said <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> <PERSON> Terrile </PERSON>, an astronomer at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>'s Jet Propulsion Laboratory `` It would have been an incredible disappointment.'' `` They would have been white images,'' Voyager project scientist <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> said Monday. Meanwhile, scientists said the spacecraft found that <ORGANIZATION> Triton </ORGANIZATION> is the coldest body ever measured in the solar system, and that <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION> has something in common with <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>: smog. Only days before Voyager made its closest approach to <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION> last Thursday and zipped past <ORGANIZATION> Triton </ORGANIZATION> on Friday, scientists recognized that the frosty surface of <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION>'s largest moon reflected much more light than originally expected, said <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Beth </PERSON> <PERSON> Murrill </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> JPL </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman. Engineers compensated by sending Voyager new computer commands reducing the exposure time on its television cameras from 6.68 seconds to 3.84 seconds for the best close-ups of <ORGANIZATION> Triton </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Murrill </PERSON> said. Those photographs revealed that giant craters, called calderas, once oozed an icy form of lava that flooded thousands of square miles of lunar terrain. They also found what scientists believe are active ice volcanoes that explosively propel frozen nitrogen particles 20 miles skyward. During its <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION> encounter, Voyager's cameras discovered six moons in addition to <ORGANIZATION> Triton </ORGANIZATION> and Nereid, which were discovered from <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>. They also found three thin rings of debris and five broad rings encircling the solar system's fourth-largest planet. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> engineers are investigating the feasibility of reprogramming Voyager to take a snapshot of the entire solar system sometime in the coming months, said <PERSON> Lanny </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, manager of the flight engineering office. By 9 p.m. PDT tonight, <PERSON> Voyager </PERSON> will be 2.76 billion miles from <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> and 4.55 million miles behind <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION>, speeding toward the edge of the solar system at 37,568 mph. Voyager 2's ultraviolet detector determined <ORGANIZATION> Triton </ORGANIZATION>'s surface temperature is 400 degrees below zero Fahrenheit, making the moon `` the coldest body we have seen in the solar system,'' said <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Yelle </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION>. Scientists believe <LOCATION> Pluto </LOCATION> and its moon <PERSON> Charon </PERSON> are the second-coldest bodies in the solar system. Voyager also found smog on <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION>. Sunlight hitting natural gas, or methane, high in the planet's atmosphere converts it into a 90-mile-thick icy layer of photochemical smog at the bottom of <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION>'s stratosphere, said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON>, an imaging team member from <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Ames </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> <LOCATION> View </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> `` Photochemical smog exists any place we've been that has an atmosphere,'' imaging team leader <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said of other planets and moons `` In <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, the problem is it's happening way down low where we have to breathe it in amounts exceeding anything we've seen except on Titan,'' he said, referring to <ORGANIZATION> Saturn </ORGANIZATION>'s smoggy moon. In another finding, the best close-up shot of the Neptunian moon 1989 N1 showed it has a huge crater half the width of its lumpy-looking, 240-mile-wide surface. That indicates that a big meteorite once smacked into 1989 N1, one of the six moons discovered by <PERSON> Voyager </PERSON> since June, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. Voyager found earlier that 1989 N1 really is <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION>'s second-largest moon after <ORGANIZATION> Triton </ORGANIZATION> Scientists previously thought Nereid was No. 2. Instruments aboard Voyager discovered <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION> is encircled by electrically charged particles that form a giant doughnut shape, called a torus. The torus is created by gases coming off of <ORGANIZATION> Triton </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> McNutt </PERSON>, of the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION>. Jupiter is orbited by a similar torus of sulfur particles spewed by sulfur volcanoes on the <LOCATION> Jovian </LOCATION> moon Io. The space probe also found <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Triton </ORGANIZATION> have auroras vaguely like <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>'s northern and southern lights. They glow in ultraviolet light wavelengths invisible to the human eye, however, unlike Earth's visible auroras. Voyager's close encounter with <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION> last week capped its epic tour of the four outer planets, including <ORGANIZATION> Jupiter </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Saturn </ORGANIZATION> and Uranus. The probe was launched in 1977 along with its twin, <ORGANIZATION> Voyager </ORGANIZATION> 1, which explored only Jupiter and Saturn.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890829-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-29-89 0047EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-IranianArrest     08-29 0374</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Iranian Arrest,0383</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iranian Opposition Figure Arrested on Visa Charge</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ANDERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A senior Iranian opposition figure has been arrested in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> on a visa fraud charge, authorities said Monday. <PERSON> Aladdin </PERSON> <PERSON> Touran </PERSON>, a senior official of the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mojahedin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Iran </ORGANIZATION>, was arrested Aug. 21 at <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> by agents of the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and other federal agencies, <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Touran </PERSON>, a member of the Mojahedin's international relations department, was wanted for allegedly entering the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in August 1988 with a fraudulent visa at <LOCATION> Dulles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> outside <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. The charge was contained in a complaint issued by the <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Attorney </ORGANIZATION>'s Office in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. A spokesman for the Mojahedin condemned the arrest of a top leader the organization says is under a death sentence issued in absentia by the Iranian government. <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Reza </PERSON> <PERSON> Jafarzadeh </PERSON> said the arrest was an effort by the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration to improve relations with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> in its attempts to win release of American hostages held by pro-Iranian groups in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. The opposition group has engaged in combat with the Iranian regime, even taking up arms in the Iran-Iraq war. <PERSON> Touran </PERSON>, 33, was being held without bail Monday at the federal <ORGANIZATION> Metropolitan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Detention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney's spokeswoman <PERSON> Grace </PERSON> <PERSON> Denton </PERSON> said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Magistrate <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Geffen </PERSON> scheduled an identification hearing for Touran for Sept. 6, Ms. <PERSON> Denton </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Touran </PERSON> probably would be extradited to <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> to face the charge if he does n't enter a plea in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, she said. <PERSON> Touran </PERSON> was arrested as he stepped off a <ORGANIZATION> Scandinavian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> flight from <LOCATION> Copenhagen </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Touran </PERSON> was carrying Swedish travel documents issued in the name of <LOCATION> Noori-Elika </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Claes </PERSON> <PERSON> Jernaeus </PERSON>, press attache to the Swedish consulate in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Touran </PERSON> used the name Noori-Elika for security purposes, fearing retribution from the Iranian regime, <PERSON> Jefarzadeh </PERSON> said. He also said <PERSON> Touran </PERSON>'s use of the other name when traveling was well-known by European and <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> officials. <PERSON> Jefarzadeh </PERSON> said <PERSON> Touran </PERSON> had a Swedish politica refugee passport and lived in <LOCATION> Stockholm </LOCATION>. He said <PERSON> Touran </PERSON> had come to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> to meet with other members of the Mojahedin when he was arrested.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890829-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-29-89 0254EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a AM-BRF--TeacherStabbed 1stLd-Writethru a069</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Teacher Stabbed, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0694,0186</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fort Worth School Teacher Fatally Stabbed Outside Classroom</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS grafs 2-3 to CORRECT spelling to `Glen' sted `Glenn' and
UPDATE with details.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FORT WORTH, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A teacher was fatally stabbed Monday outside her elementary school classroom on the city's southeast side, police said. The 24-year-old teacher's name was being withheld pending notification of her relatives, said Sgt. <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Samuels </PERSON>. He said the beginning teacher at <ORGANIZATION> Glen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> had been stabbed several times in the face and neck. `` It was pretty vicious,'' <PERSON> Samuels </PERSON> said. The woman apparently was attacked while moving school supplies to her classroom, police said. Officers had no motive or suspect in the killing. The woman's purse and car had not been taken and it did not appear she had been sexually assaulted. Another teacher found the woman lying on steps outside her classroom door about 12:40 p.m., <PERSON> Samuels </PERSON> said. No students were in the school. The teachers had been preparing for fall classes to start. The victim was pronounced dead about 2 p.m. at <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Smith </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Samuels </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890829-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-29-89 0115EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     08-29 0867</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,860</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Continues to be Top Importer of Oats</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Foreign producers are seeing some of the bloom fade from the lucrative <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> oats market as American farmers rebound from last year's drought, according to an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> report. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has been the world's largest importer of oats since 1983-84, including a spectacular increase the last two or three years as consumers discovered the grain's health benefits. `` Research has linked the fiber content of oats with lower serum cholesterol levels, and health concerns have buoyed the demand for oat food products,'' the report said. In the 1988-89 marketing year that ended May 31, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> oats imports rose to about 68 million bushels, or nearly 1 million metric tons, a 50 percent increase from 1987-88. A metric ton is about 2,205 pounds and is equal to 68.9 bushels of oats. A bushel of oats weights 32 pounds, little more than half that of wheat. Oats imports in 1989-90 are forecast to settle back to around 50 million bushels, or about 725,000 tons, but the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is expected to remain as the dominant buyer in the world market, the report said. The <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> estimates that food use of oats in 1988-89 jumped more than 40 percent from the previous year, but that the amount of oats used as livestock feed has been declining because of its relative high price relative to corn. Oats production this year is expected to rise 74 percent from the drought-stricken 1988 harvest to 381 million bushels, or about 5.53 million tons, according to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> forecasts. `` This likely will mean season average farm prices 25 percent to 40 percent below last year,'' the report said. `` Imports are expected to drop 25 percent ... -LRB- but -RRB- at this level, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> imports would still account for about half the volume of world trade forecast to 1989-90.'' The report, published in the September issue of Agricultural Outlook, said `` no significant increases'' in oats imports by other countries are expected. `` While interest in the health qualities of oats may be growing in other countries, this has not yet translated into significantly higher import demand for food-quality oats,'' the report said. Economist <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Riley </PERSON> said in his report that global export supplies of oats in 1989-90 `` are expected to be adequate to meet <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> demand'' and that even if market prices drop significantly the major suppliers `` are likely to continue producing for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION>'' market. <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> have been the biggest suppliers since the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> oats boom began, but <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION> also are providers. Some oats were bought from <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> last year, after <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION> turned out a poor harvest. <PERSON> Riley </PERSON> said that even if <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> production turns out as forecast, the proportion of top quality oats is not assured and that `` a shortage of high-quality oats suitable for milling count still push imports higher than currently expected.'' The <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> says oats prices nationally may average in the range of $ 1.55 to $ 1.95 per bushel in 1989-90, compared with $ 2.61 estimated for 1988-89.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Have plenty of calling cards, do n't be pushy, and be sure to handle liquor well. That's part of the secret of doing business in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, says a trade consultant. <PERSON> Song-Hyon </PERSON> <PERSON> Jang </PERSON>, president of S.H. <PERSON> Jang </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>, said it pays for an American exporter to learn about his country's culture, national priorities and business customs. `` The exchange of calling cards is very important,'' he writes in the current issue of AgExporter magazine published by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. `` In <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, every person has a distinct place in the organizational hierarchy. Consequently, Korean business people want to know right away what position you hold in your company.'' <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, with its 40 million people, is a prime buyer of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> farm products, ranking No. 2 last year with purchases totaling $ 2.3 billion. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> was the No. 1 single-country buyer at $ 7.3 billion. `` Do n't try to push your position too hard,'' he said. `` Sensitive issues and details may be skipped for future discussions, either by a go-between or by your staff, if available.'' The use of go-betweens can be valuable in `` delicate dealings'' involving money, <PERSON> Jang </PERSON> said. `` Never cause Koreans to lose face by putting them in a difficult position,'' he said. `` On the contrary, find something to praise, such as their country's recently earned prosperity.'' <PERSON> Jang </PERSON> said entertainment is an important part of trade relationships and, when offered, should always be accepted. In due time, it should be reciprocated in some way. `` Korean parties are often like drinking competitions,'' he said. `` A capacity for alcohol consumption may be one of the deciding factors in a successful business negotiation and relationship. The giving of small gifts is also an accepted practice and is recommended.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Broiler exports in the first five months of this year totaled 376 million pounds, up nearly 30 percent from a year earlier, says the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. A report by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said broiler parts made up 95 percent of the shipments. Lower-priced parts, mainly legs and other dark meat parts, helped boost sales in major <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> markets.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890829-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-29-89 0133EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-MexicanCult-AIDS     08-29 0292</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mexican Cult-AIDS,0303</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jailed Mexican Cult Member Has AIDS</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Mexican cult member who is accused of gory human sacrifices is suffering from AIDS, a defense attorney and the state news agency <ORGANIZATION> Notimex </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Omar </PERSON> <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Orea </PERSON> <PERSON> Ochoa </PERSON>, 23, has acquired immune deficiency syndrome, <ORGANIZATION> Notimex </ORGANIZATION> said Monday. Judicial officials confirmed <PERSON> Orea </PERSON> had been tranferred to a prison hospital but refused to disclose his illness. `` He has AIDS,'' defense attorney <PERSON> Horacio </PERSON> <PERSON> Moyar </PERSON> <PERSON> Quintanilla </PERSON> said in a telephone interview. `` That's what the doctors told me.'' <PERSON> Moyar </PERSON> <PERSON> Quintanilla </PERSON> represents the woman prosecutors say was the cult's `` godmother'' _ <PERSON> Sara </PERSON> <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON> <PERSON> Villareal </PERSON>. The lawyer said doctors' reports show Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON>, 24, does not have the fatal disease though she and <PERSON> Orea </PERSON> <PERSON> Ochoa </PERSON> both were lovers of cult leader <PERSON> Adolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON>, who died in a May 6 shootout with police in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Several other cult members also were lovers of the 26-year-old <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON>, according to court testimony. Acquired immune deficiency syndrome is a usually fatal disease in which a virus attacks the body's immune system, leaving victims susceptible to a wide variety of infections and cancers. AIDS is most often transmitted through sexual contact. Other means of transmission include transfusions of tainted blood or blood products, and the sharing of contaminated hypodermic needles or syringes by drug abusers. Cult members had been on the run since the April discovery of 15 mutilated bodies on a ranch near <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION>, across the border from <LOCATION> Brownsville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Among the victims was <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Kilroy </PERSON>, a 21-year-old <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> student who cult members say was sacrificed in a ritual to provide protection for their drug-smuggling business. <PERSON> Orea </PERSON> <PERSON> Ochoa </PERSON> and Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON> claim to know nothing about the killings. They face homicide charges.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890829-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-29-89 0138EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Cities-Children     08-29 0467</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cities-Children,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cities Say Funds Lacking in Aid to Children</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Officials of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cities say they need `` real commitments'' from the federal government to deal with problems affecting children, including child care, drugs and teen-age pregnancy. `` We need help, and we need it now,'' said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Moran </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, mayor of <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, and a member of the National League of Cities. `` We also need real commitments over the long run, not the kind of federal aid that is here one year and gone the next.'' The League released a 390-city survey Monday that found officials in nine of 10 cities regard child care as the most pressing need among children's issues. `` This report is a sobering slap of reality that should awaken our national conscience,'' said <PERSON> Moran </PERSON>, chairman of the League's human development policy committee In cities between 50,000 and 100,000 population, alcohol and drugs were rated as the second most pressing issue, named by 48 percent of those questioned. Education, especially dropout prevention, and health were second among cities between 100,000 and 300,000 population, with 41 percent of those responding mentioning each. In larger cities, however, the prevention of teen-age pregnancy became the second most serious problem, cited by 43 percent. Nearly half of the cities under 300,000 and 70 percent of the larger cities said lack of money was the chief barrier to dealing with such problems. Some cities, the report said, already are taking steps to deal with the problems: _ <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, in cooperation with <ORGANIZATION> Barnett </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> and the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Rehabilitiative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, developed a program to train mothers on welfare to operate family day-care homes _ In <LOCATION> Spokane </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> Teen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pregnancy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prevention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Task </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> has sponsored an annual conference for teens on sexuality and is working on a community action plan _ <LOCATION> Boise </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, funds 10 apartments and places homeless families with children in them for up to two months rent-free _ In <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, an advisory council of children and adults advises the City Council on young people's issues `` From coast to coast, cities are working on these issues in innovative ways,'' the report said. `` They predict their involvement will increase over time _ except there is no money to support expansion.'' One city out of four is significantly involved in child care and, the report said, that is expected to increase to one in three during the 1990s. The study covered 278 cities with populations above 50,000, and 112 smaller cities. <PERSON> Moran </PERSON> said the survey of larger cities, covering 60 percent of all those in the nation, was much broader than that for the smaller communities. `` Most of the findings run parallel for the smaller cities and can be regarded as generally good indicators,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890829-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-29-89 0123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     08-29 0915</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0952</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Eager music fans snapped up tens of thousands of tickets in an hour for former Beatle <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON>'s first concert appearances in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> in 13 years. Three shows at the Great Western Forum in <LOCATION> Inglewood </LOCATION> sold out within 29 minutes after tickets went on sale at $ 28.50 each at 9 a.m. Monday, said <PERSON> Laura </PERSON> <PERSON> Gold </PERSON>, publicity director for tour co-sponsor Parc Promotions, Inc.. Organizers decided to add two more shows, and tickets for those were gone by 10 a.m., Ms. <PERSON> Gold </PERSON> said Organizers expect a crowd of 15,500 people at each of the shows. The concerts in late November will kick off <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON>'s first North American tour since he appeared with his band <ORGANIZATION> Wings </ORGANIZATION> in the `` Wings Over America'' tour in 1976, Ms. <PERSON> Gold </PERSON> said. Other tour stops this year include <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montreal </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. More <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cities will be added for next year, she said. <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON> begins the European phase of his <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON> World Tour next month.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Unlike other aging rockers who have gone back on the road, the <LOCATION> Jefferson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airplane </LOCATION> is n't doing it for the money, lead singer <PERSON> Grace </PERSON> <PERSON> Slick </PERSON> says. `` The Who and the <ORGANIZATION> Rolling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stones </ORGANIZATION> figure, ` I want another wing on my villa,' so they go and tour,'' <PERSON> Slick </PERSON> said. `` We go on the road because the guys just like to play.'' The band that formed in 1965 and pioneered the psychedelic rock scene in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> plays in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s Radio City Music Hall tonight and Wednesday night. The group plans to release its first album in 17 years next week. Slick said she enjoyed the 1960s drug scene, but she said she is thankful to the police for helping her get off drugs and alcohol. `` The highway patrol finally said, ` Look, if you do n't stop driving 150 miles an hour we're going to take your license away,''' she said, adding that she took their advice because she is `` probably still more addicted to cars than drugs.'' `` I never thought in my wildest dreams when I was a kid that I'd thank the highway patrol for being alive,'' she said
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>JUNEAU, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
