<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891227-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-27-89 0025EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     12-27 0353</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0367</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Caesar </PERSON> glowered amid the holiday cheer. The gorilla clambered up the rocks and squatted, turning out his lower lip in displeasure as the family ate its presents and a few trees on Tuesday. <PERSON> Caesar </PERSON>'s gloom was probably caused by a cold, but if the illness was catching, his disposition was n't. The rest of the gorilla family and the family in the compound next door smelled the roses and promptly ate them. The two families of gorillas at the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> Zoo were released from their quarters at midmorning to find their compounds were strewn with popcorn balls, cranberries, bougainvilleas, rawhide chews and fruit. Banana trees decorated with purple, orange and yellow roses and sprinkled with coconut snow stood outside the grottos, with boxed presents all around. Burlap stockings were placed by the rocks with care, filled with nuts and squash and all sorts of goodies. The holiday party was the work of volunteers from the Gorilla Garden, which grows supplemental foods for the zoo's dozen gorillas. `` They enjoy it because a lot of their really special favorite treats are out there,'' said <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON> <PERSON> Chatfield </PERSON>, the gorillas' keeper `` They also have some things they do n't usually get _ like a whole banana tree.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NANAIMO, British Columbia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Lebiuk </PERSON> says he swims only once a year _ the day after Christmas _ so he likes to make it last. That's why he was the last person out of the water Tuesday during the annual `` polar bear'' swim at this <LOCATION> Vancouver </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> city. The 35-year-old spent 30 minutes in the 50-degree waters of Departure Bay. `` I started four years ago or more and I just keep doing it,'' he said as he dried off before heading for a hot tub set up on the beach. The 196 participants who braved the chilly waters ranged in age from 2-year-old <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> to 76-year-old <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Rooney </PERSON>. Swimmers receive a silver dollar and polar bear pin for their efforts. `` It's fun, but I think they're crazy,'' said 12-year-old <PERSON> Esther </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonnall </PERSON>, who was visiting from <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891227-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-27-89 0028EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Windsors'Mansion     12-27 0784</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Windsors' Mansion,0802</SECOND>
<HEAD>Villa of Duke and Duchess of Windsor Reopens in France</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUZY PATTERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> VIII </PERSON> gave up his throne to marry <PERSON> Wallis </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> 53 years ago, but the romantic <LOCATION> Windsor </LOCATION> legend has come alive again at their mansion in the <LOCATION> Bois </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Boulogne </LOCATION>. In early December the wrought-iron gates of the final and favorite residence of the duke and duchess of <LOCATION> Windsor </LOCATION> were thrown open for a high tea given by <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Fayed </PERSON>, the Egyptian tycoon who paid more than $ 8 million to renovate the mansion. The owner of the <ORGANIZATION> Hotel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ritz </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Harrods </ORGANIZATION> department store in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Fayed </PERSON> plans to keep the mansion open for friends and approved groups of visitors. `` Theirs was the love story of the century,'' <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Fayed </PERSON> said of the <ORGANIZATION> Windsors </ORGANIZATION>. He undertook renovation with the blessing of Mayor <PERSON> Jacques </PERSON> <PERSON> Chirac </PERSON> and the City of <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, which is still the official owner of the villa. <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Fayed </PERSON> said he had been shocked to see the dilapidated condition of the villa when he visited after the duchess's death in 1986, with moldy walls and tags on the furniture and art objects destined for the auction block. `` It was a sight I know would have appalled the duke and duchess,'' he said, having seen the villa in its heyday at a dinner party given by the duchess, the American socialite divorcee whom the duke had married in defiance of the royal family. So <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Fayed </PERSON> took things in hand. Supervised by an Anglo-American team of decorators, the leaky roof was repaired, the interior was given a coat of paint, tapestries and woodwork were restored. Personal valuables were left in place, including framed intimate letters and photographs and silver and crystal on the dining-room table as if the <ORGANIZATION> Windsors </ORGANIZATION> were expecting guests. Countless porcelain pug dogs around the house commemorate the <ORGANIZATION> Windsors </ORGANIZATION>' family pets who always were given pride of place. `` I feel on top of the world,'' said <PERSON> Sydney </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, 69, the duke's personal valet for more than 30 years, who is now occasionally in attendance dressed splendidly in gold and red livery as he was in the old days. `` I cried all through the party Mr. <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Fayed </PERSON> gave three years ago to celebrate his lease on the house,'' said <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, a Bahamian who was hired during World II when the duke was the governor of the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION>. `` The restoration is so authentic I expect to see the duchess stepping down the staircase asking, ` How do I look?''' Also on hand are the <ORGANIZATION> Windsors </ORGANIZATION>' chauffeur of 20 years, <PERSON> Gregoire </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, and his wife, <PERSON> Maria </PERSON>. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said he had hidden 5,000 personal photographs in a bathroom to keep them from prying eyes during the duchess's 14-year widowhood following the duke's death in 1972. The house looks as if the <ORGANIZATION> Windsors </ORGANIZATION> just stepped out for a stroll in the Bois; books are at the bedsides, brushes and combs are in the bathrooms and some of the duchess's lingerie are tidily wrapped in tissue in her dressing room. The duke's bed has its original velvet cover with his Prince of <LOCATION> Wales </LOCATION> insignia and motto, `` <PERSON> Honi </PERSON> soit qui Mal y Pense,'' which translates, roughly, as `` Shame on him who thinks evil of it.'' By his bedside sprawls a touching little chimney-sweep rag doll cherished by the duke, given to him by his mother, <PERSON> Queen </PERSON> <PERSON> Mary </PERSON>, who publicly disowned him after his indiscreet marriage. The duchess's bedroom is a symphony of `` Wallis blue'' and cream moire silk, with attractive imitation <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> XV </PERSON> and XVI furnishings and a priceless Venetian l8th century marquetry chest. Visitors also see a raft of stuffed pug dog dolls and framed needlepoint works by the duke, who loved needlepoint almost as much as golf, commemorated in souvenir golf balls all over the place. The duchess's bathroom is an artwork in itself, decorated by <PERSON> Dimitri </PERSON> <PERSON> Bouchene </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> artist who designed stage sets for <PERSON> Diaghilev </PERSON> and <PERSON> Pavlova </PERSON>. Under a Napoleonic-style striped silk tent ceiling, the bathroom walls are covered with <PERSON> Bouchene </PERSON>'s floral and animal murals, with a group of his Christmas cards framed in glass lining the doors like a gallery exhibition. One of the villa's first visitors was the British-born actress <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, who asked <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Fayed </PERSON> if he planned to use the house for his own parties. `` I will indeed,'' he said, adding that he plans to keep the mansion staffed and open to small group visits by special request. In 1991, he said, he will send an exhibition of mementoes to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> and other <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> cities, as well as to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and to the duchess's birthplace, <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891227-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-27-89 0029EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Menorah     12-27 0268</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Menorah,0275</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jewish Group Erects Controversial Menorah in Pittsburgh</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Jewish group acting on the strength of a favorable ruling by <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Justice <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON> erected a 18-foot menorah outside the <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> City-County Building on Tuesday night. `` This adds some light to the darkness of winter nights and is a victory for all the people of <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Elliot </PERSON> <PERSON> Katz </PERSON>, an attorney for the group Chabad. The city, which contends it has the right to determine what is permitted in front of the building, plans to petition the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday morning to have the Hanukkah symbol taken down. Chabad was permitted to erect the display under protection of a restraining order issued last week by <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON>. In an involved holiday legal scramble, <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON> upheld <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Barron </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> McCune </PERSON>'s order preventing the city from blocking Chabad's installation of the menorah <PERSON> McCune </PERSON> maintains that the courthouse steps are a public forum open to all types of expression, and <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON> ruled the menorah could be allowed until a trial on the matter is held in district court. The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruled last summer that the menorah, a candelabrum associated with Hanukkah, was permitted outside the building because it was accompanied by secular symbols, a Christmas tree and a sign promoting liberty. <PERSON> McCune </PERSON> aided the erection of the menorah Tuesday by reducing a $ 5,000 bond that Chabad would have been required to post to cover some potential court costs incurred by the city. Chabad requested the bond be reduced to $ 1,000 but, in a compromise, <PERSON> McCune </PERSON> set the bond at $ 2,500.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891227-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-27-89 0031EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-English     12-27 0730</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-English,0756</SECOND>
<HEAD>Language Lovers Defy Ban, Meet to Practice English</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Young Chinese determined to learn English are defying police orders and gathering weekly in a local park in a dramatic display of peaceful disobedience under martial law. The mix of soft-spoken office and factory workers and full-time students, few of whom would dare challenge the government in any other way, come each Sunday to a hilltop glade in the Purple Bamboo Park famous for five years as the English Corner. There, they awkwardly accost each other and launch into careful but determined conversation in English. A well-used opening line is `` How long have you studied English?'' The park put signs up Oct. 28, declaring the corner closed. It said students were too busy with other studies. But still the English lovers keep coming. They begin arriving shortly before 10 a.m., hovering nearby until the numbers seem large enough for them to climb the now-forbidden hill. Then, huddled deep in padded coats and mufflers and stomping feet for warmth, they mingle cocktail-party style, chatting in English. Two plainclothes police burst upon the gathering one recent Sunday, grabbing elbows and trying to move the participants along. `` Hey, do n't stand around here,'' one yelled. `` Ca n't you read the signs? The corner is closed.'' The crowd of about 60 people moved sluggishly down the hill to a lakeside, where skaters glided on the frozen surface. Conversation resumed through cold-stiffened lips. `` The police never come back,'' one corner veteran said confidently. A few minutes later, one of the police gave a frustrated shout: `` Go away! Go away!'' There was a pause, then: `` What do you think of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>?'' someone asked a visitor politely. It is a practiced ritual. `` They come every week,'' according to a young man who said he was a science student. So does he, although a bit nervously. `` I learn a lot from other people. I think my English has improved,'' he said. Many of those who frequent the corner study English on their own, and it is their only opportunity to try out words they've learned from tapes or books They consider English their best hope for going abroad _ to study and perhaps, whispered one man, `` to stay for freedom.'' Certain ground rules have prevailed since June, when the army attacked pro-democracy protesters and he government began an intense campaign against dissent. `` Before we talked about anything we wanted to,'' said the science student. `` Now we talk about daily life, maybe about our -LRB- work -RRB- units, or cooking.'' `` Laundry,'' chimed in a girl in a pink parka. `` The weather,'' said a man. `` But not politics,'' concluded the student. Most believe politics is the real reason the corner was ordered closed. The student said some people used the corner before June to make speeches about democracy, believing that police _ who generally lack college educations _ would not understand. Foreign reporters also sometimes visited, using the conversations as one barometer of what young intellectuals were thinking. But almost everything in Communist-ruled <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> touches on politics, and it is hard to avoid entirely. `` What do you think about the economic crisis in socialist countries?'' the girl in pink asked. `` Crisis?'' queried a factory technician who had somehow acquired Australian-accented English. `` Do you mean ` shizi lukou'?'' he asked, using the Chinese for crossing or intersection. Someone explained, and he was quick to learn the new word. `` I heard an interesting conversation about the crisis in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>,'' he offered. Listeners shivered with excitement at the words `` East Europe.'' `` Can we talk about international politics?'' asked a tall young man. `` Is it OK to talk about <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>?'' `` I was delighted to hear about <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>,'' whispered a man in a pale blue jacket, referring to the overthrow of hard-line Communist leader <PERSON> Nicolae </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>. Asked what they thought of <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>, the group giggled nervously. `` I have an opinion but I can not tell you,'' said one. `` He was a dictator,'' said someone bolder. `` Autocrat,'' supplied a third. `` Freedom and democracy is the trend in the world, and it makes me very happy,'' said the technician to general agreement. No one spoke of Chinese intellectuals' frustrated hopes for democratic reform in their own country. Generations of Chinese have learned to communicate dangerous ideas like that without words of any language.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891227-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-27-89 0032EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Romania-Ceausescu     12-27 0943</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Romania-Ceausescu,0975</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dictator's Rule Left 60,000 Dead, Romanians Say</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Romania</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VIOREL URMA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VIENNA, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Nicolae </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> reportedly killed 60,000 Romanians during his terrible reign, some sent to <LOCATION> Transylvanian </LOCATION> torture chambers so horrible that the dead leader is being compared to the monsters of myth. State media in post-Ceausescu <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> have begun to paint a horrific portrait of a man who killed with the epic blood lust of Count Dracula and the cavalier conscience of a real monster: <PERSON> Adolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>. His son, <PERSON> Nicu </PERSON>, was described as a drunk who ran down and killed two pedestrians with his car and had a special room where he used to rape women. <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>'s execution and the new revelations about his 24-year rule has Romanians careening between revulsion and exultation. `` Oh, what wonderful news. The anti-Christ died on Christmas,'' a <LOCATION> Bucharest </LOCATION> radio announcer said after an announcement that the former Communist leader and his wife, <PERSON> Elena </PERSON>, were executed. Christmas carols then filled the air. A secret military tribunal in Monday convicted <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> and his wife of genocide, undermining the economy and attempting to flee with more than $ 1 billion stashed in foreign banks. Romanian state television Tuesday broadcast a videotape of <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> and his wife after they were executed by a firing squad, their bloody bodies slumped in front of a wall. In an official announcement, the television said the charge of genocide covered the deaths of 60,000 people. `` This is the moment of truth. We got rid of the monsters who mutilated our history. Let these tyrants be cursed. <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>'s soil should not accept their bodies,'' anchorman <PERSON> Viorel </PERSON> <PERSON> Popescu </PERSON> said on TV and national radio. The broadcasts were monitored in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>. `` The name of <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> should never be pronounced and written again. It should be replaced with Dracula from <LOCATION> Scornicesti </LOCATION>,'' an unidentified painter in the southern <LOCATION> Transylvania </LOCATION> city of <LOCATION> Sibiu </LOCATION> told national radio. <LOCATION> Scornicesti </LOCATION> is the village where <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> was born Jan. 26, 1918, into a peasant's family. Even when he was alive, the iron-fisted <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> had earned the nickname of <PERSON> Vampirescu </PERSON> for his harsh rule, an allusion to Count Dracula's horror tales set in 19th century <LOCATION> Transylvania </LOCATION> by <PERSON> Bram </PERSON> <PERSON> Stoker </PERSON>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and some other nations appeared critical of the decision to try, convict and execute the Ceausescus so quickly. On Monday, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> statement announcing the establishment of diplomatic relations with <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> said: `` We regret the trial did not take place in an open and public fashion.'' But <PERSON> Silviu </PERSON> <PERSON> Brucan </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> Romanian </LOCATION> ambassador to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and leading dissident who is on the 37-member revolutionary governing council, said the reason behind the <ORGANIZATION> Ceausescus </ORGANIZATION>' rapid execution was to `` crush any hopes for a lethal coup'' by his hated secret police, the Securitate. `` He was probably executed on Christmas Day to show that a new hope, the hope of freedom, was born in <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> was the anti-Christ,'' an unidentified poet told the radio. During the <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> reign, dissent was ruthlessly repressed by the Securitate, a huge and sinister network of tens of thousands of people. Debt repayment and mismanaged industrialization programs triggered widespread food and energy shortages and dissidents faced prison, commitment to mental hospitals, internal exile or house arrest. Laws mandated the reporting of every unauthorized conversation with a foreigner. Every typewriter had to be registered with the police and censorship was far tighter than anywhere in the Soviet bloc. Romanian TV monitored in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> showed a former `` torture chamber'' ran by the Securitate in the western Romanian city of <LOCATION> Timisoara </LOCATION>, where more then 12,000 protesters, including children and women, were killed by the security forces when local riots erupted Dec. 17. The revolution actually began in <LOCATION> Timisoara </LOCATION> two days earlier, when small protests began eventually blossomed into the nationwide uprising that toppled <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> on Friday. `` It's terrifying what we see in this torture room,'' a commentator said. `` Calcinated bodies, pieces of hairy scalps, blood and tortured bodies lying on the floor. The victims were brought here naked. `` How small were <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>'s lackeys. They were genuine angels -LRB- by comparison -RRB-. These are nightmarish images,'' the unidentified commentator said. Tearful residents looking for missing loved ones congregated at freshly unearthed mass graves containing the bodies of hundreds of summarily executed people, some mutilated. One gruesome picture showed the body of an unborn baby whose mother had been cut open by a bayonet. The army and revolutionaries who ransacked the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> office of <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>'s youngest son, <PERSON> Nicu </PERSON>, in <LOCATION> Sibiu </LOCATION>, southern <LOCATION> Transylvania </LOCATION>, found hundreds of Kent cigarette packs and bottles of whiskey and `` tuica,'' Romanian plum brandy. The television showed a back room where, according to the commentator, <PERSON> Nicu </PERSON>, party chief of the <LOCATION> Sibiu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> county </LOCATION>, `` used to rape women.'' Also displayed were stockings, makeup and underwear of his purported victims. <PERSON> Nicu </PERSON>, 39, was known as a womanizer, heavy drinker and a fan of Western fast cars who killed at least two people in traffic accidents, Romanian officials said. He was arrested Dec. 22. `` <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> had more dignity,'' the radio and TV commentator said. Romanian TV also showed pictures of the apartment of <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>'s daughter, <PERSON> Zoia-Elena </PERSON>, where she was arrested Among the items displayed were seven expensive watches, jewelry, $ 95,000 in cash, valuable paintings taken from <LOCATION> Romanian </LOCATION> art museums and pearls `` which we do n't think are false.'' `` Such a ` modest' baggage for such a long trip -LRB- to jail -RRB-,'' the commentator said sarcastically. The TV also showed meat supposedly shipped in from <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> for her dogs. The media reported that <PERSON> Zoia </PERSON>, trained as a mathematician, asked officers before being taken away by arresting officers: `` Is there enough room for my two pets?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891227-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-27-89 0034EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Romania-TV     12-27 0919</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Romania-TV,0948</SECOND>
<HEAD>Free Romania Television _ Heart of the Revolt</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MORT ROSENBLUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BUCHAREST, Romania (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The television station that once beamed the glory of <PERSON> Nicolae </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> to a numbed nation has become not only the voice, but the soul of the revolution that toppled his government and ended his life. While everything it broadcast once was suspect, nothing now is believed until it appears on <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Romania </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION>, as the station is calling itself. Although he was reported captured and executed, it was n't until television showed <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> in captivity that the nation sighed in relief. The station first broke from the propaganda of the Stalinist past on Friday morning, when <ORGANIZATION> army </ORGANIZATION> units joined protesters to drive <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> from his palace and from power. `` We've won. We've won,'' poet <PERSON> Murica </PERSON> <PERSON> Dinescu </PERSON> suddently shouted into the camera. But those giddy opening moments only were a prelude to the battles with <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> loyalists that followed. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> clung to the television like a mantle of power, running the country from a barricaded studio while <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>'s fanatical guard tried to blast it into silence. Sniper fire smashed windows and heavy shells blew holes in the walls. Early Saturday morning, news editor <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Ionescu </PERSON> announced on the air: `` We are under attack.'' He urged people to rally outside the TV station in a masive human shield to protect the building. Almost immediately, a crowd formed. People chanted, `` Freedom! Freedom!'' until gunfire broke out. Each time, they scattered and regrouped. They shouted, `` We wo n't go,'' and they did n't Outgunned, the attackers pulled back. Later that weekend, <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>'s guard struck again. Infiltrators stabbed people in the hallways of the 13-story complex, reportedly killing three people. For a few hours, TV screens went mysteriously blank. But the interruption was merely a technical problem, it was explained. <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> was still governed from a hectic studio littered with empty bottles, cracked coffee mugs and half-eaten sandwiches and run by people who had not slept in days. Television has played a large role in the forces of reform that swept the East bloc this year. Mass demonstrations were shown live on TV in <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> in the days preceding the Communist leadership's downfall; East Germans able to watch West German broadcasts followed closely news of the loosening of travel restrictions and the rallies that brought down <PERSON> Erich </PERSON> <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON>; a Solidarity economic minister goes on the air with regular `` fireside chats'' to the people. <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Romania </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> has become a chaotic reflection of the country it covers, a jumbled but jubilant mirror of the revolution it helped orchestrate. `` It is madness here, madness,'' said <PERSON> Gratiela </PERSON> <PERSON> Ripeanu </PERSON>. Her external relations job used to consist mainly of shaking hands with fraternal Bulgarians. Suddenly, she was shepherding countless foreign TV crews all desperate to relay film back home. Reporters counted on her to find them <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> members to interview. One by one, she steered people and their bulky gear through an obstacle course of gun barrels, locked gates, roiling crowds and skittish guards who looked for explosives in balpoint pen refills. Six body searches separated the street from the studio. `` We do n't know what we are doing anymore, but we're doing it,'' she said. <PERSON> Elena </PERSON> <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Ionescu </PERSON>, a news writer and <PERSON> Victor </PERSON>'s wife, helped out on the studio, partly because her office was a gaping hole in the eighth floor. She smiled broadly when she recognized several reporters who had sat with her until morning during the first assault. They had subsequently stayed in the relative luxury of hotel rooms, but she was still on the job. `` I've slept here, ate here, washed things out here,'' she said. `` My husband is so hoarse he can hardly talk on the air.'' Nevertheless, she seemed ready for another four days. Most of the station's 1,300 employees were caught up in the mad metamorphosis. Until the revolution, the station broadcast only two hours daily, a deadening litany of the heroic and generous qualities of <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>'s austerity budget left it short of equipment and supplies. Suddenly, it was on the air around the clock, and Romanians who once scorned television sat glued to their screens. Technicians cannibalized old gear and pushed technical tolerances to the limit. Armed soldiers wandered across the set, and overtired officials reverted to the hated Communist term for comrade, `` Tovarase,'' rather than `` Domnul,'' or mister, but the show went on. During the assault, section chiefs and janitors alike beamed with pride at the unflickering image they broadcast across the fearful nation. In the face of rumors and threats, the reassuring voices on television maintained the momentum of the revolt. Unlikely heroes emerged in the heat of battle. <PERSON> Marin </PERSON> <PERSON> Constantin </PERSON>, who edited youth programs, took it upon himself to make sure the eighth floor occupants made it through the night. When the shooting started, he herded eveyone into a central hallway protected from ricochets by a double layer of walls. When he found no other way to extinguish the grilled ceiling light, he deftly smashed it with a chair. When the heavy fighting began, his grin broadened, comforting others whose thoughts were beginning to rattle them. To amuse the company, he sang an old national hymn that was almost forgotten during <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>'s reign. It went, `` Wake up, <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>, from the mortal sleep into which you have been lulled by the evil tyrant.'' The song, broadcast earlier in the day over the battered transmitters, seemed to fit <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Romania </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891227-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-27-89 0035EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Romania-FirstPerson Bjt-2Takes   12-27 1153</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Romania-First Person, Bjt-2 Takes,1199</SECOND>
<HEAD>AP Correspondent Shot 3 Times in Early Throes of Romanian Revolt</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 One of the near-victims of the Romanian revolt against their hated longtime dictator was <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Daniszewski </PERSON>, chief of the <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, who had gone to the <LOCATION> Balkan </LOCATION> nation to report the momentous events there. Here is his first-hand account, filed from his hospital bed in <LOCATION> Belgrade </LOCATION>, of the hellish situation in <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> and his brush with death.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DANISZEWSKI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Assoicated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BELGRADE, Yugoslavia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The uprising against dictator <PERSON> Nicolae </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> gave rise to fierce resistance by his secret police, turning <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> into a land of fear, suspicion and retribution. I know, I became a victim of that chaos Saturday night. I was shot three times, narrowly escaping death. One bullet grazed my skull, and two more lodged in my left arm. Thanks to some dedicated doctors in District Hospital No. 1 in <LOCATION> Timisoara </LOCATION>, and the friendly intervention of Yugoslav diplomats in the city, I survived and was evacuated within two days to <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>'s capital <LOCATION> Belgrade </LOCATION>. It is hard to describe the mood of pure panic and paranoia that pervaded <LOCATION> Timisoara </LOCATION>, a petrochemical center in western <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> with about 350,000 inhabitants. The events that led to <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>'s fall and execution began a week before Christmas. Demonstrations to prevent a <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> minister from being evicted swelled into anti-government protests. Unarmed civilians were gunned down by state security troops, the dreaded Securitate, in the main square. No Westerner has been able to verify the number of fatalities, but doctors with whom I spoke said more than 4,000 died. After the slaughter, the bodies were gathered in trucks and taken to a mass grave at the city cemetery. The blood that flowed that day on the square sparked a popular thirst for revenge. Residents responded with a general strike, and the army declared itself with the people and against <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>. After state TV in <LOCATION> Bucharest </LOCATION> fell to the opposition Friday, the borders opened for the first time in four days to Western journalists. I flew to <LOCATION> Belgrade </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> late Friday, rented a car at the airport, and started driving to <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>'s border. Just before entering <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>, I met a <LOCATION> Yugoslav </LOCATION> journalist, <PERSON> Ljuba </PERSON> <PERSON> Pajic </PERSON>, who was to be my companion in the days that followed. Although I arrived at the border with no visa, the slightly drunken border guards wearing armbands in the national colors of red, blue and yellow let me in with little formality. `` American? You are with us,'' one guard whispered out of earshot of his superior. On the two-hour drive to <LOCATION> Timisoara </LOCATION>, we were repeatedly stopped by groups of peasants waving the Romanian flag _ with the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> emblem cut out of it. `` Ceausescu kaput! <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> finito!'' they shouted to the foreigners. But once entering <LOCATION> Timisoara </LOCATION>, tension replaced jubilation. A siren wailed and young people on the street talked fearfully of an air raid. <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>'s forces were going to bomb the city, they claimed. So, with car lights off, fearing the bombs that never fell and avoiding the black silhouettes of tanks at many street corners, we began to look for the main hotel, where I thought we would find other journalists. <PERSON> Ljuba </PERSON> and I ended up at the Hotel <LOCATION> Timisoara </LOCATION>, near the Opera Square. Inside the darkened lobby, we were frisked by nervous young people carrying knives, clubs and sharpened sticks. A young woman who spoke English gave me an account of the massacre: Children peacefully praying the previous Sunday, Dec. 17, were mowed down by automatic weapons, she said. When their mothers ran to them, they too were shot. It was also in the lobby, less than an hour after arriving in town, that I met my first casualty. French photographer <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Langevant </PERSON> hobbled in holding his buddy's arm, a bullet hole in his leg. He was bleeding badly, but the rat-a-tat-tat of gunfire growing nearer outside made everyone reluctant to go for help. Finally, a `` machina'' _ a car _ rolled up to the front door and Langevant was bundled inside. <PERSON> Ljuba </PERSON> and I decided to follow in our car. Headlights still off, we raced through the deserted streets, afraid to stop. We screeched into the courtyard of District Hospital No. 2. The photographer was taken to the operating room and we spent the night huddled in the doctors' lounge. The hospital, like the other buildings in <LOCATION> Timisoara </LOCATION> at night, was kept in eerie darkness whenever possible. `` They shoot at the light,'' one physician said, drawing a curtain closed when the flicker of a television set dimly lighted the lounge. Doctors said they had been working with a constant stream of shooting victims since Dec. 17. They too were afraid, cowering on the floor when the noise of gunfire came too close. Red tracers arched over the hospital roof. It was a hairy night, but at last, by midmorning Saturday, the shooting had died down enough to go outside. Saturday we spent trying to locate an outside phone line to tell the story. In the evening, I returned to <LOCATION> Hotel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Timisoara </LOCATION>, where we talked to the leader of the pro-democracy forces, headquartered there. Their chief was an automotive engineer, a tall and dignified young man dressed in a black beret and trenchcoat who spoke some French. The hotel was again in total blackness and he led us through the empty restaurant to a small cafe off the kitchen, where he pushed together two tables and fed us a Romanian feast _ sliced sausages and salty cheese, washed down with grapefruit soda. A Romanian soldier with a Soviet submachine gun and several rebels looked on politely. I asked them what kind of country they wanted. Democracy and free elections was the reply. And the Ceausescus? Killing was too good for them, the group agreed. Maybe torture. After a short drive around downtown, where the fighting had been the heaviest, all appeared quiet. I made one outside phone call and left the building, Outside, the scene had suddenly changed. Gunfire erupted very close by as soon as we left. Retreating to the car, we backed away in the opposite direction. Two Italian journalists who had left the consulate with us followed in another car. What followed was a nightmare of running with nowhere to hide. Every turn in the strange city seemed to lead to another firefight. We tried to make our way back to the hotel, going in ever wider circles because of the fighting. Finally, luck ran out. Driving into an intersection, somebody flashed a light on us and shouted in Romanian. Before we could answer or get out of the car, I saw the flash of a gun and realized in an instant they were shooting at us. Immediately, I felt something slam into my arm and what felt like warm water being poured on my head. My own blood.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891227-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-27-89 0035EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Romania-FirstPerson 1stAdd   12-27 0301</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Romania-First Person, 1st Add,0310</SECOND>
<HEAD>BELGRADE, own blood.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 For what seemed like an eternity, we screamed that we were journalists. The men who came out of a bunker to us _ some in uniform, some in civilian clothes _ screamed at us and dragged us to them. We were roughed up. One man came at me with a knife but stopped just before stabbing me. A soldier kept a gun aimed at my head. I thought they were going to kill us. My companion, <PERSON> Ljuba </PERSON>, was not hit by the gunfire, but he was beaten. They took our money. Of the Italians, one was badly wounded in the chest, and the other unhurt. Finally, to my relief, two ambulances arrived. The Italian photographer, <PERSON> Pasquale </PERSON> <PERSON> Modita </PERSON>, went first. Then me. The ride to the hospital was mercifully brief, and for my second night in <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>, I was once again under the physicians' protection. The bullets had gone into my upper left arm, a few inches from my heart. The other one cut a gash in my scalp, but did not penetrate my skull. `` You were very, very lucky,'' my favorite doctor told me. Time and again, the doctor said after my first operation to explore the wound in my arm, `` Someone as lucky as you will live a long time.'' For the two nights and a day that I convalesced in the hospital, battle raged outside my window between the Romanian army and small, ruthless commando units loyal to <PERSON> Ceasescu </PERSON>. I worried that the Securitate would win and murder us all. But Christmas Day, about 36 hours after being shot, ambulances arranged by the <LOCATION> Yugoslav </LOCATION> government and The <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> took me and <PERSON> Zzeljko </PERSON> <PERSON> Ssajan </PERSON>, a wounded reporter from <LOCATION> Zagreb </LOCATION> television, to <LOCATION> Belgrade </LOCATION>. I was never so happy to cross a border.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891227-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-27-89 0036EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Brazil-Floods     12-27 0259</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Brazil-Floods,0269</SECOND>
<UNK>Floods Leave 24 Dead, 140,000 Homeless in Brazil</UNK>
<DATELINE>RIO DE JANEIRO, Brazil (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Flooding in <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s normally dry east-central region has killed 24 people and left at least 140,000 homeless, national civil defense spokesman <PERSON> Silvio </PERSON> <PERSON> Reiner </PERSON> says. Speaking by telephone on Tuesday from <LOCATION> Brasilia </LOCATION>, the capital, 750 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Reiner </PERSON> said 140 cities and towns in five of the 26 states were affected by flooding, caused by more than two weeks of torrential rain. Unofficial reports said most of those killed drowned or were buried when houses collapsed. <PERSON> Reiner </PERSON> said the worst hit area was northeastern <LOCATION> Bahia </LOCATION> state, where 105,000 people were driven from their homes. Road traffic between <LOCATION> Cachoeira </LOCATION>, 930 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION>, and the rest of the country was cut off by the <LOCATION> Paraguacu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, which overflowed and covered much of the city. TV film showed canoes and rowboats paddling down flooded streets with families carrying sofas, stoves and other household goods to dry ground. The city dates from the <LOCATION> Portuguese </LOCATION> colonial era and is considered a national historic monument. <PERSON> Cachoeira </PERSON> was without electricity and was running out of food and drinking water, <PERSON> Reiner </PERSON> said. Civil defense workers were flying in emergency shipments of food, blankets and medicine, mainly antityphoid and snakebite serum, he said. In <ORGANIZATION> Minas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gerais </ORGANIZATION> state, south of <LOCATION> Bahia </LOCATION>, 5,765 houses collapsed in 70 townships, the official said, and 24,200 people were homeless. About 11,000 Brazilians had to abandon their homes in nearby <LOCATION> Goias </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tocantins </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Maranhao </LOCATION> states, he said. More rain for the region was forecast.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891227-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-27-89 0037EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Panama-Military     12-27 0914</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Panama-Military,0940</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S., Panamanian Officials Argue About Military Strength</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELOY O. AGUILAR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> is gone, but the question of fashioning a security force to replace his bully boys is causing friction between the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military and the new Panamanian civilian government. Sources on both sides agree there's a problem. The civilians want a weakened army that would be little more than a police force and would not represent a threat to the government. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is pressing for a professional army to provide security for the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION>. Panamanian civilians have been intimidated by the military for more than 20 years, suffering exile, torture, imprisonment and death. The Panamanian military has not had much respect for politicians, whom they considered weak and beholden to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` The truth is that both, the civilian and the military must be re-educated,'' a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military source told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. `` We are telling the <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> military that they must understand their role in society under civilian power. And we are telling the civilians that a strong military organization is needed too,'' the source said, on condition of anonymity. The <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> is due to be turned over to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> on Dec. 31, 1999, and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bases are to be closed unless a further agreement is reached with the Panamanian government. Since the treaties give the two countries joint responsibiilty for canal security even after 2000, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sources say at least two bases probably will be maintained, rather than the 10 major installations that now support 12,000 troops. Ironically, the Panamanian army under <PERSON> Omar </PERSON> <PERSON> Torrijos </PERSON> was the core of the long drive to eliminate the sovereign <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> enclave in the Canal Zone and negotiate the 1977 treaties. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials insist the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will honor the treaties. The dispute over how to reconstitute the Panamanian forces is taking place even as <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officers work with Panamanian officers to do exactly that, despite civilian unease. `` It is a matter of concern that the members of the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> are being reintegrated, and not by the Panamanian government, but by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>,'' said <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Materno </PERSON> <PERSON> Vasquez </PERSON>, a lawyer who helped negotiate the 1977 canal treaties but left the government in a dispute with <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. Vice president and minister of government <PERSON> Ricardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> <PERSON> Calderon </PERSON> has spoken of a <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, avoiding all reference to the old name of <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> or previous names, such as National Guard. `` You can call it what you will,'' a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> source said. `` It has to be a professional force, army, national guard or whatever.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military leaders here, who worked with the Panamanians for years and know them well, feel some _ especially those jailed by <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> following coup attempts _ can be trusted enough to form the core of an army. Before the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attack that toppled <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> Dec. 20, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military sources told the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces could `` work with some of the Panamanian top officers, even if they are not shining examples of democracy.'' According to a <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> military source, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officers were rather blunt when they told President <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> what they want in a Panamanian army. <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> was elected president May 7, but <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> nullified the vote and <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> was not installed until after the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> assault. `` The politicians did not shed any blood,'' another source said. `` The blood was shed by the Americans and the few <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> units that fought.'' Both the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Panamanian military, even those opposed to <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, feel the opposition was unwilling to take risks to try to topple <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. Comparisons with uprisings in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and, lately, <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> were raised frequently. `` They want us to do the job for them,'' a top-ranking <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officer told the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> before <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces did exactly that. Some of the new leaders of the future Panamanian military are the majors and captains who were arrested March 16, 1988, after their failed coup against <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. They include men like Maj. <PERSON> Santiago </PERSON> <PERSON> Fundora </PERSON> and Maj. <PERSON> Aristides </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdonedo </PERSON>, who have been named directors of logistics and public security respectively, and Maj. <PERSON> August </PERSON> <PERSON> Villalaz </PERSON>, who will be in charge of the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>. They have been working closely with the commander of <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION>, Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Marc </PERSON> <PERSON> Cisneros </PERSON>, and other <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> officers at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Clayton </LOCATION>, near <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. `` The person who is really governing in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> now is <PERSON> Marc </PERSON> <PERSON> Cisneros </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Vasquez </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Vasquez </PERSON> said he saw a former lieutenant colonel surrender with other officers and return home with a `` passport from <PERSON> Cisneros </PERSON>, not even from <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> authorities.'' `` We're concerned about too many of those guys coming back in,'' said a <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> politician involved in forming the new government. The <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> government would like to set up `` something like what <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> has.'' <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>, just north of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, has been spared coups and military rule in large measure because the armed forces were dissolved more than 40 years ago. <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> has only a civilian police force and relies on the Organization of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> charter, which calls for collective defense in case of attack. In essence that means relying on the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, but <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials are not sympathetic to the civilian government's desires. `` <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> may feel that he was elected in May,'' one source said `` but his majority meant nothing and he is where he is because of the American guns.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891227-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-27-89 0032EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     12-27 0740</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0765</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Columnist <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Buchwald </PERSON> came up with an original idea when he proposed a movie based on the comic adventures of an African king in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, says the co-creator of the old TV series `` <ORGANIZATION> Barney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Miller </ORGANIZATION>.'' <PERSON> Buchwald </PERSON> is suing <ORGANIZATION> Paramount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pictures </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> for $ 5 million, alleging the 1988 <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> hit `` Coming to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'' was based on an idea he optioned to the studio in 1983. Paramount's attorney, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Draper </PERSON>, has contended that <PERSON> Buchwald </PERSON> failed to live up to his contract with <ORGANIZATION> Paramount </ORGANIZATION> because his idea was not original _ that it was based on a <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Chaplin </PERSON> movie called `` A King in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>.'' But `` Barney Miller'' co-creator <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> disagreed. `` I can not remember a particular work or motion picture about an African king transposed into a situation in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' he testified Tuesday in the <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> trial. The <PERSON> Chaplin </PERSON> movie was about a European king who is kicked out of his own country and tries to sell atomic energy ideas to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials. <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON>, called as an expert witness for <PERSON> Buchwald </PERSON>, also testified that the elusive show business term `` based upon'' refers to the beginning of an idea. But under cross-examination, he said: `` There is no industry standard for ` based upon.' It's a purely subjective determination.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BEVERLY HILLS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Willem </PERSON> <PERSON> Dafoe </PERSON> said he was attracted to the role in the new film `` Triumph of the Spirit'' in much the way he was drawn to his roles in `` Platoon'' and `` The Last Temptation of Christ.'' `` They're so unusual,'' said <PERSON> Dafoe </PERSON>, who is picky about parts he will play. `` They're so huge. They raise so many interesting questions that you do n't quite know what it is before you start working on it.'' <PERSON> Dafoe </PERSON>, whose acting career took off two years ago after the movie `` Platoon,'' is back in the spotlight again with his new film. In `` Triumph of the Spirit,'' <PERSON> Dafoe </PERSON> portrays a boxer who fights for his survival after he is imprisoned at a Nazi death camp with his family. The critically acclaimed film is based on the life of <PERSON> Salamo </PERSON> <PERSON> Arouch </PERSON>, a Greek Jew and middleweight boxing champion who was sent to <LOCATION> Auschwitz </LOCATION>. `` I think I'm attracted to roles that are kind of mythic and have some size and, you know, are full of possibility,'' he said of his penchant for playing unforgettable screen characters.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MERIDIAN, Miss. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. G.V. `` Sonny'' <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON> said he was thankful for the chance to dine with the first family on Christmas Day at Camp <PERSON> David </PERSON> and did n't even mind being put on the spot by the president's request that he give the Christmas blessing. `` It was a good Christmas,'' said <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON>, a Democrat. `` I was honored. That was really something.'' Along with the traditional meal of turkey and dressing, sweet potatoes topped with marshmallows and green beans, <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON> said guests were given the choice of pumpkin or pecan pie for dessert. `` The meal was terrific, the entire day was very well done. Everyone was definitely in the Christmas spirit,'' he said Tuesday. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> recently extended the Christmas invitation to the single <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> congressman.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Civil rights leader <PERSON> Hosea </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, who has organized a Christmas dinner for the homeless and hungry for 19 years, is hospitalized with bronchitis and pneumonia, but plans to get back into action soon. `` I'm feeling much better, and I hope to be release in a few days,'' <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said Tuesday in a telephone interview from his room at <ORGANIZATION> Emory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, 64, said his annual Christmas and Thanksgiving feasts since 1970 combined have fed nearly half a million people at a cost of nearly $ 1 million, and used 65,000 volunteers. `` This was our 19th year, and I'd say we fed a total of about 35,000 at the Christmas dinner, counting the deliveries to sick and old people at their homes,'' he said. `` You watch these families eating, and you realize, if they did n't eat here, where would they eat? They'd just go to bed hungry.'' <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said the program has expanded so much that he is going to turn it into a year-round operation. `` I've a job, a real obligation to feed the hungry _ they're the fastest growing population in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, even more so than the homeless. A lot of people have homes, they live here, but they have nothing to eat,'' said <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891227-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-27-89 0059EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-India-Bofors     12-27 0469</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-India-Bofors,0484</SECOND>
<HEAD>Singh Government Halts Future Contracts With Swedish Firm Bofors</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The new government of Prime Minister V.P. <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> says it will temporarily stop buying weapons from a Swedish armaments firm accused of paying huge bribes to secure a 1986 contract with the Indian army. The alleged impropriety in <ORGANIZATION> AB </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bofors </ORGANIZATION>' $ 1.4 billion Howitzer gun deal was a key campaign issue for <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, whose centrist coalition ousted <PERSON> Rajiv </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> from power in last month's elections. <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, who is also the country's defense minister, announced in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday that <ORGANIZATION> Bofors </ORGANIZATION> will be barred from future contracts until `` they satisfy us in their conduct in regard to -LRB- the -RRB- Howitzer guns.'' At least two newspaper investigations have sought to prove that <ORGANIZATION> Bofors </ORGANIZATION> paid as much as $ 50 million in bribes and commissions to yet unnamed persons. The allegations have not been proved since they surfaced in April 1987, but one newspaper, The Hindu, has published purported documents that it said established <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s links with recipients of the alleged bribes and commissions. The Hindu, and another newspaper, Indian Express, said senior officials in <LOCATION> Gandhi </LOCATION>'s cabinet and persons close to him received the bribes. <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> has also been accused of covering up the investigation by handing it over to pliant officers. <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> has denied the charges and maintained that his actions have been above board. <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> coalition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> government </ORGANIZATION> said in its election manifesto that it will unearth and disclose the names of the commission recipients within 15 days of taking office. <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> was sworn in Dec. 2. On Tuesday, <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> denied that he is not longer keen on probing the <ORGANIZATION> Bofors </ORGANIZATION> deal now that his coalition is power. <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> said the government order Tuesday covers `` supply of names of recipients and return of money paid in regard to <ORGANIZATION> Bofors </ORGANIZATION> gun transactions.'' `` This shows there is no lack of enthusiasm. We are determined. There is no question of compromise on anything. `` We will do everything to get the names and come to the truth,'' <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> said. His colleagues in Parliament loudly thumped desks. <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> was interrupted by <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> members when he continued with the statement. <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Shankar </PERSON> <PERSON> Dayal </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharma </PERSON> adjourned the session amid the uproar triggered by angry shouts from <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>'s colleagues. Hours after <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>'s truncated statement, the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> said it had been directed by the prime minister to stop all future contracts with <ORGANIZATION> Bofors </ORGANIZATION>. It was the new government's first major policy decision on the <ORGANIZATION> Bofors </ORGANIZATION> deal since taking office. `` The embargo will be till such time as the company satisfied the government of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> about their previous conduct,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> said in a statement. The current Howitzer gun deal apparently remained unaffected by the decision as neither <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> nor the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> referred to it.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891227-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-27-89 0218EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--Scotus-Menorah     12-27 0151</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Scotus-Menorah,0157</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pittsburgh Plans Renewed Fight Against Courthouse Menorah</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Jewish group erected a 40-foot menorah outside the City-County Building, and the city said it was renewing legal attempts to have the holiday symbol removed from public property. The city planned to petition the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> today to have the Hanukkah symbol taken down, attorneys said. The city contends it has the right to determine what is permitted in front of the building. The Orthodox Jewish Chabad group was permitted to erect the display Monday under protection of a restraining order issued last week by <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Justice <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>. <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON> upheld <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Barron </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> McCune </PERSON>'s order preventing the city from blocking Chabad's installation of the menorah <PERSON> McCune </PERSON> ruled that the courthouse steps are a public forum open to all types of expression. The eight-day Jewish Feast of Lights ends Saturday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891227-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-27-89 0104EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Nicaragua     12-27 0186</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Nicaragua,0190</SECOND>
<HEAD>Batteries Fire at Unidentified Aircraft</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANAGUA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Anti-aircraft batteries opened fire late Tuesday at two unidentified aircraft that flew low over the capital, the government radio station <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nicaragua </ORGANIZATION> reported. The radio broadcast said the control tower at the <ORGANIZATION> Augusto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cesar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sandino </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airport </ORGANIZATION> unsuccessfully tried to establish radio contact with the aircraft as they approached <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION> from the north and the east before the batteries opened fire at about 9:30 p.m. The aircraft escaped, but the incident panicked residents of neighborhoods close to the airport as firing continued for several minutes and anti-aircraft tracers blew across the sky. The Sandinista government has placed the army on `` maximum alert'' since <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops invaded <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> one week ago to oust Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. Earlier Tuesday, the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> said it was continuing efforts to arrange the evacuation of 156 Nicaraguan nationals from <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. Most of the Nicaraguans were businesspeople, the ministry said. The government also sought to remove two aircraft operated by the national airline <PERSON> Aeronica </PERSON> that have been trapped at <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s Omar Torrijos airport since the invasion began.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891227-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-27-89 0117EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SECEnforcement Bjt   12-27 0663</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SEC Enforcement, Bjt,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>SEC Creates New Fraud Unit to Protect Small Investors</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Economics Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, catapulted into the headlines by its pursuit of multimillion-dollar insider trading scandals, is putting out the word that it intends to be just as aggressive in protecting small investors. <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Breeden </PERSON> is creating a new fraud unit at the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> designed to police the sale of securities by savings and loan institutions. Investigators have charged that some small investors lost their life savings when they bought securities sold by <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L branches in the mistaken belief that their investments were protected by federal deposit insurance. `` We intend to see to it that when people are sold securities, they are provided all the necessary information,'' <PERSON> Breeden </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Breeden </PERSON> also announced Tuesday that he had selected <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> McLucas </PERSON>, a 12-year <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> veteran, to be the new director of enforcement at the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION>. He will succeed <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Lynch </PERSON>, who resigned in July after supervising such landmark insider trading cases as the investigation of <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON> <PERSON> Boesky </PERSON> and the Wall Street firm of <ORGANIZATION> Drexel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Burnham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lambert </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc </ORGANIZATION>. Both <PERSON> Breeden </PERSON> and <PERSON> McLucas </PERSON> stressed that insider trading still would be a top <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> priority, but they also indicated that the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION>, with a 20 percent increase in its budget, would devote more resources to more low-profile crooks. `` Where there is an abuse of a customer's trust, those are the kinds of cases where we are going to make sure we have an impact,'' <PERSON> McLucas </PERSON> said at a news conference where his selection was announced. Individual investors have been leaving the market in droves in recent years, scared off in part by extreme trading volatility. Many officials believe the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> must return to its primary mission of bolstering confidence in financial markets through protection of the small investor. <PERSON> Breeden </PERSON>, who was picked for the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> post by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> last summer, said both the administration and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> had expressed a strong desire to crack down on abuses against individual investors. <PERSON> Breeden </PERSON> noted that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> approved a 20 percent increase in the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> budget this year, enough to allow the agency to hire 100 more attorneys. Part of the increased staffing will be used, <PERSON> Breeden </PERSON> said, to create a special 25-attorney unit to investigate overly aggressive sales of securities by savings and loans and other financial institutions. Such sales became a major focus of congressional hearings into the activities at <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> Irvine </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Calif.-based </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L whose failure is expected to end up costing taxpayers a record $ 2 billion. Small investors told congressional investigators they were lured into purchasing bonds in <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION>' parent company, <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, in the mistaken belief that their money was protected by federal deposit insurance. When <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION>, which is headed by <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> businessman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, filed for protection under the bankruptcy law, it left some 22,000 small investors who had purchased nearly $ 200 million in corporate bonds in the lurch. <PERSON> Breeden </PERSON> said the new <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> unit will try to prevent financially ailing <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls from turning to fraudulent practices in a desperate effort to raise cash. <PERSON> McLucas </PERSON>, 39, joined the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> in 1977, two years after receiving a law degree from <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Lynch </PERSON>, who resigned to join a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> law firm, served for four years as <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> enforcement chief, taking over from <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Fedders </PERSON>, who was forced to resign after allegations surfaced that he had beaten his wife. <PERSON> Lynch </PERSON> was credited with restoring morale at the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> and directing some of the agency's biggest investigations, beginning with the exposure of <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Levine </PERSON> in May 1986. <PERSON> Levine </PERSON>'s cooperation led to a $ 100 million settlement with speculator <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON> <PERSON> Boesky </PERSON> <PERSON> Boesky </PERSON> in turn implicated <ORGANIZATION> Drexel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Burnham </ORGANIZATION>, which led to a $ 650 million settlement with the securities firm, the largest securities fraud case ever brought by the government. Civil and criminal charges are still pending against former <ORGANIZATION> Drexel </ORGANIZATION> junk bond pioneer <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Milken </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891227-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-27-89 0118EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Panama-Democracy     12-27 0719</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Panama-Democracy,710</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lack of Democratic Tradition in Panama Stymies US Efforts, Scholars
Say</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RUTH SINAI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> presidents since <PERSON> Teddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> in 1903 have talked about the need to install democracy in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. Some sent troops under the banner of shoring up democratic rule. But all have been stymied by the lack of democratic tradition in the strategically placed isthmus and by their overriding desire to protect <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> rights of passage through the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION>, scholars say. When President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> went on television Wednesday morning to explain why he dispatched troops to remove Panamanian strongman <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> from power, he cited the <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> people's desire for democracy and peace `` The people of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> seek only to support them in pursuit of these noble goals,'' he said. `` The rhetoric about favoring democracy is no more than that. It's a pretense,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Peeler </PERSON>, who heads the Center for the Study of the <LOCATION> Americas </LOCATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Bucknell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>. The real <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> desire is `` for democratic government, read reliable government, one that wo n't threaten our control of the canal,'' <PERSON> Peeler </PERSON> added. The few times in their 86-year history of independence when Panamanians have supported a truly democratic government, `` We were n't willing to accept their choice,'' <PERSON> Peeler </PERSON> said. That includes <PERSON> Arnulfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Arias </PERSON>, a populist leader elected president twice in the 1940s and again in 1968. <PERSON> Arias </PERSON>' left-leaning views did not sit well with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, which was not sorry to see him ousted after several days in office by <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> commander Gen. <PERSON> Omar </PERSON> <PERSON> Torrijos </PERSON>. But <PERSON> Torrijos </PERSON> proved an even bigger problem for the administration, with his pro-Cuban policies and strong nationalism which opposed the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> right under the 1903 treaty to use the canal `` in perpetuity.'' Increasing friction with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> led to the ratification of a new treaty in 1978 ceding the canal to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> in the year 2000 but reserving the right to intervene if shipping through the waterway were threatened. Threats to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> use of the canal were what prompted the first dispatch of military force to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. When <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, which ruled <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> in the 19th Century, refused to approve the 1903 canal treaty with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> sent warships to help the growing Panamanian secessionist movement. But the warships only stood by as the secessionists launched a bloodless revolt and declared independence. In August 1914, the same month World War I broke out, the first ships passed through the canal. But political chaos reigned and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> sent troops to register voters and supervise elections. Each time that happened _ in 1908, 1912 and 1916 _ the losing side blamed <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> interference. By the 1930s, `` there was growing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> frustration with the attempts to instill democracy in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerome </PERSON>, a professor of history at <ORGANIZATION> James </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Madison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gerome </PERSON> has written extensively about <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> efforts to organize the 1912 elections. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s strategic importance grew immensely in World War II, when the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military presence rose sharply to defend oil shipments from <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> against German interception. The hitherto limited <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military presence, which had been centered mostly around the canal, spread to other parts of the country. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> in the 1950s and 1960s was ruled by a succession of families from among a thin elite. While not a military state, neither was it truly democratic. <PERSON> Torrijos </PERSON>' rise to power in 1968 transferred power to the military, with a nominal role for civilian governments. Such was the setup under <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, too, after <PERSON> Torrijos </PERSON> died in a 1981 plane crash. `` Various American presidents hoped the roots of democracy might grow,'' said <PERSON> Gerome </PERSON>. `` What they failed to understand is that you ca n't export democracy.'' <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, abhorrent though he is now to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> administration which nurtured him in the 1970s, enjoyed strong popular appeal among <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s poor. <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Endara </PERSON>, who was installed at a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military facility as <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s president on Thursday based on the results of last May's elections, does not enjoy <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s popular appeal. His main support comes from middle-class merchants. `` Support for him is weak, not passionate,'' and being propped up by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> can only be a liability, said <PERSON> Peeler </PERSON>, adding, `` People are n't celebrating democracy, they're looting. Does n't <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> see that?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891227-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-27-89 0119EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-Vacation     12-27 0737</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Vacation,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Quail Hunting a Tradition for President Busyh</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is winding up his first year as president pretty much the same way he ended the year before, and the year before that, going back several decades: quail hunting on a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> ranch. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> aides say they hope he'll have better luck than last year, when dry conditions made the tiny game birds scarce. The president will spend several days isolated _ but never out of touch, aides insist _ at the 10,000-acre Lazy F Ranch near <LOCATION> Beeville </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, owned by his friend, <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> millionaire <PERSON> Will </PERSON> <PERSON> Farish </PERSON>. `` It's been a tradition for the past 20 years,'' said aide <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, who worked for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as vice president and has been along on several of the previous quail-hunting trips. `` They drive around the ranch in big specially designed trucks, then hunt with dogs. If they can catch turkey, too, then that's a big treat,'' <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> said. In the past, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has hunted quail with a 20-gauge shotgun, dressed in snake-resistant chaps, heavy leather boots and an orange hunting cap. Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, expected to be along on the trip, is known to prefer turkey hunting, which requires greater patience. But <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who likes to jump from event to event, has defended the sport of quail hunting as more to his liking _ and has asserted that the birds are not to be regarded as cute animals but as wily, determined quarry. `` These are n't animals _ these are wild quail, `` <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> declared during last year's trip in a remark that angered animal rights groups. `` You've got to eat. Our forefathers ate by harvesting game.'' The <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> office of The Fund for Animals has written to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> asking him to cancel the hunt, and plans to have animal activists travel to <LOCATION> Beeville </LOCATION> to protest his activities if he carries out his hunting plans. It seems likely that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> will discuss another wily, determined quarry while on the ranch _ deposed <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> dictator <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s decision to go Sunday to the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> embassy in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, where he is currently in hiding, took a lot pressure off the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration as it seeks to help restore post-invasion order in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. However, aides said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> never wavered from his determination to make the hunting trip, and that little _ short of a major crisis _ would force him to cancel the trip. The town of <LOCATION> Beeville </LOCATION>, population about 15,000, is throwing a barbecue for the president tonight upon his arrival _ but probably wo n't see him again. Once he enters the vast ranch, he is not expected to be seen publicly in the area. He will fly by helicopter directly to <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> on Friday. Meanwhile, the <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> of neighboring <LOCATION> Goliad </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, is fussing to the White House that the part of the ranch where <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> hunts is actually in <LOCATION> Goliad </LOCATION>, not <LOCATION> Beeville </LOCATION> _ and that it should be able to share in the publicity. But the sheriff of <LOCATION> Goliad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <PERSON> J.K. </PERSON> <PERSON> McMahan </PERSON>, says it's fine with him if the president keeps a low profile. Referring to recent stories that Colombian drug lords may have put a $ 30 million price on the president's head, <PERSON> McMahan </PERSON> said recently: `` I do n't want him killed, period, but I damn sure do n't want him killed in my county.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also plans to bracket his quail-hunting with two fishing expeditions _ another endeavor in which the president has not had much recent luck. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> planned to fish for redfish in the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, off <PERSON> Corpus </PERSON> <PERSON> Christi </PERSON>, today on his way to <LOCATION> Beeville </LOCATION>. And on New Year's Day, after spending several days in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, including a side trip on Sunday to two military hospitals in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION> to visit soldiers wounded in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will take about five hours out on his return to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to fish for bass on a private lake near <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 The White House says it's glad that <ORGANIZATION> Time </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Magazine </ORGANIZATION> selected Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to be `` Man of the Decade'' in its current year-end issue. `` We certainly congratulate him,'' said presidential spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>. `` He has contributed greatly to the changes in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and reforms in his own country. They have all been very productive to Western interests. We congratulate him on it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891227-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-27-89 0133EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     12-27 0599</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Modest Consumer Food Price Rise Expected in 1990</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Consumer food prices are still on track to increase by a modest 3 percent to 5 percent in 1990 despite the bitter cold that has ravaged citrus and winter vegetable crops, says an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> analyst. The food price forecast was made last month, and economist <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Parlett </PERSON> said Tuesday he is sticking by it, at least for now. Overall food prices are up an average of about 5.7 percent this year, the largest annual gain since a 7.8 percent jump in 1981. Much of this year's increase was due to lingering effects of the 1988 drought and poor weather early in 1989. `` I'm not worried about my overall forecast -LRB- for 1990 -RRB- at this point,'' <PERSON> Parlett </PERSON> said in a telephone interview. `` But there'll be some impact, and possibly higher prices in the first quarter.'' <PERSON> Parlett </PERSON> said he and other agency analysts are `` still trying to assess the damage'' to citrus and vegetable crops in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and elsewhere. `` The main thing is oranges,'' he said. `` Vegetables _ tomatoes, bell peppers, celery _ they're some of the big volume things that would be coming out of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> now.'' <PERSON> Parlett </PERSON> said 90 percent of the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> oranges are for processing and that a lot of them can be salvaged for juice. The main source of `` fresh market'' oranges is <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. `` There will be some -LRB- retail -RRB- price impact,'' he said. `` But since we do have decent supplies in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> this year ... the supply impact will be minimal.'' With the supply of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> orange juice reduced by the freezing weather, <PERSON> Parlett </PERSON> said imports from <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> will probably rise sharply. `` We've got super supplies in <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> this year, but the price has been fairly low because of the higher supplies,'' he said. `` But now that we probably will be importing, that will push the price up some.'' <PERSON> Parlett </PERSON> said he had not seen damage reports from <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, where state officials have estimated losses of 70 percent of the citrus and 80 percent of the winter vegetables. Vegetable losses are `` a more temporary kind of thing'' because those crops can be replanted, he said. Growers were just starting to harvest <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s main supply of winter vegetables when the cold weather struck. <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> is still producing vegetables, however, and `` this time of year we start getting produce out of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, too,'' <PERSON> Parlett </PERSON> said. `` There's no doubt that some of the supplies will be cut short, and we'll probably see higher prices'' at produce counters, he said. In his forecast last month, <PERSON> Parlett </PERSON> said 1990 average retail prices of all fruits and vegetables might rise only 1 percent to 3 percent, compared with the preliminary 7.8 percent gain registered this year and 7.6 percent in 1988. <PERSON> Parlett </PERSON> said the current freeze damage `` might push us to the high end'' of the 1990 forecast range _ 1 percent to 3 percent _ and, if conditions worsen, could push it even higher. `` Oranges themselves are n't going to do much to hurt that range, and the vegetables will recover later on,'' he said. According to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> computations based on <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> price information, prices of fresh fruits and vegetables last year accounted for 11.4 percent of the <ORGANIZATION> BLS </ORGANIZATION> consumer price index for food bought in grocery stores, while processed fruits and vegetables made up only 6.8 percent of the index. Meats, by comparison, accounted for 20.3 percent of the <ORGANIZATION> BLS </ORGANIZATION> food-at-home price index, while cereals and bakery products accounted for 14 percent; and dairy products, 12.3 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891227-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-27-89 0138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-RogerPorter     12-27 0774</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Roger Porter,760</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Domestic Policy Adviser Takes `Honest Broker' Approach</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 He is President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s top adviser on domestic issues _ from gun control to clean air _ a veteran of three presidencies who knows government inside out and is such a workaholic he sometimes sleeps in his White House office. From <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Porter </PERSON>'s arrival at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> on the same day <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> left office in scandal, through every Republican administration since, he has had a hand in crafting policies that affect millions of Americans. Today as <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s domestic policy adviser, he is the presidential assistant who reigns over issues such as child care, the drug war, education and auto pollution. But <PERSON> Porter </PERSON>'s is a name little known to most Americans. `` He does n't like to hog attention,'' says <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> legal counsel <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyden </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, adding, `` Do n't mistake that for lack of influence or lack of force.'' The president typically consults with <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> on a daily basis for what some describe as <PERSON> Porter </PERSON>'s `` honest broker'' approach to sifting through competing policy options. He is <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s intermediary to interest groups, members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and government agencies that want to sell their side of a given issue. He also gives speeches on administration policy, with a methodical style recalling his days as a Rhodes scholar and professor of government and politics at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Oxford </LOCATION>. But his low-key image belies a tough-minded dealer who is fiercely protective of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s interests, associates say. `` I found <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> to be cautious. He likes you to verify everything,'' said <PERSON> Dewey </PERSON> <PERSON> Stokes </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Fraternal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Order </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION>, who sought <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s support for a waiting period and background check for gun purchasers. That idea was rejected. And under <PERSON> Porter </PERSON>'s guidance, other ideas for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s much-proclaimed `` kinder, gentler'' <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> have been muted along the way. As the administration point man at the education summit with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and the nation's governors, <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> ensured joint endorsement of results-oriented education without committing <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to specific spending. While he led the administration's drive for a new clean air package that went well beyond President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s stringency, it did n't quite measure up to the aspirations of environmental groups. Perhaps because he tries to give <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a balanced view of all viable policy options, <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> is seen by some as a weaker adviser than might be expected of his position. One White House colleague said <PERSON> Porter </PERSON>'s effectiveness is dampened by White House Chief of Staff <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON>'s unquestioned dominance, making it impossible for <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> to assume a larger role. Asked if that is true, <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> says he is `` quite happy to be part of a collegial effort.'' `` I do n't go out and do things that I'm not going to discuss with him, but he gives me a lot of latitude,'' he said, referring to <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON>. <PERSON> Porter </PERSON>, who often spends the night in his White House office, admits to being a workaholic and `` a bit of a perfectionist.'' `` I have never regretted the extra effort. ... I know I'm not going to be doing this for the rest of my life,'' he said. `` I view it as a rare opportunity.'' His introduction to the White House came Aug. 9, 1974. Arriving from <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> to start work as a White House fellow, <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> recalls, he ran into his new boss, then-Vice President <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>, at the elevator. <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> greeted him somewhat distractedly and headed off to his historic final Oval Office meeting with <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> recalled. Later that day, a <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> aide assigned <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> to be the secretary of <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>'s transition team. He helped write a report based on interviews with all the Cabinet members and senior players in government. Under <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> had a variety of jobs including special assistant to the president and executive secretary to the <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Policy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. During the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration he also held several <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> jobs, including director of the Office of Policy Development. Porter me <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> over tennis, a game for which both share a passion and considerable skill. <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> had just named <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to be his <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> director and invited both men to play on the White House courts. <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> says he can tell a lot about a person from his tennis game. About <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, he said: `` One thing I look for is how they call the lines ... In all the time I've played with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> over a 15-year period, I have never once had occasion to question his line calls. He is scrupulously honest.'' Other <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> tennis traits, <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> said, are patience, persistence and strategy, reflecting a methodical approach in how he approaches other things as well.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891227-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-27-89 0143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Stealth-Panama     12-27 0244</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Stealth-Panama,250</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stealth Fighter Passes its First Combat Test</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Pentagon says the Stealth fighter passed its first combat test during the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> military intervention by hitting its targets in a raid on a field outside a Panamanian military barracks. `` The mission was successful,'' spokesman <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said Tuesday, telling reporters that the F-117 aircraft's sophisticated bombs `` precisely hit their targets.'' Asked whether the F-117's had any other role in the intervention, the spokesman said, `` No, that was the sole mission. Others were considered but they were discarded.'' He declined to say what they were. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> also declined to say how many of the airplanes were involved or what kind of bombs they dropped. The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> on Saturday quoted unnamed government officials as saying they understood the plane was tapped for the job of bombing hideouts of Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> before he could get away. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> repeated earlier <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> statements that the objective of the Stealth plane was `` not to hit the barracks, but rather, in fact, the mission was to miss the barracks and hit the field _ and by nature of the explosion, disorient and stun and confuse and frighten, frankly,'' the Panamanian soldiers. `` I'm told that the F-117 hit it very precisely and that it was the precision of the F-117's bombing capability that was the reason it was used,'' he said. `` I do n't know how much of a factor the stealthiness was,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891227-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-27-89 0115EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     12-27 0026</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0025</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Up In Tokyo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 38,801.63, up 120.32 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Wednesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891227-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-27-89 0145EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BatteredWife     12-27 0874</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Battered Wife,0899</SECOND>
<HEAD>Attorneys Say Wife's Murder Acquittal a Victory for Battered Wife
Defense</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONG BEACH, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
