<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890307-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-89 2336EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Mayor'sRace 3rdLd-Writethru a0830 03-07 0618</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mayor's Race, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0830,0630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Socialist Mayor's Party Wins Mayoral Contest</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 16th graf, ``In about ...,'' to UPDATE number of towns
voting on death-penalty resolution.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BURLINGTON, Vt. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Four-term socialist Mayor <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanders </PERSON>' party won another victory Tuesday, as former community development director <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Clavelle </PERSON> defeated <PERSON> Alderman </PERSON> <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Chioffi </PERSON> to become <PERSON> Sanders </PERSON>' successor <PERSON> Clavelle </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Progressive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> candidate, had 5,626 ballots, or 52 percent of the vote, to 4,400, or 41 percent, for Democrat <PERSON> Chioffi </PERSON>, a store owner who also had Republican backing, according to unofficial results. Sanders _ often billed as the nation's only socialist mayor _ had decided against another term. <PERSON> Clavelle </PERSON> shies away from the socialist label, but ran under the banner of <PERSON> Sanders </PERSON>' party. `` Today was a referendum on Progressive government, and we won it,'' <PERSON> Clavelle </PERSON> told a throng of 150 supporters. He said he would continue to push most of <PERSON> Sanders </PERSON>' platform, which includes affordable housing and public access to the <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Champlain </LOCATION> waterfront. Also in the race were Greens party candidate <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Baird </PERSON> and `` tax revolt'' candidate <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Hackett </PERSON>. <PERSON> Baird </PERSON> received 596 votes, or 5 percent, and <PERSON> Hackett </PERSON> 91, or slightly less than 1 percent. Cold weather, which brought the wind chill factor to 43 degrees below zero Tuesday morning, may have kept some of the city's 25,000 registered voters away from the ballot box. <PERSON> Jo </PERSON> <PERSON> Lamarche </PERSON>, secretary to City Clerk <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Rader </PERSON>, said turnout was below average in the city of 38,000. The Progressives' success once again deprives the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> of the mayor's seat, which Democrats have not held since <PERSON> Sanders </PERSON> beat longtime incumbent <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Paquette </PERSON> by 10 votes in 1981. <PERSON> Sanders </PERSON> said the win was significant because it showed the Progressives' strength. `` It's not a one-man show, it's a movement,'' he said. `` That's what we've accomplished tonight. He said <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> voters have been demoralized by the political process. `` People look to the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, they do n't see anything. They look to the Republicans, and they do n't see anything. There is one city in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> that has said we can go beyond staus quo politics, we can talk real issues to the people, we can have a dream of a city and a state and county that is fundamentally different than it is now,'' <PERSON> Sanders </PERSON> said. The 47-year-old mayor, who is known for railing against the rich and powerful, decided in the fall to leave politics to teach and write. With a promise to fight for the underdog, the <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, native was elected in 1981 by 10 votes over a Democrat. He was re-elected three times by more comfortable margins, winning in 1987 with 6,901 votes to 5,594 votes. Even <PERSON> Sanders </PERSON>' critics give him credit for reinvigorating city politics. <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> and World Report rated him in 1987 as one of the nation's 20 best mayors. <LOCATION> Burlington </LOCATION> has prospered and has been ranked highly in national quality-of-life surveys. Elsewhere around <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> it was Town Meeting Day, and residents braved the cold to travel to their town halls and approve school budgets and socialize with friends and neighbors not seen for a year. In nearly 70 towns, residents voted on a non-binding resolution asking the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> to reinstate the death penalty, last used in the 1950s. At least 45 towns supported capital punishment, but 18 rejected or tabled it. One town that voted down the resolution cited the recent film, `` The Thin Blue Line,'' which suggests that an innocent man faced the death penalty in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Two years ago, about 30 towns took up the question, and two-thirds voted for reinstatement, said Republican Rep. <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheltra </PERSON>, a proponent of capital punishment and major force behind the town meeting resolution.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890307-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-89 0038EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PizzaConnectionII     03-07 0256</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pizza Connection II,0262</SECOND>
<HEAD>Some Charges Dismissed After Judge Blasts Prosecutors</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN M. DOYLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal judge Monday dismissed charges against half of the 14 defendants in a massive, mob-linked drug conspiracy trial, finding prosecutors failed to prove their case because of `` ineptitude.'' `` If these drug dealers are walking free it's because you people are not competent,'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sprizzo </PERSON> told protesting prosecutors as he dismissed narcotics conspiracy charges against seven defendants in the Pizza Connection II drug trial. `` You let them go,'' <PERSON> Sprizzo </PERSON> told prosecutors later in the day. `` Do n't lay at my feet your ineptitude.'' The judge then barred lawyers from talking to reporters about the case. <PERSON> Sprizzo </PERSON> dropped the drug conspiracy charge after the government finished presenting its case and defense lawyers, contending the charge was too broad, made routine requests for the dismissal of charges for lack of evidence. The trial, which began last October, is a spinoff from the original, 17-month-long Pizza Connection drug trial, so named because prosecutors accused the defendants of using pizzerias in the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Northeast </LOCATION> as fronts for their heroin dealing and money-laundering conspiracy. Eighteen of the 19 defendants in the first Pizza Connection trial were convicted. The 14 defendants in the Pizza Connection II case were accused of participating in a massive conspiracy to distribute heroin, cocaine and marijuana. Some also were charged with possession of drugs with intent to distribute. The seven remaining defendants face maxiumum penalties of life in prison if convicted.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890307-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-89 0028EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Jackson 2ndLd-Writethru a0755 03-07 0827</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Jackson, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0755,0846</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jackson Hit By Fellow Dems For Anti-Daley Campaign</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 4 grafs after 12th graf, ``Jackson identifies ...,''
to UPDATE with Jackson letter; picks up 13th graf, `` Jackson backed ...''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BERNARD SCHOENBURG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> fasted for three days because he hungers for the defeat of Democratic mayoral nominee <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Daley </PERSON>, but some Democrats say <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s efforts are straining the two-time <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> presidential contender's party credentials. `` What kind of credibility does that give <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> nationwide with other Democrats?'' asks <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> party Chairman <PERSON> Vince </PERSON> <PERSON> Demuzio </PERSON>. `` This is certainly not going to bode well for <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> nationally if he has any future ambitions, which I'm sure he does.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> backed Mayor <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON> in the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> primary won last week by <PERSON> Daley </PERSON>, but that was because his candidate of choice _ <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alderman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Timothy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Evans </ORGANIZATION> _ sat out the primary in favor of a third-party bid in the April 4 general election. The attack on <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s party credentials is only the latest event in what has become an imbroglio in the politics of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>'s black community since <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON>, the city's first black mayor, died near the start of his second term in 1987 <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has tried to be a peacemaker, but his plea for unity among supporters of <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON> and <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> during the primary went unheeded. Now his position is at odds with the man <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> successfully backed to head the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, the first black to hold the top post, has announced his support of <LOCATION> Daley </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> McCurry </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> DNC </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. To top it off, Republicans have taken note of the black split in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and some see it as playing into the hands of new <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>, who is trying to lure disenchanted blacks to the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> says he is unfazed. `` In these contests, sometimes you win the votes and sometimes you do n't, but you must always preserve your dignity,'' he said Monday in a telephone interview while enroute from <LOCATION> Tuskegee </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION> `` What that <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> machine represents is a violation of people,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said of what he thinks would be a closed Democratic party under <PERSON> Daley </PERSON>. `` It strips them of their dignity.'' <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> denies that he represents the past or the politics of his father, the late Mayor <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Daley </PERSON>, who ran a vast patronage army. Young <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> talks, as do others, of unifying the city and giving all people opportunities. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> identifies the issue in his support of <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, running on the <ORGANIZATION> Harold </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> ticket, as `` reciprocity,'' meaning he wo n't support those who have n't supported him. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Marty </PERSON> <PERSON> Russo </PERSON>, D-Ill., a <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> ally who has criticized <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s opposition to the Democratic mayoral nominee, received a letter from <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> that requested a meeting, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> said later Monday `` If you are serious about unity in the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, I am perfectly willing to meet with you and <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> to discuss a similar deal,'' said the letter drafted by <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>. `` If I do run -LRB- for president -RRB- in 1992 will you support my candidacy as a favorite son? That is the basis of a reciprocal deal.'' <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> said the letter was `` kind of a rhetorical device.'' `` He's really not willing to talk to <PERSON> Daley </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> said. `` Rev. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> is supporting <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> backed a slate of <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cook </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> candidates last year, including <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> in his successful bid for a third term as county state's attorney. But he notes <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> did n't support him in his 1988 presidential bid and did n't endorse <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> in 1987. `` I reached out to <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> and endorsed him, and yet he seems to have no sense of obligation to be reciprocal or fair,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> denies that race is the only issue, although <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> is white and <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> is black. He says the issue is one of `` going forward'' instead of backwards. `` In <LOCATION> Daley </LOCATION>, there is relief for those who have a history of monopolizing; grief for those who've been locked out,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said Saturday at an Operation PUSH meeting where he also announced his three-day fast. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who was taking only liquids, planned to return to a normal diet on Tuesday. A mostly white coalition of aldermen elected <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON> over <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> a week after <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> died and many <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> supporters sat out last week's primary. <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON> got about half the votes <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> did from the city's 19 predominately black wards. Some political analysts say <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s run against the party's endorsed candidate in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> will have little bearing on his national standing `` It will certainly be used against him, but I think <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> politics is seen as.. a unique situation,'' <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Cavanagh </PERSON> director of <ORGANIZATION> Johns </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hopkins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s Center for the <ORGANIZATION> Study </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, said Monday `` People who like what he stands for probably wo n't care if he endorses the -LRB- Democratic mayoral -RRB- nominee or not.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890307-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-89 0039EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-Kennedy-Democrats     03-07 0360</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Kennedy-Democrats,0369</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kennedy Says Time Ripe For Democrats To Seize Ideological Initiative</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW HAVEN, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said Monday the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> is `` succumbing to the delusion'' that the old ways will still work, opening the door for Democrats to regain the ideological initiative. `` It is time for Democrats to become once again the party of ideas,'' the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Democrat said in a lecture at <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` Our opportunity now _ our responsibility _ is to ... to put forth a vision for the 1990s and beyond.'' The 1988 election, which he said was `` so apparently devoid of ideas,'' also revealed how important they are. The Republicans succeeded in defining the contest because `` there was no compelling Democratic message,'' he said. `` Competency was not enough,'' he said in a reference to the failed presidential campaign of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. `` Ideology, which is about ideas, was missing, and our opponents filled the gap ...'' `` If you do n't define yourself, your opponent will. That is very dangerous in life and devasting in politics,'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said at a news conference after his speech. `` The Republicans were able to define both Governor <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in a way I did n't recognize.'' The senator said the Democrats are now presented with a great opportunity because `` this <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> president _ and perhaps the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> _ have run out of ideas.'' `` The administraion has no agenda other than coping, no real budget, no major initiatives and very little to say about what <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> calls ` the vision thing,'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said. `` The administration holds office, but does n't know what to do with it,'' he said. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> `` ca n't live permanently off the legacy of <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> any more than Democrats can succeed by simply repeating <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> or <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. `` The other side is now succumbing to the delusion that did so much demage to Democrats in other days: They assume that old ways will continue to work, that they do n't have to rethink them, that they have won and will win if only they rerun the campaigns of the past.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890307-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-89 0242EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Norway-Second-Hand     03-07 0552</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Norway-Second-Hand,0569</SECOND>
<HEAD>Second-Hand Shops Flourish As Norway's Economy Slumps</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUG MELLGREN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OSLO, Norway (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A slumping economy is sending Norwegians on bargain hunts in junk shops and second-hand stores. When <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> oil wealth flowed, Norwegians spent freely in an economy that quickly became overheated, but the boom came to an abrupt end two years ago when oil prices plunged. `` Business is booming,'' said <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Andersen </PERSON>, who runs a <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> shop in the city of <LOCATION> Stavanger </LOCATION>. `` It's better than ever. So far this year sales are up 30 percent compared to last year. `` People come here looking for everything from used clothes to furniture. They're being more careful with their money. `` We just may run out of used merchandise. People seem to be holding onto their things. They make do with an old couch for another year or use an old dress another season.'' <LOCATION> Stavanger </LOCATION>, the nation's oil capital on the west coast, was hardest hit by the collapse of oil prices in 1986, but the drop in national income has squeezed the whole country. With its offshore oil fields pumping 1.44 million barrels a day, lower crude prices quickly chilled <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>'s overheated economy. Tough measures, including legislated wage controls, have helped reduce inflation and the trade deficit. But unemployment doubled in the last year to 4 percent, the highest since the 1930s, and thousands of businesses went broke. The government decisions, combined with a modest recovery of oil prices, hold out promise for the future, but it may take time before it is felt in the household budget. `` Many Norwegians may be willing to lower their standards a little compared to 1986,'' said <PERSON> Oddbjoern </PERSON> <PERSON> Eiden </PERSON>, an economist for the Confederation of Norwegian Business and Industry. He said consumer spending declined 1.6 percent in 1988 after dropping 2.7 percent in 1987. In 1986, the peak of the oil boom and spending spiral, consumption leaped 5.7 percent. `` It's hard to say why people would buy more used merchandise,'' said <PERSON> Oddbjoern </PERSON> <PERSON> Knutsen </PERSON> of the state Institude of Social Research. He said it was possible that Norwegians were simply returning to a normal state of affairs. `` I do n't think the spending spree of mid-1980s was typical. Oil resulted in an economic growth that was without equal in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>. And people spent money freely,'' he said. `` It's more typical of Norwegians to be careful with money. If they are indeed buying more used things and not discarding as much, then it seems we are returning to the cautious ways of the 1950s and 1960s, when <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> was not a rich nation.'' <PERSON> Arne </PERSON> <PERSON> Johansen </PERSON>, who works for <LOCATION> Oslo </LOCATION>'s five-store Elevator thrift shops, said he noticed an upswing in sales just after the economic slump began. `` We have n't noticed much of an increase since 1987 at any of our stores individually. Sales are pretty stable. But a lot more used merchandise shops have opened in <LOCATION> Oslo </LOCATION> during the past year or two,'' he said. `` Business is up,'' said <PERSON> Willy </PERSON> <PERSON> Olsen </PERSON>, who has owned <LOCATION> Oslo </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Willy </PERSON>'s Used Merchandise for 22 years `` But a lot of new stores have opened. There must be 10 that opened in the past two years.'' Twenty-nine thrift shops are listed in the telephone book for <LOCATION> Oslo </LOCATION>, a city of 425,000.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890307-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-89 0041EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-RebelCountry Bjt   03-07 0648</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rebel Country, Bjt,0665</SECOND>
<HEAD>Communist Rebels Operate Even In Marcos Homeland</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EILEEN GUERRERO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MARCOS, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Communist rebels have established a shadow government and are collecting taxes in this northern town named for the family of <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> _ a fierce anti-Communist during his 20-year rule. Local military and civilian officials say this town of 12,000 people that is 230 miles north of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> became a rebel stronghold after the former president fled to <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> in the 1986 military-civilian uprising that propelled <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> to power. `` In the time of <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, they were only in the mountains,'' Mayor <PERSON> Felicito </PERSON> <PERSON> Tamayo </PERSON> said of the rebel <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. `` Now they have been able to reverse that. It's as if the timing was great _ Communists entering and <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> leaving.'' <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> town is about 10 miles south of <PERSON> Sarrat </PERSON>, where the former president was born 71 years ago. The town's 13 outlying hamlets, most named for members of <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' family, have become gateways for guerrillas to slip down from the mountains into populous areas of <LOCATION> Ilocos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Norte </LOCATION> province. `` They just pass through,'' said <PERSON> Melecio </PERSON> <PERSON> Duldulao </PERSON>, 45, chief of the hamlet of <PERSON> Imelda </PERSON>, named for <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' wife. `` Occasionally, when they come at lunchtime, we ask them to join us. But that's all.'' <PERSON> Tamayo </PERSON> said the rebels have killed civilians, seized private property for their `` revolutionary agrarian reform'' and have forced businesses to pay protection money, or what they call `` revolutionary taxes.'' On March 1, army troops raided a 14-acre rebel training camp less than two miles from the town. The camp, which was abandoned, contained obstacle courses and a makeshift clinic. <PERSON> Tamayo </PERSON> said the rebel activity has created a climate of fear in the town which civilian and military officials appear powerless to stop. `` By 6 p.m., you should have already eaten and gone home,'' <PERSON> Tamayo </PERSON> said. `` Then make sure all the windows are closed.'' Townspeople say they try to remain neutral in the conflict but find themselves increasingly drawn into the cycle of violence. `` <PERSON> Cory </PERSON> arrived and the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> arrived,'' said <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Abrigado </PERSON>, wife of a town official. `` We are really having a hard time. We are afraid. If we see the -LRB- rebels -RRB-, we get scared. When we see the military we also get scared.'' <PERSON> Duldulao </PERSON> said the rebels began infilrating his hamlet, about a mile east of the town center, in 1984. Four years later, they killed <PERSON> Artemio </PERSON> <PERSON> Manguma </PERSON>, leader of the village security volunteers and a suspected military informant, he said. Several months later, rebels tied up <PERSON> Duldulao </PERSON> in front of his eight children but released him after his wife, <PERSON> Milagros </PERSON>, convinced them he had no links to the military. `` They have organized in the -LRB- village -RRB- level,'' said Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Bayani </PERSON> <PERSON> Fabic </PERSON>, northern <LOCATION> Luzon </LOCATION> commander. `` They have organized economic committees and are already collecting taxes.'' The army's 45th Infantry Battalion operates in the area, and <LOCATION> Fabic </LOCATION> has stepped up intelligence-gathering operations against the shadow governments, which he considers the principal threat. `` To us, the armed component is easy to control,'' <PERSON> Fabic </PERSON> said, referring to armed guerrillas. `` But to uproot the political structure of the shadow government, that is a very tedious process.'' Rev. <PERSON> Rock </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonoan </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> archdiocese, said the church plays a leading role in mediating between the military and the rebels. He said priests often must defend parishioners accused by the military of sympathizing with the rebels, whose insurgency is 20 years old. `` Most of them are victims in this war,'' <PERSON> Bonoan </PERSON> said. `` People are branded Communist rebels even before they become one.'' Last May, gunmen who <PERSON> Bonoan </PERSON> said were believed to be soldiers massacred a family of five in the nearby town of <LOCATION> Vintar </LOCATION>. No one was arrested, he said. `` That has added to the people's dissatisfaction and demoralization with the government,'' <PERSON> Bonoan </PERSON> said. `` They have lost confidence in the government.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890307-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-89 0243EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BRF--OnlyLaundry     03-07 0182</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Only Laundry,0185</SECOND>
<HEAD>Regulations Force Town's Only Laundry to Close</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIO, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Residents left high and dry when this town's only coin-operated laundry was forced to close over safety concerns now have to drive at least 15 miles to wash their clothes Others among the 50 or so Wash-Out customers travel 30 miles to do their laundry in other towns. `` I feel very badly if someone has to travel 32 miles to do a load of laundry,'' said <PERSON> Virginia </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> of the state Department of Natural Resources. `` On the other hand, I would feel a lot worse if someone contracted a disease that terminated their life.'' Authorities said <PERSON> Wash-Out </PERSON>'s owner, <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Morse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, used to allow waste water into a sewer near a neighboring nursing home. But he was told last year the state agency would not renew its permit if the laundry continued to dump water there. `` They're going to have to change the law, because if they do n't, you're not going to see a Laundromat in a small town,'' said <PERSON> Morse </PERSON>, who closed his 13-year-old business recently.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890307-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-89 0242EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-US-Math     03-07 0238</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-US-Math,0244</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chinese Pupils Better Than Americans At Math</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Chinese primary school pupils are far better at mathematics than <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> youngsters and are more organized and attentive in their studies, a study by experts from the two countries indicates. The study by the <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> surveyed pupils in 20 <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> schools and 11 <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> schools, the official <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> reported today. Professor <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> <PERSON> Ge </PERSON> of the Chinese academy's <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Psychology </ORGANIZATION> said in a report on the study that said one reason the Chinese outshined the Americans was that American textbooks teach less about fractions, ratios, proportion and decimals than Chinese textbooks. She also said Chinese teachers spend more time on math, and that general math concepts are taught earlier in Chinese than American schools. Ms. <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> noted that <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> children spend half their class time without leadership `` and are more likely to be engaged in inappropriate activities than Chinese students.'' American students spent less than half the time on assigned tasks as Chinese children, and <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> children pay less attention to their teachers, the paper quoted her as saying. Ms. <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> added that <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> children may be under greater social pressure to succeed because passing national examinations to get into good schools is directly related to their future jobs. The report did not provide figures on how the two groups scored in the math tests.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890307-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-89 0241EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Rats     03-07 0669</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rats,0691</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rats Flourish In Britain's Mild Winter</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BARR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Wintertime, and the living is easy in the kingdom of Rattus norvegicus, the common brown rat which has become uncommonly numerous around <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. Complaints about rats are up as much as 70 percent in parts of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, which has had just a touch of slush during a very mild winter. Similar increases have been reported in <LOCATION> Bristol </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Manchester </LOCATION> and other large cities. `` I've never, never known such a year,'' said <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> <PERSON> Slater </PERSON>, chief environmental services officer of <ORGANIZATION> Babergh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> northeast of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. `` I have n't had a Saturday off since the end of November.'' <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Foster </PERSON>, health officer for the <ORGANIZATION> Mid-Suffolk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, said he received 1,323 rat complaints last winter. This year, he had matched that total by late December _ before winter had officially begun. <ORGANIZATION> Rentokil </ORGANIZATION>, one of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s largest exterminators, has doubled its sales of poisons this winter, said <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Bateman </PERSON>, the company's director of public relations With the increase in rats, there has been a growing concern about <PERSON> Weil </PERSON>'s disease, which is spread by rat urine in water. The ailment used to be seen mostly in miners and sewer workers, but cases have cropped up among water skiers and canoeists. The reasons for the rat's prosperity are various. `` We've had mild winters before, without having more rats,'' said <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> <PERSON> Twigg </PERSON>, retired senior lecturer in Zoology at <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Holloway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION> and author of scholarly books on vermin. `` Certainly in towns, one aspect of it is the lack of good hygiene,'' said <PERSON> Twigg </PERSON>, who has done research on rats in coal mines and <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> canefields. `` It's one of those things, a general lack of attention. This country is pretty scruffy,'' he said. <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the Institution of Environmental Officers, said decaying Victorian sewage systems in big cities have contributed to the problem. She also blamed the illegal dumping of garbage, and the spread of fast-food restaurants. Efforts to poison rats have been frustrated by the rich menu of trash and debris, especially from fast-food restaurants, said <PERSON> Angela </PERSON> <PERSON> Moon </PERSON>, environmental health officer for the borough of Lambeth in south <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. `` They would rather eat that than our poison,'' she said. The sewers, at least, have their defenders. `` There have been a lot of stories around recently, a story which comes up year after year after year, that rat populations are increasing and sewers are decaying. I just say: prove it,'' said <PERSON> Brigette </PERSON> <PERSON> Daniels </PERSON>, spokeswoman for Thames Water, which is responsible for a thousand miles of sewers in and around <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. If there are more rats about, she said, `` we believe they are above-ground rats.'' In <LOCATION> Bristol </LOCATION>, an industrial city in western <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, the sewers are taking the blame without dispute. `` The sewers are crumbling because of lack of upkeep, and the rats are finding it increasingly easy to get out,'' said <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Archer </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Bristol </LOCATION>'s assistant chief environmental health officer. `` Also, there is a great deal of redevelopment going on, and if the drains are not properly sealed when the old buildings are knocked down the rats can find their way up them and appear, to everyone's horror, on the nice piece of landscaped garden outside the gleaming new office blocks.'' <PERSON> Archer </PERSON> said his rat-control budget has not been increased in three years, and nine of 54 positions in his department are vacant. `` We can control rats in two ways _ by blocking up the holes in the sewers so that they can not get out, and by poisoning them. We want to do both, but the government's spending limits mean that we can not do either properly,'' he said. <PERSON> Twigg </PERSON> dismissed stories in the tabloid press which have claimed that a `` super rat'' has emerged from the sewers. He recalled coal miners telling him about big rats, rats big enough to enter in a dog show, and the sage insight of one miner: `` No one ever sees a small rat.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890307-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-89 0240EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Britain-Moslems     03-07 0993</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Moslems,1026</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rushdie Case Reveals Gap Between Europeans, Moslem Minorities</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 The furor over <PERSON> Salman </PERSON> <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>'s novel `` The Satanic Verses'' highlights a gulf between <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and its Moslem minorities. Here is a report from an English city with a large Moslem community.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By MAUREEN JOHNSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BRADFORD, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON>'s Moslems invited <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Pickles </PERSON>, leader of the city council, to a public burning of `` The Satanic Verses'' and were surprised when he refused. The incident illustrates the gap <PERSON> Salman </PERSON> <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>'s novel opened between <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and its minority Moslems _ between men like <PERSON> Sher </PERSON> <PERSON> Azam </PERSON>, spiritual leader of <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON>'s 60,000 Moslems, and Pickles, the Anglo-Saxon businessman to whom he extended the invitation. <PERSON> Azam </PERSON>, born in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> 48 years ago, was equally offended by British outrage at the book-burning. `` We were left with even more hurt and frustration,'' he said. `` The publicity we got was that Moslems are doing something not in line with <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> culture and tradition.'' Pickles, 36, said: `` They were genuinely surprised I would n't go. That burning book brought back all kinds of images of repression, in particular <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> in the'30s. ... It's an obscene act.'' The protest Jan. 14 in this north <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> city of 500,000 people was widely publicized in Moslem countries. Some analysts believe it began the international crisis in which Iranian spiritual leader <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> ordered <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> killed, driving the author him into hiding. Outraged Moslems say `` The Satanic Verses'' blasphemes Islam by portraying the prophet <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON>'s wives as prostitutes and suggesting he wrote the holy Koran rather than receiving it directly from Allah. Like most Bradford Moslems of his generation, <PERSON> Azam </PERSON> arrived from <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> in the 1950s to work in a textile mill. He now heads a chain of Moslem-run supermarkets and is president of the <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mosques </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Bradford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> organization. From book burning in <LOCATION> Bradford </LOCATION> to pro-Khomeini demonstrations in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, the uproar over `` The Satanic Verses'' has increased the alienation of <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s 5 million Moslems. Officials in <LOCATION> Ravenna </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, ordered increased security around a monument to <PERSON> Dante </PERSON> <PERSON> Alighieri </PERSON> on Sunday after a group threatened to blow it up because the medieval poet's famed `` Divine Comedy'' places the prophet <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> in hell. The main Moslem communities are <LOCATION> Turkish </LOCATION> immigrants in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, who have made no significant protest about <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>'s book; <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africans </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>; and Pakistanis and Indians in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. Firebombs have been thrown at two mosques in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and there are fears of a religious and racial backlash against Moslems. <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mosques </ORGANIZATION> is on the edge of the <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> quarter and has been under discreet police guard since intruders broke in last month and left a message: `` Leave Rushdie Alone.'' Most government and intellectual comment has focused on <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>'s right of free speech, but the affair has racial undertones and has revived calls for stricter curbs on Third World immigration `` It is becoming disturbingly clear that immigrants, anyhow from Islamic countries, are going to constitute the biggest concentration of religious fanaticism ... this country has experienced for many centuries,'' <PERSON> Peregrine </PERSON> <PERSON> Worsthorne </PERSON>, editor of the conservative <ORGANIZATION> Sunday </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION>, wrote in a signed editorial. <PERSON> Jean-Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Pen </PERSON>, president of the extreme-right <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, said the controversy reflects `` exactly what I am afraid of for <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, namely the invasion of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> by Moslem immigrants.'' Conservatives like <PERSON> Worsthorne </PERSON> say British liberals are reaping the harvest of their multicultural doctrines, which hold that ethnic minorities should be free to preserve their cultures rather than blending into the society. Commentator <PERSON> Auberon </PERSON> <PERSON> Waugh </PERSON> pointed to the irony of <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> enjoying the protection of a government he has likened to a police state and the police he has denounced as racist. `` He should pay for any police protection he may judge advisable,'' <PERSON> Waugh </PERSON> wrote in the conservative weekly Spectator. <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> was born in <LOCATION> Bombay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, of Moslem parents but now is a British citizen. `` The Satanic Verses'' was published in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> last fall. Liberal intellectuals, among whom <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> is prominent, have united with <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, the Conservative prime minister who ordinarily is their favorite hate figure, in defense of free speech. The opposition <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> also joined it, but notes that Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s record includes banning broadcast interviews with members of the outlawed <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> and spending millions on law suits to suppress `` Spycatcher,'' the memoirs of a retired intelligence agent. `` They -LRB- the government -RRB- are total hypocrites,'' Labor foreign affairs spokesman <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaufman </PERSON> said in an interview. `` They've spent the last several years suppressing freedom of speech in every way they can. Labor also has been accused by some of its own supporters of pulling its punches for fear of losing Moslem votes. Many British Moslems consider speeches by <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> ministers about democratic values and civilized behavior insensitive at best and at worst intolerant. `` Those who wish to make their home in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, to contribute to our society and to prosper within it, can not deny to others the very freedoms which drew them to this country,'' Education Secretary <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said at a political meeting in <LOCATION> Bradford </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Liaqat </PERSON> <PERSON> Hussain </PERSON>, one of <PERSON> Azam </PERSON>'s deputies, responded: `` They are turning the attention of the British public against the Moslem people.'' Former Mayor <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Ajeeb </PERSON>, the first non-white to run a British city, said: `` A form of racism manifests itself in times of tension and that's what is happening now,'' In one view, the <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> affair is a power struggle between fundamentalists and secularized Moslems. Some Islamic religious leaders have supported <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s death call and none has publicly rejected it. Moderate Moslems are embarrassed and fear association with a fundamentalist image that equates in many West European minds with hostage-taking, airline bombings and keeping women in veils. Pickles said of the situation in <LOCATION> Bradford </LOCATION>: `` We've done all right so far over this ... but if something happens to Mr. <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>, then we could be in trouble.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890307-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-89 0239EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-FoodSmugglers     03-07 0237</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Food Smugglers,0243</SECOND>
<HEAD>Polish Border Authorities Block More Than 3,000 Food Smugglers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 3,000 Poles have recently been caught trying to smuggle food into <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> to sell at a profit, the official <ORGANIZATION> PAP </ORGANIZATION> news agency reported. In one case, a Pole tried to smuggle a goat and a baby pig into <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Zygmunt </PERSON> <PERSON> Janczyk </PERSON>, spokesman for the main customs office, was quoted as saying. `` We will fight this negative phenomenon until it vanishes completely,'' <PERSON> Janczyk </PERSON> was quoted as saying in the report Monday. <ORGANIZATION> PAP </ORGANIZATION> did not say during what period of time the offenders were caught by customs officials. <ORGANIZATION> PAP </ORGANIZATION> did not say during what period of time the offenders were turned back. Communist authorities on Jan. 1 eased procedures to obtain passports and thousands of Poles have headed West to trade, mainly to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> where visas are not required. <PERSON> Janczyk </PERSON> said Poles were allowed to take enough food for their journey, but a 300 percent customs duty is charged on any excessive amount. He said some Polish passengers on a train en route to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> threw food away when they saw customs officers approach. Trading in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> is tempting to Poles because they can buy goods in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> for zlotys, sell them for hard currency in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> and then convert that money back into zlotys at the black-market rate for a profit.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890307-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-89 0214EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--NightStalker     03-07 0165</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Night Stalker,0168</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Defense Attorney Appointed</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A judge who rejected a defense lawyer's claim of stress as the basis for a mistrial has added an attorney to help represent `` Night Stalker'' defendant <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON>. Superior Court Judge <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Tynan </PERSON> announced Monday he had appointed <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> as co-counsel in the serial 1985 murder case that took six months to select a jury. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> will assist <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> and <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON>, no relation, in the defense of <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON>, 29, a drifter from <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON> is charged with 13 slayings and 30 related felonies in a string of nighttime attacks that terrified <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> in the summer of 1985. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> has been the lone defense attorney since last July when <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> left the case without explanation. <PERSON> Tynan </PERSON> ordered him back to court after <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> threw the case into turmoil two weeks ago by reporting he was suffering from nervous exhaustion and needed a six-week break to recuperate.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890307-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-89 0055EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Immigration-Nelson     03-07 0375</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Immigration-Nelson,0388</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: Immigration Commissioner Alan Nelson Being Ousted</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Immigration and <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> Commissioner <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> will be replaced as part of a `` major turnover'' in the administration intended to reflect President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s priorities and views, the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said. Despite a concerted effort by <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> to hold onto his job, the search for his replacement is under way, the newspaper said in Tuesday editions. <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> presided over the government's massive program to give legal status to illegal aliens. The report came in the wake of a recent <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> audit that was highly critical of <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> management practices, citing such problems as missing documents, massive backlogs of cases and failure to conduct background checks on many applicants for citizenship. In addition, <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> has been criticized for the agency's plan to dig a four-mile-long ditch on the <LOCATION> Mexico-California </LOCATION> border near <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> to deter smuggling. Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON>, whose department oversees the <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION>, wants to bring `` new blood'' to the agency, the Times said. The president indicated `` he would like to see major turnover of people in the Administration to reflect his views and priorities,'' a <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> source told the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. `` The attorney general has been engaged in the process of interviewing people for major positions,'' said spokesman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON>. `` No determination has been made with regard to <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION>.'' No decision on a replacement is expected this month, the Times said. Administration sources said several people have been mentioned as possible successors to <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, but no front-runner has emerged. `` We're not in a position to confirm or deny that. To the best of my knowledge, he has not been told that. I just talked to him,'' said <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>'s chief spokesman, <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Leo </PERSON>. The report that <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> was being ushered out was no surprise to several immigrant rights activists. `` There are enough people out there who want him out to start a club,'' said <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Moreno </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Mexican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> and Educational Fund. <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> attorney who took over the job in 1982, oversaw implementation of the landmark 1986 immigration reform law and was sharply criticized by alien advocates who said he was slow in informing the public about the measure's provisions.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890307-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-89 0224EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Italy-Fashions     03-07 0517</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Italy-Fashions,0531</SECOND>
<HEAD>Milan Presents A Cozy, Sporty Look</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANIELA PETROFF</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Fashion Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MILAN, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The 1989-1990 winter look _ Italian style _ is a cozy combination of soft fabrics and casual styles. <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s top ready-to-wear designers, including <PERSON> Armani </PERSON> <PERSON> Versace </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ferre </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Krizia </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Fendi </PERSON>, <PERSON> Moschino </PERSON> <PERSON> Missoni </PERSON> and <PERSON> Biagiotti </PERSON>, are showing their winter wears during the five days of shows here. As the second day unfolded Monday, it became apparent that <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION> designers are not going to sacrifice wearability for creativity. Gone are the padded shoulders, frilly blouses, and short hip-hugging skirts, to be replaced by dropped sleeves, sporty sweaters, and lots and lots of pants. There are skirts as well, but except for <PERSON> Gianni </PERSON> <PERSON> Versace </PERSON>, who shocked the fashion crowd with a miniskirt so short it barely covered the derriere, designers opted for a classic knee length, or a comfortable mid-calf hemline. <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION> will always favor black, but the winter wear was also full of bright colors and prints for both day and night. Its a big season for message prints as well, with such slogans as `` very expensive'' appearing on a Moschino jacket, and the word `` fog'' written on the back of a gray cashmere dress by <PERSON> Biagiotti </PERSON>. Then there are the usual floral prints, this time inspired by rich velvet, geometric figures and letters, and the animal prints championed by <ORGANIZATION> Krizia </ORGANIZATION>. This year she dedicates her collection to the ferocious tiger, putting his stripes as well as his face and tail on sweaters and dresses alike. Speaking of animals, there is a runway battle going on between the conservationist designers, who are showing only fake furs this season, and those who can not abandon the luxurious feel of the real thing. Thus <PERSON> Giorgio </PERSON> <PERSON> Armani </PERSON> at his <ORGANIZATION> Emporio </ORGANIZATION> collection opened with a group of stuffed animals ranging from teddy bears to sables to introduce his new line of synthetic fun furs. The look-alikes were fashioned into elegant stoles and capes, full length coats, and sporty jackets. At the other end of the spectrum are the <ORGANIZATION> Fendis </ORGANIZATION>, who show their new fur collection today, but who are showing off their original ultra-light workmanship of humble skunks and squirrels as well as lofty sable and mink, throughout the week at their downtown Milan showrooms. In the accessory department, the big item is the long strand of beads in shiny stones or gold, somewhere between a designer jewelry rip-off and 1920's flapper beads. These beads can be worn casually by day, or decorate an otherwise simple black evening gown. <ORGANIZATION> Krizia </ORGANIZATION> even had strands twined around the collar of a lavish fur coat. Shoes this season are generally flat to go with the comfortable look of the clothes, with a rare spiked heel for more sophisticated evening wear. After a number of seasons of cropped boyish haircuts, designers are proposing women with manes of wild curly hair. If all hair growing lotions fail to produce the required length by October, chief Italian fashion pranster <PERSON> Franco </PERSON> <PERSON> Moschino </PERSON> offers a solution _ a curly blond wig, the same one the balding black mustachioed designer wears in his present ad campaign.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890307-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-89 0223EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--FatalFestival     03-07 0142</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Fatal Festival,0146</SECOND>
<HEAD>At Least 25 Die While Worshiping Destruction God</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At least 25 Hindu pilgrims were reported killed in a stampede and a separate building collapse during the Hindu festival that celebrates the birthday of <ORGANIZATION> Shiva </ORGANIZATION>, the faith's god of destruction Twenty people died Monday near <LOCATION> Patna </LOCATION>, capital of <LOCATION> Bihar </LOCATION> state, of suffocation during a stampede as people rushed to a shrine to worship, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> news agency reported. Five pilgrims died at <LOCATION> Ginar </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Gujarat </LOCATION> state in the partial collapse of a building containing a <ORGANIZATION> Shiva </ORGANIZATION> idol, news reports said. Millions of Hindus across <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> celebrated the festival, believing <ORGANIZATION> Shiva </ORGANIZATION> will ensure well-being. People rush to shrines on festival days to offer flowers in a ritual of worship, causing periodic stampedes because idols are normally located within enclosed spaces or rooms.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890307-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-89 0223EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Drugs-Parole     03-07 0387</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drugs-Parole,380</SECOND>
<HEAD>Drug Related Parole Violations to be Reported Sooner</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN SKORNECK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parole </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> is tightening its drug regulations on federal parolees who used to get up to three chances to slip up and use drugs before the commission heard about it. The previous policy `` stated that when any three violations occurred in a 12-month period, the probation officer did n't have to notify us until after the three violations occurred,'' said <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Marble </PERSON>, the commission's director of case operations and program development. `` Now we require it immediately,'' she said Monday. `` As soon as the first drug violation occurs, they have to notify us.'' The new procedures are effective immediately. Affected by the new rules are about 12,900 people on parole and 2,500 who were required to serve their full sentences less good time off, she said. The latter are under <ORGANIZATION> Parole </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> supervision until the end of their original sentences. They are supervised by about 2,220 probation officers. `` The reason that it's so important to find out immediately if these people are using drugs is because they commit criminal behavior to support their drug addiction,'' Ms. <PERSON> Marble </PERSON> said. `` It's a very expensive habit and they have to get the money for it somewhere,'' she said. `` Most of them do n't have jobs or good enough jobs to pay for the drugs, and it's important to get those people off the streets to protect the public.'' Parolees who have had a history of drug abuse `` are required to submit to urinalysis, to participate in drug counseling sessions and, on occasion, to be placed in an inpatient drug treatment program,'' Ms. <PERSON> Marble </PERSON> said. Not all parolees found to have used drugs, missed a counseling appointment or failed or refused to submit a urine sample would be sent back to prison, she said. The commission has a range of options from returning the parolee to prison immediately after a hearing to sending him to a community-based drug-treatment center, she said. Ms. <PERSON> Marble </PERSON> estimated that 50 percent of federal prisoners are confined for drug charges _ drug dealing to money-laundering _ but these rules are aimed at those among them who use drugs. The new procedures were approved by the commission 7-0 at a Feb. 8 meeting but not announced until Monday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890307-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-89 0222EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ScotusRdp     03-07 0665</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus Rdp,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Refuses to Intervene in Corporal Punishment Case</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES H. RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Conflicts are sure to continue among the nation's courts over the use of corporal punishment in public schools due to the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s reluctance to address the issue. The court on Monday refused, without comment, to review a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> law that permitted two kindergarten girls to be paddled severely for snickering. Lawyers for the girls cited <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> studies indicating that 30,000 American schoolchildren are physically injured each year `` because of the infliction of corporal punishment to a degree that requires medical treatment.'' Their appeal said those studies estimate `` at least 100,000 children develop emotional and learning disabilities from excessive and inappropriate school punishment each year.'' The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prevention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Child </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Abuse </ORGANIZATION> also urged the justices to hear arguments in the case. But the court left unresolved whether the Constitution affords any protection against corporal punishment by teachers and school administrators. Left intact is a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> law that allows the use of all necessary corporal punishment, short of deadly force. The 5th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> upheld the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> law, but other federal appeals courts have made it easier for schoolchildren to sue in such cases. For example, the 10th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> ruled in a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> case that `` at some degree of excessiveness or cruelty'' such punishment violates constitutional rights. The justices in 1977 ruled that public school disciplinary measures involving physical force do not amount to `` cruel and unusual punishment'' banned by the Constitution's Eighth Amendment. While the decision barred students from suing teachers and school administrators in federal court over alleged Eighth Amendment violations, it left them free to sue in state courts under state laws. The 1977 decision left it unclear whether corporal punishment ever may violate the Constitution's 14th Amendment that protects due process rights. The case the court turned aside Monday came from <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, where on May 6, 1987, <ORGANIZATION> Crystal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cunningham </ORGANIZATION>, 5, and <PERSON> Ashley </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, 6, were paddled twice _ once by their school principal and once by their teacher. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruno </PERSON>, the principal at <ORGANIZATION> Westside </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kindergarten </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, saw the two girls snickering in the hall and gave each child two swats on the buttocks with a wooden paddle. When the girls returned to the classroom, teacher <PERSON> Rosa </PERSON> <PERSON> Cook </PERSON> saw them still snickering. She took the girls into the hallway and gave each three more swats across the buttocks with a wooden paddle. Each girl missed six days of school. The lawsuit filed in their behalf said the reason for their absence was `` severe pain'' and fear of returning to school. According to court documents, both girls were taken to a child welfare office where social workers who examined the paddling bruises said the two had been subjected to child abuse. The children's federal lawsuit _ dismissed by a judge _ sought monetary damages in alleging the girls were victims of conduct that was `` excessive, brutal, disproportionate to the circumstances -LRB- and -RRB- shocking to the conscience.'' In other action Monday, the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>: _ Ruled that people accused of drunken driving usually have no right to a jury trial if they face a jail term of no more than six months The court said unanimously in a <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> case that states do not violate fair-trial rights by treating drunken driving as a petty offense not warranting trial by jury. _ Rejected an appeal by Northeastern states seeking to force the federal government to crack down on acid rain and other pollution they say is caused by factories and power plants in other states _ Agreed to review the fines imposed against four <LOCATION> Yonkers </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, councilmen for defying a federal judge's order to adopt a housing desegregation plan _ Agreed to decide in a case from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state whether a prison inmate is entitled to a court hearing and other constitutional safeguards before being forced to take anti-psychotic drugs
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890307-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-89 0123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     03-07 0026</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0025</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Up In Tokyo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 31,937.94, up 61.08 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Tuesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890307-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-89 0237EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Panama     03-07 0609</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Panama,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Crisis in Relations Drags on; Election Seen as Rigged</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With the prospect of a rigged election perpetuating the rule of <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, administration officials and other experts see little hope of any thaw in U.S.-Panamanian relations. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s ruling coalition has selected a <LOCATION> Noriega </LOCATION> confidant, <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Duque </PERSON>, as the official candidate in the May 7 election, an indication that <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> intends to continue running the government from behind the scenes, much as he has for the past five years. This is causing headaches for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy makers, who see <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> as one of the major hemispheric issues facing the new administration, ranking alongside debt, drug trafficking and Marxist penetration of <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> as priority problems. A prime concern is the continued smooth functioning of the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION>. Almost nothing has gone right for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> since relations began to deteriorate in June 1987. A year ago, administration officials confidently predicted <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> would quickly fall after a series of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sanctions were imposed. But <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> commander who is under indictment in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> on drug smuggling charges, has survived the challenge, leaving <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials perplexed and divided on what to do next. Gen. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Woerner </PERSON>, the Panama-based commander of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, has taken the unusual step of going public with his concerns, suggesting that <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> is the beneficiary of a policy vacuum in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. There is virtually unanimous agreement among government and outside analysts that <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> is laying the groundwork for a fraudulent election. <PERSON> Woerner </PERSON> says <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> `` has been moving adroitly to manipulate'' the balloting against an opposition slate. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said last month that `` it is hard to imagine a free and fair election'' being carried out in an atmosphere of `` heavy-handed repression and intimidation.'' A report released last week by the <ORGANIZATION> Puebla </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, a lay <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> human rights group, said <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> denies basic civil liberties and that <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> allies control the electoral tribunal and voter lists and also are in charge of the balloting. <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>, who wrote a portion of the report, said there is a widespread expectation in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> that `` these elections will be the most fraudulent of all in a series of fraudulent elections'' in that country. <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Gershman </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S.-funded </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Endowment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democracy </ORGANIZATION>, said a huge majority of Panamanians oppose <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and they may be able use the election process to their advantage. <PERSON> Gershman </PERSON>, who returned recently from <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> could be weakened politically from the process if it exposes the depth of the sentiment against him. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> may be faced with a choice of calling off the election or engaging in massive fraud to ensure victory, leaving him in a difficult position both at home and internationally, <PERSON> Gershman </PERSON> said. Ambassador <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sosa </PERSON>, a captain of the anti-Noriega forces in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, agreed that <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> may have to confront that unhappy choice. `` Nobody believes the election will be a solution in the struggle,'' <PERSON> Sosa </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Sosa </PERSON> was appointed by ousted President <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> as ambassador, and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> continues to recognize both. In February 1988, <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> tried to fire <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> but instead was deposed by <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s allies hours later. Latin American democracies have kept a diplomatic distance from the Noriega-led government, and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has shunned virtually all dealings with it. This has created a variety of problems for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomats in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, including obtaining such mundane items as license plates and driver's licenses. To minimize hardship, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has sharply reduced its staff in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> and additional cuts are under consideration.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890307-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-89 0230EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-EspionageCase     03-07 0489</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Espionage Case,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Army Warrant Officer Asks Mercy After Pleading Guilty to Spy Charges</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID PACE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Army Warrant Officer <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> feels remorse for spying in behalf of <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact nations and hopes for clemency from the military judge before whom he pleaded guilty to 10 counts of espionage, his lawyer says. <PERSON> Vaughn </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>'s civilian counsel, said Monday that the 30-year-old <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> native is `` truly sorry for whatever damage he may have done to national security'' and will `` throw himself on the mercy of his military judge.'' Under a plea agreement, Hall can not receive the death penalty. <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> admitted during his court-martial Monday that he participated between 1983 and 1988 in a conspiracy to deliver classified military information to <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Col. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Eggers </PERSON>, the military judge presiding at the court-martial at <ORGANIZATION> Fort </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> McNair </ORGANIZATION> in southwest <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, will decide whether to accept <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>'s plea after hearing the prosecution's case and defense witnesses. Court officials said the final verdict and sentence probably would come Friday at the soonest. Hall, an intelligence analyst with a top-secret security clearance, was arrested Dec. 21 near <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, and accused of delivering film and documents dealing with communications intelligence and war plans to <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact nations. At the time of his arrest, <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> was assigned to the 24th Infantry Division and worked as an intelligence analyst in the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s G-2 intelligence section. He joined the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> in 1976 and spent most of his career in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> working as an analyst of intercepted radio and telephone traffic and coded messages. Hall pleaded guilty under an agreement that prohibits the government from seeking the death penalty. The maximum punishment he could receive is life in prison, forfeiture of all pay and allowances, dishonorable discharge and a fine. A still-secret part of the plea agreement outlines the sentence that Hall will receive unless the presiding judge, who is not permitted to see the sentencing agreement, imposes a lighter sentence. If the judge imposes a sentence that is harsher than the one in the agreement, the agreement will prevail. <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> waived his right to a grand jury-type hearing to determine if a court-martial was warranted and agreed to be tried by a single military judge rather than a panel of officers. He also agreed to submit to `` unlimited debriefing'' and polygraph examination by government officials and to testify, if called, at grand jury proceedings against <PERSON> Huseyin </PERSON> <PERSON> Yildirim </PERSON>, a Turkish-born, naturalized citizen to whom <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> allegedly passed the classified information. The plea agreement requires that Hall sign away any profits he might earn in the future from any publication based on his involvement in the espionage case. <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> said through a military spokesman that he would not comment on <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>'s motivation for passing classified information until after <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> has been questioned by <PERSON> Eggers </PERSON> during the closed part of the court-martial.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890307-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-89 0228EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Heflin-Tower     03-07 0479</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Heflin-Tower,470</SECOND>
<HEAD>Heflin no Stranger to Partisan Battles Over Presidential Appointments</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID PACE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The first <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Democrat to support Defense Secretary-designate <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON> has frequently sided with Republicans but also cast crucial votes against three of former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s nominees. Sen. <PERSON> Howell </PERSON> <PERSON> Heflin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> was <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s most consistent Democratic supporter in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, but he played a major role in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> rejection of <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> nominee <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bork </PERSON>. He also cast the deciding vote in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>'s rejection of two other <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> nominees, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> for the number three post in the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON> B. Sessions for a federal judgeship in south <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>. But <PERSON> Heflin </PERSON> on Monday announced that he would break ranks with his <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> colleagues and support Tower's confirmation. `` I will rely on his pledge and give him a chance to prove himself,'' <PERSON> Heflin </PERSON> said in a speech on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> floor, referring to Tower's promise to swear off drinking if he is confirmed to head the Pentagon. <PERSON> Heflin </PERSON> met privately with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for 45 minutes last week to discuss the Tower nomination. He said afterward that he believes a president's appointments should be confirmed unless it can be proven `` that the person is flawed or that he would be a detriment to the country.'' In Tower's case, <PERSON> Heflin </PERSON> said he was not convinced after reading the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> reports that the former <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> senator has a drinking problem that would disqualify him from serving in the nation's top military post. `` In reviewing all of the charges, I have concluded that his conduct in many areas is not applaudable and not without justifiable criticism, but on the other hand, not disqualifying,'' he said. <PERSON> Heflin </PERSON> also cited Tower's qualifications for the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> post and said that in the six years that he served with Tower in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, between 1978 and 1984, he never saw nor heard any evidence that Tower had a drinking problem. Had Tower been nominated for a lifetime judgeship, <PERSON> Heflin </PERSON> might well have voted against confirmation. But he said the since the secretary of defense serves at the pleasure of the president, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will be responsible and accountable for Tower's conduct. `` It is the president's cabinet,'' <PERSON> Heflin </PERSON> said, `` not <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' cabinet. <PERSON> Heflin </PERSON>, a 67-year-old ex-Marine and former <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> chief justice, was widely criticized in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> for his opposition to both <PERSON> Bork </PERSON> and Sessions, but neither vote appears to have caused him any lasting political damage. First elected to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in 1978 with more than 90 percent of the general election vote, <PERSON> Heflin </PERSON> was re-elected in 1984 with 63 percent of the vote against a conservative <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> opponent. His only announced challenger in 1990 is Republican state Sen. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Cabiness </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION>, a businessman who chaired the state's delegation to the Republican convention that nominated <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for president
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890307-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-89 0233EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SolarFlare     03-07 0413</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Solar Flare,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>Massive Flare from Sun Disrupts Communications, May Affect Satellites</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDs: May be topped.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One of the most intense solar flares since 1984 could still be making itself felt Wednesday by triggering the aurora borealis and giving faulty commands to satellites. The massive flare erupted Monday on the eastern edge of the sun, sending a burst of radiation that interfered with a navigation system and some communications, federal officials said. Officials expected havoc early today as a result of a burst of high-energy particles from the flare, which they said could affect some aircraft communication and television signals. Forecaster <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Kunches </PERSON> at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atmospheric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, said the flare was beyond the measuring capacity of the agency's GOES satellites. He estimated the solar eruption was the most powerful since April 1984. The flare, detected at 9:05 a.m. EST, affected the Loran navigation system of the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> and disrupted some short-wave radio communications. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Heckman </PERSON>, director of the <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION> center, said another effect, called a geomagnetic storm, may arrive at Earth about 9 a.m. EST Wednesday. A geomagnetic storm is a wave of magnetically charged particles smashing into the Earth's magnetic field, disrupting natural currents and triggering the aurora borealis, or northern lights. The storm also slightly heats the atmosphere, causing it to expand. This, in turn, can affect the flight paths of satellites in relatively low orbits. The geomagnetic storm, said <PERSON> Heckman </PERSON>, also could energize particles trapped in the Earth's magnetic field. If these particles hit a satellite, he said, it could cause the craft to receive stray signals or faulty commands. <PERSON> Heckman </PERSON> said the flare occurred on the eastern edge of the sun, which means that much of the radiation will not affect the <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> directly. The same area of the sun that spawned the flare, however, is rotating closer into view. `` Over the next two weeks we could more more vulnerable to more flares,'' he said. The sun goes through phases of intense activity. It passed a low point in 1986 and is now climbing toward an expected peak in intensity later this year or early in 1990. A flare occurs when energy stored by the sun's magnetic fields suddenly becomes unstable and is converted to heat and radiation within a few minutes, <PERSON> Heckman </PERSON> said. He said <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION> solar telescopes recorded a flare of particles rising some 70,000 miles from the surface of the sun.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890307-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-89 0648EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     03-07 0550</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0575</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BISMARCK, N.D. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A lawmaker wants the state to change its name to `` Dakota'' to project a simpler, warmer image, but one newspaper suggests officials should take a hint from their neighbor to the north. Sen. <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Mathern </PERSON> is sponsoring a resolution to drop `` North'' from the state's name, a change voters would have to approve. Supporters say `` North'' connotes a cold, harsh climate. <PERSON> Mathern </PERSON> told the state <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Constitutional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revision </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Monday that the adjective detracts from the word `` <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>,'' which means `` friend'' or `` ally'' in the <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> language. `` Dakota speaks to what we are most proud about, the wholesomeness and hospitality of our people,'' he said. Business also would appear to support the change, said state Tourism Director <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuglie </PERSON>. Telephone books in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>'s four largest cities list only 27 businesses with `` <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>'' in their name while 233 use `` <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>,'' he said. A <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> newspaper poked fun at the debate by sponsoring a contest to suggest a better name. The winner of The Billings Gazette contest was `` Manitscolda,'' pronounced `` Man-it's - cold-uh,'' an apparent takeoff on <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>'s northern neighbor The committee took no action on the resolutions.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEWPORT BEACH, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Crothers </PERSON> thought his pet lizard was a goner until he began hearing about sightings of a creature variously described by frightened residents as a 6-foot alligator or a diminuitive Godzilla. Then he knew that <PERSON> Cleopatra </PERSON>, his 3 -LCB- - foot Nile monitor lizard, was alive and leaping `` I had already supposed she was dead or someone had stolen her. But when I heard a few months ago about this thing people were seeing, I knew right away,'' he said. Animal control officers captured <PERSON> Cleopatra </PERSON> on Saturday after a resident reported seeing the lizard. <PERSON> Crothers </PERSON> no longer has room in his life for the reptile, though, so he sold the lizard to a woman for $ 75 on Sunday. `` I have a 10-month-old daughter and my wife does n't want it around the baby,'' he said. `` I do n't have the money to go buy it a new cage, and anyway, I ca n't keep pets at the apartment I have now. It's three strikes and you're out.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>FREDERICK, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Officials trying to reclaim city streets from flocks of messy birds have found an unlikely ally: brightly colored beach ball-sized balloons with huge, buggy eyes. `` Supposedly, they look like predators and the birds go somewhere else,'' Mayor <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said. Flocks of blackbirds, crows and other birds have been befouling sidewalks, cars and pedestrians in this city 45 miles west of <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>. `` I was learning how to do the two-step real well,'' said <PERSON> Bonnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Zimmerman </PERSON>, a secretary at city hall, which is surrounded by trees and has received a heavy bombing from the birds. Advice on how to solve the potentially unsanitary problem has been plentiful, ranging from mass poisonings to a community bird shoot. Officials seeking a bloodless solution tried electronic chirping devices and plastic owls without success. But since setting up about two dozen of the menacing ballooons, the birds have moved along and city workers have reclaimed park benches in front of city hall. `` We're crossing our fingers,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Strine </PERSON>, the city's director of public works `` The short-term results appear good.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890307-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-89 0321EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-PeaceNow     03-07 0662</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Peace Now,0687</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israel's Largest Peace Movement Under Attack</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RONI RABIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s largest peace movement has come under a new barrage of criticism from hawks and Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> is heading the attacks by questioning group members' loyalty to their country. <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s remarks Sunday that Peace Now activists are in cahoots with `` the most dangerous and extremist of our enemies'' triggered a barrage of accusations and counterattacks. Peace Now members, like all other <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> citizens, serve in the armed forces and do annual reserve duty. `` They are sabotaging <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s political war, the war for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s security ... They are helping the most dangerous and most extremist of our enemies,'' <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Tzahi </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanegbi </PERSON>, a member of <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s hard-line <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> bloc, agreed. `` At the height of the uprising when there are blood riots and Jews are being murdered, they -LRB- Peace Now members -RRB- go crawling toward the leaders of the uprising and break a rule that every self-respecting Jew abides, which is to wait for the government's decisions,'' <PERSON> Hanegbi </PERSON> said He was referring to the actions Saturday of thousands of Peace Now members, who tried to drive into the occupied territories to talk peace with Palestinians. The army, which bars political activity in the occupied areas, sealed the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and turned back activists headed to <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> villages. Underlying the attacks on Peace Now, however, is the group's controversial decision several months ago to change its stand toward the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> _ which right-wing circles still consider a terrorist organization dedicated to the destruction of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> _ and call on the government to talk peace with Chairman <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> The government refuses to negotiate with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>. Peace Now also favors territorial compromise. The loosely organized Peace Now does not keep membership rosters, and therefore has no clear estimate of its popularity. But scores of thousands of people turned up at a recent rally calling for talks with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>. On Monday, Foreign Minister <PERSON> Moshe </PERSON> <PERSON> Arens </PERSON> urged leftist legislator <PERSON> Yossi </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarid </PERSON> to cancel a scheduled trip to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> later this week for a <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> conference with <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> officials. `` This is an attempt to try and influence the -LRB- <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> -RRB- government, not through a debate in Parliament or through elections ... but through the foreign media and foreign governments,'' he said. `` This, to my mind, is something that should not be done.'' <PERSON> Yisrael </PERSON> <PERSON> Harel </PERSON>, a leader of the Gush Emunim Jewish settlement movement in the occupied territories, has accused Peace Now of running to talk with Palestinians while resisting talks with right-wing Israelis. `` The agenda should be that first we come to a national consensus, and then present that to the Arabs,'' <PERSON> Harel </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>, meanwhile, called Peace Now `` the most marginal of marginal elements,'' and added: `` They are n't worth the paper used to write on about them.'' Twenty legislators of left-wing parties and the center-left <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> signed a letter to the prime minister, demanding he retract the statements, made at a meeting of his right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> bloc. Peace Now activist and playwright <PERSON> Benny </PERSON> <PERSON> Barabash </PERSON> had harsh words for <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>, and accused him of `` starting a drive of incitement and bloodletting.'' He was referring to the 1983 murder of peace activist <PERSON> Emil </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenzweig </PERSON>, killed by a fellow Israeli who hurled a hand-grenade into an anti-war and Peace Now rally. Peace Now does not plan to give up its struggle. The movement was formed in 1978 as a pressure group to persuade then-Prime Minister <PERSON> Menachem </PERSON> <PERSON> Begin </PERSON> to make concessions for peace with <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>. A peace treaty was signed the following year, with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> returning the entire <LOCATION> Sinai </LOCATION> desert captured in 1967. Movement leaders feel the 15-month-old Palestinian uprising has created an historic opportunity for another peace settlement in the region. `` It's our job to prepare people's hearts for compromise,'' <PERSON> Barabash </PERSON> said. Some 399 Arabs and 17 Israelis have been killed in the Palestinian revolt against <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s 21-year occupation of the <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890307-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-89 0321EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ColoredWrap     03-07 0326</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Colored Wrap,0336</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reynolds Introducing Colored Plastic Wrap</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HILARY APPELMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RICHMOND, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 That green stuff you see the next time you open the refrigerator might not be last week's meatloaf. <ORGANIZATION> Reynolds </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Metals </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, the people who brought you <ORGANIZATION> Reynolds </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wrap </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Reynolds </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plastic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wrap </ORGANIZATION>, has introduced colored plastic wrap. The clear, clingy stuff will now be available in red, blue, yellow and yes, green. The company's advertising says the new wrap, which costs the same as its clear counterpart, `` makes the mundane task of wrapping leftovers fun.'' `` The addition of color gives an emotional appeal to plastic wrap, which in its clear form is considered purely a functional product,'' said <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> brand manager <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nims </PERSON>. <PERSON> Marabel </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, author of `` The Total Woman,'' who has advocated that women add excitement their marriages by greeting their husbands at the door wearing only in plastic wrap, says the colored wrap `` is a great idea. It would really add a lot of zip,'' she said in a telephone interview from her home in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. Crystal Color Plastic Wrap generated lots of enthusiasm in focus groups and simulated test markets, said <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Waring </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON>' consumer products division. `` Adding color to plastic wrap makes a useful product exciting,'' she said, noting that the same thing has been done to paper clips and rubber bands. The company will promote use of the colored wrap in crafts as well as food storage, Ms. <PERSON> Waring </PERSON> said Monday, and will have several special promotions around the holidays. Ms. <PERSON> Waring </PERSON> declined to speculate on the impact the colored wrap might have on sales or how much the new product, which has been in the works three to fours years, cost to develop. The consumer products division accounts for 10 percent of <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON>' sales, she said. In 1988, <ORGANIZATION> Reynolds </ORGANIZATION> reported a record net income of $ 482 million, or $ 8.35 per share, on revenues of $ 5.6 billion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890307-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-89 0244EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Japan-Markets     03-07 0313</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Markets,0321</SECOND>
<HEAD>Share Prices Recover, Dollar up</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
