<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890211-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-11-89 0104EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-S&amp;Ls Bjt   02-11 0626</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-S&amp;Ls, Bjt,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Savings and Loans Had Record Withdrawals in December</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Savings and loan customers withdrew a record $ 8.1 billion from their accounts in December, evidence, economists say, that the industry is being squeezed by higher interest rates. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, which regulates 2,955 federally insured savings and loans, said Friday that December marked the eighth consecutive month of net withdrawals, reversing the tide of deposits that poured into S & amp; Ls following the 1987 stock market crash. Meanwhile, in other developments: _ <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deposit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. Chairman <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Seidman </PERSON>, in an interview, confirmed published reports that the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> put together a contingency plan last weekend in the event that the announcement of President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s proposal for the savings and loan crisis triggered depositor _ The <ORGANIZATION> FDIC </ORGANIZATION> said it has taken control of six more savings institutions, bringing to 10 the number of <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls brought under the agency's jurisdiction since <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> gave it that responsibility on Monday The December withdrawals, topping the one-month record of $ 7.0 billion set in November, occurred at a time of mounting publicity about S & amp; L problems. Regulators closed or merged 75 institutions that month. But <PERSON> Bert </PERSON> <PERSON> Ely </PERSON>, a financial institutions analyst in <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, attributed the development to interest rate movements rather than to nervousness by S & amp; L customers. He said customers are turning to money market mutual funds and other investments because S & amp; Ls are resisting pushing up interest rates as fast. However, he predicted S & amp; L deposit rates likely would be forced higher as the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> tightens credit in an effort to dampen inflation. `` Boy, that's hard on the bottom line,'' he said. `` This does not bode well for thrift earnings.'' Indeed, one member of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Martha </PERSON> <PERSON> Seger </PERSON>, dissented from a policy-making board's decision in December to push interest rates higher on the grounds that could aggravate S & amp; Ls' problems Her opposition to higher rates was revealed in minutes released Friday of the Dec. 13-14 meeting of the Federal Open Market Committee. However, economist <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Regalia </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutions </ORGANIZATION> said the president's effort this week appears to have bolstered confidence in savings institutions. `` If you look at the stock market, they look at this whole process as being a net plus,'' he said. `` Thrift stocks have risen in the last few days because I guess they feel the problem is being addressed.'' <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Barth </PERSON>, chief economist of the bank board, attributed a large share of the December deposit flow to a single, healthy institution which shrank its deposit base by $ 3.4 billion as part of a deliberate strategy of substituting lower cost borrowing. He also noted that money normally flows out of savings accounts in December as people spend to celebrate the holidays. <PERSON> Seidman </PERSON>, in an interview Friday, said administration officials who he declined to name were predicting depositor runs when <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> announced his S & amp; L plan and that the president insisted the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> have an emergency plan in place. `` I was on the other side -LRB- of the argument -RRB- but I was just as eager as anybody to have a plan in place in case I happened to be wrong,'' he said. The <ORGANIZATION> FDIC </ORGANIZATION>, which insures bank deposits, will take control of more than 200 insolvent S & amp; Ls in the next four to six weeks under a cooperation agreement with the agency insuring thrift deposits, the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. The six institutions taken over Friday by the <ORGANIZATION> FDIC </ORGANIZATION> are: First Federal of <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Savers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, both of Little Rock, Ark.; <ORGANIZATION> Sandia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION>; Bright Banc, <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>; <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>; and <ORGANIZATION> Deseret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890211-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-11-89 0105EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Baker Bjt   02-11 0708</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Baker, Bjt,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Whirwind Trip to Highlight Defense and Trade Issues</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Top prospects uncertain.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OTTAWA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hoping he has put questions about his private bank holdings behind him, Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> set out today on a week-long trip to the capitals of the 14 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> allies in <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> likely to be dominated by defense and trade issues. For <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, whose foreign policy experience is slight, the trip beginning in <LOCATION> Iceland </LOCATION> and winding up next Friday in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> is a learning experience and a warmup for a probable <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> summit meeting in the spring. `` It is a listening trip and it is a consulting trip,'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said Friday at a news conference here. `` But I am carrying a message. We want to make it clear the way to approach the <LOCATION> East-West </LOCATION> relationship is with prudence and with realism. We want you to know we are not dragging our feet, seeking delay for the sake of delay.'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said he would solicit the views of the allied governments on how to negotiate strategic nuclear weapons reductions with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and what to do about modernizing <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>'s battlefield weapons. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> hopes, meanwhile, he has put to rest a potentially ticklish problem over his holdings in <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> by saying he would `` tend to be guided'' by whatever conclusions are reached by government ethics lawyers. The holding company has $ 4.5 billion in loans to Third World nations, and <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> as secretary of state will be called on to play a leading role in addressing the economic problems of developing countries. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said he would ask for a presidential waiver allowing him to participate in such decisions. But <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said he would also consider other options, such as selling his stock or changing the terms of the blind trust in which all his holdings have been placed in order to avoid even the appearance of a conflict of interest. `` I have concluded I should seek a waiver because that gives me additional protection and helps avoid any appearance of impropriety,'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Ottawa </LOCATION>, where he stopped with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for five hours of talks with Canadian leaders. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyden </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s top adviser on ethics, and other government lawyers were trying to find `` a mechanism or actions that would be taken in my case to insulate me from charges or appearances of a conflict of interest.'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said he had not talked to <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, and that the President's ethics adviser had not asked him to sell the bank stock But <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> had raised selling as an option in talking to <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kimmit </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> lawyer who was named Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs. `` I have been very careful about recusing myself from specific issues that might constitute a conflict of an appearance of conflict,'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said, referring to his jobs as White House chief of staff and then <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> Secretary in the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. However, he said government attorneys also told him he could participate in `` general policy determinations'' without violating ethical standards. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> are in the midst of a review of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> foreign policy. Negotiations with the Soviets to reduce long-range missiles are on hold, and the administration also faces a decision on whether to ease restrictions on technology sales to the Soviets. At the same time, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> will try on the trip to promote increased defense spending by the allies even while the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration tries to keep its own outlays in check. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, who began his <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> discussions Friday night with Foreign Minister <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, is also under pressure from the allies to ease restrictions on trade with the Soviets. Automatic curbs on technology that could have a military use were imposed by the <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> administration to punish the Soviets for the 1979 invasion of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. The Soviet troops are leaving, with the last soldier due out by next Wednesday. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said he had not made up his mind, despite reports that he had decided to lift the automatic curbs. But he stressed that if the curbs are eased `` this does not mean we are opening the doors to technology transfers.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890211-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-11-89 0133EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-ChicagoSymphony     02-11 0370</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Chicago Symphony,0377</SECOND>
<HEAD>Solti Conducts Shostakovich</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: No PMs planned.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RONALD BLUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With two years remaining in World War II, <PERSON> Dmitri </PERSON> <PERSON> Shostakovich </PERSON> composed his harrowing Eighth Symphony, a reflection on the destruction of war. Sir <PERSON> Georg </PERSON> <PERSON> Solti </PERSON> brought all the flash he is know for to the hour-long piece Friday night as he led the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Symphony </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orchestra </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Carnegie </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hall </LOCATION>. Sir <PERSON> Georg </PERSON> surely has never met a cresecendo he did n't like, which suits this Shostakovich perfectly. As the strings and the woodwinds fade in the desolation of the score's final pages, the previous thunder of brass and percussion has left the audience yearning for peacefulness. `` In this work, there was an attempt to express the emotional experience of the people,'' <PERSON> Shostakovich </PERSON> wrote, `` to reflect the terrible tragedy of war.'' To convey that experience, <PERSON> Shostakovich </PERSON> uses all the orchestral artillery he can muster. After 15 minutes of buildup, begun darkly by the cellos and basses, the percussion lets loose like a marching band, sounding the drumbeat of the war that surrounded <PERSON> Shostakovich </PERSON>. And what orchestra better to capture that sound than the Chicagoans? More than any other orchestra, it has managed to maintain a distinctive sound in the age of plane-hopping music directors. It's tone is bold and brash, powered by perhaps the best brass section in the world. Sir <PERSON> Georg </PERSON>, celebrating his 20th season as music director and his 75th birthday, still leaps about the podium with the energy of a teenager, whipping his troops to let loose. Even when the score briefly turns towards peasant dance music at the beginning of the fifth and final movement, Sir <PERSON> Georg </PERSON> reaches for the big sound. Earlier, with a much-reduced orchestra, Sir <PERSON> Georg </PERSON> led a warm rendition of <PERSON> Schubert </PERSON>'s Fifth Symphony. <PERSON> Schubert </PERSON> wrote it during a month-long stretch in 1816, when he was 19, and although it does not come close to the quality of his Eighth and <ORGANIZATION> Ninth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Symphonies </ORGANIZATION>, it has an almost Mozartian softness. The Chicagoans had a chance to show off their violins, especially during the three allegros. Sir <PERSON> Georg </PERSON>, in contrast to his `` Falstaff'' four years ago, let the sis-boom-bah rest in a piece that did n't need it.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890211-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-11-89 0134EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     02-11 0025</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0026</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Friday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 01; 12; 29; 31; 36; 40.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890211-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-11-89 0137EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People--Dalton     02-11 0069</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People--Dalton,0072</SECOND>
<HEAD>Singer To Wed Valentine's Day</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Country singer <PERSON> Lacy </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dalton </PERSON> will marry her tour manager on Valentine's night in <LOCATION> Carmel </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, a spokeswoman says. <PERSON> Dalton </PERSON> and <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, her tour manager the past four years, will be married Tuesday in a small, private ceremony, spokeswoman <PERSON> Pam </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> said Friday. <PERSON> Dalton </PERSON>'s hit songs include `` 16th Avenue'' and `` Hillbilly Girl With the Blues.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890211-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-11-89 0140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Fumes-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0827 02-11 0314</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fumes-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0827,0317</SECOND>
<HEAD>Four Dead, One Person Critical, From Deadly Fumes In Chicago House</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: UPDATES throughout with blocked pipe blamed for fumes, identity
of thee of victims. No pickup.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By F.N. D'ALESSIO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A blocked heater pipe spread deadly fumes through a house, killing four young men and leaving a woman in critical condition, authorities said Friday. The deadly fumes `` might be either gas or carbon monoxide, but we're leaning toward carbon monoxide,'' <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Greca </PERSON> said. `` It appears that they have been dead for some time, in terms of hours or days, I do n't know,'' <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Greca </PERSON> said. `` Somehow, the woman was able to survive.'' A flue pipe inside the living room heater and a separate pipe connecting the heater to an outside wall were blocked, causing the fumes to seep into the room, said <ORGANIZATION> Peoples </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON>. The four men were pronounced dead on arrival at <ORGANIZATION> Holy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, said supervisor <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON> <PERSON> Kopecky </PERSON>. She identified two of the victims as brothers <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Blazek </PERSON>, 17, and <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Blazek </PERSON>, 21. Another victim, <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON>, 27, and <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Prykop </PERSON>, 18, who was in critical condition at <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, did not live at the house but were neighbors. The fourth victim, a 36-year-old man, was not immediately identified. Four people were found in the living room and one person in a bedroom, authorities said. Carbon monoxide is a colorless, odorless, extremely poisonous gas. Because it has no odor or color, persons breathing it usually fall asleep without realizing they are being poisoned. It results when fuels containing carbon like coal or oil burn in stoves or furnaces that contain insufficient oxygen. <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Greca </PERSON> said authorities determined there was no need to evacuate nearby buildings after gas company workers shut off the supply of gas to the building.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890211-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-11-89 0141EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Czechoslovakia-Ecology     02-11 0148</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Czechoslovakia-Ecology,0151</SECOND>
<HEAD>Entire National Park Polluted</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PRAGUE, Czechoslovakia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Giant Mountains National Park, <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>'s largest, has become so heavily polluted that half its trees are severely damaged, the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> daily Rude Pravo reported. It said Friday that the 80,000-acre park, a popular skiing resort 80 miles north of <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>, has been damaged by pollution from chemical plants and power stations using low-grade coal. `` Over 5O percent of pollution comes from the equipment of our neighbors,'' Rude Pravo quoted <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Korinek </PERSON> of the Forests and <ORGANIZATION> Water </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> as saying. He apparently was referring to factories in nearby <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. The paper quoted <PERSON> Korinek </PERSON> as saying the fate of two ski-jumping hills in <LOCATION> Harrachov </LOCATION>, a prime venue for international competitions, would likely be affected by ecological disaster _ `` There are no trees left and there is simply too much wind, which makes ski-jumping dangerous.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890211-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-11-89 0118EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ImposterAstronaut     02-11 0747</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Imposter Astronaut,0768</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Who Posed as Astronaut Faces Trial for Fraud, Larceny</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: First available for Saturday AMs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ARLENE LEVINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunt </PERSON> scorched some kitchen tiles and told his wife they fell off the ill-fated Challenger space shuttle. That, police say, was just one prop in <PERSON> Hunt </PERSON>'s pose as an astronaut during a period of make-believe that carried him through several states, speaking engagements and marriages. Now his wife is leaving him and he faces fraud and larceny charges for taking his make-believe too far. State police arrested Hunt on Jan. 28 in suburban <LOCATION> Medford </LOCATION>. The 27-year-old plumber's son from <PERSON> Everett </PERSON> is accused of swindling his fourth wife and bride of five months, <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Sweeney </PERSON>, of up to $ 50,000 on her company-issued credit card without her knowledge and for taking $ 4,000 from a <LOCATION> Saugus </LOCATION> family on the promise he could get their 18-year-old son out of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>. On Jan. 6, calling himself Marine Capt. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON>. Hunt, the fake astronaut spoke before a group called the <ORGANIZATION> Experimental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aircraft </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. `` He was a very good speaker, he entertained us. He held us spellbound for 2 -LCB- hours,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Greater </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> chapter president, <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Pascucci </PERSON>. <PERSON> Sweeney </PERSON>, 23, a former optical engineer, also believed he was an astronaut. `` I love the person I thought I was married to,'' she said. Recalling the day he was unmasked, <PERSON> Sweeney </PERSON> said, `` I was shocked. It was almost like watching someone die. He just dissolved, disappeared.'' Hunt is being held on $ 100,000 bail in a <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> jail. His case in <ORGANIZATION> East </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> was continued to Feb. 15 after a request for reduced bail was denied. <PERSON> Hunt </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Cipoletta </PERSON>, could not be reached Friday, but he has said he urged his client not to speak to the news media. Investigators compiling the story of <PERSON> Hunt </PERSON>'s alleged stories say that for the past eight years he has been fooling many people in imaginative ways _ in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Montour </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Township </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Lighow </PERSON> said <PERSON> Hunt </PERSON> allegedly rode around <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> in a limousine seeking models for his baby powder while pretending to be a powder maker. He said Friday that he was investigating charges that <PERSON> Hunt </PERSON> swindled his third wife, a local woman, out of large amounts of money. He would not elaborate. Authorities say <PERSON> Hunt </PERSON> is believed to have been married to two other women. <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Doan </PERSON>, the owner of an air service in <LOCATION> Daytona </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, was convinced by <PERSON> Hunt </PERSON> that he was a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> helicopter pilot. Last summer, <PERSON> Hunt </PERSON> chartered a jet to fly with his wife to <LOCATION> Montreal </LOCATION>, allegedly charging it on his wife's credit card while telling her the flight cost nothing because he was a space shuttle pilot. In <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> Oct. 8, he was granted a 10-minute interview with <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Briscoe </PERSON>, lord mayor of <LOCATION> Dublin </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Briscoe </PERSON>'s spokeswoman said the meeting at <ORGANIZATION> Mansion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, the official residence, was arranged after <PERSON> Briscoe </PERSON> was told <PERSON> Hunt </PERSON> was a visiting astronaut. The spokewoman said when <PERSON> Hunt </PERSON> told the lord mayor that <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> was arranging for him to be married at <ORGANIZATION> Westminster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Abbey </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Briscoe </PERSON> realized <PERSON> Hunt </PERSON> was `` not the full shilling,'' but politely said nothing. Others were completely taken in. During Hunt's arrest, police searched the apartment and found assorted military paraphernalia, flight jumpsuits and a helmet bearing the insignia of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. Dr. <PERSON> Park </PERSON> <PERSON> Dietz </PERSON>, a forensic psychiatrist who is an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> consultant and a professor at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION>, said there are cases in legal circles falling under the category of the so-called imposter phenomenon. `` It's generally believed that people who are able to dupe others into believing that they have some professional status that's untrue, most likely suffer from antisocial personality disorder,'' said <PERSON> Dietz </PERSON>, who is on sabbatical in <LOCATION> Newport </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif </LOCATION> He said a recent <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> survey found about 5 percent of adult urba men and nearly 1 percent of adult urban women suffer from the disorder. <PERSON> Dietz </PERSON> said the ailment can be hereditary and that `` people who -LRB- practice -RRB- such deceptions tend not to have the same depth of emotions, of empathy and warmth, despite their charm.'' Why are so many duped? `` It takes energy, thought, mental work to be skeptical about the myriad claims to legitimacy we come upon every day,'' he said. `` It's easier to take people at their word, particularly when it conveys some status by associating with them.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890211-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-11-89 0150EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Budget-Energy     02-11 0569</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Budget-Energy,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Experts Disagree on Whether Tax Plan Would Help Oil Output</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s proposed tax breaks for oil drillers are winning an expected round of applause from the oil industry, but officials and analysts disagree over whether the measures will stem the decline in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> oil production. `` I do n't think we're going to get that much more oil out of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> even if these tax incentives were passed,'' said <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Rothschild </PERSON>, assistant director of the <ORGANIZATION> Citizen-Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION>, an advocacy group that favors greater use of renewable energy sources as an alternative to fossil fuels. `` It's more of a political gesture to the industry'' than a plan for revitalizing domestic oil production, <PERSON> Rothschild </PERSON> said in an interview Friday. Industry officials said the proposed tax incentives, worth at least $ 350 million a year, would, if enacted, result in a measurable gain in oil and gas production. `` This is a very healthy step forward,'' said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Groninger </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> director of governmental affairs for the <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>. `` Tax incentives are an important component of a national energy policy.'' The tax breaks unveiled by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in his budget address Thursday to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> were coupled with a postponement of lease sales for oil drilling off the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> coasts _ areas the oil companies consider prime drilling prospects. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he was seeking to balance environmental needs with a desire to revitalize the depressed oil and gas industry, which he called vital to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> national security. The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, representing the nation's major oil companies, welcomed the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> tax incentives but said more steps would be needed, including opening up more federal lands and offshore areas to oil exploration. `` The tax incentives ... are a step in the right direction, but they alone can not stem the serious decline in domestic petroleum production,'' said <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> DiBona </PERSON>, president of the petroleum institute. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> oil production has fallen by more than 1 million barrels a day over the past three years, and last December the oil production rate was the lowest in nearly a quarter of a century. At the same time, oil demand has increased in recent years, leading to a reliance on imports that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says poses security risks. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> rejected the idea of imposing a tariff on imported oil but proposed four tax incentives aimed at boosting exploratory drilling, particularly by smaller operators. The tax breaks would be phased out if the price of oil, currently about $ 17 a barrel, rose above $ 21. The tax package includes: _ A 10 percent credit on the first $ 10 million of spending, per company per year, on intangible drilling costs, those not directly associated with drilling a well, such as hauling equipment _ A 10 percent credit for spending on all new tertiary enhanced recovery projects, those that use steam, carbon dioxide or chemical injectants to increase the production rate from oil and natural gas fields _ Allow drillers to exclude a major part of their income from the alternative minimum tax _ Change oil and natural gas depletion rules that the administration says discourage the transfer of marginal wells from major oil companies to independent producers and result in the premature abandonment of producing wells The administration said the tax package was aimed mainly at the smaller producers, which traditionally have drilled the majority of new wells in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890211-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-11-89 0120EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ComputerDating     02-11 0195</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Computer Dating,0201</SECOND>
<HEAD>Computer Students Come Up With Romantic Way To Raise School Funds</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GRAND RAPIDS, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Students trying to raise money usually go in for bake sales or car washes, but kids at a high school here have come up with a service that's a hit with their classmates _ computer dating. With Valentine's Day approaching, students have been lining up in the halls of <ORGANIZATION> Ottawa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hills </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> at lunch hour, ready to pay $ 1 for the names of three potential dates whose answers to 20 questions most closely match theirs. `` The first two days we've had people piling around the table, throwing money at us,'' student <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Woods </PERSON> said recently. Computer student <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruder </PERSON> said he spent two or three months writing the software for the dating service, then distributed questionnaires. `` We're not up to Dating Game standards, yet,'' <PERSON> Ruder </PERSON> said. `` We have n't said it is the perfect date or anything like that.'' So far, the students have raised about $ 200, which will go toward computer lab equipment. <PERSON> Woods </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ruder </PERSON> have bigger ideas for their computer program. They hope to copyright it and market it to other schools.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890211-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-11-89 0144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AntiquarianFair     02-11 0560</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Antiquarian Fair,0576</SECOND>
<HEAD>Antiquarian Fair Lures Longtime Buyers, Ensnares New Devotees</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: First available for Saturday AMs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CATALINA ORTIZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The aroma of old leather mingled with the smell of new money at the nation's largest book fair, where you could pick up a 1632 edition of <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON> or `` The Philosophy of <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON>'' bound with $ 5 bills. `` I love to lose myself in other men's minds,'' wrote <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Lamb </PERSON> in an essay on books and reading, and he would have been blissfully transported at the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> International Antiquarian Book Fair, which opened Friday. Organizers hoped a record 8,000 people would browse through the centuries of writers' and bookbinders' art, not to mention buy. But the 188 booksellers from throughout the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and seven other countries anticipated winning new devotees as well as making profits. `` Book fairs cultivate book collectors. They come here and see things they've never seen before,'' said <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kane </PERSON>, a bookseller and chairman of this year's fair. `` They love literature or see the beauty of the illustrations. ... They get into it, and pretty soon, they're hooked,'' said <PERSON> Kane </PERSON>, whose necktie was printed with rows of books. `` In most cases, it's a consuming disease _ a consuming passion, that's better.'' Future collectors might catch the bug while admiring a second folio edition of <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON>'s plays, offered for $ 60,000, a painstakingly illuminated 15th century Flemmish manuscript Book of Hours for $ 35,000 or a 1482 Venetian volume of Euclid priced at $ 25,000. The most expensive item is a three-volume set of the first edition of Moby <PERSON> Dick </PERSON>, published in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> in 1851 and entitled The Whale. It's price? A quick $ 75,000. But it's in first-class condition and a gold-embossed whale adorns the spine of each volume. Collectors on a tighter budget could choose an autographed copy of <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilde </PERSON>'s `` An Ideal Husband'' bound in gold-stamped blue morocco leather and costing $ 4,950. Even some 20th century authors command a handsome price. A first edition of <PERSON> Ian </PERSON> <PERSON> Fleming </PERSON>'s `` Casino Royale,'' for example, is offered for $ 1,250. Despite fears that television and videos have produced a nation of people who do n't read, dealers said growing numbers of people are becoming fascinated by _ and buying _ rare books. `` Business is better that it's ever been,'' said <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinstein </PERSON>, manager of <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Book </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shop </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. Some collectors think of their purchases as investments that will increase in value with the years. But even collectors with an eye toward possible resale buy the old and rare volumnes primarily out of love. `` The preponderance of them are buying not for investment but for just having it as something beautiful, just like having a Picasso,'' <PERSON> Weinstein </PERSON> said. Having something rare and beautiful does n't have to cost thousands of dollars. Prices at the fair start at about $ 20, and some first editions of well-known authors such as <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinbeck </PERSON> and <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON> can be had for about $ 100. `` If you fall in love with an illustrator or an author ... from <PERSON> Elior </PERSON> <PERSON> Wylie </PERSON> to <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON> ... you'll search for the things you can afford,'' said <PERSON> Kane </PERSON>, who gave up newspaper work to become a book dealer in <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> Cruz 18 years ago. A part of the admission proceeds from the fair, which continues through Sunday, goes to the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Library </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890211-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-11-89 0146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-RailMX     02-11 0562</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rail MX,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Air Force Says Environmental Impact Minimal</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NORMAN BLACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> study concludes that deploying huge MX nuclear missiles on railroad cars would neither interfere with the operation of the nation's rail network nor harm the environment significantly. The final Environmental Impact Statement, released Friday at the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, turned up some problems at a few of the 11 <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> bases that are being considered as candidates for `` rail garrisons.'' But the statement insists that `` while there is a very slight potential for accidents with the deployment of the -LRB- MX -RRB- Rail Garrison System, the system would be safe and would pose negligible risk to human health and the environment.'' Former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> ordered the development of a rail-basing plan for the 10-warhead MX _ a weapon he dubbed the Peacekeeper _ in December 1986. His goal was to overcome congressional concerns about the vulnerability of the missiles inside underground silos. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is now facing a March 15 congressional deadline to decide if he'll back <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s plan. If he does, and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> agrees, the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> plans to build 25 six-car trains with each carrying two MX missiles. Each garrison could house up to four trains. Because of the small number of trains involved, the conclusion Friday that the system would not interfere with commercial operations had been expected. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> also went out of its way to note that training operations for crews would be conducted with fake trains that would n't carry real MX missiles. In the event of a derailment or other accident, the chances of an explosion or fire involving the missile's propellants are `` unlikely'' and for the nuclear warheads, virtually impossible, the report says. `` <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> nuclear weapons include safety features and control over arming mechanisms that assure there is virtually no possibility of an inadvertent nuclear detonation,'' the report states. The rail car launchers would remain inside fortified military bases unless there was a threat of war, and only then would scramble on the commercial rail network to avoid a Soviet first-strike attack, the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> said. The heaviest environmental impact would stem from construction activities at any bases selected to serve as garrisons for the MX cars, the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> said. Those would consist primarily of increased traffic congestion, the short-term degradation of air quality and in a few instances, the relocation of inhabited buildings. Of the 11 <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> bases reviewed, however, four would likely suffer `` significant degradation of biological resources'' if rail garrisons were built, the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> reported. Those four are <ORGANIZATION> Barksdale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, La.; Fairchild Air Force Base, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Whiteman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Mo </LOCATION>.; and <ORGANIZATION> Wurtsmith </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Mich </LOCATION>. Despite those findings, the impact statement offers no ranking of the 11 bases, nor does it disqualify any base from consideration. It repeats a decision made two years ago that F.E. <ORGANIZATION> Warren </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Wyo. </LOCATION>, will be the headquarters and first home for any MX trains. But it noted that rail deployment has not been approved by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and that it is premature to select other bases. The other bases considered candidates are <ORGANIZATION> Eaker </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> and Little Rock Air Force Base in <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Dyess </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Grand </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Minot </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>; and <ORGANIZATION> Malstrom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, Mont.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890211-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-11-89 0148EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TradeZones     02-11 0448</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Trade Zones,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study Says Trade-Zone Program Hurts US Parts Makers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM BOVEE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A congressional study concludes that a foreign-trade zone program intended to encourage <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> exports instead is helping foreign auto parts manufacturers by giving millions of dollars in tariff breaks. `` Although originally created in order to encourage export-oriented trade, in its current form the program provides greater benefits to firms who import more parts,'' the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, the investigative arm of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, said in a report issued Friday. The report was immediately praised by the <ORGANIZATION> Automotive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accessories </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION>'s findings `` underscore our industry's conviction that the ... program is broken and needs fixing,'' said the trade association's president, <PERSON> Julian </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>, from its <LOCATION> Lanham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, headquarters. The report recommended that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> amend the 1934 foreign-trade zone law to provide guidance on what public benefits are needed to justify such zones or subzones. Factors to be considered would be exports, imports, employment and investment. Foreign trade zones were originally created to encourage the export of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> goods that contain foreign parts. The program, however, has `` become a major base'' for manufacturers serving domestic markets, the report said. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> report, requested in 1987 by Rep. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rostenkowski </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ill </LOCATION>. and chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, estimated the foreign-trade zones and their subzones in 1986 reduced tariffs on auto parts by $ 38 million The value of parts flowing through the subzones has risen explosively, from $ 200 million in 1978 to $ 5 billion in 1986, the report said. Rep. <PERSON> Sander </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, D-Mich. a member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said the discrepancy between tariffs on parts and on finished vehicles created an obvious `` private benefit'' for automakers under the program Imported auto parts are subject to tariffs ranging from 4 percent to 11 percent. Finished vehicles are assessed at a 2.5 percent tariff rate. When vehicles built in foreign-trade zones are sold in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the imported parts are taxed at the lower 2.5 percent rate, <PERSON> Levin </PERSON> said. Automakers using the foreign-trade zone program run the spectrum from the Michigan-based domestic giants _ <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> _ to foreign makers like <ORGANIZATION> Nissan </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Toyota </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Mazda </ORGANIZATION> that have established assembly plants in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Most auto assembly plants in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> come under the program, the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said. Although the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, which administers the program, uses public benefit as its criterion for judging requests, that standard has not been officially adopted and applications have seldom been denied, the report said. The report recommended the public benefit standard be made part of the law.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890211-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-11-89 0149EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Walesa     02-11 0741</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Walesa,0772</SECOND>
<HEAD>Walesa Tries To Keep Solidarity In Check</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: First available for Saturday AMs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH G. SEWARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> BIELSKO-BIALA </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> is a man gingerly dividing his time between two types of working clothes these days: a blue suit for his talks with the government and a jacket and jeans for his union supporters. He has been meeting with both this week, a delicate balancing act aimed at winning concessions from the government and while keeping the support of the increasingly fractious Solidarity independent labor movement. Since the Monday opening of the talks, known as the round table, <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> has met with thousands of Solidarity supporters in three cities to explain why he agreed to negotiate with the same government that banned their union. The Nobel Peace Prize winner visited <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> on Tuesday, <LOCATION> Krakow </LOCATION> on Thursday and this industrial town on Friday. Not since the heady days of Solidarity's legal existence in 1980-81 has <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> been able to so freely travel the country and openly meet with the union rank-and-file. More than 400 workers cheered when <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> strode into a hall in <LOCATION> Bielsko-Biala </LOCATION>, an industrial center, for the first open meeting of the banned union here in seven years. But they voiced worry about the outcome of the talks first proposed by the government during a wave of strikes in August, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s worst labor unrest since the martial law crackdown of December 1981. `` People have doubts. ... They do n't know what these talks are going to bring,'' said <PERSON> Miroslaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Styczen </PERSON>, a veteran solidarity activist in <LOCATION> Bielsko-Biala </LOCATION>. `` Most people are really happy about the talks. But there's not complete unity,'' he said. A textile town in the <LOCATION> Beskidy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> 180 miles south of <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Bielsko-Biala </LOCATION> was one of the strongest Solidarity regions during the union's 16-month legal existence. The Solidarity leader launched into a speech he has consistently delivered all week. He told the workers he did n't really trust the government, but that `` <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> badly needs agreement.'' His listeners fired back questions. `` How will you get people to join the new unions?'' asked one young worker. `` Today everybody who wants to will soon be able to organize a group,'' <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> replied. `` How is Solidarity going to be organized?'' asked another worker. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> had no concrete answer, but he assured them that authorities have made a political decision and that the union would exist again soon. He pleaded for time and urged workers to be patient and not to strike. `` We all have a moral right and arguments to strike. ... Give me a chance at the round table,'' he said. `` If it is too little, we will fight,'' he said. Earlier in the day, <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> did don his dark blue suit for talks with Cardinal <PERSON> Franciszek </PERSON> <PERSON> Macharski </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Krakow </LOCATION> and a later meeting with faculty and students at the 14th century <ORGANIZATION> Jagiellonian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> asked the students and professors to excuse him for any grammatical errors he might make, saying he was just a worker. About 2,000 students crowded the halls near loudspeakers outside the small, ornate room where <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> addressed about 200 invited guests. One visitor was not allowed in _ a reporter from the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> newspaper, <ORGANIZATION> Trybuna </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ludu </ORGANIZATION>. `` Believe in yourselves and build structures that can bring <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> into <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and the world,'' <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> told the audience. Students were dismayed that they had been given only 25 seats in the room, and some seemed skeptical about the round table. `` People are still trying to learn what the round table is about. It's too early to tell,'' said <PERSON> Piotr </PERSON> <PERSON> Hertig </PERSON>, a spokesman of the illegal independent students' association. `` <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>'s speech lacked concrete propositions. People are n't sure how to organize or what to do,'' said another student `` As soon as there will be agreement, we will be able to work,'' <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> said. He did not say how long he expected it would take. The trip was grueling, but <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> says he must make contact with people to grasp the situation, to reacquaint himself with movement veterans and to meet the new generation of activists. He plans another trip across <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> next week. Traveling by car, <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> appeared tired and impatient when he arrived in <LOCATION> Krakow </LOCATION> late Thursday. More than 3,000 people jammed the <ORGANIZATION> Mistrzejowice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> near the <LOCATION> Nowa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Huta </LOCATION> steel mill to hear <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> speak. `` Lech, welcome, Solidarity is not underground and was not destroyed,'' said <PERSON> Stefan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jurczak </PERSON> of the Solidarity region <LOCATION> Malopolska </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890211-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-11-89 0200EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Soviet-Jews     02-11 0691</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Jews,0710</SECOND>
<HEAD>World Jewish Leaders to Open First Soviet Jewish Center in 50 Years</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: First available for Saturday AMs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANDREW KATELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nobel laureate <PERSON> Elie </PERSON> <PERSON> Wiesel </PERSON> and dozens of other world Jewish leaders are coming to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to help open the first cultural center for Soviet Jews in more than 50 years. While one of the leaders hailed Sunday's opening of the center as a sign of the improving fortunes of the country's 1.8 million Jews under President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, he said it's too soon to declare an end to the problems of Jews in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. `` Glasnost has taken hold here. The question will be, can it continue?'' said Rabbi <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hier </PERSON>, dean of the <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wiesenthal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hier </PERSON>, World Jewish Congress President <PERSON> Edgar </PERSON> <PERSON> Bronfman </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Wiesel </PERSON> _ a survivor of the Holocaust and 1986 Nobel Peace Prize winner _ are to speak at Sunday's opening of the Solomon Mikhoels Cultural Center. About 70 Jewish leaders from <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and other countries plan to attend. The opening comes a few days after a Soviet newspaper made a major admission: that Soviet Jews have suffered discrimination for decades and that dictator <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> destroyed Jewish culture in the country. <PERSON> Mikhoels </PERSON>, a Jewish actor for whom the center was named, was among the thousands of Jews who fell victim to <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON>'s terror. He was killed in 1948 in what was officially termed a traffic accident but what many Jews believe was an assassination ordered by <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON>. The center is located in the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> Jewish Musical Theater on <LOCATION> Taganka </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> in the southeastern section of the capital. Its director, <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gluz </PERSON>, told the official news agency <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> on Friday that Yiddish and Hebrew classes are planned, itself a major change. The teaching of Hebrew was once punished as a crime, and several Jewish activists were jailed for religious instruction. Soviet laws bar the private teaching of religious subjects to anyone under 18, but authorities have indicated a new law on religion being drafted will ease those and other restrictions. <PERSON> Hier </PERSON> said in an interview that Soviet promises to allow the teaching of Hebrew as well as membership by Soviet Jews in international Jewish organizations `` have been couched in very diplomatic terms.'' `` We have no commitment yet,'' he said. In a report previewing Sunday's opening, <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said: `` The perestroika, or restructuring drive, has altered the life of Soviet society and prompted the development of Jewish cultural associations.'' But <PERSON> Hier </PERSON> said plans for the center to have a public library, Jewish museum and art gallery could be ruined if Soviet authorities interfere. `` It is not the time to be euphoric, but to make sure the center will be free to develop cultural and educational programs. If that is what the center becomes, it will be a great and epic event,'' <PERSON> Hier </PERSON> said. If authorities step in, he said, `` we will be back where we started from.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wiesenthal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> has donated to the center an exhibit and Russian-language books about the Nazi campaign against the Jews, and has shown in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> a film that accuses the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> of kidnapping <PERSON> Raoul </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallenberg </PERSON>, a Swedish diplomat who saved thousands of Jews during World War II and later disappeared. As part of his effort to improve relations with the West, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has taken several steps to address complaints that his country violates human rights. For Jews, the changes have meant a rise in emigration _ 1988 marked an eight-year high with about 20,000 leaving _ less harassment at Jewish holiday celebrations, and the opening of a private Jewish museum and library in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. But <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Chlenov </PERSON>, a member of a private group called the <ORGANIZATION> Jewish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said the government has a long way to go. `` Jewish life in the <LOCATION> U.S.S.R. </LOCATION> is in a state of crisis,'' he wrote in a brochure on the Mikhoels center. `` Official Jewish cultural institutions ... such as magazines, newspapers and theaters do not satisfy the demands of our time. The growing Jewish consciousness refuses to be compressed into an outlived framework.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890211-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-11-89 0201EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Budget     02-11 0471</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Budget,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congressional Democrats Say Bush Budget is a Trap for Them</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Democratic chairmen of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> budget committees meet with <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> budget officials next week to try to find out what they say President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s 1990 budget neglected to reveal: how the deficit will be trimmed. <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Panetta </PERSON>, D-Calif., and his <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> counterpart, <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON>, D-Tenn., said Friday they would not proceed with the high-level budget negotiations the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration wants until they get those details on deficit `` Before we go any further, we want to sit down and find out specifically where they're going, program by program,'' <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON> said. The lawmakers said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s $ 1.16 trillion spending plan was vague when it came to specifying savings, a strategy aimed at putting the pressure _ and the blame _ on <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for cuts that will inevitably be unpopular. `` Mr. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> chose to give us only the good news,'' <PERSON> Panetta </PERSON> said of the president's budget address Thursday night to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. `` He has left it for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to give the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people the bad news.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said his proposal would leave a deficit of $ 91.1 billion next year, well within the $ 100 billion target required by the Gramm-Rudman deficit reduction law. He achieves that level by holding the growth in the defense budget to the rate of inflation, providing $ 309 billion in new spending; making a controversial cut in the capital gains tax rate that he says will raise $ 4.8 billion in new revenues; slowing the growth of Medicare by $ 5 billion; selling $ 3.7 billion in federal assets; and extending taxes on telephone service and airline tickets that are due to expire. But of most concern to Democrats is <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s proposal to limit a collection of more than 1,000 programs _ most of them domestic _ to the $ 136 billion spent for them this year. Democrats said this meant that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was leaving the onus for finding $ 11 billion in cuts up to them, reductions that could affect programs like toxic waste cleanups, mass transit assistance, and law enforcement. `` This is not what we would call a flexible freeze,'' <PERSON> Panetta </PERSON> said, referring to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign promise to reduce the deficit by limiting spending increases to the rate of inflation. `` It's a flexible squeeze.'' Sen. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Domenici </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, the ranking Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, defended <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s strategy of lumping those programs together. `` There's more room for negotiation this way,'' he said. <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> briefed <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> senators and representatives on the budget early Friday, and told reporters afterward that it is time for the administration and congressional leaders to begin negotiating on a spending plan. `` The spirit is very good at the moment and we've got to build on that spirit,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890211-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-11-89 0039EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PlaneFire     02-11 0254</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Plane Fire,0259</SECOND>
<HEAD>Air National Guard Plane Crashes, Crew Member Killed</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FORT WAYNE, Ind. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A military aircraft crashed Friday night despite efforts of a crew member to land the plane when the cockpit caught fire and the pilot lost consciousness. One crew member was killed, officials said. The weapons specialist aboard the <ORGANIZATION> F-4 </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> plane tried to land the craft but bailed out before it crashed on a runway at the city airport, said supervisor <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON> at <LOCATION> Baer </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Field </LOCATION>'s control tower Lt. <PERSON> Kathleen </PERSON> <PERSON> Rzepka </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> said one crew member was killed and the other was hospitalized. She did not know his condition. It was not immediately known which of the two on board died. Earlier, patrolman <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> said the pilot was in very critical condition, according to medics at the scene. He did not believe the weapons specialist had suffered serious injuries. Both men were taken to <LOCATION> Lutheran </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, but a nursing supervisor there said no information would be released pending notification of relatives. Police learned about the pilotless plane, when the craft was six minutes away from <LOCATION> Baer </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Field </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> said. The weapons specialist piloted the plane to the runway, but ejected before it landed. There was no fire at the scene of the crash and the fire in the cockpit had been extinguished, <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> said. Capt. <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON> <PERSON> Dickerson </PERSON>, squadron flight surgeon for the <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, said an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> accident board would be appointed to investigate the crash.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890211-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-11-89 0206EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FairnessDoctrine     02-11 0534</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fairness Doctrine,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Doctrine Supporters Hope for New Legislation in Wake of Ruling</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAY ARNOLD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Supporters of laws to force broadcasters to present both sides of controversial issues say they're heartened by the refusal of a federal appeals court to consider the constitutionality of such a statute. The <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> ruled Friday that the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> properly used its authority in August 1987 when it repealed the so-called Fairness Doctrine. The commission had said the doctrine, written in 1949, no longer served the public interest as defined by the 1934 Communications Act and was unconstitutional on First Amendment grounds. The appeals court said the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> was `` exercising both its congressionally delegated power and its expertise'' when it said the law did not serve the public interest. But the court sidestepped the constitutionality question, which had been a primary issue in the court challenge. The doctrine's constitutionality is likely to be tested if <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> writes the doctrine into law again this year as expected `` The big victory here is that any law that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> passes ... will not be presumptively unconstitutional,'' said <PERSON> Gigi </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sohn </PERSON>, an attorney representing an anti-nuclear group whose fairness complaint against a <LOCATION> Syracuse </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, television station led to the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION>'s repeal of the doctrine. The court's decision `` leaves the door wide open for congressional action to codify the Fairness Doctrine,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Buchanan </PERSON>, chairman of People for the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Way </ORGANIZATION>, a constitutional liberties group. Rep. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Markey </PERSON>, D-Mass., whose Energy and <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> telecommunications subcommittee held hearings on a new fairness bill Thursday, also said the court's decision gave <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> the green light to pass the measure `` I pledge that the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION>'s ill-considered decision to repeal the Fairness Doctrine will be remedied at expeditiously as possible,'' <PERSON> Markey </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION>, however, said the court `` has vindicated the public's right to receive broadcast press coverage free from government interference. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has said he would veto a Fairness Doctrine bill. Proponents have said they expect a First Amendment test in the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. All three judges concurred in Friday's ruling, although there were partial dissents. In its complaint to the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION>, the anti-nuclear <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> said that <ORGANIZATION> WTVH </ORGANIZATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> Meredith </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> station, had not presented conflicting views when the station ran a series of advertisements in 1982 that said the Nine Mile 2 nuclear power plant was a `` sound investment for <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>.'' The <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> agreed with the anti-nuclear group, and <PERSON> Meredith </PERSON> appealed to the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> in 1985 on grounds the Fairness Doctrine violated its First Amendment rights. But the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> denied the petition, saying the constitutional question should be left in the hands of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the courts. However, in January 1987 the <ORGANIZATION> federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> appeals </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> court </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> ordered the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> to consider the constitutional challenge. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> stepped in and wrote the doctrine into law, but President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> vetoed the bill in June 1987 before the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> repealed the doctrine. Writing for the court Friday, Judge <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said `` The <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION>'s decision that the Fairness Doctrine no longer served the public interest was neither arbitrary, capricious nor an abuse of discretion.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890211-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-11-89 0206EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Sweden-Seals     02-11 0126</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Sweden-Seals,0128</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mild Winter Threatens Seal Population</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SODERHAMN, Sweden (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gray seals, thinned out by past hunting and chemical pollution, face a new threat this spring because warm temperatures have melted away their calving areas on the Baltic ice. The national news agency <ORGANIZATION> TT </ORGANIZATION> reported Friday that 100 seals had gathered near <LOCATION> Soderhamn </LOCATION> along the central <LOCATION> Baltic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> coast, apparently in search of the ice floes where they usually bear their young. Most of the Baltic is ice-free, and <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> is more than halfway through the mildest winter in recorded history. An estimated 1,500 gray seals remain in the Baltic. The seals numbered about 100,000 in 1900, but were hunted through most of this century because they compete with commercial fishermen for their catch.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890211-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-11-89 0208EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AssaultWeapons     02-11 0623</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Assault Weapons,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Call for Ban on Sale of Assault Rifles</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sale of rapid-fire assault rifles like the one used last month in a <LOCATION> Stockton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, shooting spree that left five children dead and 29 more wounded should be outlawed, the nation's police are telling lawmakers `` In my judgment, these weapons have to go,'' <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> police Chief <PERSON> Daryl </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gates </PERSON> told a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> subcommittee </ORGANIZATION> Friday as it opened hearings on assault rifles. The hearing spotlighted a bill being sponsored by Sen. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, that would ban the sale of AK-47s, Uzis and other military-style, semiautomatic rifles as well as shotguns equipped with drum magazines that can fire 12 blasts in three seconds. Sgt. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Pattison </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Nassau </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, policeman and executive vice president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organizations </ORGANIZATION>, had a blunt message for the committee. `` Our streets are becoming a combat zone,'' he said. `` Prompt and decisive action by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is needed.'' On display was an arsenal of grease guns and semiautomatic pistols as well as such standbys as the semiautomatic adaptation of the AK47, long the basic weapon of Communist infantrymen from <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON> used an AK47 on Jan. 17 when he opened fire on 400 children on a playground outside the <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Stockton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. Five children died and 29 children were injured as well as one teacher The hearing fell silent as <PERSON> Lori </PERSON> <PERSON> Mackey </PERSON>, a teacher at the <PERSON> Stockton </PERSON> school, told how she and her pupils huddled on their classroom floor while shots crackled across the schoolyard and the shadow of the gunman crossed back and forth across their window. `` We hoped that he would not notice that we were there and that he would maybe think that we were at recess too,'' she said. Since then, she said, nightmares and fear of strangers have plagued her pupils. She said she has become distrustful and winces at unexpected sounds. <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>'s bill is being opposed by gun groups on grounds that it would outlaw not only so-called assault rifles but also traditional hunting rifles with a semiautomatic capacity. In fact, there is no functional difference between the two, testified <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Conroy </PERSON>, acting deputy associate director for law enforcement of the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alcohol </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tobacco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Firearms </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Gates </PERSON> scoffed at the notion that there was no way to outlaw assault rifles without also banning the guns of legitimate hunters. `` It seems to me that we're smart enough to do it,'' he said. `` I can tell you -LRB- the difference -RRB- because I've had two police officers killed with assault weapons,'' <PERSON> Gates </PERSON> said. `` Gang members love these weapons because in their drive-by shootings they do n't have to be marksmen, they do n't have to be sportsmen, all they have to do is spray,'' the chief said. <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> episode showed that the AK-47 was not meant for use `` in a duck blind.'' `` We know of only one instance in which this was used for hunting,'' he said. `` When a psychopath in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> went hunting school children.'' Representatives of some of the nation's gun-owner groups argued that firearms themselves are not the problem. The <PERSON> Stockton </PERSON> incident `` reflects a breakdown in the criminal justice system,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON>, public affairs director of the Washington-based <ORGANIZATION> Citizens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> to Keep and Bear Arms. He urged tougher laws to keep guns out of the hands of criminals. <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rifle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> lobbyist <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>'s bill conflicted with the Second Amendment to the Constitution, guaranteeing citizens the right to keep and bear arms. `` It is just the kind of ill-considered legislation that the Second Amendment was designed to prevent,'' he told <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890211-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-11-89 0214EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Quayle     02-11 0383</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quayle,380</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quayle Addresses Human Rights in Domestic Appearances</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, in his first domestic trip as vice president, gave a pair of speeches on human rights and democracy, singling out <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> as needing improvement. In remarks to the Cuban <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> on Friday night, the vice president attacked <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> as `` an obstacle to democracy and human rights for the <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> people and people throughout the region.'' `` It is a country that has compiled a record of brutality and oppression that is without parallel in the history of our hemisphere. And it is a country whose leader has come to personify they tyranny that the rest of <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> is trying to cast off once and for all.'' Similarly, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> attacked <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, accusing the Sandinista government of driving its citizens into exile through repression of freedom, thus causing the massive influx of refugees into <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. He said the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration currently backs the diplomatic efforts ongoing in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> in lieu of military aid to the Contra rebels, but added, `` We will not yield in our determination to end <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s threat to democracy in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said the U.S.-backed government in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> also must do better on human rights. Mentioning his trip to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> last Friday, in which he warned the government and military that their sizable <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid might be jeopardized if the country's human rights record did not improve, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> told the Cuban-American group, `` I believe I succeeded in getting my message across.'' While <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> statistics show that political murders have declined from a high of 750 per month there in 1980 to 18 per month in 1988, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said that figure ` is still unacceptable.'' But <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> blamed the worst human rights abuses in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> on the leftist guerrillas trying to overthrow the democratic government. Earlier in a speech to the Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> reinforced the recent <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> report that faulted <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s armed forces for excessive measures against <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> civilians. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said the number of civilian deaths in the Israeli-occupied <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> were `` clearly unacceptable.'' Still, the vice president promised, the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration wants to strengthen longstanding and close U.S.-Israeli ties.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890211-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-11-89 0110EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-MultipleKillings 3rdLd-Writethru a0832 02-11 0899</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Multiple Killings, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0832,0921</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Jury Returns Guilty Verdict In Slaying Of 14</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 14 grafs to UPDATE with death sentence recommended
and execution date set. Picks up 10th graf pvs, `During the...'.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BILL SIMMONS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CLARKSVILLE, Ark. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A jury found a man guilty of capital murder Friday in the shooting and strangulation deaths of 14 family members then recommended that he be sentenced to die for the killings. <ORGANIZATION> Johnson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON> accepted the recommendation and set an execution day of March 16 for <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> after <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> told the judge he know of no reason why he should not be immediatedly sentenced. <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON>, who already faces the death penalty in two other slayings, did n't visibly react to the verdict or the sentence but several people in the courtroom applauded. Jurors deliberated more than four hours before reaching a verdict, and three hours later announced a sentencing recommendation. They could have recommended life imprisonment with no parole. Prosecuting attorney <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Bynum </PERSON> told the jury that <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> deserved the death penalty because he killed some of the victims to avoid arrest before he completed his plan to kill them all. `` Eye for eye, tooth for tooth, life for life, `` <PERSON> Bynum </PERSON> told the jury. `` That's where we are now in this case. That's old and ancient and hard. But that is what we are down to in this case.'' Defense attorney <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Irwin </PERSON> said <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> did not kill to escape detection. ` His motive was not to avoid arrest, but to satisfy a base, primeval and vile human passion,'' <PERSON> Irwin </PERSON> said in asking the jury to recommend life imprisonment. `` And then we can say a jury stood staunch against an onslaught of publicity,'' <PERSON> Irwin </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON>, 48, has already been sentenced to die for the slayings of two people during a 40-minute shooting rampage on Dec. 28, 1987, in <LOCATION> Russellville </LOCATION>. After his arrest, authorities searching his home near <LOCATION> Dover </LOCATION> found the bodies of <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON>' wife, his seven children, two of the children's spouses, and four grandchildren. They had been all been shot or strangled. As the jury deliberated, <PERSON> Irwin </PERSON> said he had received <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON>' permission to appeal if he was convicted <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> had waived appeal on his earlier conviction. In his closing statement, defense attorney <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> said there was no evidence that placed <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> at his home at the time of the deaths nor any evidence that he personally fired the gun he gave police when he was arrested. <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> told the jury that the state was asking the jury to convict <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> on the basis of circumstantial evidence. <PERSON> Bynum </PERSON> said that the evidence, though circumstantial, was strong, including evidence that <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> was driving his dead son's car when arrested, owned the gun and and had it in his possession. He also said the bodies were found at his house and that the burial of seven bodies and the hiding of two others showed that `` this was not the work of some phantom passer-by.'' During the trial Friday, <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> slugged <PERSON> Bynum </PERSON> in front of the jury, sending spectators shrieking and ducking beneath their seats. Law enforcement officers posted around the courtroom immediately swarmed over <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON>, subdued him and whisked him out a side door. After a recess, <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> was brought back in handcuffs, and the state completed its case early in the afternoon. The defense did not call any witnesses. `` I'm all right,'' said prosecutor <PERSON> Bynum </PERSON>, who was hit on the chin as the attorneys and defendant huddled in conference at the judge's bench `` He just got me one time.'' <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON>, who had immediately ordered the startled jurors removed from the courtroom, brought them back before declaring a recess. `` I want you to set aside what happened in the courtroom just now,'' said <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON>. `` This trial has gone on five days. We want to finish it if we can. You need to disregard the incident that happened here today.'' After the recess, Lt. <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Winters </PERSON> of the Pope County sheriff's office read a five-page note found in <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON>' safety-deposit box in <LOCATION> Russellville </LOCATION> The jammed courtroom was hushed during the eight minutes that <PERSON> Winters </PERSON> needed to enter the statement into evidence. The statement was to <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON>' eldest daughter, <PERSON> Sheila </PERSON> <PERSON> McNulty </PERSON>. She was killed along with her husband and 6-year-old daughter. Family members say <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> had fathered the 6-year-old. `` I told you that your lack of communication with me was going to be your downfall,'' <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> wrote. `` You have destroyed me and in time, you will destroy yourself. `` If you are trying to hurt me, then you should be very proud of yourself, because you have done a very good job of it. You have destroyed me. I do not want D. to set foot on my property. He turned you against me. You want me out of your life. I will be out of your life. I will see you in hell.'' <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> sat with downcast eyes while the statement was read. Shortly after <PERSON> Winters </PERSON> finished, the state rested its case. After a break, the defense said it would stand on its previous motions. In testimony before the morning disruption, firearms expert <PERSON> Burwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Monroe </PERSON> of the state Crime Lab in <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION> testified that a .22 - caliber revolver <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> handed over when he was arrested fired the bullets that killed several of the family
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890211-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-11-89 0220EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Bush 1stLd-Writethru a0405 02-11 0707</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0405,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>President Delays Action on Pay Raise</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 11th graf pvs, bgng Maintained there, to CORRECT rate to
point; picks up 12th graf, ``I would xxx; Prenoon lede unlikely.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MERRILL HARTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KENNEBUNKPORT, Maine (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says he's putting the volatile issue of congressional pay raises on the back burner, delaying any new move until `` the timing is right.'' Chatting with reporters en route to this seacoast resort from a summit in <LOCATION> Ottawa </LOCATION> with Canadian Prime Minister <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said there had been `` a lot of wounds, a lot of hemorrhaging'' on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> over the pay raises. The president said that while he signed <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> legislation rejecting a 51 percent pay raise, he still believes in a substantial increase for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, the federal judiciary and top government executives. Closing out the third full week of his presidency, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Friday: _ Gave <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> personal assurances that he would move as quickly as possible to attack the acid rain pollution problem in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, which also has harmed <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>'s environment But the president gave the Canadian prime minister no precise timetables for reducing sulfur dioxide and nitrogen oxide emissions from coal-burning plants, mostly in the industrial <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he believed <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> was `` reasonably well satisfied'' with his statements on the issue. _ Said he had not talked to Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> about reports that <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> faces a potential conflict-of-interest problem `` I know there is nobody more ethical than <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told reporters aboard <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> One as he headed to his family compound for a weekend of relaxation. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> told reporters in <LOCATION> Ottawa </LOCATION> he is seeking a waiver from ethical requirements so he could continue to hold stock in <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a bank holding company that has lent some $ 4.5 billion to Third World countries. _ Maintained there is no inflation scare in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, despite fresh producer price figures showing a full percentage point increase during January This translated into an annual inflation rate of 12.7 percent. `` I would not make assumptions based on one monthly release,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` And I am not overly concerned about inflation at this point.'' He did say, however, that `` I do n't like the figures.'' _ Said that `` I'm very pleased'' with congressional reaction to the $ 1.16 trillion fiscal 1990 budget he proposed to a joint session of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> acknowledged his plan did not go into detail on what areas of spending should be cut, saying `` there's a big black hole in the budget.'' But he also said that `` I did what I said I'd do: Here's what I want to do.'' He said he was `` certainly conscious of the fact'' that there would be arguments with lawmakers over spending priorities. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> planned a relatively quiet weekend with his wife, <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON>, and other family members. He said he likely would go to church Sunday, and hinted that he might go out jogging, saying that he had been unable to get enough exercise recently because he suffered from a cold. On the lingering question of pay raises for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, judges and senior executives, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> retreated somewhat from his statement of last Wednesday, when he suggested he would propose a new pay package in the wake of the congressional defeat of the 51 percent raise. `` All I can do is make recommendations to the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> about the future legislation,'' he said. But he said that `` I do n't want to do something that'll look like I am simply trying to step into the breach and raise a problem that already has caused a great deal of divisiveness in the Capitol.'' `` That's not what I want to do,'' he said. `` I've got to rely on my people here to make a recommendation to me when I can be effective for the changes that I think are overdue,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` But what you do n't want to do is come in and, when the wounded are still lying on the battlefield, and start fighting another battle,'' he said. `` Let's take a little time. ... I'm not sure the timing is right. I think we've got to let the dust settle over that battlefield.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890211-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-11-89 0222EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WashingtoninBrief     02-11 0312</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Washington in Brief,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Justice Department Charges Operator of Fitness Centers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The operator of <ORGANIZATION> Holiday </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Spa </ORGANIZATION> fitness centers in six states was accused by the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> of discriminating against blacks who seek membership in the exercise clubs. In a civil suit filed in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> here on Friday, the department charged that <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> had instructed its employees to discourage blacks from joining the Holiday Spas and offering less favorable membership terms. The company operates spas in <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> as well as the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>. In one report, the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> found that a manager in Media, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, told employees `` whites wo n't patronize a place if there is a mix of races,'' the report said. A reporter's telephone call seeking comment from the company was not immediately returned.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>Number Of Workers Hired Declines Sharply In January</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Poor weather conditions helped push the number of workers hired by farmers down to an estimated 701,000 in January from 976,000 last October, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said. The report released Friday said `` substantial rains'' occurred during the Jan. 8-14 week when the labor survey was made, from eastern <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> into the middle <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> states. Average pay for all workers hired directly by farmers was $ 5.51 per hour, up from $ 5.18 during last fall's survey week of Oct. 9-15.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>Honey Output Down 7 Percent Last Year</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Honey production dropped 7 percent last year to 212 million pounds. The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said Friday that about 3.2 million colonies produced honey in 1988, a decline of less than 1 percent. But the yield of honey per colony dropped to 66.4 pounds, down from 71.1 pounds in 1987. `` Some states had excellent production while production in other states suffered from drought and disease,'' the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> report said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890211-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-11-89 0226EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     02-11 0413</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0428</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WINONA, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
