<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890919-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-19-89 2342EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Mexico-QuakeAnniversary     09-19 0464</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mexico-Quake Anniversary,0476</SECOND>
<HEAD>Anti-government Demostrations Mark Anniversary of 1985 Quake</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRIS ANGELO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Organizations formed after the 1985 earthquake that killed more than 10,000 people marked the anniversary of the disaster with anti-government demonstrations and memorial services Tuesday. About 250 people from the Sept. 19 Seamstresses Union attended a Mass and then briefly blocked busy <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Abad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION>, where hundreds perished in garment factories that collapsed during the quake. About 50 riot police forced the demonstrators back to the sidewalk, allowing morning rush-hour traffic to resume. Several groups placed flowers at Solidarity Plaza where a hotel burned in the quake. Residents of the <LOCATION> Tlatelolco </LOCATION> housing complex attended a Mass at 7:19 a.m. _ the time the quake collapsed two of the three sections of a 14-story apartment building. Organizations demanding housing for the homeless made a 20-block march to the <LOCATION> Zocalo </LOCATION>, the capital's main plaza, where an estimated 12,000 people gathered for a rally. `` There are more than 2,000 homeless families still living in temporary camps in the Cuahtemoc borough,'' <PERSON> Alejandro </PERSON> <PERSON> Varas </PERSON>, one of the protest organizaers, said in an interview. He said there are about 1,500 housing units promised by the government that have n't been turned over to the quake victims. `` There is open corruption in the delivery. We demand cleanliness in the distribution of housing,'' Varas said. President <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON> raised the flag to half-staff in the Zocalo earlier Tuesday, observed a minute of silence and dedicated a new government hospital that replaced a 12-story building that fell. He said the new <ORGANIZATION> Juarez </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> `` comes out of the tragedy of the September 1985 earthquakes. It is, in essence, a memorial to those who died, and at the same time, shows us that Mexicans can convert adversity into regeneration and above all, permanently maintain the solidarity in benefit of all our countrymen.'' The destroyed hospital was one of two where 19 babies survived in the rubble for from eight hours to nearly nine days before they were rescued. Dehydrated and covered with infected wounds when they were found, the `` miracle babies'' today are active 4-year-olds. The government said 6,000 people perished in the earthquake and an aftershock the next day. Others have placed the death toll as high as 32,000. More than 400 buildings in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, with a population of 18 million, were destroyed and 5,700 damaged, according to the government. The Sept. 19 Seamstresses' Union and the organizations for the homeless were among groups that were organized after the quake. Many have developed into permanent activist groups. In July 1988, leftist political parties with the support of many of the groups made their strongest showing in a Mexican presidential election, holding <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> to just over 50 percent of the vote.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890919-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-19-89 2346EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Hugo-Bahamas     09-19 0525</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hugo-Bahamas,0544</SECOND>
<HEAD>Residents of Bahamas Brace for Hugo's Passage</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NASSAU, Bahamas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Islanders boarded up their homes and bought supplies Tuesday as Hurricane Hugo, blamed in at least 25 deaths, swept along the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION> after leaving an estimated 50,000 people homeless in the eastern <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION>. Weather officials said the hurricane would begin affecting the British colony of Turks and <LOCATION> Caicos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> southeast of the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION> chain on Tuesday night. The storm was moving on a parallel course east of the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION>. `` All of the islands at some time or another are going to get some effects -LRB- from Hugo -RRB-,'' said <PERSON> Noel </PERSON> <PERSON> Risnychok </PERSON>, specialist with the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hurricane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Coral </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gables </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla </LOCATION>. Weather officials in the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION> feared <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> could drift westward toward more populated islands, including <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Providence </LOCATION>. That island, which includes the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION> capital city of <LOCATION> Nassau </LOCATION>, is the most populated with an estimated 135,000 people. The government of the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION> Tuesday downgraded the hurricane watch for the central <ORGANIZATION> Bahamas </ORGANIZATION> to a tropical storm warning. A tropical storm warning remained in effect for the southern <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION>, though it was discontinued for the Turks and <LOCATION> Caicos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>. At 10:30 p.m. EDT Tuesday, the hurricane's center was near latitude 23.8 degrees north and longitude 69.5 west, about 190 miles east northeast of <LOCATION> Grand </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Turk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> in the southern <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION>, according to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> was moving in a northwesterly direction at about 12 miles per hour with its highest sustained winds at 105 mph. Government officials in <LOCATION> Nassau </LOCATION> were monitoring the hurricane but had not made any special preparations Tuesday for Hugo, said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Kalis </PERSON>, press secretary for the government's information office. Residents were told to monitor weather advisories but could go about their daily businesses, he said. `` They were telling everybody to get the water, the lamps handy,'' said <PERSON> Dorothea </PERSON> <PERSON> Seymour </PERSON> <PERSON> of </PERSON> <PERSON> Naussau </PERSON>, who has a stall at The Straw Market on <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION>. `` We never had a storm here for some years. We're always hearing about storms, but they never come. `` Some people worry, some people do n't,'' she said. `` Although the indications are that it's going to move east of the more populated areas, no one is relaxing their vigil because it can change direction,'' <PERSON> Kalis </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Kalis </PERSON> said residents were gathering supplies in preparation. `` The stores have reported brisk sales of supplies such as flashlight batteries and lumber for boarding up windows,'' he said. Weather officials in the <ORGANIZATION> Bahamas </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON>'s threat to the northwestern <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION> has intensified because of the west-northwestern drift that the hurricane is expected to take. `` This westward drift can spell trouble for the northwestern <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION> which includes the bulk of the population,'' said <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Lightbourne </PERSON>, chief meteorological officer for the government's weather agency in <LOCATION> Nassau </LOCATION> Officials with <ORGANIZATION> Paradise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, said they had not changed flight schedules yet, but were monitoring the hurricane's path. `` We're just keeping a close eye on it like everybody else,'' said <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Riesdorph </PERSON>, director of flight operations for the airlines. He said the company makes 11 round-trip flights daily from <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Paradise </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, which is linked by a bridge to <LOCATION> Nassau </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890919-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-19-89 0019EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-QuayleVisit 1stLd-Writethru a0813 09-19 0409</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Quayle Visit, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0813,0416</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vice President Says Exxon Will Be Back</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 4th graf, `The tanker...,' to CORRECT barrels to gallons.
^With AM-Bush Rdp, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROSANNE PAGANO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ANCHORAGE, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> stopped in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> on Monday and reassured officials that cleanup work is not over on the oil-smeared beaches of Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON>. `` The job is not complete,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said during a brief refueling stop en route to <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. `` You have our assurance that we will stay until the job is complete.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was referring to the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>'s role as federal coordinator in <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> Commandant <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Yost </PERSON> has been monitoring <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>'s cleanup work since three weeks after the March 24 wreck of the tanker <PERSON> Exxon </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON>. The tanker spilled nearly 11 million gallons of oil into Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON> after slamming into a reef, resulting in the nation's worst oil spill Exxon declared its summer cleanup finished on Friday. The company said dwindling sunlight and deteriorating weather made further work this year unsafe. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s visit came as President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> visited the <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION> in a swing through <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> defended his decision not to travel to <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, saying he had sent his `` environmental vice president.'' During his visit, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> spent about a half-hour with <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s `` oiled mayors'' _ the mayors of five coastal communities where crude continues to wash up on shore and where fishing fleets generally were tied up for the summer Last May, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> inspected the oil spill cleanup on <LOCATION> Smith </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said Monday it would not surprise him to learn that parts of the island, among the first and hardest hit by the spill, remain oily months after cleanup began. The <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> mayors apparently won no new promises of action from the administration. But <LOCATION> Kodiak </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brodie </PERSON> said <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> seemed to listen to the mayors' concerns about the federal cleanup role next spring. `` We told him the spill's not over just because <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> has completed work and gone,'' <PERSON> Brodie </PERSON> said. The vice president also met briefly with driftnet fishermen, who are concerned about the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's new agreement aimed at restricting driftnet fleets from <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> from fishing the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> for squid. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> fishermen oppose the use of driftnets by foreign fleets because they contend the lightweight nets illegally harvest thousands of tons of salmon and steelhead.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890919-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-19-89 0053EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Namibia     09-19 0263</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Namibia,0270</SECOND>
<HEAD>SWAPO Taken To Court In Dispute Over Missing Detainees</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WINDHOEK, Namibia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Court proceedings were instituted against the leader of the <ORGANIZATION> South-West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Africa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> by a group seeking information about hundreds of people the guerrilla movement allegedly detained. <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nujoma </PERSON>, who returned last week after 30 years in exile, was served with court papers Monday by a deputy sheriff following the legal move by the <ORGANIZATION> Parents </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>. The committee alleged that <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> has failed to account for about 1,400 people who were put to work at guerrilla bases in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> during the movement's 23-year bush war against <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> African rule in neighboring <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> has agreed to grant the territory independence, and <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> is favored to win U.N.-supervised elections in November for an assembly that will draft a constitution. <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> contends that it complied with the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> independence plan by releasing all prisoners in its custody. But the <ORGANIZATION> Parents </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, in documents filed with the territorial <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, claimed 1,400 people either remain in <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> prison camps or have disappeared. The committee called on <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> to account for the whereabouts of the missing people. A <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> delegation is due back in <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> soon after a trip to <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Zambia </LOCATION> to determine whether any prisoners are at <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> camps. According to freed detainees, hundreds of <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> members were accused of being South African spies and many were tortured until they signed confessions. <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> leaders have confirmed incidents of torture, and have countered that the South African-led security forces also were guilty of brutality.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890919-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-19-89 0107EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Soviet-Incentive     09-19 0212</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Incentive,0219</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pay in Foreign Products Inspires Soviets to Work 10 Times Harder</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Berry-pickers in the Soviet Far North gathered ten times as many blueberries and cranberries this year after a Swedish-Soviet firm offered to pay them with foreign fashions and consumer electronics, <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> says. The Soviet news agency reported <PERSON> Mondya </PERSON> that cooperatives in the <LOCATION> Murmansk </LOCATION> area gathered 100 tons of blueberries and 500 tons of cowberries, a type of tundra cranberry, for a Swedish-Soviet joint venture called Artikfryuz. That is ten times the amount they collected in their most productive years. Soviet stores are nearly empty, particularly in provincial towns like <LOCATION> Murmansk </LOCATION>. The few goods often are allocated by privilege, so Soviet workers paid in rubles can find themselves with nothing to buy. Soviet citizens are not allowed to hold foreign currency, and the handful who work for foreign firms receive a fraction of their pay in credit at hard currency stores. The Tass story was the first to indicate that foreign firms might be able to pay Soviets directly with imported consumer goods. The Soviet government also has started an experiment that will pay grain farmers in hard currency for producing extra wheat in hopes of cutting the amount they now import at higher, world-market prices.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890919-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-19-89 0111EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AIDS-Stats     09-19 0220</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS-Stats,0243</SECOND>
<HEAD>CDC Statistics On U.S. AIDS Cases</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest statistics on acquired immune deficiency syndrome in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, as reported by the national Centers for Disease Control:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Number of Cases</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Total cases reported since June 1981: 105,990. Cases, last 12 months: 33,690. Total deaths: 61,655, or 58 percent of all cases.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Transmission Categories</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Homosexual or bisexual males: 63,497, or 60 percent. Intravenous drug abusers: 21,370, or 20 percent. Homosexual male and drug abusers: 7,379, or 7 percent. Heterosexual cases: 4,807, or 5 percent. Transfusion or blood cases: 2,766, or 3 percent. Hemophilia patients: 1,098 or 1 percent. Children of parents with AIDS or at risk: 1,422, or 1 percent. Other or undetermined transmission cause: 3,657, or 3 percent.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Age and Race</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Childhood cases -LRB- under age 13 -RRB-: 1,780, or 2 percent. Cases among whites: 60,040, or 57 percent. Cases among blacks: 28,743, or 27 percent. Cases among Hispanics: 16,182, or 15 percent. Cases among Asians or Pacific Islanders: 638, or 1 percent. Cases among American Indians or Alaskan natives: 141, or 0 percent. -LRB- NOTE: These statistics are through August 1989 and have been rounded to the nearest whole percent. Cumulative totals are for AIDS cases reported since 1981, and include cases subsequently found to have occurred prior to that date. -RRB-
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890919-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-19-89 0111EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APAppointment     09-19 0121</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Appointment,0124</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Correspondent Named in Johnson City, Tenn.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON>, a newswoman in the <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> bureau of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, has been named AP correspondent in <LOCATION> Johnson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn </LOCATION>. The appointment was announced Monday by <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> Chief of <PERSON> Bureau </PERSON> <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> <PERSON> Flanagan </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON>, 27, joined the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> in 1988 and worked in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> before moving to <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> later that year. Previously, she worked at The Union -LRB- <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> and in the <PERSON> Aiken </PERSON>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, bureau of The Augusta -LRB- <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION> -RRB- Chronicle-Herald. She is a native of <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ark. </LOCATION>, and a graduate of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Georgia </ORGANIZATION>. In <LOCATION> Johnson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, she succeeds <PERSON> Leanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, who has been promoted to the General Desk in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890919-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-19-89 0112EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CrashTape-Excerpts     09-19 0477</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Crash Tape-Excerpts,0536</SECOND>
<HEAD>Excerpts of United 232's Cockpit Conversation</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Crash Tape</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are portions of the transcript of <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> Flight 232's cockpit voice recorder released Monday by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. The board put unclear words in parentheses and deleted expletives. At 30 minutes before landing: Unidentified voice: `` Come on baby, come on baby.'' First Officer <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Records </PERSON>: `` What's the hydraulic quantity?'' Second Officer <PERSON> Dudley </PERSON> <PERSON> Dvorak </PERSON>: `` Down to Zero.'' Records: `` On all of them?'' <PERSON> Dvorak </PERSON>: `` All of them.'' Capt. <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON>: `` You got ahold of SAM -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> System </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airline </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maintenance </ORGANIZATION> base in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> -RRB-?'' <PERSON> Dvorak </PERSON>: `` Yeah, I've talked to ` im. <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON>: `` What's he saying?'' <PERSON> Dvorak </PERSON>: `` He's not telling me anything.'' <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON>: `` We're not gon na make the runway, fellas. We're gon na have to ditch this son of a -LRB- expletive deleted -RRB- and hope for the best.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 At 10 minutes: <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON>: `` Level up here.'' <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON> -LRB- after talking on radio: -RRB- `` Right turn, he said ... Well, momma, we'll -LRB- make or miss -RRB- those baseball games after all.'' Records: `` Are you in good and tight? Training officer <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitch </PERSON> -LRB- operating throttles -RRB-: `` I'm not in at all, <PERSON> Bill </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 At 9 minutes: <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON>: `` Back, back.'' Fitch: `` Hold this thing level if you can.'' <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON>: `` Level, baby, level, level.'' <PERSON> Dvorak </PERSON>: `` We're turning now.'' Unidentified: `` More power, more power, give'em more power.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 At 7 minutes: <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON>: `` Come back, come back, all the way back.'' Unidentified, apparently Fitch: `` I ca n't handle that steep of bank, ca n't handle that steep of bank ... Dammit, wish we had n't put that gear down.'' Unidentified: `` Ah, well. -LRB- I did n't ... you know. -RRB-'' Unidentified: `` We do n't know.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 At 6 minutes: <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON>: `` Want to keep turnin' right, want to go to the airport.'' Fitch: `` You want to go to the airport?'' <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON>: `` I want to get as close to the airport as we can.'' Fitch: `` Okay.'' <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON>: `` -LRB- If we have to set this thing in the dirt, we set it in the dirt.'' -RRB-
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 At 4 minutes: <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON>: `` Back, back, back, back ... forward, forward, forward ... Wo n't this be a fun landing?''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 At 2 minutes: Fitch: `` I got the runway if you do n't'' <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON>: `` I do n't. Come back, come back.'' Fitch: `` It's off to the right.'' <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON>: `` Right there, right there.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 The last 30 seconds: <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON>: `` Stop your turn ... Ease the power back, ease the power back.'' Records: `` Maybe you can pull'em all the way off.'' <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON>: `` Left turns, left turns ... close the throttles.'' Records: `` Close'em off.'' <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON>: `` Right turn, close the throttles.'' Records: `` Pull'em -LRB- all -RRB- off.'' Fitch: `` Nah, I ca n't pull'em off or we'll lose it. That's what's turnin' ya. Unidentified: `` Okay.'' Unidentified: `` Okay.'' Records: `` Left, <PERSON> Al </PERSON>. Left throttle, left, left, left, left, left, left, left, left, left, left.'' Unidentified: `` We're -LRB- turnin', turnin', turnin' or tryin', tryin', tryin'. -RRB- Unidentified: `` God.'' Sound of impact.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890919-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-19-89 0114EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ProvincetownAngel     09-19 0735</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Provincetown Angel,0754</SECOND>
<HEAD>Heiress Leaves Estate To Help Town Children Go to College</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALLISON J. PUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PROVINCETOWN, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An heiress who considered residents of this resort town her family worried that the tourist wealth was n't reaching them So when she died, she left an estate of $ 800,000 to help each child go to college. When <PERSON> Celia </PERSON> <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> graduated from <ORGANIZATION> Provincetown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in 1921, she was herself a recipient of a scholarship. <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> reportedly was criticized for taking the money because her family was wealthly and some say she left her fortune to ease the sting of those remarks. <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> used the money to attend <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and went on to become a government lawyer. She returned home in the 1950s to be with her mother and brother, who were all that remained of her immediate family. But soon after her arrival, both died suddenly within two months of each other. <PERSON> Francis </PERSON>, who was unmarried, was left with a substantial inheritance from her father's and brother's real estate business _ much of it was made supplying housing to the artists and writers who made up the first wave of tourists here. Alone, she took on the <LOCATION> Provincetown </LOCATION> community as her new family, said <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, a close friend. `` She always kept her eye on what was happening in the town,'' said <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> on Friday. `` She kept in contact with her friends through an address book. She put down their names, and their children's names, where they went to school _ and it was whole family trees.'' <LOCATION> Provincetown </LOCATION>, at the farthest end of <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cod </LOCATION> from the mainland and about a three hour's drive from <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, is like many seaside resorts: its population, normally around 4,000, swells to more than 10 times that in the summer. Tourist dollars provide a livelihood for many residents, but it's largely seasonal work. `` Most -LRB- young residents -RRB- work in the summertime and collect unemployment benefits in the winter,'' said <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boxer </PERSON>, the high school's guidance counselor. `` There's not a lot of high-paying jobs.'' <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> often talked about how important education was for expanding a person's options, <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> said. In the end, <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> stayed true to her adopted family. She died from cancer in 1983, but her bequest established a fund of almost $ 800,000, enough to offer financial aid of $ 500 to $ 5,000 for every college-bound student. Between 30 and 40 students graduate from <LOCATION> Provincetown </LOCATION> High each year, and more than three-quarters go on to two - and four-year colleges Students say the money encourages them to think about wider options. `` Whereas before maybe some kids ruled out college altogether, maybe now they'll consider it,'' said one recent scholarship recipient on Monday, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>, who used his $ 5,000 award to help pay tuition at <ORGANIZATION> Worcester </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Polytechnic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>. `` I just think more are thinking about going to college,'' said <PERSON> Elmer </PERSON> <PERSON> Silva </PERSON>, who retired in 1985 as the high school's principal. `` And even if they go and only last a year, it's expanding their horizons.'' They are also thinking more about <PERSON> Francis </PERSON>, although she remains something of an enigma even to those who knew her. Dr. <PERSON> Wilsa </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryder </PERSON>, who was <PERSON> Francis </PERSON>' neighbor for the last six years of her life, suggests <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> was trying to repay the community for the scholarship she accepted more than 60 years ago. `` I think that's why she bequeathed this huge amount, in order to pay back that scholarship grant,'' said Ryder, who sits on the committee charged with dispensing the fund. The scholarship program itself is not without controversy. The scholarship committee has come under fire from residents for the way it awards the money, and the amounts it doles out. In the four years that the scholarships have been awarded, less than half of the available interest of about $ 80,000 a year has been handed out. This year' applicants got a total of $ 30,000, and in an irony that might have pained <PERSON> Francis </PERSON>, the committee rejected one student on the basis that aid was not needed. The will stipulated those with need and academic ability get a scholahship, but almost every applicant gets some money. Ryder said that management expenses and the need to add to the principal to keep pace with inflation have cut into the available funding. `` It always sounds like a terrible bundle, but the cost rises each year,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890919-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-19-89 0048EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-TripleHomicide 1stLd-Writethru a0665 09-19 0617</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Triple Homicide, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0665,0629</SECOND>
<HEAD>Teen-Ager Charged with Four Murders Arraigned Amid Death Threats</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Eds: Fixes typo in 2nd graf; INSERTS 1 graf after 8th, `Stabbing
victim...,' to UPDATE with police saying Price implicated himself. ^By
DOUG FISHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WARWICK, R.I. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A teen-ager was arraigned under heavy security Monday in connection with the Labor Day weekend stabbings and beatings of a woman and her two daughters and the death of a woman in 1987. <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON>, 15, entered no plea to four counts of delinquency by first-degree murder and two counts of burglary. Family Court Judge <PERSON> Carmine </PERSON> <PERSON> DiPetrillo </PERSON> ordered Price held at the state <ORGANIZATION> Training </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, a juvenile prison `` for his protection and the protection of the public.'' The judge closed the second floor of the <ORGANIZATION> Kent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Courthouse </ORGANIZATION> to all but reporters, lawyers and police because of `` certain death threats that were made against the defendant.'' DiPetrillo and Attorney General <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neil </PERSON> did not elaborate. Price, a former high school football player known as `` Iron Man'' who was repeating the ninth grade, said nothing during the hearing. His mother, father and older brother attended the hearing but had no comment. `` He gave a statement to the investigating detectives ... which would very strongly implicate himself and no others in both homicides,'' <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON> said at a news conference after the arraignment. About 30 people gathered outside the courthouse, including some of Price's friends who claimed he could not have killed anyone. Price was arrested Sunday at his house, about a block from where <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Heaton </PERSON>, 39, and her daughters, <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON>, 10, and <PERSON> Melissa </PERSON>, 8, were found beaten and stabbed to death in their home Sept. 4. Stabbing victim <PERSON> Rebecca </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON>, 27, who died in July 1987, lived two houses away from Price. `` He gave a statement to the investigating detectives ... which would very strongly implicate himself and no others in both homicides,'' police Chief <PERSON> Wesley </PERSON> <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON> said at a news conference after the arraignment. Some residents of the neighborhood said they had been wary of letting their children play outside because of the killings, and gun dealers and alarm companies reported increased business. <PERSON> DiPetrillo </PERSON> said Price was charged with three counts of deliquency first-degree murder and one count of deliquency burglary in the <PERSON> Heaton </PERSON> killings. He also was charged with one count each of deliquency first-degree murder and burglary in <LOCATION> Spencer </LOCATION>'s killing. <PERSON> O'Neil </PERSON> said that under the state's juvenile laws, Price, if found delinquent, could be held at the <ORGANIZATION> Training </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> only until age 21. The attorney general has been unsuccessfully trying to get the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> to pass legislation allowing juveniles under age 16 who face capital charges to be tried as adults. DiPetrillo set a probable cause hearing for Thursday at which the state must outline its case against Price. Investigators have declined to provide details so far. An autopsy revealed that Ms. <PERSON> Heaton </PERSON> and her daughters had bruises and numerous broken bones, apparently from a struggle with their killer, leading police to speculate the killer might have been cut or injured. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Putnam </PERSON>, 18, who said he lived with the Prices until a few days ago, said Price showed him a cut left index finger when <PERSON> Putnam </PERSON> returned home early on Sept. 2. ` You could see the bone on one side. It was deep,'' <PERSON> Putnam </PERSON> said. Price said he had punched out a car window, he said. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrews </PERSON>, 18, said Price also showed him the cut, but hours before police said they believed the Heatons were killed. Although <PERSON> Andrews </PERSON> described Price as a `` tough and vicious'' lineman on the football team, `` I just do n't think he's capable of it. He's not cold-hearted like that.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890919-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-19-89 0049EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-FosterHomeFire     09-19 0373</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Foster Home Fire,0384</SECOND>
<HEAD>11-Year-Old Charged in Blaze that Killed Four</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An 11-year-old girl has been charged with setting a fire that killed four children at a foster home and injured 12 other people. <PERSON> Lakeya </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartwell </PERSON>, whose half-brother was among the dead in the Aug. 31 blaze, was arrested Sunday and ordered held without bail pending a preliminary hearing Sept. 27. <PERSON> Lakeya </PERSON>, who also lived in the home, was not injured in the fire. She appeared in the arraignment room about 2:30 a.m. Monday without an attorney or any family members present. When Bail Commissioner <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cubbage </PERSON> asked her if she understood the charges, she nodded her head. She was charged with four counts of murder, 11 counts of aggravated assault, 11 counts of simple assault, 11 counts of recklessly endangering another person, one count of arson and one count of risking and causing a catastrophe, police Lt. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON> said. According to an unidentified police source quoted in Monday's editions of The <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> Inquirer, investigators believe <PERSON> Lakeya </PERSON>, just hours before the blaze, told another occupant not to sleep at the house because a fire was going to occur <PERSON> Lakeya </PERSON> also had mentioned a blaze would occur in the house before one of two previous fires, the source said. Police would not speculate on a motive. The fire started about 3 a.m. on Aug. 31 in the six-bedroom stone and frame house where <PERSON> Hubert </PERSON> and <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> <PERSON> Artis </PERSON> had kept foster children since 1972. Gasoline had been poured on an enclosed porch, the living room and stairwell, investigators said. Killed were <PERSON> Lakeya </PERSON>'s half-brother, <PERSON> Anwan </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Reid </PERSON>, 8, and three other children. All were trapped in a second-floor bedroom. Eleven residents of the house and a firefighter were injured. The Artises, both 65, were injured. Authorities described them as `` outstanding foster parents'' but added that too many children were residing in the house. <PERSON> Lakeya </PERSON> had been placed in the home in 1986 by the city <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, police said. She and her half-brother had been taken from their mother, <PERSON> Wanda </PERSON>, 29, because of neglect, said the children's grandfather, <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartwell </PERSON>. Shortly after the fire, he said his daughter had a drug problem and `` would n't take care of the kids.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890919-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-19-89 0120EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-UN-GeneralAssembly Bjt   09-19 0625</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-UN-General Assembly, Bjt,0647</SECOND>
<HEAD>General Assembly Opens; Officials See New Era of Consensus</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Session not scheduled to begin until 3:30 p.m. EDT</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER JAMES SPIELMANN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNITED NATIONS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As the 44th General Assembly opens, diplomats and officials are looking forward to a new era of international cooperation after last year's session saw `` an end to the Cold War.'' In the last two years, the 159 nations have built upon the thaw between the superpowers, addressing in earnest issues such as peacekeeping, pollution and the world economy in a new, cooperative spirit. `` There's a feeling that fundamental changes are happening ... and that now is not the time ... to play up national differences,'' said <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Spiers </PERSON>, the undersecretary for <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION>. `` People want to work together and seek solutions to problems rather than score debating points.'' President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> approved that approach in speeches to the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> last year. Those speeches, said <PERSON> Dante </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Caputo </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, the departing assembly president, `` are the deepest and most eloquent reflection of profound change that has occurred.'' `` They demonstrate, I would venture to say, the end of the Cold War, which hovered over our world for such a long period,'' he said. On Monday, <PERSON> Caputo </PERSON> closed the yearlong 43rd session of the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>. Several unresolved issues were postponed for consideration by the 44th session, which was to begin today. The most dramatic was the Palestinian question and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s crackdown on the 21-month-old uprising in the occupied territories that has left at least 572 Palestinians and 40 Israelis dead. That issue also provoked the biggest controversy of last year's assembly, when the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> refused to allow <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> to enter the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to address the assembly <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> denied him a visa on the grounds that <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> supported terrorism against <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. The General Assembly took the unprecedented protest step of moving to <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> for five days in December to hear the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> chief. At the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> meeting, <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> renounced terrorism and recognized <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s right to exist, eliminating the two key issues on which the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> had refused his visa request. <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> has said he wants to address this year's <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has said it has not yet received a visa request and will not comment on whether it would be granted. <PERSON> Spiers </PERSON>, the top-ranking American in the world body and a former <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> undersecretary, told reporters that <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> should be allowed to speak if he wishes. Arab League Ambassador <PERSON> Clovis </PERSON> <PERSON> Maksoud </PERSON> said he was confident the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration would grant a visa if one was requested. If the visa is not granted, said <PERSON> Maksoud </PERSON>, `` of course we would want to go back to <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> has more than enough allies in the assembly to change its venue. Among speakers scheduled to present their governments' views are President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who is to address the assembly Monday, and Soviet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>, set to speak the following day. President <PERSON> Virgilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> <PERSON> Vargas </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> on Sept. 29 will have a chance to speak about his nation's battle against the cocaine cartels. Other heads of state scheduled to speak include the presidents of <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Zaire </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Lesotho </LOCATION>. The assembly was to choose a new president today. Under a system of rotating regional representation, the African nations nominated the assembly leader this year. They selected <LOCATION> Nigeria </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> ambassador, Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Garba </PERSON>, a crusader against apartheid, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s legal system of racial segregation. The main portion of the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>'s work ends in mid-December, but it will then hold a five-day special session on apartheid.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890919-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-19-89 0104EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-SeattleMayor     09-19 0243</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Seattle Mayor,0249</SECOND>
<HEAD>Voters Chose From 13 Mayoral Candidates in Seattle</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Retransmits a0420 to fix category code</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A city councilman bidding to become the city's first black mayor was considered the frontrunner in Tuesday's mayoral primary, in which 13 candidates are vying to succeed outgoing Mayor <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> Polls showed City Councilman <PERSON> Norm </PERSON> <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> leading the clutch of five political insiders who rose to the top the field. <PERSON> Rice </PERSON>, who lost to <PERSON> Royer </PERSON> four years ago, was a last-minute entry, but quickly emerged the favorite. His likely opponent in November will be either the city attorney or a former King County executive. The two top finishers in the non-partisan election advance to the November election. Among other <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> cities, mayoral primaries will be held in <LOCATION> Spokane </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tacoma </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Royer </PERSON> is not seeking a fourth term and has accepted a top post at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Rice </PERSON>, 46, is a former broadcast reporter, <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> official and a banker. He said he jumped into the fray because of what he called a divisive anti-school busing initiative. The measure will be on the November ballot. Another top candidate, City Attorney <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Jewett </PERSON>, is co-sponsor of the initiative, and backers say he can ride it into the mayor's office A co-favorite for the second runoff spot is <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> Revelle </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> attorney who headed <LOCATION> King </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> government for four years after a stint on the <ORGANIZATION> Seattle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890919-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-19-89 0059EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     09-19 0927</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0965</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIDLAND, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 First lady <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> dedicated the first school named after her husband, then met `` <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>,'' the guinea pig and `` <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>,'' the hermit crab, in kindergarten. It was Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s first visit since the election to the city where she and the president spent 11 years in the 1950s and 1960s. Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was in <LOCATION> Midland </LOCATION> on Monday to dedicate <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> H.W </PERSON>. Bush Elementary School. After a brief ceremony, she visited the 36 children in the school's two kindergarten classes. `` What's his name?'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> asked one of the kindergarten students as she pointed at a brown and white guinea pig in a glass tank. A little boy told her the name. `` Oh!'' she said, raising her eyebrows in feigned shock. `` <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>!'' Then she walked over to another tank containing a hermit crab and said, `` I'm not going to ask who the crab's named after.'' She was told that the crab's name was `` <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>VIRGINIA BEACH, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Television correspondent <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Walters </PERSON> says women can not have it all _ career, marriage and children _ and she pointed to herself as an example. `` You can have a great marriage and great children; great marriage and great career; great career and great children. But I think it is so hard to have a great marriage, a great career, not a job but a career, and great children,'' Ms. <PERSON> Walters </PERSON> told the `` Virginia Woman'90s'' conference sponsored by Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Va </LOCATION>. She advised the 2,100 women in the audience Monday not to feel guilty if they have trouble meeting the demands of career and family, and admitted it has n't been so easy for her `` I've been divorced. I have a daughter, who, thank God, is 21 and out of her adolescence,'' said the 57-year-old <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> correspondent and star of the `` 20-20'' show. Ms. <PERSON> Walters </PERSON> advised the women to have a life beyond getting up in the morning and going to work, `` although that can be pretty wonderful and intoxicating.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Todd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bridges </PERSON> got engaged to his 23-year-old girlfriend while he was in jail on charges he shot and wounded a man in a reputed drug den, according to a publicist. Bridges, who played <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>'s older brother on television's `` Diff ` rent Strokes,'' proposed marriage to <PERSON> Becky </PERSON> <PERSON> San </PERSON> <PERSON> Filipo </PERSON>, according to the publicist who spoke on condition The date of the engagement was not revealed, the agent said Monday. Bridges, 24, remains in jail on $ 2 million bail awaiting trial on charges he shot <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Clay </PERSON>, 25, on Feb. 2 in a <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> home authorities alleged was used as a gathering place for people to smoke `` crack'' cocaine. Clay survived the shooting. Bridges has pleaded innocent to attempted murder charges.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Dravecky </PERSON>, the baseball pitcher who came back from cancer in his throwing arm, has won the 1989 <ORGANIZATION> Willie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mac </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Award </ORGANIZATION> as the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Giants </ORGANIZATION>' most inspirational player. The award, voted by the <ORGANIZATION> Giants </ORGANIZATION>' players, was announced Monday. <PERSON> Dravecky </PERSON>, 34, underwent surgery in October to remove a cancerous tumor located in a muscle near his left shoulder. After months of therapy and a minor league rehabilitation stint, he returned to the mound Aug. 10 at <LOCATION> Candlestick </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> and pitched eight innings to earn a 4-3 victory over <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>. Five days later in <LOCATION> Montreal </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dravecky </PERSON> broke a bone in his upper left arm while making a pitch to the Expos' <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Raines </PERSON>. He got the victory to finish the year with a 2-0 record and a 3.46 earned run average. <PERSON> Dravecky </PERSON>, the 10th winner of the award named for Giants Hall of <PERSON> Famer </PERSON> <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> McCovey </PERSON>, will receive this year's plaque from McCovey on Sunday. The award recognizes inspiration, courage, leadership, character and dedication in the tradition of <PERSON> McCovey </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PARK CITY, Utah (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Everett </PERSON> <PERSON> Koop </PERSON>, who is leaving his post as <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> surgeon general, has been elected to the board of the non-profit <ORGANIZATION> Medic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alert </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Koop </PERSON>, who leaves his government post of seven years on Oct. 1, was selected by the <LOCATION> Turlock </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, board during its meeting here Sunday, said Medic Alert President <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Harms </PERSON>. <PERSON> Koop </PERSON>, who has been outspoken on issues such as smoking, environmental hazards and AIDS, did not attend the meeting. Harms said that adding <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> to the board was `` a great honor.'' Medic Alert provides medical information to emergency personnel 24 hours a day on its records hotline.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>OTTAWA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ballet dancer <PERSON> Rudolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Nureyev </PERSON>, who recently leaped into the musical theater with `` The King and I,'' said he has no qualms about taking over a role dominated for years by one actor _ the late <PERSON> Yul </PERSON> <PERSON> Brynner </PERSON>. `` I've never been intimidated by anything,'' <PERSON> Nureyev </PERSON> told reporters Monday. `` I danced ` Giselle.' <LOCATION> Nijinsky </LOCATION> danced ` Giselle,''' he said, referring to the late <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> dancer <PERSON> Vaslav </PERSON> <PERSON> Nijinsky </PERSON>, considered one of the best dancers of all time. <PERSON> Nureyev </PERSON>, 51, plays the role of the king of <LOCATION> Siam </LOCATION> in the revival of the <PERSON> Rodgers </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hammerstein </PERSON> hit, with British actress <PERSON> Liz </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> playing his <PERSON> Anna </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Ottawa </LOCATION> is the second stop of a tour that began in <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION> last month. <PERSON> Nureyev </PERSON>, who has been artistic director of the <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> Opera Ballet since 1983, said he's enjoying the musical, in which he sings a couple of songs and must pretend he does n't know how to polka for the famous `` Shall We Dance'' number. `` I enjoy it very much, yes, I do. It's not as hard as dancing.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890919-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-19-89 0301EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--GunmanArrested     09-19 0154</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Gunman Arrested,0158</SECOND>
<HEAD>Armed Man Arrested, Tragedy Averted</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A former employee armed with a revolver and five Molotov cocktails was arrested outside <LOCATION> Northwestern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Memorial </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, where he intended to stage a massacre, police said. <PERSON> Connell </PERSON> <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON>, 31, was angry about his forced resignation last year as emergency room clerk, police said. `` We learned from him that he intended to go in and kill everybody in the hospital,'' said police Lt. <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Logan </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON> was armed with a .357 - caliber Magnum, more than 40 rounds of ammunition, and five bottles of alcohol rigged so they could be lit and thrown, authorities Police said <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON> walked into the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> offices on Monday after mistaking it for the hospital's offices. He was given directions at the <ORGANIZATION> ABA </ORGANIZATION> but was stopped by police before reaching the hospital. <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON> was being held in a lockup while investigators determined the specific charges, police said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890919-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-19-89 0104EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BoxOffice     09-19 0461</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Box Office,0481</SECOND>
<HEAD>Universal Sweeps Top Three</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN HORN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Sea of Love,'' `` Uncle Buck'' and `` Parenthood'' gave <ORGANIZATION> Universal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studios </ORGANIZATION> a sweep of the top three spots at the nation's box offices last weekend. The last time a studio did that was in January 1987, when <ORGANIZATION> Paramount </ORGANIZATION> grabbed the top spots with `` Critical Condition,'' `` Star Trek IV'' and `` The Golden Child.'' The fall movie season is off to a strong start, with the top 16 titles collecting $ 37.2 million, $ 10 million more than the top 18 movies a year ago. Led by the <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Pacino-Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Barkin </PERSON> romantic thriller `` Sea of Love,'' with a record fall opening of $ 10 million, Universal's films accounted for nearly 50 percent of the over-all domestic theater gate, the studio said. Universal has held the No. 1 box-office spot for seven-straight weeks. Finishing in second last weekend with $ 4.1 million in ticket sales was `` Uncle Buck,'' a comedy starring <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Candy </PERSON> as a maladroit babysitter. In third was the family comedy `` Parenthood,'' with <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Robards </PERSON>, on grosses of $ 3.7 million. `` When <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Met </PERSON> <PERSON> Sally </PERSON> ...,'' the story of best friends who become lovers, landed in fourth with $ 2.7 million. In fifth was the martial-arts adventure `` Kickboxer,'' which netted $ 2.6 million. The action sequel `` Lethal Weapon 2'' was next, with $ 2.206 million. In seventh, with $ 2.15 million, was the underwater suspense tale `` The Abyss.'' Rounding out the top 10 were `` sex, lies and videotape'' with $ 1.75 million, `` Turner and Hooch'' on $ 1.66 million, and `` Batman'' with $ 1.5 million. `` Batman'' has now grossed more than $ 243 million, passing `` Raiders of the Lost Ark'' to become the fifth biggest smash in <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> history. Here are the top movies for the weekend as tallied by <ORGANIZATION> Exhibitor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>: 1. `` Sea of Love,'' Universal, $ 10 million weekend gross, 1,246 screens, $ 8,040 per screen, $ 10 million total gross, one week in release. 2. `` Uncle Buck,'' Universal, $ 4.1 million, 1,817 screens, $ 2,270 per screen, $ 45.88 million, five weeks. 3. `` Parenthood,'' Universal, $ 3.7 million, 1,392 screens, $ 2,680 per screen, $ 74.5 million, seven weeks. 4. `` When <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Met </PERSON> <PERSON> Sally </PERSON> ...,'' <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2.65 million, 1,171 screens, $ 2,680 per screen, $ 75.3 million, 10 weeks. 5. `` Kickboxer,'' Cannon, $ 2.6 million, 973 screens, $ 2,677 per screen, $ 7.9 million, two weeks. 6. `` Lethal Weapon 2,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2.206 million, 1,393 screens, $ 1,583 per screen, $ 137.9 million, 11 weeks. 7. `` The Abyss,'' 20th Century <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, $ 2.15 million, 1,361 screens, $ 1,580 per screen, $ 47.6 million, six weeks. 8. `` sex, lies and videotape,'' <PERSON> Miramax </PERSON>, $ 1.75 million, 397 screens, $ 4,411 per screen, $ 13.2 million, seven weeks. 9. `` Turner & amp; Hooch,'' <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.66 million, 1,371 screens, $ 1,214 per screen, $ 62 million, eight weeks. 10. `` Batman,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.5 million, 1,080 screens, $ 1,363 per screen, $ 243.1 million, 13 weeks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890919-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-19-89 0131EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     09-19 0586</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0610</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STURGIS, S.D. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Norbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, who keeps his <ORGANIZATION> Cessna </ORGANIZATION> 150 in a pasture, says he will add one more item to his preflight inspection. `` I'm definitely adding ` snake' to my checklist,'' said the <PERSON> Sturgis </PERSON> pilot, who came face-to-face with a 1 -LCB- - foot-long bull snake while cruising comfortably at 800 feet Friday night <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Rovere </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Black </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hawk </LOCATION> were about 10 miles north of <LOCATION> Sturgis </LOCATION>, a western <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> community, when the snake popped its head up through a hole in the dashboard, about 2 feet in front of their faces. `` He was hissing and sticking his tongue out at us,'' <PERSON> Rovere </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> reached for a rag, grabbed the snake and threw it out the window. `` Stuff just flew everywhere. It was a mess,'' <PERSON> Rovere </PERSON> said. `` After it was over, we got quite a chuckle out of it,'' said <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>. He figures the snake crawled up the tail assembly, through the fuselage and into the engine compartment. The bull snake is nonpoisonous and feeds mostly on rodents.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>EL TORO, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Koravos </PERSON> and <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Guzzetta </PERSON>, Interstate 5 is their freeway of love. The two said `` I do'' Sunday while parked in a stretch limousine on the freeway. It was an appropriate spot: The couple first met on the interstate three years ago. `` I was driving along, heading south on I-5, and I could just feel this car tailing me,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Koravos </PERSON>. `` So I pulled into the other lane and looked over to give this person a dirty look.'' Instead, she found herself grinning at a winking <PERSON> Guzzetta </PERSON>. He motioned to her to pull off. She did, and they went out for a drink. They discovered that a mutual business acquaintance had suggested two days before that the two get together to discuss the direct mail business, which Ms. <PERSON> Koravos </PERSON> was in at the time and <PERSON> Guzzetta </PERSON> was considering entering. `` I tell my friends to forget the single bars,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Koravos </PERSON>. `` If you're looking for the right person, just drive on the freeways ... and smile.'' <PERSON> Guzzetta </PERSON>, who eventually bought a direct-mail firm, also took an unusual approach in his marriage proposal. He sent her a package of direct-mail ads, including one that asked, `` Dear <PERSON> Joan </PERSON>, will you please marry me? <PERSON> Larry </PERSON>.'' Ms. <PERSON> Koravos </PERSON> answered by calling a <LOCATION> Newport </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> restaurant that night and asking the maitre d' to write on the portable menu board, along with the specials, `` Yes, <PERSON> Larry </PERSON>, I will.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ARLINGTON, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Cruse </PERSON> is happy he does n't have to take the Scholastic Aptitude Test again. After all, there's no way to improve on his perfect 1,600 score. `` I can concentrate on some other things now,'' he said. <PERSON> Cruse </PERSON> was one of only 14 students in the nation who achieved a perfect score on the SAT during the 1988-89 school year. About 1.8 million took the multiple-choice test, and the national average score of verbal and mathematical reasoning was 903. Most students wait until their senior year to take the college entrance exam. <PERSON> Cruse </PERSON> did it as a sophomore. `` There really is no secret,'' said <PERSON> Cruse </PERSON>, now a 16-year-old junior at <ORGANIZATION> Martin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. `` The test includes material that's covered in class And I have to study just like other students.'' <PERSON> Cruse </PERSON>'s class schedule this semester includes Latin II, pre-calculus, physics, English, history and biology. All but Latin II are advanced classes. He said he was thinking about going to <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> as a prelaw major.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890919-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-19-89 0137EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Bootmaker     09-19 0457</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bootmaker,0475</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bootmaker Appeals to Professional Cowboys, Yuppies</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By J.L. SCHMIDT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ELLSWORTH, Neb. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man who spent 20 years on the rodeo circuit now makes his living making boots and other items that fit the special needs of professional cowboys. And a few yuppies who would like to look like professional cowboys. <PERSON> Veldon </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, his wife and two sons, run the <ORGANIZATION> Old </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Spade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Store </ORGANIZATION> that greets visitors to this community of about two-dozen people in the heart of the <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Panhandle </LOCATION>. Handmade Morgan boots, which line the walls of the rustic store built in 1869, run from $ 119 to $ 750, excluding custom orders. The newest boot, a lace-up roper, was the brainchild of the 54-year-old <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> and a professional rodeo friend and customer. `` Regular cowboy boots have a somewhat flimsy shaft,'' explained <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Veldon </PERSON>'s son and general manager. `` Professional ropers complain that when they step, jump or fly off a horse it's easy to twist an ankle in conventional boots. A U-shaped toe and a block heel make the new lace-up boots working boots bound to be a hit with cowboys. `` The professional rodeo cowboy is a honed athlete, but they've always had to dress like a ranch cowboy,'' the elder <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> said Monday `` To send them into the rodeo arena dressed like a ranch cowboy is like sending a boxer into the ring wearing cowboy boots,'' said <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, who was on the professional rodeo circuit for 20 years. `` The guy with the boxing shoes would beat the other guy every time.'' The company also has found a new market: `` one we'd never expect, among yuppies on the coasts,'' his son said. `` The idea of a lace-up cowboy boot must just appeal to them.'' So, apparently, does the gear used to carry coiled ropes and boots and saddles, he said. `` We've expanded the nylon luggage line into a whole area of backpacking, horsepacking and camping equipment as well,'' <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> said. More than 40 people work in the large manufacturing plant and warehouses attached to the store. The complex has been expanded twice as the business has grown, <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> said. Last spring, the company bought the <ORGANIZATION> Laramie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boot </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and some manufacturing is done in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Handmade saddles ranging from $ 895 to $ 2,000 have become another staple of the business. It takes 15 hours to assemble a plain saddle's 25 to 30 parts, <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> said. Craftsmen work at individual booths in the factory, concentrating on one saddle at a time. `` We've tried to make things that are needed,'' <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> said. `` Somebody made lace-up boots back in the'30s and then quit. We decided to pick it up again. It's a new frontier out there.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890919-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-19-89 0121EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-AIDS-Children Bjt   09-19 0622</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS-Children, Bjt,0642</SECOND>
<HEAD>AIDS Drugs Showing Promising Initial Results in Children</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RAEBURN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Editor</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOUSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Long-term studies with AZT show the AIDS drug can reverse many symptoms of the disease in children while avoiding side effects, researchers say. The drug previously has been shown to extend the lives of adults with AIDS and to delay the development of symptoms in those who are infected but not yet sick. A year ago, <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cancer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> scientists reported it could prevent brain abnormalities in children, but concerns about its side effects remained. The most extensive study of AZT in children now shows it is safe, helps children gain weight and avoid life-threatening infections, and improves their well-being, says <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> <PERSON> McKinney </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Duke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>. The study, part of a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> project to assess AZT in children, was reported Monday at a meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Microbiology </ORGANIZATION>. At the same time, AZT's maker, <ORGANIZATION> Burroughs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wellcome </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Triangle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, announced it was cutting the wholesale price of the drug by 20 percent, from $ 1.50 to $ 1.20 per capsule. A year's supply has been costing patients $ 7,000 to $ 8,000 In other studies reported here, <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cancer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> researchers said they had obtained promising initial results with two newer AIDS drugs, called ddI and ddC. The drugs helped restore some brain function to a few children out of several dozen tested, without causing dangerous side effects, said Dr. <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Pizzo </PERSON>, the institute's chief of pediatrics. A 32-month-old boy who had lost the ability to stand and walk and was losing his speech _ all because of an AIDS infection in the brain _ stood, began walking with help and began to speak more clearly after being given ddI, said Dr. <PERSON> Karina </PERSON> <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> of the cancer institute. About one-third of the children given ddI and ddC showed signs that their AIDS-damaged immune systems were at least partially restored. Furthermore, both the new drugs seem to work well in combination with AZT, said <PERSON> Pizzo </PERSON>. `` That seems to us to be an area worthy of study,'' he said. `` We're on the lookout for agents that can be put into combination regimens.'' The combination may, as is the case with cancer drugs, reduce side effects while increasing efficacy, <PERSON> Pizzo </PERSON> explained. One child in the study, for example, could not tolerate regular doses of AZT without serious side effects but is now doing well on an alternating combination of AZT and ddC. Twelve of 35 children required blood transfusions to counteract anemia caused by AZT's toxic effects on their bone marrow, <PERSON> McKinney </PERSON> said. Some also showed low white blood cell counts. But those side effects were considered manageable. Only five of the patients developed the so-called opportunistic infections that often kill AIDS patients. The children ranged from 5 months to 13 years old. Ten were younger than age 2. `` It's looking more and more that that's who's going to be getting it among kids,'' <PERSON> McKinney </PERSON> said Giving it to children early may delay the development of serious brain disorders, which occur in about 80 percent of children with AIDS, <PERSON> McKinney </PERSON> said. Determining when to give AZT to children will be difficult, however, because studies have shown that AIDS can be quite different in children and adults, <PERSON> McKinney </PERSON> said. `` It may be that children need to start earlier and get higher doses,'' he said. For example, AIDS does n't usually appear in adults until their T4-cell count, a measure of the immune system's health, drops below 500. Adults with a T4-cell count above 500 are usually healthy. `` That's not a valid number for children,'' said <PERSON> McKinney </PERSON>. `` All of us have lost kids who have had T4 counts above 1,000.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890919-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-19-89 0209EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-KingDay     09-19 0583</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-King Day,0602</SECOND>
<HEAD>Arizona Senators Face Martin Luther King Day Bill Again</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY LOPEZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHOENIX (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Backers of a holiday to honor assassinated civil rights leader <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> are hoping the prospect of a Super Bowl can succeed where convention boycotts and bad publicity failed. `` Without a holiday, there is little chance in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> for a Super Bowl,'' House Minority Leader <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>, a Democrat who leads the pro-holiday forces, said Monday. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Shover </PERSON>, a newspaper executive who heads the booster group <ORGANIZATION> Phoenix </ORGANIZATION> 93, agreed. `` We feel sure if we do n't have a King holiday we wo n't be on a level playing field for the'93 Super Bowl,'' said <PERSON> Shover </PERSON>, director of community and corporate services for <ORGANIZATION> Phoenix </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspapers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, publishers of The <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Phoenix </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gazette </ORGANIZATION>. The issue comes up as part of a special session that begins Wednesday on prison crowding, drugs and economic development, and both sides are squirming already. `` If we fail again, the frustration level ... will rise,'' <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> said. But Senate President <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Usdane </PERSON>, a Republican who wants the issue referred to a general election ballot, said the bill is not appropriate for a special session. `` With a special session, you want to get out quickly,'' Usdane said. `` You do n't need controversy in a special session.'' The Republican-controlled House has voted for a King holiday in the past, but conservative <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republicans </ORGANIZATION> have defeated the proposal. The fight has been going on for years. Democratic Gov. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON>, then about to launch a presidential campaign and frustrated by lack of progress on the King issue, signed an executive proclamation in 1986 giving state employees the day off. Republican state Attorney General <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Corbin </PERSON> declared that <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON> lacked authority to issue such an order, however. <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON>'s successor, Republican <PERSON> Evan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON>, rescinded the proclamation before it could take effect <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> also said he did not believe that King deserved a holiday, and civil rights groups launched a boycott of the state as a convention site. <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON>'s impeachment in April 1988 on unrelated charges brought Secretary of State Rose Mofford to power as governor. Mrs. <PERSON> Mofford </PERSON>, a Democrat, has pledged to do whatever is necessary for a King holiday. But while Mrs. <PERSON> Mofford </PERSON> has lobbied quietly for the bill since then, most <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republicans have held fast against it. A recent study estimates the state has lost $ 256 million in convention and tourist business since <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON>'s order, and some Super Bowl boosters say <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>'s bid for the 1993 game is doomed if there's no holiday. But some <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republicans say the holiday is a slap in the face to <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> because it would follow the federal practice of combining holidays for <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> and <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON> into a single holiday in exchange for a state holiday honoring King. Some <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> senators have offered to vote for a bill that would trade in Columbus Day for King Day. But Mrs. <PERSON> Mofford </PERSON> said she rejects that option, and <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> lawmakers say they would prefer to avoid it, even though they consider it a possibility. Religious leaders and business executives have been urging approval of the King holiday for years, but <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> lawmakers say their constituents do n't agree. Furthermore, they note, many of the businesses that are pushing for the holiday do n't even give their own employees the day off. `` They ought to take a look in the mirror,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Todd </PERSON>, a Republican who is among those targeted by the executives.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890919-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-19-89 0158EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Long-PlayVideocassettes Bjt   09-19 0544</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Long-Play Videocassettes, Bjt,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>10-Hour Videocassette Tapes on the Way</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAY ARNOLD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tired of all those videocassettes cluttering up your house? Would n't it be nice to be able to tape 10 favorite TV soaps or five or six movies on one cassette? How about 30 hours of recording per cassette? West German videocassette manufacturer <ORGANIZATION> BASF </ORGANIZATION> says that by 1991 it will be offering <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> viewers a tape with a 10-hour capacity. Meanwhile, a Finnish company, <ORGANIZATION> Nokia </ORGANIZATION>, says it has developed a new technology allowing a new line of VHS recorders to cram those 10 hours onto a tape without the loss of picture quality that results when today's VCRs are cranked down to their slowest speeds. `` The picture quality is better than existing long-play systems,'' <ORGANIZATION> Nokia </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Lauri </PERSON> <PERSON> Kivinen </PERSON> said in a telephone interview last week. <ORGANIZATION> Nokia </ORGANIZATION>, a major manufacturer of television sets in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, hopes to license its new technology to VCR manufacturers and the new recorders could be on the market sometime in 1990, <PERSON> Kivinen </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> BASF </ORGANIZATION> tape will be usable on existing videocassette recorders. <ORGANIZATION> BASF </ORGANIZATION> will use a superstrong, thin polyester film to pile more tape into each videocassette, according to the Sept. 11 issue of TV Digest, which reviewed the new <ORGANIZATION> Nokia </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> BASF </ORGANIZATION> products at the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Audio-Visual Fair. The <ORGANIZATION> BASF </ORGANIZATION> cassette will allow up to 15 hours of taping on VCRs with a European system that uses a slower speed than <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> videocassette recorders. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> VCRs provide two hours of recording at normal speed on a standard cassette. American VCRs also have a half-speed, long-play mode that allows four hours of recording, and a one-third, extended-play speed that allows six hours of recording. The higher the taping speed, the better the image quality. <ORGANIZATION> Nokia </ORGANIZATION> says it has found a way to record at a speed equivalent to the extended-play mode while maintaining image quality that is better than long-play mode. <PERSON> Kivinen </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> Nokia </ORGANIZATION> hopes its system will become the new standard for VCRs. TV Digest quoted the system's inventor, <ORGANIZATION> Nokia </ORGANIZATION> engineer <PERSON> Gerd </PERSON> <PERSON> Reime </PERSON>, as saying that although no tests have been conducted, 30 hours of taping may be possible using his new technology. <PERSON> Reime </PERSON> said the new circuitry could cost as little as $ 3 to incorporate into new VCRs. <ORGANIZATION> BASF </ORGANIZATION> has been testing its new super long-play tape for about a year and will introduce it in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> this fall, according to <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Neidhart </PERSON>, director of marketing at <ORGANIZATION> BASF </ORGANIZATION>'s information systems division in <LOCATION> Bedford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>. `` By 1991 we expect to offer the 10-hour tape in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Neidhart </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> BASF </ORGANIZATION> already markets a videocassette in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> that allows eight hours of taping at slow speed. But the tape has captured only a small percentage of the blank videocassette market, which is approaching 300 million units in annual sales, <PERSON> Neidhart </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> BASF </ORGANIZATION> launched a national television ad campaign last month to try to boost sales for the eight-hour tape. `` We know from research that most people would like to use a longer tape for some or all of their recording purposes,'' <PERSON> Neidhart </PERSON> said, noting that it means viewers wo n't run out of tape too soon and that the tapes will take up less space in their video libraries.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890919-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-19-89 0216EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Hungary Bjt   09-19 0639</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Hungary, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Moves Toward Closer Economic Ties With Hungary</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration plans to boost <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s trade status following a series of steps viewed by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials as progress on economic and political issues by the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact nation. `` <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> has undertaken major steps toward economic and political reform,'' leading to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> plan to grant most-favored nation status to the Eastern European communist state, President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said on Monday. Speaking at a news conference in <LOCATION> Helena </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mont. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the move `` will open new doors for the <LOCATION> Hungarian </LOCATION> economy, encouraging greater market orientation and increasing the foreign exchange earnings.'' That and other initiatives were announced Monday by <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON>, who was in <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION> for talks with Hungarian officials. Meanwhile, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> today quoted <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s new parliament speaker, <PERSON> Matyas </PERSON> <PERSON> Szuros </PERSON>, as saying he sees the possibility that his nation could withdraw from the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact and become neutral by the end of the century. <PERSON> Szuros </PERSON> said the shift to neutrality could take place `` within a climate of trust'' between <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. The package announced by <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON> also includes new development programs and the establishment of a $ 25 million fund to help create private business in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. The proposals are part of a comprehensive pact to `` support <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s efforts to develop a freer political system and to create and expand private enterprise,'' said <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON>. The White House released <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s letter to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in which he said `` it is my intent to add <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> to the list'' of countries that qualify for most-favored nation status, which would guarantee <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> the lowest tariffs for its products that any competing country gets. <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> recently defied authorities in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> by allowing thousands of East German citizens to use <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> as a conduit to emigrate to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. In May, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> tore down the barbed wire fence that had sharply restricted travel by Hungarians to the West. According to his spokeswoman, the only foreign gift that Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> keeps in his office is a piece of the fence which Hungarian officials gave him during his visit to <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> in July. The administration also attaches significance, officials said, to the withdrawal of some Soviet troops from <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> in recent months, part of a commitment by Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to reduce overall troop levels in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. Monday's announcement came four days after <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s decision to double food aid to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> _ another <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pact </ORGANIZATION> member _ to $ 100 million in the next fiscal year. Many in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> had criticized <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for not doing more for <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> following the accession of a non-communist premier in <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION>. There has been less pressure for an increase in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cooperation with <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> because <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s economic situation is far bleaker than <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s. <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON> said the $ 25 million to help develop private business in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> `` is an important part of implementing President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s goal of building an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> partnership with <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. He said <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> will be granted permanent most-favored trade status in October if its parliament, as expected, enacts legislation on freedom of emigration by the end of September. <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON> also said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is notifying <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> of his intention to designate <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> as eligible for Generalized System of Preferences treatment, which would offer Hungarian exporters duty-free tariff treatment for a broad range of exports to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> worth more than $ 110 million. Meanwhile, <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, complained Monday that the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration has n't moved quickly enough to support East European communist nations _ such as <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> _ that are moving toward democratic change. `` The administration's timidity in the face of these opportunities is puzzling and dismaying,'' <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. `` Instead of encouragement and engagement, the administration has adopted an almost passive stance.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890919-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-19-89 0218EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Yeltsin Bjt   09-19 0726</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Yeltsin, Bjt,710</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Sponsor Denies Accusation of Yeltsin Drunkenness</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The American who sponsored <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>'s tour of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> strongly denies accusations published by a Soviet newspaper that the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> maverick was publicly drunk for much of the trip `` If there was any problem with <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>, it was jet lag,'' said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Garrison </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Esalen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Soviet-American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Program </ORGANIZATION>, which sponsored the nine-day, 11-city tour. `` Most of the time he was cold sober.'' Pravda, organ of the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, on Monday reprinted an article from the Italian newspaper <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republica </ORGANIZATION> saying <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> was repeatedly drunk during the tour and squandered his lecture fees shopping. <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> `` leaves behind him a wake of catastrophic prophecies, insane expenses, interviews, and above all the perfume of <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Daniels </PERSON> Black label,'' said the article, translated into Russian. Pravda did not comment on the article, but advertised it in a front-page box that said <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> found the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> `` a holiday, a stage, a bar 5,000 kilometers long.'' <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>, interviewed as he arrived back in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> from the trip, called the report `` garbage.'' `` It's a simple lie, slander and revenge for the fact that Americans received us with admiration,'' he said, flushing with anger. The Pravda article clearly reflected Kremlin anger at <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>'s criticism of Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and other top leaders While in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> said <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> had made mistakes and faced a potential revolution from Soviet citizens dissatisfied with the pace of reform. <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> was dumped from his job as <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> party chief and his post on the ruling Politburo for making similar comments in late 1987. But <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> voters overwhelmingly elected him to the newly constituted <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peoples </ORGANIZATION>' Deputies last March. Before leaving <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> `` predicted the knives would be out on his return,'' said <PERSON> Garrison </PERSON>, who accompanied him throughout the tour. `` What Pravda has done is for political motivations,'' said <PERSON> Garrison </PERSON>. Asked to comment on reports that <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> drank a bottle and a half of whiskey the night before he spoke in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> last Tuesday, <PERSON> Garrison </PERSON> said: `` He certainly did not finish off a bottle and a half of <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Daniels </PERSON>. The entire delegation of five Soviets drank a bottle. But for five Soviet men to drink a bottle of <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Daniels </PERSON>, that's normal That's the culture. Soviets tend to drink a lot.'' <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> suffered from jet lag and a hectic schedule, and by the time he spoke in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Garrison </PERSON>, `` he had not slept for three nights.'' <PERSON> Garrison </PERSON> said he personally called off a scheduled appearance by <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> on the <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION> program `` Nightline,'' to be taped last Monday, the afternoon before the <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> speech. `` I canceled it because he was jet-lagged. He was just dropping,'' <PERSON> Garrison </PERSON> said in an interview in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. On the day the appearance was canceled, <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> had no alcohol, said <PERSON> Garrison </PERSON>. <PERSON> Garrison </PERSON> also denied that <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> had blown his lecture fees on a shopping spree. On Sunday night, <PERSON> Garrison </PERSON> said, he and <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> signed an agreement to use the proceeds of the lecture tour `` toward eradicating AIDs in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>.'' <LOCATION> Esalen </LOCATION>, based in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, is a non-profit institution that deals in exchange programs with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. The fund will ship `` $ 100,000 worth of medical equipment to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, primarily in the form of disposable syringes,'' said <PERSON> Garrison </PERSON>. `` All the bills are not in yet, but he is going to earn roughly $ 20,000 to $ 40,000'' from the lecture tour, said <PERSON> Garrison </PERSON>. `` The gross was close to $ 160,000 to $ 170,000.'' The speakers' bureau will take 30 percent, and much of the balance will pay the costs of the nine-person entourage. <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> `` will accept none of the proceeds. All of the proceeds will go to buy medical equipment,'' said <PERSON> Garrison </PERSON>. The AIDs program will be run by <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>'s parliamentary office in the Moskva Hotel off Red Square and by the <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Innovation </ORGANIZATION>, which has offices in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. `` We gave him $ 100 a day as a per diem. So he had $ 900 of personal money. That is all he had,'' said <PERSON> Garrison </PERSON>. `` He sent his aide out to buy a few things, basically children's clothes, <PERSON> Levis </PERSON> and toys for his grandchildren.'' Additionally, <PERSON> Esalen </PERSON> gave <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> a personal computer for his parliamentary office, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890919-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-19-89 0221EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LonesomeDove     09-19 0360</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lonesome Dove,0375</SECOND>
<HEAD>Texans Angry About `Lonesome Dove' Snub at Emmys</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PATRICE GRAVINO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Stampeded. Plucked. Left in the Dust. The angry headlines in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> newspapers said it all. The CBS miniseries, `` Lonesome Dove,'' a saga of western frontier life, got barely a nod from the television industry in Sunday night's Emmy awards and Texans were n't happy about it. `` It's something that you ca n't help feeling bitter or upset about,'' said <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Human </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> actress who portrayed the bossy and buxom `` Peach.'' The epic depicted a cattle drive from dusty Lonesome Dove, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, to <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>. It's central characters were two aging <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rangers </ORGANIZATION> portrayed by <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Duvall </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>. Although `` Lonesome Dove'' gathered a leading seven trophies including Saturday's technical ceremony, the adaptation of <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> McMurtry </PERSON>'s acclaimed novel won only one key category Sunday, for director <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> <PERSON> Wincer </PERSON>. It received 18 nominations, more than any show. `` I just wish the people who were more vitally involved with it got the recognition they needed to get,'' said Ms. Human. `` It kind of gives me the impression that somebody woke up with a sore tooth when they voted _ that's how ridiculous it is.'' Sore heads might have been involved, too, Ms. <PERSON> Human </PERSON> said. `` Mr. <PERSON> Duval </PERSON> is a very talented person, but he's also a very strong person and a lot of times, <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> does n't like that. ... But, there's no way you're going to know for sure.'' A television critic at the <ORGANIZATION> Fort </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Worth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Star-Telegram </ORGANIZATION> called the decision `` an unbelievable lapse in judgment.'' <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> `` embarrassed itself by refusing to honor ` Lonesome Dove' as the season's finest miniseries,'' <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON> wrote. The winner of that category was the monumental <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> saga `` War and Remembrance.'' Many industry watchers thought <PERSON> Duvall </PERSON> had a virtual lock on a best actor Emmy for his portrayal of the talkative <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Ranger Gus. The award went instead to <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Woods </PERSON>, who played the co-founder of Alcoholics Anonymous in the <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> movie `` My Name is Bill W.'' Even <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Curtis </PERSON>, the executive producer of `` War and Remembrance,'' called his victory `` a major shock.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890919-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-19-89 0224EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Pentagon-Iowa     09-19 0576</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pentagon-Iowa,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cheney: No Reason to Question Iowa Report</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
