<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890427-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-27-89 2341EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PlaneDoorHearing 2ndLd-Writethru a0785 04-27 0738</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Plane Door Hearing, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0785,0753</SECOND>
<HEAD>United Did Not Fully Inspect Ill-Fated Cargo Door</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 10 grafs to recast, emphasizing that FAA was unaware
of cargo door problems. Picks up 10th graf pvs, `Another FAA...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NICHOLAS K. GERANIOS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The federal inspector who oversees <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>' <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747 fleet testified Thursday he had not been aware the airline had a problem with a cargo door that later blew off in flight, killing nine passengers. Inspector <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Batiza </PERSON> also said the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> had failed to ensure that <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> complied with a federal rule that took effect last July 1, requiring airlines to inspect cargo doors after they were manually operated because of electrical problems. Testimony on the final day of a three-day hearing into the accident held by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> also centered on <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION>'s design for the door. But the hearing failed to unearth any definite cause for the accident. On Wednesday, the airline testified that it was unaware of the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION>'s inspection rule and was not in compliance for about nine months. But by coincidence, company mechanics made a partial inspection of the ill-fated cargo door in late December, two months before the Feb. 24 disaster, a <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> executive said Thursday. The inspection followed repairs made to the door, which had failed to open and close electrically. `` I am convinced the check ... verified that the door was working,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Doll </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> vice president for technical services. He added, however, that the inspection was not as thorough as the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> required under the new rule. <PERSON> Batiza </PERSON> testified that he was unaware of the repairs at the time and had not found any deficiencies in <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION>'s maintenance program recently. <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramakis </PERSON>, manager of aircraft maintenance for the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION>, testified later that agency inspectors were required to review rule changes with airlines to see if airline plans for responding to the changes were adequate. <PERSON> Ramakis </PERSON> declined to comment when asked to explain how <PERSON> Batiza </PERSON>, who oversees <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION>'s 31-plane 747 fleet, could not know that <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> was failing to follow the new rule. Another <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> inspector, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanchez </PERSON>, said Thursday he was unaware that <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> was using power tools to operate some cargo doors, despite recommendations from <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> not to do so for fear of damaging the mechanisms. <PERSON> Sanchez </PERSON>, who oversees maintenance for <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION>'s entire 412-plane fleet, said he was unaware until just a few weeks ago that the company had received <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> approval to use the power tools. The <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> hearing was being held to gather evidence on why the door and part of the fuselage tore off <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> Flight 811 as the 747 was climbing to 23,000 feet. Nine passengers were sucked out of the plane over the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION>, 85 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> as the plane headed for <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>. Speculation has focused on a possible malfunction in the locking mechanism of the cargo door, which remains on the bottom of the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> has not decided whether to retrieve it. <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> was sharply criticized by an accident investigator for the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Line </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pilots </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> for insisting 747 cargo doors are safe despite two incidents since 1987 of the doors opening in mid-flight. A door on a <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> flight out of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> partially opened in 1987 and the plane had to return to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, with no loss of life. No definite cause has ever been established for that incident. `` We can not explain the Pan American incident, and we have the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> accident where the door failed, but we steadfastly are saying the door is safe,'' Capt. <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> ALPA </ORGANIZATION> complained. <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> engineering manager <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON> spent two hours in the witness chair defending the design and operation of the cargo door, which has been the main focus of the investigation. `` I do n't know how the door came open,'' <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON> said. `` I do n't want to speculate on how it happened.'' Under questioning, <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> that <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> had not done projections on the effect of cargo-door openings in mid-flight. `` You had no idea what would happen ... when the door came off the airplane?'' an incredulous <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> asked. `` The doors are not designed to come off the airplane,'' <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON> replied. `` We had no way of knowing exactly what would happen if a door came open in flight.'' <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> builds 747s in nearby <LOCATION> Everett </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890427-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-27-89 2348EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-RiteAidArrest     04-27 0439</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Rite Aid Arrest,0450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rite Aid President Charged With Bribing Pharmacy Board Member</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CLEVELAND (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The president of <ORGANIZATION> Rite </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aid </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, the nation's largest retail pharmacy chain, was arrested Thursday on charges of paying a $ 33,000 bribe to a state <ORGANIZATION> Pharmacy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> member, authorities said <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Grass </PERSON> allegedly was videotaped saying the money was intended to induce the board member to quit so a replacement of Rite Aid's choosing could be appointed by the administration of Gov. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Celeste </PERSON>, prosecutors said. Assistant Cuyahoga County Prosecutor <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Caine </PERSON> said Grass also promised the pharmacy board member family medical insurance for four years if the member signed an undated resignation letter. Rite Aid, in a statement, said the arrest stemmed from a vendetta by the pharmacy board against Rite Aid and said the payment by check reflected money legally owed by the chain to the board member. A spokesman for the governor denied <PERSON> Celeste </PERSON> intended to appoint a pharmacy board member who would be supportive of Rite Aid, which is based in <LOCATION> Shiremanstown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa </LOCATION>. The prosecutor's office did not identify the target of the alleged bribe attempt but Rite Aid said Grass met with board member <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilczynski </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Toledo </LOCATION>, who declined to comment on the allegations. <PERSON> Caine </PERSON> said Grass brought six drafts of an undated resignation letter, one of which the board member signed, and suggested that the board member retire between June and October. `` ` We'll let you know,''' <PERSON> Caine </PERSON> quoted Grass as telling the board member with regard to the effective date of the resignation. The pharmacy board is made up of eight voting members appointed to staggered four-year terms by the governor subject to <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> confirmation. The executive director only votes to break ties. Grass was charged with bribery and was freed after posting 10 percent of his $ 100,000 surety bond. His attorney, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pyle </PERSON>, declined comment. <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> South </PERSON>, <PERSON> Celeste </PERSON>'s communications director, said the governor knew nothing about the matter. `` He -LRB- the governor -RRB- has never heard of the guy -LRB- Grass -RRB-,'' South said. `` He is either using the governor for cover or using too many drugs from his own drug store.'' <PERSON> Suzanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Mead </PERSON>, assistant vice president for corporate communications for Rite Aid, said the charge was `` totally without merit and the payment in question was made in satisfaction of a contract between a pharmacist, who also is an <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> pharmacy board member, and <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drugstores </ORGANIZATION>, his former employer.'' She said Rite Aid acquired the <ORGANIZATION> Lane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Division </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peoples </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drugstores </ORGANIZATION> on April 10 and was liable for the payment under the contract. The payment was made in settlement of the contract and was legal, she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890427-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-27-89 2347EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-Bush-Mellon     04-27 0114</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush-Mellon,110</SECOND>
<HEAD>President Pays Tribute to Art Philanthropist</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> paid tribute Thursday night to the late <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Mellon </PERSON>, the philanthropist and onetime <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> Secretary who founded the National Gallery of Art. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, just back from a four-day, cross-country trip, attended the black-tie dinner at the National Gallery with his wife, <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said <PERSON> Mellon </PERSON> created a tradition that reaffirms the nation's `` decency and kindness. The president also praised <PERSON> Mellon </PERSON>'s son <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>, whose family remains intimately involved in donating art and raising funds for the gallery. <PERSON> Mellon </PERSON> announced that former Ambassador <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Annenberg </PERSON> and his wife will lend 50 of their Impressionist and post-Impressionist works to the gallery next spring.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890427-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-27-89 2347EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Georgetown-Drugs     04-27 0375</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Georgetown-Drugs,370</SECOND>
<HEAD>Coach Thompson Says He Met With Alleged Drug Dealer</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Georgetown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> basketball coach <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said Thursday that he met with an alleged drug kingpin and asked him to steer clear of his players after learning that several members of his team were frequenting a bar where drug trafficking is common. <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> told ABC News that he summoned the alleged drug dealer, 24-year-old <PERSON> Rayful </PERSON> <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, after learning that many players on the <ORGANIZATION> Hoyas </ORGANIZATION> team were socializing at Chapter III, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> nightclub where both college students and alleged drug dealers regularly gather. `` I sent the word out on the street that I'd like to talk to him,'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said. `` It was almost like a tacit agreement: ` Do me a favor: If you see anything going on out there, use whatever resources you have to stop it from happening.''' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, who coached the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> basketball team in the 1988 Olympics in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>, said he met with <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON> in February. On April 15, <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON> and 15 others were arrested and charged with running a massive transcontinental cocaine ring. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stephens </PERSON> has estimated that <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON>'s group may be responsible for up to 20 percent of the cocaine trafficking in the nation's capital. <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said he was trying to head off a problem before it developed. `` What I was trying to do ... was not wait until something happened, that would hurt one of the kids,'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>. `` -LRB- I did n't want -RRB- to have a body laying there, someone who had been using drugs.'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> did not elaborate on whether he suspected any of his athletes were using drugs. `` Nightline'' host <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Koppel </PERSON> reported that <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> learned that freshman center Alonzo Mourning and sophomore forward <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> were among the <ORGANIZATION> Hoyas </ORGANIZATION> who frequented the nightclub. <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> described <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON> as `` very polite.'' `` It was ` Yes sir, no sir,''' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said. District of <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> police suspect that <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON>'s organization may be responsible for up to 30 drug-related murders in the nation's capital during the past two years. The city became the nation's murder capital last year with 372 murders, most of the drug-related. So far this year, there have been 164 slayings, compared with 102 at the same time last year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890427-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-27-89 2352EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-WeatherpageWeather 1stLd-Writethru a0756 04-27 0652</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Weatherpage Weather, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0756,0663</SECOND>
<HEAD>Winter Lingers in the Rockies</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 5 grafs to UPDATE with twisters in Iowa, Nebraska;
picks up 3rd graf pvs: `Heavy snow ...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 A spring snowstorm swept across the <ORGANIZATION> Rockies </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday, dumping up to 8 inches of heavy, wet snow in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, while winds and new snow created near blizzard conditions in parts of <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> and tornadoes hit southern <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>. A twister struck the Bluffs Run greyhound racetrack in <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bluffs </ORGANIZATION> about 8 p.m. Thursday, sending one man to the hospital for stitches after he was struck by flying debris, officials said. The tornado, which touched down in a field about 1,000 yards from the track, ripped siding from the building, downed trees and damaged some cars with wind-blown debris, officials said. The dog races were delayed about 15 minutes. Another tornado was reported on the ground in southern <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Neb. </LOCATION>, about 7:40 p.m. and funnel clouds were sighted over the central part of the city as well as near <LOCATION> Papillion </LOCATION> and 20 miles west of <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>, the weather service said. There were no immediate reports of injury, streets flooded in <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION> and golf-ball sized hail caused extensive damage to many cars after a day of record high temperatures in <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> and in the South. Heavy snow warnings were posted through Friday over the northern mountains of <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, with up to a foot of snowfall expected by late Friday in the <LOCATION> Laramie </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Range </LOCATION>. Near <LOCATION> Cheyenne </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wyo. </LOCATION>, about 6 inches of new snow combined with strong and gusty winds to create near blizzard conditions Thursday morning. In south-central <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, 8 inches of snow fell on <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lodge </ORGANIZATION>, a ski resort community. Great Falls, <LOCATION> Cut </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Helena </PERSON>, Butte, <PERSON> Bozeman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Livingston </PERSON> all had accumulations of 2 to 4 inches. `` We've got big, white flat flakes coming down here, about the size of a quarter,'' said <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Kumm </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mont </LOCATION>. Elsewhere, afternoon showers and thunderstorms extended Thursday along the northern coast of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, as well as from southwestern <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> into eastern <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>. Showers were scattered over west-central <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, as well as from southwestern <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> across western <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> and eastern <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> and eastern <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>. High-temperature records for the date were set in seven cities and tied in two. <LOCATION> Grand </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Neb. </LOCATION>, broke its record of 87 set in 1901 with and afternoon high of 88. Other records included <LOCATION> Apalachicola </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, high of 86, breaking its record of 84 set in 1948; in <LOCATION> Lincoln </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Neb. </LOCATION>, -LRB- 92, 91 set in 1896 -RRB-; <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, -LRB- 90, 89 set 1987 -RRB-; <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Neb. </LOCATION>, -LRB- 88, 87 in 1981 -RRB-; <LOCATION> Paducah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, -LRB- 89, 87 in 1987 -RRB-. <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, tied its record of 93, set in 1986 and <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, tied its record of 89, set 1956. Temperatures around the nation at 3 p.m. EDT ranged from 31 degrees at <LOCATION> Miles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mont. </LOCATION>, to 93 degrees at <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, S.C. The nation's low Thursday was 16 degrees at <LOCATION> Truckee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif </LOCATION>. The national forecast for Friday called for showers and thunderstorms from the <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> across southern lower <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, from much of <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> across southwest <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>; the <LOCATION> northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION>, and from <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> across northern <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>; rain becoming snow in the higher elevations of the northern and central Rockies; and showers scattered through northeast <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. High temperatures were forecast in the 30s from western <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> across central <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>; in the 40s and 50s from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> across the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lakes </LOCATION>, the upper <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION>; northwest <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, and the <ORGANIZATION> Rockies </ORGANIZATION>; the 60s and 70s from southern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> across <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, northern <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, the central Plains, western <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Oklahoma-Texas </LOCATION> panhandles, and the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>; in the 90s from southeastern <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> across much of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> and northern <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, as well as southwest <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> into southeast <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>; and in the 80s throughout the rest of the nation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890427-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-27-89 2356EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AirForce-Discrimination     04-27 0436</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Air Force-Discrimination,0446</SECOND>
<HEAD>Appeals Court Upholds One of Largest Air Force Discrimination Settlements</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN S. CARLSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal appeals court, spurning charges of reverse discrimination, affirmed an agreement Thursday that calls for the government to promote 240 black civilian workers at <ORGANIZATION> Robins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Base. The 11th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> upheld a consent degree issued by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Wilbur </PERSON> <PERSON> Owens </PERSON> that also required the government to pay $ 3.75 million in back pay to 3,200 black civilians who were employed at the base between 1972 and 1979. The agreement, reached in 1984 on a lawsuit filed in 1975, was one of the largest discrimination settlements in <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> history. The three-judge appeals panel agreed with <PERSON> Owens </PERSON> that black civilian workers were entitled to the promotions because of past discrimination at the base near <LOCATION> Warner </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Robins </LOCATION>, about 100 miles south of <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. The appeals court earlier had ordered <PERSON> Owens </PERSON> to allow a group of white and non-minority employees, called the <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Robins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Constitutional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION>, to intervene in the lawsuit and challenge the promotions. That group had challenged <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>' decision in October 1987 to reaffirm the 1984 decree. The court ruled on an appeal by the fund, upholding the consent decree and saying the interveners had failed to present any evidence that the decree would have hurt their own chances for promotion. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Poss </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Robins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Constitutional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION>, said in a telephone interview that the group would discuss the ruling before deciding whether to appeal future. But, he added, `` We thought from the beginning it would be a case that would have to be decided by the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>.'' Thursday's opinion, written by Circuit Judge <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, noted that 169 promotions were granted to blacks under the decree between December 1984 and October 1986 and that those promotions `` comprised only 4.3 percent of the promotions made at <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Robins </ORGANIZATION> during that period of time.'' The court noted that the decree was narrowly written so the promotions were made only to 38 target positions to which the original black plaintiffs had `` demonstrated that black employees were promoted in proportions less than their representation in the work force or in lower grades.'' <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> wrote that the white and non-minority employees `` did not present any evidence that any one of them otherwise eligible for a target position was denied that position.'' <ORGANIZATION> Robins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Brinkman </PERSON> said Thursday night that base officials had not had time to study the court's ruling so it was `` premature for me to make any statement on it.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890427-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-27-89 0037EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SushiWorms     04-27 0556</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sushi Worms,0571</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sushi Worm Startles Surgeons During Operation</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Note language in 8th graf, ``I said ...''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANIEL Q. HANEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As he was finishing an emergency appendectomy, Dr. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> noticed what he throught was a stray thread on the surgical drapes. Then it wiggled. The thread was actually a 2-inch-long skinny red worm slithering out of the patient's incision. It was a fish worm, inadvertently eaten by the patient in sushi the night before. The patient was undergoing the operation for abdominal pain, but doctors believe the worm was the real cause of his misery. The incident, described in today's <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> England </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION>, `` is an uncomfortable reminder of the potential danger of eating raw fish,'' noted Dr. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schantz </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. Raw fish in sushi and sashimi has become popular with the spread of Japanese restaurants in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, but health experts say most cases of worm infection occur when people prepare raw fish at home. Experienced sushi chefs are good at spotting wormy fish so it does n't reach customers. In the latest case, the victim ate raw fish at a friend's home in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. `` He looked like anybody else with appendicitis,'' recalled <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, a surgeon at Booth Memorial Hospital. `` I operated, and much to my chagrin the appendix was normal. I was getting ready to close the abdomen, and I see this little thing, and it looks like it's moving. `` I said, ` Wait a minute. There's something wrong. I'll be damned. It's a worm.''' The astonished doctors sent the worm to <ORGANIZATION> Albert </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Einstein </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION>, where it was identified as a larval nematode known as eustrongylides. `` There is a clear danger involved in eating raw fish. This underscores that danger,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Murray </PERSON> <PERSON> Wittner </PERSON>, an <PERSON> Einstein </PERSON> parasitologist. The adult form of eustrongylides is a parasite of fish-eating birds, while the larvae are found in the flesh of fish that live in brackish and fresh water. In an editorial in the journal, <PERSON> Schantz </PERSON> noted that only four other cases of human infection with a nematode have been reported. All were fishermen who swallowed bait minnows whole _ `` a practice not likely to be widely imitated.'' The worms most commonly acquired from raw seafood are larvae of the family Anisakidae. Between 25 and 50 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cases have been documented, but experts believe most cases are not recognized or reported to health officials. The worms often pass harmlessly through the digestive system or are coughed up a few hours after the meal. Doctors have even described a condition known as `` tingling throat syndrome,'' which occurs when the worms get stuck in the back of the throat. Sometimes, however, the worms burrow into the wall of the stomach or the intestines. They must be removed with a tube that's pushed down the victim's throat <PERSON> Schantz </PERSON> noted that many commercial fish are commonly infected with worms. These include mackerel, herring, rockfish, salmon and cod. The parasites also are more common in fish from the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> than from the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION>. The number of worm infections is increasing in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. But <PERSON> Schantz </PERSON> doubts that this will ever become a major health problem, since most Americans still prefer their fish cooked, which kills the worms.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890427-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-27-89 0044EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-LibyanDefection     04-27 0240</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Libyan Defection,0245</SECOND>
<HEAD>Libyan Airman Lands Helicopter, Requests Egyptian Asylum</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAIRO, Egypt (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Libyan air force officer split away from a five-helicopter squadron flying to <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>, landed his craft in southern <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and requested asylum, a senior security source said. The incident Wednesday was the fourth defection-motivated landing by <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> military aircraft in <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> in just over two years. Relations between <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> have been badly strained since 1972. The security source, speaking by telephone from the southern provincial capital of <LOCATION> Aswan </LOCATION>, identified the officer as Maj. Fat ` hi <PERSON> Miloud </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Saghir </PERSON>, He said <PERSON> el-Saghir </PERSON> landed his Soviet-made helicopter about 62 miles south of <LOCATION> Aswan </LOCATION> and told Egyptian officers he wanted asylum because he opposed participation in military operations in southern <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION> and was `` unhappy'' with the regime of <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> leader Col. <PERSON> Moammar </PERSON> <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> has been giving military aid to the Sudanese government of Prime Minister <PERSON> Sadek </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahdi </PERSON> to fight a 6-year-old rebellion in three southern regions. Libyan-Egyptian relations soured in 1972 after <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION> spurned a bid by <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> for immediate merger of the two countries. Five years later, the two countries fought a five-day border war after a series of bombings in Egyptian cities that <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION> blamed on Libyan agents. Relations chilled further after <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> denounced <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> for signing a peace treaty with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> in 1979. <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> expelled more than 40,000 Egyptian workers in 1986, but tens of thousands of Egyptians continue to work there.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890427-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-27-89 0044EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--LovelornBusinessman     04-27 0157</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Lovelorn Businessman,0160</SECOND>
<HEAD>Businessman Shells Out $3,744 For Full-Page Personal</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GENEVA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A small slot in the personals section was not enough for <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON>, a lovelorn businessman who took a full page in a <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> newspaper to seek out his dream woman _ to the tune of $ 3,744. `` I am looking for a very special woman who would like to share adventures and a taste of the high life with me on an occasional basis,'' said the advertisement placed Wednesday in the La Suisse daily by <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON>, who identified himself only by his first name. A spokesman for the newspaper said it was the most expensive personal it had ever printed. The 39-year-old <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> businessman, who said he was recovering from a broken relationship, told The Associated Press the advertisement was no joke. <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> said the successful applicant would find him a `` generous and creative'' person offering presents of jewels, flowers, clothes and exotic holidays.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890427-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-27-89 0045EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--RevolutionaryStar     04-27 0162</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Revolutionary Star,0164</SECOND>
<HEAD>French Bicentennial Celebration Wishes On A Star</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Gamma </PERSON> <PERSON> Boo </PERSON>, a little-known star in the constellation Bootes, has been thrust from obscurity and named the `` astrophysical symbol'' of the French Revolution bicentennial. Hundreds of people toasted the new twinkling symbol with champagne at the <ORGANIZATION> Paris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Observatory </ORGANIZATION> at sunset Wednesday and peered into the gathering twilight to the northeast trying to make it out. <PERSON> Jean-Noel </PERSON> <PERSON> Jeanneney </PERSON>, head of the commission planning the festivities marking the revolution's 200th birthday, said choosing an official star showed the poetic side of the celebration. <PERSON> Gamma </PERSON> <PERSON> Boo </PERSON>, also known as Seginus, was chosen because it is the brightest of several stars that are roughly 200 light-years from earth. Light now reaching <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> would have left the star at about the time Parisians were storming the Bastille prison in July 1789. To spot <PERSON> Gamma </PERSON> <PERSON> Boo </PERSON>, a skywatcher should locate the Big Dipper, then follow the direction of the Dipper's handle another handle-length away.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890427-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-27-89 0046EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Ball-Filmography     04-27 0399</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ball-Filmography,0488</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ball Career Includes Dozens Of Movies</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Obit-Ball, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the films, radio programs, TV shows and Broadway productions in which <PERSON> Lucille </PERSON> <PERSON> Ball </PERSON> appeared during her career:
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>FILMS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Broadway Through a Keyhole,'' 1933. `` Blood Money,'' 1933. `` Roman Scandals,'' 1933. `` Moulin Rouge,'' 1934. `` Nana,'' 1934. `` Bottoms Up,'' 1934. `` Hold That Girl,'' 1934. `` Bulldog Drummond Strikes Back,'' 1934. `` The Affairs of <PERSON> Cellini </PERSON>,'' 1934. `` Kid Millions,'' 1934. `` Broadway Bill,'' 1934. `` Jealousy,'' 1934. `` Men of the Night,'' 1934. `` The Fugitive Lady,'' 1934. `` Carnival,'' 1935. `` <PERSON> Roberta </PERSON>,'' 1935. `` Old Man Rhythm,'' 1935. `` Top Hat,'' 1935. `` I Dream Too Much,'' 1935. `` Chatterbox,'' 1936. `` Follow the Fleet,'' 1936. `` Bunker Bean,'' 1936. `` That Girl From <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>,'' 1937. `` Winterset,'' 1937. `` Do n't Tell the Wife,'' 1937. `` Stage Door,'' 1937. `` Joy of Living,'' 1938. `` Go Chase Yourself,'' 1938. `` Having a Wonderful Time,'' 1938. `` The Affairs of <PERSON> Annabel </PERSON>,'' 1938. `` Room Service,'' 1938. `` Next Time I Marry,'' 1938. `` Annabel Takes a Tour,'' 1938. `` Beauty for the Asking,'' 1939. `` Twelve Crowded Hours,'' 1939. `` <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> Lady,'' 1939. `` Five Came Back,'' 1939. `` That's Right_You're Wrong,'' 1939. `` The Marines Fly High,'' 1940. `` You Ca n't Fool Your Wife,'' 1940. `` Dance Girl Dance,'' 1940. `` Too Many Girls,'' 1940. `` A Girl, a Guy and a Gob,'' 1941. `` Look Who's Laughing,'' 1941. `` Valley of the Sun,'' 1942. `` The Big Street,'' 1942. `` Seven Days' Leave,'' 1942. `` <PERSON> Du </PERSON> <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> Was a Lady,'' 1943. `` Best Foot Forward,'' 1943. `` Thousands Cheer,'' 1943. `` Meet the People,'' 1944. `` Without Love,'' 1945. `` <PERSON> Abbott </PERSON> and Costello in <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>,'' 1945. `` Ziegfeld Follies,'' 1946. `` The Dark Corner,'' 1946. `` Lover Come Back,'' 1946. `` Easy to Wed,'' 1946. `` Two Smart People,'' 1946. `` Lured,'' 1947. `` Her Husband's Affairs,'' 1947. `` Sorrowful <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>,'' 1949. `` Easy Living,'' 1949. `` Miss Grant Takes Richmond,'' 1949. `` A Woman of Distinction,'' 1950. `` Fancy Pants,'' 1950. `` The Fuller Brush Girl,'' 1950. `` The Magic Carpet,'' 1951. `` The Long Long Trailer,'' 1954. `` Forever Darling,'' 1956. `` The Facts of Life,'' 1960. `` Critics Choice,'' 1963. `` A Guide for the Married Man,'' 1967. `` Yours, Mine and Ours,'' 1968. `` Mame,'' 1974. `` Stone Pillow,'' 1985, TV movie.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RADIO</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 `` The <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> Show,'' 1938. `` <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Haley </PERSON> Wonder Bread Show,'' 1938. `` My Favorite Husband,'' 1947-51.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>TELEVISION</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 `` I Love Lucy,'' 1951-57. `` Desilu Playhouse,'' 1958-60. `` The Lucy Show,'' 1962-68. `` Here's <PERSON> Lucy </PERSON>,'' 1968-74. `` Life With <PERSON> Lucy </PERSON>,'' 1986. -LRB- Some summer rerun series of `` I Love Lucy'' appeared under such titles as `` The Top Ten Lucy Shows'' and `` Lucy in <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>.'' -RRB-
</TEXT>
<NOTE>BROADWAY</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 `` Wildcat,'' 1960.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890427-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-27-89 0047EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PresidencySeminar     04-27 0706</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Presidency Seminar,0746</SECOND>
<HEAD>Panelists Discuss Selection Process</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL GEITNER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s mass media adviser for the 1988 presidential race denied Wednesday that his campaign strategy and tactics were dirty or too negative. `` Look at ` trash TV,' look at the lines blurring between tabloid journalism and journalism, look at the garbage that is out there in general,'' said <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Ailes </PERSON>, a panelist at a seminar on `` The Presidency in the'90s'' at <ORGANIZATION> Fordham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` I would submit that the political campaigns are among the cleanest things on television today,'' <PERSON> Ailes </PERSON> said. NBC News commentator <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Chancellor </PERSON>, who moderated the seminar, said that since presidential candidates are spending public money _ about $ 41 million each in 1988 _ `` we ought to have some say in how they spend it.'' <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenfield </PERSON>, political and media adviser for <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, defended political advertising as admittedly `` a short and clumsy way to get to know a candidate. Yet even within those limits, you pick up something.'' <PERSON> Kathleen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> <PERSON> Jamieson </PERSON>, an expert on presidential politics from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION>, suggested a nonpartisan panel be instituted to review political advertising and rule on its fairness and accuracy. And while some may complain that the presidential campaign drags on, `` I do n't know what you can do about the process being too long short of legislating it and that would just drive it underground like booze,'' he said. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, suggested that allowing the political parties a bigger role in selecting candidates might produce more leaders on a par with the great presidents of years past. `` There are people who believe when it comes to selecting candidates for president, that you use participatory democracy to its fullest extent in a general election, but that there are other ways that parties ought to select candidates,'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said. `` Certainly no changes are going to be made by 1992, but it certainly isnce because there are `` too many imponderables'' in making a successful campaign. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said that negative campaigning was one of the factors that turn people off and keep them away from the polls on Election Day. <PERSON> Greenfield </PERSON> said he believed the role of television was `` vastly exaggerated.'' Even with the skills of media gurus like <PERSON> Ailes </PERSON>, `` you run the 1988 campaign with 10 percent unemployment and you have a very different result,'' he predicted. <PERSON> Greenfield </PERSON>, a former speech writer for Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, also criticized the level of public discourse the campaigns have reached. `` Every time a candidate breaks through the puerility of the debate,'' he said, `` whether it's <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and his ` working poor' litany or <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s acceptance speech -LRB- at the Republican convention -RRB-, you can feel the public almost come alive, say, ` More, please give us more.''' At a later seminar Wednesday night, pollster <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> said he believed that presidents should turn to public opinion polls after they confront the issues and make a decision. But, he pointed out, `` our polling is either victimized or a reflection of what is reported. There's no question about it. And television is the most powerful medium.'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> correspondent <PERSON> Lesley </PERSON> <PERSON> Stahl </PERSON> said television's coverage of issues is dependent, like it or not, on the president presenting them in a simplified manner `` If they want to communicate what their policies and their thoughts and their decisions are to the American people over television, they simply must learn how to simplify it,'' she said. She also noted that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has not been getting his message out as well as President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> or even as well as he did during the campaign. `` Presidents win support in these times not because the public agrees with them on their ideology or their policies or on substantive issues, but because they come to like them over television,'' she said. `` <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> became adored by the public because the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> manipulated very brilliantly'' the media with staged events and photo opportunities, she said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has not done that, she said, adding `` I kind of respect it but it's not doing him any good.'' The seminars at <LOCATION> Fordham </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> were part of the city's commemoration of the bicentennial of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON>'s presidential
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890427-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-27-89 0047EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--PopPoster     04-27 0142</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Pop Poster,0144</SECOND>
<HEAD>Beatles And Hurricanes Poster Goes To Japan</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A rare poster advertising the Beatles at <LOCATION> Hamburg </LOCATION>'s Kaiserkeller was sold for $ 5,950 to an unidentified Japanese bidding by telephone, <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> auctioneers said The poster dates from around 1960, advertising performances by `` original rock' n' roll Bands'' featuring the Beatles and <PERSON> Rory </PERSON> <PERSON> Storm </PERSON> and his Hurricanes. Beatles drummer <PERSON> Ringo </PERSON> <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> played or the Hurricanes before he joined the Beatles who, like some other British groups, were famous in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> before they made the big time at home. The poster made the top price in Wednesday's sale of 283 lots of pop and rock music memorabilia which totaled $ 181,000. A Fender Stratocaster cream guitar once owned by Sting, former lead singer of Police, was bought by <PERSON> Warwick </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> of the Hard Rock Cafe in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> for $ 5,500.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890427-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-27-89 0048EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LucyRemembrance     04-27 0542</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lucy Remembrance,0554</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lucy Always Credited Others And Never Knew How Great She Was</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Obit-Ball, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> has covered <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> for 45 years.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>By BOB THOMAS</NOTE>
<NOTE>Associated Press Writer</NOTE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 She never knew how great she was. Amid the blimp-size egos of the entertainment world, <PERSON> Lucille </PERSON> <PERSON> Ball </PERSON> stood out like an orange beacon. She never bragged. She never exercised her considerable power. She always seemed astonished, even embarrassed, when honors inevitably came her way. When she was to receive a humanitarian award from Variety Clubs on a CBS special five years ago, she told me: `` There comes a time in your life when you get a lot of plaques. It's very flattering and I'll go along with it, especially if it benefits children.'' Whenever she was praised for `` I Love <PERSON> Lucy </PERSON>,'' she invariably replied: `` Well, all of the credit should go to -LRB- writers -RRB- <PERSON> Madelyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Pugh </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>'' Or, `` <PERSON> Desi </PERSON> was a genius: He was responsible for the show's success.'' Or she cited co-stars <PERSON> Desi </PERSON>, <PERSON> Vivian </PERSON> <PERSON> Vance </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Frawley </PERSON>. Yes, the writing and producing and casting of `` I Love Lucy'' were marvelous, but <PERSON> Lucy </PERSON>'s performance added the quantum force. Her inspired pantomime could be written by no one: the growing panic as the chocolate assembly line speeded up; her catalog of pained expressions after tasting the patent medicine she was demonstrating. Unlike many stars, <PERSON> Lucille </PERSON> <PERSON> Ball </PERSON> rarely indulged in self-analysis. But on one occasion she revealed why her feelings about the `` I Love Lucy'' triumph might have been ambivalent: Living through the last five years of the show, she said, `` took the edge off any enjoyment I might have had. <PERSON> Desi </PERSON>'s drinking and carousing were a terrible embarrassment, bad for a woman's self-esteem The talk around town was ` poor <PERSON> Lucy </PERSON>.' Because I could n't face people, I became a recluse for more than 5 -LCB- years. `` I never demonstrated my unhappiness at the studio, and actually, working together was a blessing. <PERSON> Desi </PERSON> had everything so well organized that it was easy to do the work.'' <PERSON> Lucy </PERSON> was late in reaching her comedy potential. She was 40 when `` I Love Lucy'' started on CBS and revolutionized television. And although she spent many years in <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>, `` none of the studios ever designed comedies for me the way <ORGANIZATION> MGM </ORGANIZATION> did for <PERSON> Red </PERSON> <PERSON> Skelton </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Paramount </ORGANIZATION> did for <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hope </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldwyn </PERSON> did for <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaye </PERSON>,'' she once said. `` Television was the medium for me, the medium for anyone who wanted to be well known a lot faster than waiting a year and a half for a movie to come out,'' she said in an interview late in life. `` Television is an instant barometer, especially the way we did it. `` It was all new. Nobody knew anything about television. Nobody was there to say, ` No, do n't do that, it's wrong!' We never knew what was wrong and what was right. We were all feeling our way. <PERSON> Desi </PERSON> was very innovative and very showmanship-conscious and was very intent on going ahead and doing it: ` That sounds all right, let's go!' So we went.'' Always the credit to someone else. But millions upon millions of television watchers know otherwise.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890427-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-27-89 0052EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Georgia-Protester     04-27 0777</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Georgia-Protester,0799</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tbilisi Protest Organizer Still Detained Two Weeks After Unrest</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANN IMSE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TBILISI, U.S.S.R. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When 200 officers in riot gear came to arrest protest organizer <PERSON> Zviad </PERSON> <PERSON> Gamsakhurdia </PERSON> two weeks ago, they stormed over the walls of his home _ actually a museum to his poet-father. And when the heavily armed officers returned to search the premises, they were stymied outside for four hours because <PERSON> Gamsakhurdia </PERSON>'s 9-year-old son refused to open the door when he was home alone. <PERSON> Gamsakhurdia </PERSON>, 50, is one of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>'s most prominent dissidents, who helped organize demonstrations that ended April 9 in a bloody confrontation between troops and protesters. At least 20 people died in the unrest. One of the southern republic's most prominent activists, he is following the example of his late father, <PERSON> Konstantin </PERSON>, a revered writer who was involved in creating the independent republic of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> that existed from 1918 to 1921. After the government confiscated some of his father's earnings six years ago, his son persuaded authorities to use the disputed funds to renovate the family home into a house-museum showcasing <PERSON> Konstantin </PERSON>'s life. The leaky roof and old linoleum are gone, according to <PERSON> Zviad </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Manana </PERSON> The family now lives in spacious rooms with carved wooden shutters and a sweeping staircase. Mrs. <PERSON> Gamsakhurdia </PERSON> said in an interview Tuesday that her husband is still being held, and she has not been allowed to see him or heard from him since. <PERSON> Gamsakhurdia </PERSON> helped start the series of demonstrations that culminated in the April 9 tragedy when he went on a hunger strike March 11, with a list of 20 demands. Many of the demands involved ethnic issues, such as vandalism of an antique church, allegedly by Southern Ossetians, and anti-Georgian discrimination in <LOCATION> Abkhazia </LOCATION>, a region of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> on the <LOCATION> Black </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>. But in seeking a resolution to these disputes, he drew accusations that he was inciting ethnic tensions himself. By the end of March, Abkhazians were holding mass meetings to complain about discrimination against them by Georgians. The <LOCATION> Tbilisi </LOCATION> demonstrations started as a response to the Abkhazian demands for secession from <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, and evolved into a mass call for <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>'s secession from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. On April 9, protesters helped <PERSON> Gamsakhurdia </PERSON> and other organizers escape the <LOCATION> Tbilisi </LOCATION> clash because they assumed the leaders were the targets of the soldiers, said Mrs. <PERSON> Gamsakhurdia </PERSON>. At 6 a.m. that day, <PERSON> Gamsakhurdia </PERSON> was at <ORGANIZATION> Tbilisi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, organizing a general strike, Mrs. <PERSON> Gamsakhurdia </PERSON> said. At 8:30 a.m., about 200 officers of the <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> and police descended on the family home in a neighborhood of antique meandering streets, and scaled the 12-foot-high brick wall rather than ring the bell, Mrs. <PERSON> Gamsakhurdia </PERSON> said. They had no arrest warrant _ `` nothing at all,'' she said. The officers donned riot gear, burst through a door, attacked her husband and dragged him off to jail, she said. The officers did not damage the shrine of books, photographs and memorabilia of <PERSON> Gamsakhurdia </PERSON>'s father and his involvement in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>'s heady three years as an independent nation. But in the garden, the officers uprooted the crosses on the graves of <PERSON> Konstantin </PERSON>, his wife and daughter. `` Why do they do that to dead people?'' Mrs. <PERSON> Gamsakhurdia </PERSON> asked. When the police returned April 15 for a search, only to be put off by the 9-year-old, Mrs. <PERSON> Gamsakhurdia </PERSON> called the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> headquarters of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>. She said she threatened to release to the world press a photograph of the troops swarming over her home if such actions did not halt. On April 20, her home was searched _ by just four officials, she said. Mrs. <PERSON> Gamsakhurdia </PERSON> says she does not believe new <ORGANIZATION> Georgian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Givi </PERSON> <PERSON> Gumbaridze </PERSON> when he says he wants a dialogue with opponents to replace the traditional party monologue. `` They still do n't want a dialogue,'' she said. If officials really wanted to talk with her husband and other activists, they would release them from prison, she said. She also noted that her husband's 20 demands have never been published in the local press, but <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> TV </ORGANIZATION> ran daily reports last year on an American hunger striker in front of the White House. <PERSON> Gamsakhurdia </PERSON>'s other demands include halting construction of the <ORGANIZATION> Transcaucasian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Railway </ORGANIZATION> and several hydroelectric dams, closure of the polluting oil refinery at <LOCATION> Batumi </LOCATION> on the <LOCATION> Black </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>, return of the deported Meskhetian minority from <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> to their homeland in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, and restoration of university-level Georgian studies programs. Authorities have taken action on only one of his 20 demands: conversion of the Metekhi chapel from a concert hall to a place of worship, his wife said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890427-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-27-89 0647EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--SoCalEarthquake     04-27 0184</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--SoCal Earthquake,0191</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quake Jolts Coast and San Fernando Valley</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A quake rattled the metropolitan area, including 30 people at an earthquake preparedness meeting who thought the jolt was staged as part of their training. No injuries or damage was reported. The tremor, which measured 3.5 on the Richter scale, struck Wednesday afternoon and was centered in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> nine miles west of <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Segundo </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Finn </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION>. `` It was pretty strong. It was a rolling kind,'' said dispatcher <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> at the <ORGANIZATION> Santa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monica </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Santa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monica </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> coordinator had just opened the meeting in the <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> chambers when the tremor shook the building. `` Everybody just looked at each other like, ` Are they causing this for the meeting?''' said <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON> <PERSON> Sweet </PERSON>, a reserve police officer. The <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale is a measure of ground motion as recorded on seismographs. Every increase of one number means a tenfold increase in magnitude. An earthquake of 3.5 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale can cause slight damage in the local area.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890427-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-27-89 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ANPA-BarbaraBush     04-27 0428</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-ANPA-Barbara Bush,0443</SECOND>
<HEAD>First Lady Urges Publishers: Press Onward With Campaign Encouraging
Literacy</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LINDSEY TANNER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has called on the nation's newspaper publishers to step up their efforts to fight illiteracy. `` We know the job of building a literate <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> is far from done and newspapers have a crucial role to play,'' the first lady told an audience of about 1,000 gathered at the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publishers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>'s 103rd annual convention on Wednesday. Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s talk came on the final day of the three-day meeting, which President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> addressed Monday. Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> plans to direct much attention to the nation's literacy problems during her husband's presidency `` Tens of millions of Americans will never pick up a newspaper,'' and that has obvious implications for the industry, she told the publishers. She said one of the main thrusts of literacy programs should be family literacy, `` where it all begins.'' `` Parents are their children's first role models,'' and illiterate parents are likely to raise children who can not read or write, the first lady said. `` To break this cycle of despair we have to establish literacy as a value in every American family.'' She gave several examples of disadvantaged people across the country, who, with the help of literacy programs, have gotten off welfare and continued their educations. One woman, <PERSON> Evelyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Vega </PERSON>, 29, of <LOCATION> Stamford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, was a third-generation welfare mother who learned to read and got off public aid last year with the help of a <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Way </ORGANIZATION> literacy program. `` These are the stories of struggle and triumph that newspapers nationwide have used to mobilize'' literacy efforts, Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. Newspapers also should look within their own ranks in tackling the problem, she said, citing the case of a typesetter at a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, publication `` who could not read what she produced.'' The woman is an example of people who learn to cope and mask their reading problems, but still must be helped, Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> Times Publisher <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, who spoke after the first lady, cited his newspaper's efforts as an example of what the industry can do to address the problem. The Times has organized a literacy program that includes centers where children and their parents can learn to read, <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said. `` No profession is more affected by illiteracy than ours,'' he said. `` The future of newspapers depends on the ability of our citizens to read.'' <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> urged his colleagues to take part `` in an all-out national campaign against illiteracy. Together,'' he said, `` we can make a difference.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890427-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-27-89 0122EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BeardCaucus Bjt   04-27 0669</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Beard Caucus, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bearded Legislators Caucus, Deny They're Endangered Species</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX10</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Beards, an ancient badge of wisdom and virility, are vanishing from the halls of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. But a few of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members who are still sporting chin whiskers _ and proud of it _ gathered to keep the faith. `` There'll always be beards,'' said Rep. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON>, D-Mich., the undaunted chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Caucus </ORGANIZATION>, whose members convened in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> barber shop Wednesday to count noses and admire each other's facial adornments Only two others showed up _ Reps. <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Leland </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Dana </PERSON> <PERSON> Rohrabacher </PERSON>, R-Calif. The two remaining members, Reps. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Dellums </PERSON>, D-Calif., and <PERSON> Floyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Flake </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, sent their regrets The dwindling ranks of the beard caucus, down to only five members from about a dozen last year, surely make it one of the smallest and least influential special-interest groups on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. Indeed, Rep. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ackerman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, says with a laugh that he recently shaved off his distinctive goatee, which he'd worn for 17 years, `` when I discovered there was no PAC -LRB- political action committee -RRB- that was interested in the beard caucus.'' <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON>, who also is chief deputy whip for <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Democrats, says the caucus is a `` fun group'' that meets `` anytime we can get a photographer to come and give us some free publicity.'' Its sole purpose, he says, is to `` allow members to fraternize about the politics of having hair on your face.'' <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON> confessed that he shaved off his 10-year-old beard briefly during the Christmas holidays. `` My family had n't seen me for 10 years, so I shaved. They did n't like what they saw, so I grew it back,'' he said. Beards may not be an endangered species, as <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON> claims, but they have fallen on hard times. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> is full of earnest, clean-shaven yuppies. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> has n't seen a beard since <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, the liberal Democrat from <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, died in 1976. There has n't been a bearded president since <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> left office in 1893. In the turbulent Sixties, beards enjoyed a brief renaissance as symbols of antiwar liberalism, but <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON> says they are a `` non-ideological growth'' today. <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON> might be right. Although he, <PERSON> Dellums </PERSON>, <PERSON> Flake </PERSON> and <PERSON> Leland </PERSON> are all liberal Democrats, the bearded <PERSON> Rohrabacher </PERSON> is a staunch <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> conservative who won a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> seat last November with active campaign support from Iran-Contra defendant <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>. `` The experts told me that if I had any chance of winning, I had to shave my beard and stay away from <PERSON> Ollie </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>. I refused to do either, and I won,'' <PERSON> Rohrabacher </PERSON> said. Another conservative <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Republican, Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dornan </PERSON>, shaved off his beard and won re-election handily. But when liberal former Rep. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowry </PERSON>, D-Wash., tried the same trick in his bid for a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seat last fall, he lost `` I had my beard for six years,'' <PERSON> Lowry </PERSON> said in a telephone interview from <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, where he is teaching college and reassessing his political future. `` I had it so long I was becoming identified with it. I was tired of being a <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> look-alike. Also, my mother hated it.'' Rep. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Gejdenson </PERSON>, D-Conn., shaved a beard he'd worn for six months last year `` During that time, I got more nasty mail over my beard than over any other issue since I've been in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said. `` Generally, they did n't like the way it looked, or thought it was unclean.'' <PERSON> Gejdenson </PERSON>, who intends to grow a new beard, believes the rise and fall of their popularity has some mysterious connection with the economy. `` When the stock market goes down, there are more beards, and when the market goes up there are fewer beards,'' he observes. `` When I showed up for the 101st <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, I was clean-shaven and the economy was back up again.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrews </PERSON> is an <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> reporter in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> who has sported a beard for the last 19 years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890427-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-27-89 0140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AbortionDecision Bjt   04-27 0550</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Abortion Decision, Bjt,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Breadth of Court's Abortion Ruling the Big Question Mark</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD CARELLI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The future of abortion in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> will be on the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s discussion agenda when its nine members gather for a closed-door conference Friday morning. First item: Must the court, in resolving an abortion-regulation controversy from <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, plunge into its landmark 1973 decision that women have a constitutional right to end their pregnancies? Although Chief Justice <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rehnquist </PERSON> may conduct an initial vote Friday and begin the opinion-writing process, the court's final decision likely will not be announced until late June or early July. <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> officials and the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration are urging the court to overturn or curtail the 16-year-old ruling in <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON>. And while speculating about the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s direction is always tricky business, questions from the bench in Wednesday's argument session indicated three key justices may be willing to undertake a broad review of abortion rights Justices <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Day </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>, <PERSON> Antonin </PERSON> <PERSON> Scalia </PERSON> and <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> _ all appointees of former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> _ pointedly asked lawyers for both sides about the dimensions of abortion rights. `` Do you say there is no fundamental right to decide whether to have a child or not? A right to procreate?'' <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> asked the administration's lawyer. `` Do you deny that the Constitution protects that right?'' <PERSON> Scalia </PERSON> asked the lawyer representing opponents of the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> law, `` How can you derive -LRB- a fundamental right -RRB- without making a determination as to whether the fetus is a human life or not?'' The justice added, `` It is very hard to say it just as a matter of basic principle that it must be a fundamental right unless you make the determination that the organism that is destroyed is not a human life.'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> asked the administration's lawyer about a 1965 <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decision striking down a state law that barred use of contraceptives _ the high court's first enunciation of the constitutional `` privacy'' right which served as the basis for <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON>. `` Does the -LRB- 1965 -RRB- case stand for the proposition that there is a right to determine whether to procreate?'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> asked. Of the justices considered strong supporters of abortion rights _ <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Blackmun </PERSON>, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Thurgood </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> _ only <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> participated fully in the session. <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON> asked one question; <PERSON> Blackmun </PERSON> and <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> none. <PERSON> Rehnquist </PERSON> and Justice <PERSON> Byron </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, dissenters in and consistent critics of <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON>, each asked several questions but seemed intent on giving the three junior justices as much time as they needed. Their questions could have zeroed in on the particulars of the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> law's regulations. Many of them did not. The court, however, still could resolve the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> case without reconsidering <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON>. Such a decision still would be read as a barometer of the current justices' commitment to the 1973 ruling, but might not affect many women outside <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>. Higher stakes would be left for a future case. But the possibility exists for a broader ruling, one that includes in its scope a nation in which 1.5 million legal abortions are performed each year.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Carelli </PERSON> has covered the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> since 1976.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890427-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-27-89 0140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-UN-Afghanistan     04-27 0574</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-UN-Afghanistan,0592</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S., Soviets In Bitter Exchange Over Afghanistan</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VICTORIA GRAHAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNITED NATIONS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> traded charges of hypocrisy, lying and bad faith in a blistering finale to three weeks of debate on <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> in the <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. The meeting adjourned Wednesday without resolution and no further meeting was scheduled. The debate marked the first full-fledged council discussion of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> since January 1980, right after Soviet troops intervened in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, replacing one Marxist government with another and staying on to help fight a Moslem insurrection. The session began April 11 and included more than 40 speakers, all of them calling for a political settlement and self-determination by the Afghan people. Ambassador <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> representative to the council, told delegates Wednesday, `` It is the height, or should I say the depth of hypocrisy for the representative of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> to claim that the regimes in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> U.S.S.R. </ORGANIZATION> are fulfilling their obligations under the Geneva Accords of April 14, 1988, and that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> have failed to do so. `` The truth is precisely the opposite ... distortion and falsehood will not work. `` The whole world knows full well who created the dreadful situation by its invasion of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has at least withdrawn its troops but it is seeking to lay the blame for the chaos and continued suffering at the feet of others.'' Soviet Ambassador <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Belonogov </PERSON> earlier delivered an extensive and stinging rebuke to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for arming the Afghan guerrillas with weapons transported across the border from <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. `` The world community ... has formed a very clear idea about who is hypocritical and who has been lying in this hall,'' he said, jabbing his finger in the air for emphasis. Referring to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> arms being supplied to the rebels through <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Belonogov </PERSON> gibed, `` We do n't believe babies are borne by storks or come from cabbage patches, so how did these arms from the territory of <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> get there into <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>? `` Did they fall out of the sky, or were they brought by some other force?'' Neither the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> nor <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> admitted supplying weapons, including Stinger and Blowpipe missiles and other arms to Afghan guerrillas. `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is not setting the best example -LRB- of respect for international agreements -RRB-,'' <PERSON> Belonogov </PERSON> said during an hourlong statement. `` By supplying the Afghan opposition with weapons on Pakistani territory, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has thereby been pushing <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> toward a violation of the bilateral agreement between <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>.'' That U.N.-mediated agreement between the two west <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> neighbors, guaranteed by <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, calls for non-interference in domestic affairs of <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. It also provided for the Soviet troop withdrawal, completed in February. <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> say <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> violated the accords by arming and training Afghan rebels in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and sending them into <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> along with weapons convoys. They claim the Pakistani military, intelligence units, logistics officers and militia are involved _ both directly and indirectly _ in fighting within <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> denies it and says Soviet supply of weapons to the <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> regime has continued the warfare and suffering in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. Most Afghans reject the Marxist government in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> says. Pakistani Ambassador <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shah </PERSON> <PERSON> Nawaz </PERSON> said in response to an Afghan threat of retaliation issued in the council Monday that his government will defend itself against any aggression from its neighbor.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890427-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-27-89 0149EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Pope-Africa     04-27 0613</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pope-Africa,0628</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pope Heads To Africa For A Fifth Time</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEPHEN R. WILSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VATICAN CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> heads for the troubled island of <LOCATION> Madagascar </LOCATION> on Friday, where opposition parties have declared a `` papal truce'' following violent anti-government protests. The pope later will go on the <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> island of Reunion, to <LOCATION> Zambia </LOCATION> and finally to <LOCATION> Malawi </LOCATION> on his nine-day trip, his fifth to <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> as <PERSON> pope </PERSON> and the 41st foreign pilgrimage of his 10 -LCB- - year papacy The visit comes seven months after his tour of five southern African countries and underlines <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>'s emphasis on the fastest growing segment of the <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>. The <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> counts 75 million adherents in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and expects the number to reach 100 million by the turn of the century. Among issues he is expected to address are human rights, AIDS, apartheid in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, foreign debt, the environment, the shortage of priests and the process of adapting African traditions to a faith imported from <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. In a papal first, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> will fly on the Concorde, although the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> France </ORGANIZATION> jetliner that will take him from Reunion to <LOCATION> Zambia </LOCATION> will not travel at supersonic speed because of the shortness of the trip. <LOCATION> Madagascar </LOCATION>, a 235,000-square-mile island off southeast <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, has been the scene of turbulent demonstrations against the government of President <PERSON> Didier </PERSON> <PERSON> Ratsiraka </PERSON>, who has been in power since 1975 and was re-elected last month to a third seven-year term. At least five people have been killed and 74 wounded in the past week in demonstrations by opposition parties, which accuse the government of rigging the election. Opposition leaders said Tuesday they will suspend their demonstrations during the pope's visit, recognizing the work of <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> and the church `` in favor of democracy and the rights of man.'' About 25 percent of <LOCATION> Madagascar </LOCATION>'s 10 million people are <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION>, and the church has spoken out against some of <PERSON> Ratsiraka </PERSON>'s policies. <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> officials said the pope is expected to stress the need for respect of human rights and political freedoms in <LOCATION> Madagascar </LOCATION>. Church-state relations improved in recent years after <PERSON> Ratsiraka </PERSON> turned from many of his socialist policies to gain Western aid to tackle a severe economic crisis and protect the country's unique plant and wildlife. In Reunion, a French overseas territory where 90 percent of the 500,000 people are <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> will be received by Premier <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Rocard </PERSON> of <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> in the capital <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Denis </LOCATION> and address bishops from other <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> islands. The pope is expected to raise the issue of apartheid in <LOCATION> Zambia </LOCATION>, a front-line state that provides headquarters in exile for the <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> _ the main group fighting to end white domination in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. In a major document released in February, the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> condemned apartheid _ <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s policy of racial segregation _ as the `` most systematic'' form of racism in the world. <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> officials, previewing the trip on the condition of anonymity, said <LOCATION> Malawi </LOCATION> could provide the pope the opportunity to address the problem of AIDS, which is estimated to have stricken up to 20 percent of the male population. In the past, the <PERSON> pope </PERSON> has urged compassion for AIDS victims. The <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> has condemned the use of condoms as a means of stopping the spread of acquired immune deficiency syndrome, prescribing abstinence as the best means of avoiding the fatal disease. <LOCATION> Malawi </LOCATION>, one of <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s smallest and poorest nations, has been strained by an influx of 650,000 to 800,000 refugees fleeing the civil war in neighboring <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION>. The church is inviting the Catholic refugees to attend the papal events. The pope is scheduled to return to <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> on May 6.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890427-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-27-89 0204EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     04-27 0064</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0066</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Wednesday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 08; 14; 19; 20; 23; 27.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 02; 14; 28; 34; 48; 50. Supplementary 22.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 0-4-3; 6-3-8-0; 6-1-9-3-9; 9-2-1-8-9-6.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>PENNSYLVANIA</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Super 7 Game: 06; 16; 24; 34; 35; 37; 40; 41; 45; 60; 71.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890427-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-27-89 0209EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Soviet-Cats     04-27 0623</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Cats,0647</SECOND>
<HEAD>Like Those Furry Soviet Hats? Think Again</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By COTTEN TIMBERLAKE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Brace yourself. In the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, the cat IS the hat. But the good news is that not all Soviets like felines turned into fedoras, and in a kind of `` purr-estroika,'' members of a <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> cat club are in animal-loving <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> seeking advice on how to promote better treatment of their furry friends. `` The position of homeless cats in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> is very difficult,'' said <PERSON> Nikolai </PERSON> <PERSON> Nepomnyaschy </PERSON>, vice chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Fauna </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>. `` The sanitary inspectorate is very strict on homeless cats and they destroy a lot of them. They poison them with different poisons and they make hats out of them,'' <PERSON> Nepomnyaschy </PERSON> said. Dogs are no better off. `` It's not just cats they're after, but also dogs,'' <PERSON> Nepomnyaschy </PERSON> said. `` They're very bad people, even people who have been setting up cooperatives'' to make and sell cat hats. Such profit-making cooperatives have become possible under President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s policy of `` perestroika,'' or social and economic reforms. While cruelty to cats is illegal in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, it's not against the law to make hats out of them. `` Nobody is actually going to punish you if you turn a cat into a hat,'' <PERSON> Nepomnyaschy </PERSON> said. How did the problem start? `` As we do n't have a tradition of looking after cats, some parents buy cats for their children simply as toys. So it happens that children can play with the cats until they get tired of them and then they let them out into the street and parents do n't say anything about it,'' he said. <PERSON> Nepomnyaschy </PERSON> brought a film crew that is making a movie about cats. They arrived Tuesday and will stay until May 2, visiting cat rescue centers and talking to experts. `` Three or four years ago such contacts between our countries would not have been possible. They probably would have said, ` You're completely mad. You ca n't do that,''' <PERSON> Nepomnyaschy </PERSON> said Wednesday. `` It's only been possible since the process of perestroika starting in our country in 1985-86.'' <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> is the first non-communist country the club has visited. `` We could n't have possibly not come to <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, because there are almost legends about how -LRB- well -RRB- people treat their pets,'' <PERSON> Nepomnyaschy </PERSON> said. `` We were very pleased indeed that we were approached to ask if we would be willing to hold their hands a little,'' said <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Wood </PERSON>, deputy chairman of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Cats </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>. With uncharacteristic British immodesty, he said: `` We do have quite a good international reputation.'' Cats are increasingly popular in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, where perhaps 30 million people keep felines as pets, <PERSON> Nepomnyaschy </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> Fauna </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s oldest and biggest cat club, was established in 1986 and has attracted 1,000 members. Its opening cat exhibit was attended by 80,000 people, he said. `` And the cats they were queuing to see were just household cats,'' he said. The film is targeted at young people and will be shown in movie theaters, and perhaps on television. `` The film we are going to make is a continuation of this propaganda of the advertisement of cats,'' said <PERSON> Nikita </PERSON> <PERSON> Voronov </PERSON>, the film's director and a <ORGANIZATION> Fauna </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> member. `` We'd like to make a film that shows that everything alive has a right to life.'' Incidentally, it's not just tough being a cat in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Owning one is n't easy either. For starters, there's no canned cat food, said <PERSON> Nepomnyaschya </PERSON>. The club recommends boiled hake, a kind of fish. There also are no covered cat litter pans, fitted plastic liners, or mint-scented cat litter. Soviets use plastic photo-developing trays filled with paper or sand, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890427-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-27-89 0214EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LottoLunacy     04-27 0801</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lotto Lunacy,0825</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lure of `Super-Mega-Jackpot' Fans Lottery Fever</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Lottery Fever, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT DVORCHAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP National Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Why should n't a crack at the fattest jackpot in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> create a ticket-buying frenzy? How else can you turn a one dollar lottery chance into a $ 100 million payoff? `` The lure of great prizes fires people up. There's a kick of anticipation,'' said <PERSON> Abe </PERSON> <PERSON> Kramer </PERSON>, a psychologist who counsels compulsive gamblers in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. `` The bigger the prize the better, even though they do n't have a snowball's chance in hell of winning.'' <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>'s Super 7 Lottery drawn Wednesday night was worth more than $ 100 million, the world's largest prize outside <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>'s $ 159 million pot divvied up in last December The <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> prize illustrates how popular lotteries have become since <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hampshire </ORGANIZATION> opened its game in 1964. Lottery sales are expected to top $ 15 billion this year in 32 states and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, up from an estimated $ 14 billion last year. Sales in at least eight states exceed $ 1 billion. `` The lottery is the poor man's stock market. It let's you fantasize about the lifestyles of the rich and famous,'' said <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Blaine </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> and Provincial Lotteries. For $ 1, players of Super 7 picked seven numbers from one to 80. The winner must match them against 11 numbers drawn. The official winning numbers were 06; 16; 24; 34; 35; 37; 40; 41; 45; 60; 71. The odds of winning were 9.6 million-to-one, and the pot grew because there was no winner for six weeks. Tickets were sold at a rate of 500 a second. In a scene reminiscent of a gold rush, rabid prospectors invaded <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> by car, bus and plane to queue up. It was as if an entire state had gone mad. `` It's a dream, the fantasy of getting rich, of never having to work again,'' said <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Baucum </PERSON>, a professor of psychology at <ORGANIZATION> Birmingham-Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>. `` People get to carry around a little extra glow.'' Part of the fascination was getting a piece of the action. `` Not many people really expect to win. But somebody's going to. Everybody wants to be part of the fun,'' said <PERSON> Russ </PERSON> <PERSON> Gladieux </PERSON>, acting director of the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> state lottery. `` It's generated a super-mega-jackpot.'' <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Zurenda </PERSON>, owner of <ORGANIZATION> Ticket </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, in <LOCATION> Wilkes-Barre </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, put in four extra phone lines and ran ads in newspapers for out-of-staters. He charged $ 100 for a minimum order of 50 tickets, twice the going rate. <PERSON> Madelyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> came in person, spending $ 796 for roundtrip air fare from <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>. `` I had a vision a year ago that I won the largest jackpot in jackpot history. This is my chance,'' she said. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>, jetted in for tickets. `` It's only once in a lifetime that you get to participate in the largest gambling action in the history of mankind,'' <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> said Promoters bill lotteries as benign entertainment, but critics say players can spend their life savings or write bad checks to cover debts. `` There's a dramatic increase in lottery addicts,'' said <PERSON> Valerie </PERSON> <PERSON> Lorenz </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pathological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gambling </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>. `` Gambling used to be immoral, sinful and illegal, associated with greed and crime. The lotteries are promoting it as an act of civic responsibility because it supports education, transportation and elderly programs,'' she said. Lotteries were introduced as a way to raise money without raising taxes. In a way of using a vice to fund a virtue, lottery proceeds pay for senior citizens programs in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, education in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, and economic development in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>. But states pocket an average of 35 percent of lottery sales, and the games account for only a small percentage of a state's budget. `` The lottery is a rather inefficient and ineffective method of general revenue. But nobody wants to raise taxes. That's a dirty word,'' said <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaplan </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION>, who has studied state lotteries for 20 years. `` I look at the lottery as the flip side of work. Gambling gives the tantalizing thought of achieving success without work,'' <PERSON> Kaplan </PERSON> said. `` It's an innocent diversion for a few days.'' The sheer magnitude of a $ 100 million treasure, and the chance to chase rainbows and get rich instantly has a strong American appeal. But while a dollar may make you rich, it can also cost you your privacy. <PERSON> Glen </PERSON> <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON>, a coal miner, won $ 5.6 million in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> lottery in 1986 and spent $ 6,000 for a chain-link fence adorned with a `` no soliciting'' sign. One stranger asked him for $ 10,000 so he could buy new cars for his kids. A woman asked for $ 10,500 to have her breast enlarged.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890427-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-27-89 0106EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-WyomingElection 6thLd-Writethru a0423 04-27 0736</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Wyoming Election, 6th Ld - Writethru, a0423,0752</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thomas Wins Wyoming's Special U.S. House Election</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Eds: Leads with 8 grafs to UPDATE with latest returns, comments from <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> and Democratic congressional campaign committee officials; DELETES outdated material. Picks up 5th graf pvs: ` The special ...
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By KURT J. REPANSHEK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHEYENNE, Wyo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
