<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890301-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-89 2343EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PlaneEmergency 2ndLd-Writethru a0852 03-01 0665</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Plane Emergency, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0852,0680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Navy Has Equipment To Recover Stricken Jet's Cargo Door</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 5 grafs after 4th graf, `Investigators suspect ...,
to UPDATE with first lawsuits filed; picks up 5th graf pvs: `Capt. David
...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTINE DONNELLY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HONOLULU (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> has equipment capable of recovering the cargo door that sank in 16,800 feet of water after tearing away from a <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> jumbo jet, an undersea technician said. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> has not decided whether to attempt to recover the door from the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> 85 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION>, said member <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON>. He said, however, that examining the front cargo door would be `` very helpful to us in our analysis.'' <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> radar tracked a large object falling into the ocean about 45 seconds after the pilot of <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION>'s Flight 811 reported an in-flight emergency early Friday soon after taking off for <LOCATION> Auckland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> said Tuesday night. Investigators suspect the cargo door popped open at 22,000 feet, tearing away with a large section of fuselage. Nine passengers seated on the right side of the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747 jet were swept to their deaths. The first lawsuits stemming from the accident were filed here Wednesday. <PERSON> Mae </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sapolu </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> flight attendant from <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION>, filed a state court lawsuit seeking unspecified damages from <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, maker of the jumbo jet. According to court documents, <PERSON> Sapolu </PERSON> was serving drinks in business class when the hole opened in the right side of the aircraft. <PERSON> Sapolu </PERSON> said she was thrown to the floor and had to cling to the leg of a seat to keep from being swept out of the plane. <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Tudor </PERSON> a passenger from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wales </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, also sought unspecified damages in his lawsuit filed in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, accusing from <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> of neglect in maintaining the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747. <PERSON> Sapolu </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tudor </PERSON> said they suffered physical injuries and emotional distress. Capt. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cronin </PERSON> turned the crippled jet around and flew it 100 miles on two of four engines, landing safely at <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>. `` The radar picked up something that could be a large piece of metal, possibly the cargo door,'' <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> said. `` That information is going back to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION><LOCATION> , </LOCATION> <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, to see if we can indeed determine ... that was the cargo door, and its exact location.'' `` We have the location at the surface of the water,'' he said. `` You're talking about three miles -LRB- down -RRB-, one can only guess where that is.'' <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolcott </PERSON>, a technician and submersible launch pilot at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hawaii </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Hawaii </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Undersea </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION>, said it would be difficult but probably not impossible to find the cargo door. A search for the door probably would begin with a towed underwater sonar sled to determine possible locations of the door and then the use of a remote operation vehicle equipped with a camera to pinpoint the location, <PERSON> Wolcott </PERSON> said Wednesday. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> has ROVs capable of hooking a line to the door so it could be pulled to the surface, he said. The least likely possibility because of the tremendous expense involved would be the use of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s San Diego-based Sea Cliff, one of the world's few manned submersibles capable of reaching that depth, <PERSON> Wollcott </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION>'s field work was nearly completed and investigators would leave <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> by Thursday. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Guyette </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION>'s executive vice president for operations, said the damaged jetliner will be repaired, although there was no estimate on when it will be returned to service. The air frame will be fixed in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> and the engines will be repaired in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Guyette </PERSON> told a news conference here Wednesday. About 10 of the passengers who were on Flight 811 remain in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> as well as a few survivors of the missing and <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> is paying all expenses, <PERSON> Guyette </PERSON> said. Two <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> flight attendants are the only ones on the plane who remain hospitalized.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890301-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-89 0000EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     03-01 0433</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0446</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ANNAPOLIS, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gaining weight accompanies gaining office for many members of the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>. Lunches with lobbyists, snacks during committee meetings and rounds of receptions and late-night dinners at the state capital's leading restaurants make staying thin as tough as _ and sometimes tougher _ than getting re-elected Just talk to Delegates <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Counihan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Elijah </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cummings </PERSON>, <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rawlings </PERSON>, and <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> McCaffrey </PERSON>. The foursome top the scales at 1,200 pounds collectively and, in a well-publicized weigh-in, they vowed to lose weight by the end of the assembly's 90-day session. `` There are just too many opportunities for too much eating,'' said <PERSON> Counihan </PERSON>, who put on 25 pounds during his first year in <LOCATION> Annapolis </LOCATION> six years ago and has steadily gained since then. Delegate <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Palumbo </PERSON>, who picked up a few pounds each session until he hit 200, said he understood his problem graphically when he started looking at photographs taken during his <LOCATION> Annapolis </LOCATION> career: `` Me getting fatter and fatter and fatter.'' `` It's hard. There is food everywhere,'' <PERSON> Palumbo </PERSON> said. `` You go to a reception and you are talking with someone about something important to them. They have a drink in their hand, you have a drink. They are plucking shrimp off a shrimp tree, so you pluck some, too. ... You end up eating both sides of an issue.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BLACKSBURG, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Wildlife specialist <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bromley </PERSON> has a way to get rid of mosquitoes in the yard: put up a bat house, which is similar to a bird house except it attracts a different type of winged occupant. `` A bat might eat up 2,000 mosquitoes every night,'' said <PERSON> Bromley </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cooperative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Extension </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tech </ORGANIZATION>. `` If you have six or seven bats in your house, that's more than 10,000 mosquitoes.'' Besides, a bat house can be entertaining for homeowners, <PERSON> Bromley </PERSON> said. `` On a summer night, you just have to get a lawn chair, sit it outside and wait to see if a bat flits out the bat house,'' <PERSON> Bromley </PERSON> said. `` They're great fliers, so they have aesthetic appeal. Plus, it's fun to have guests look at your bat house and say, ` There's no hole in the front. Then you can say, ` That's a bat house,' and have a lot of fun talking about it around your place.'' <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tech </ORGANIZATION> said people can get free plans for a bat house by sending in a self-addressed, stamped envelope. But so far, the <ORGANIZATION> Extension </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> has not been going bats answering requests: it has n't received any inquiries yet.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890301-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-89 0627EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d p PM-BRF--NoVotes     03-01 0156</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--No Votes,0159</SECOND>
<HEAD>Assemblywoman Proposes Repealing `None of These Candidates' Vote</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CARSON CITY, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A law that lets voters pick `` none of these candidates'' would be erased under a proposal by a state assemblywoman who says the option made <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> `` the laughingstock of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' Assemblywoman <PERSON> Eileen </PERSON> <PERSON> Brookman </PERSON> on Tuesday asked the <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elections </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> to amend a bill she has introduced to repeal the option. During the 1986 Democratic primary for state treasurer, `` none of these candidates'' got more votes than five hopefuls. However, the `` none'' voting is advisory only, and does n't stop a person from winning a race. `` I think we are the laughingstock of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> because of this,'' she said. `` I'd like to have this amended and the law repealed.'' The 1975 Legislature created the option. Sen. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Mello </PERSON>, who introduced the original bill then as an assemblyman, said the category was intended to boost voter turnout.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890301-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-89 0000EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Brite-GadhafyLookalike     03-01 0132</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Brite-Gadhafy Lookalike,0138</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gadhafy Lookalike at Denny's Prompts Call to 911</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MERRITT ISLAND, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sheriff's Deputy <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> responded skeptically when someone phoned 911 to report that <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Moammar </PERSON> <PERSON> Gadhafy </PERSON> was dining at <PERSON> Denny </PERSON>'s. But when White and another deputy arrived at the restaurant Sunday night, he quickly spotted the customer that had prompted the call. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Belman </PERSON>, 34, was eating quietly with his 3-year-old son. `` We sat down beside him, and we were just laughing about the whole situation,'' <PERSON> White </PERSON> said. `` He favors him.'' <PERSON> Belman </PERSON>, a jeweler from <ORGANIZATION> Cocoa </ORGANIZATION>, said his face has gotten him into trouble before. `` At times it's fun and at times it's fearful,'' he said. `` I've seen -LRB- <PERSON> Gadhafy </PERSON> -RRB- on TV just a few times We do favor each other quite a bit.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890301-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-89 0005EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LateNightTown     03-01 0286</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Late Night Town,0294</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bolan, Iowa, Residents Off to Letterman Show</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GREG SMITH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOLAN, Iowa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Volleyball and bowling leagues, two big attractions this time of year in northern <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, will play second fiddle tonight to <ORGANIZATION> NBC-TV </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Late Night With <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Letterman </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Letterman </PERSON>'s show will feature the town of <LOCATION> Bolan </LOCATION> _ all 16 residents. `` I do n't think there's anybody in <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> that wo n't be watching it,'' said <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> VanHorn </PERSON>, a secretary in the county sheriff's department. At JJ's tavern in <LOCATION> Northwood </LOCATION>, home of about 2,000 people, <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> and <PERSON> Judy </PERSON> <PERSON> Jorgensen </PERSON> are planning a `` Bolan Bonus'' night, featuring a `` Bolan cocktail'' and a `` Bolan burrito.'' `` We were going to promote Wednesday night as ` <ORGANIZATION> Northwood </ORGANIZATION> _ the suburb of <PERSON> Bolan </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Jorgensen </PERSON> said. Mrs. <PERSON> Jorgensen </PERSON> said the usual crowd that comes to her place after volleyball and bowling leagues will likely stay a little longer to watch `` Late Night'' on the color TV above the bar. `` If I had any influence with those people in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, I'd have them put the <LOCATION> Bolan </LOCATION> people on at the very end of the show so everybody will stay longer,'' she said. Area residents are proud of the Bolanites, who will be seated together in the `` Late Night'' audience before being introduced. One or two will be on stage with <PERSON> Letterman </PERSON>. The show and all the national attention has given the little town a big-city attitude. <PERSON> Bolan </PERSON> residents have arranged for friends to stay at each of their homes, and they've hired additional security officers to protect their belongings while they are being wined and dined in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Sheriff <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Storffregen </PERSON>'s deputies also will patrol the town at all hours until the homeowners return.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890301-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-89 0014EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SisterSuicide     03-01 0195</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sister Suicide,0198</SECOND>
<HEAD>Four Young Sisters' Suicide Bid An Attempt To Help Impoverished Parents</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Four young daughters of a poor factory worker swallowed rat poison in a suicide attempt aimed at easing the family's economic plight and enabling their brother to get an education, police said today. The youngest girl, 6, died. The others, aged 8, 10 and 13, were in serious condition. Their mother, <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Ok-soon </PERSON>, found the girls in the family's rented two-room apartment when she returned from grocery shopping Monday. Their 3-year-old brother was nearby _ unharmed. Police said the eldest daughter, Soon-mi, 13, regained consciousness and told police the sisters decided to kill themselves because it would leave more money for the parents and for education expenses to raise their brother. <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> newspapers quoted the girls' teachers as saying they studied hard and were quiet, model students. But a neighborhood store owner said Soon-mi recently told him she could not afford $ 5.80 worth of notebooks and pencils she needed for school and asked to pay later. The father, <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> <PERSON> Tae-bum </PERSON>, 44, supported the family of seven on $ 362 a month in factory wages, police said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890301-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-89 0021EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Poland-Graffiti     03-01 0183</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poland-Graffiti,0189</SECOND>
<HEAD>Walls To Go Up In Warsaw For Uncensored Graffiti</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Graffiti has become such a scourge in <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> that city authorities intend to erect walls where people can scrawl whatever they please without fear of censorship, a spokesman for the mayor says. In <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, graffiti usually carries a political message and is most often quickly painted over by authorities with dull hues that accentuate the eyesore. Graffiti and other vandalism cost the city more than $ 1.8 million last year, and slogans scrawled during a `` happening'' Friday near <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION>'s main department store caused $ 9,000 in damage, authorities say. Municipal officials decided Monday to build the free-speech graffiti walls at locations still to be decided, said <PERSON> Zbigniew </PERSON> <PERSON> Kopka </PERSON>, the mayor's spokesman. `` Everyone will have a chance to express themselves, if only the paint is no longer sprayed on the walls of our buildings or underground passageways,'' he said Tuesday. Scrawling on walls has a long tradition in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. A cross-and-anchor symboly with the initials `` PW'' for `` <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> is Fighting,'' became a national symbol of resistance during World War II.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890301-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-89 0025EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ToothyGold     03-01 0770</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Toothy Gold,0787</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Gator Boom Is On Where Black Gold Tarnished</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By AUSTIN WILSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Call it toothy gold, a get-rich quick plan for an area devastated by the crash of the oil market. Across <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>'s marshes, once flush with profits from black gold, small patches of land increasingly are being turned into alligator farms, with investors hoping to quintuple their investments in short order. `` Year before last, there were just under 9,000 farm-raised gators sold'' by 37 farms, said <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, alligator research coordinator for <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fisheries </ORGANIZATION>. `` That number is going to reach 60,000 quickly and could be up to 100,000, certainly, within five years.'' That's in addition to the 24,000 wild alligators trapped each fall in carefully supervised hunts. Spurred by prices of $ 37 a linear foot for hides, 21 new farms have opened in the past two years, and `` We expect them to produce 18,000 gators,'' <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> said. The waiting list for permits for new farms is about 100. <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, 28, went into business two years ago near <LOCATION> Sweetlake </LOCATION> and expects to put 12,000 hides a year on the market. His farm is state-of-the-art: automated cleaning, water-source heat pumps, carefully supervised diets. The result is quicker growth at less cost. `` We have some are 5-6 feet long in a year and six months. We have 8-month-old gators that are 26-30 inches.'' Skins of wild alligators average seven feet in length, and are used for luggage. Farm-raised gators are skinned at two years old and about four feet long. Their hides are used for shoes, purses, belts and other smaller high-fashion accoutrements requiring smaller patterns on the hides. For about $ 30,000 a potential farmer can put up a couple windowless cinder-block buildings on concrete slabs and be ready to raise 1,000 gators a year. It would take another $ 25,000 to $ 30,000 to operate until the gators grew enough to sell. At current prices, 1,000 four-foot hides would bring $ 148,000. `` The minimum requirements are 1 square foot per alligator up to two feet in length and 2 square feet up to four feet in length,'' <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> said. Buildings must be able to hold a few inches of water and be kept about 89 degrees. The first thing is to gather alligator eggs from wild nests, paying landowners for the eggs and committing 17 percent of the hatch for return to the wild at 4 feet long. That's a carefully researched percentage designed for zero growth in the population of 1.5 million wild alligators _ reached after the alligator was taken off the endangered species list in the mid-1970s. The wild nests are n't easy to find, and female alligators guard their eggs _ about the only time in their lives they show maternal instincts. No task for the timid, <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> agreed. `` But everybody's got to learn some time or another, if they want to get into farming. `` Obviously, what would be best, for a guy's first involvement, would be to hire someone with a little experience in locating nests from the air. That's the only way to go: rent a helicopter and go find them and pick them up.'' The success of farming ventures will almost certainly drive prices down, and there are risks any time a market depends on fashion or something volatile, he said. `` I do n't think the bottom will fall out of the price. I do n't think they'll go to $ 2 a foot. But it certainly could go to half of what it is now.'' <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, a former trapper, commercial diver and underwater welder who now devotes full time to his farm, agrees with <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>'s analysis `` A lot of these farms, you'll see what happens. Prices are good right now, but with all these hides coming on the market, it's going to have to go down.'' But <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> believes he will survive when others fail because his expenses are low. `` Look at it this way, you've got an electricity bill of $ 500 a month to raise 1,000 alligators, and my bill is $ 150 a month to raise 12,000.'' His major problem is finding enough nutria _ small water rodents _ to feed the gators. Nutria often are dyed like beaver, and <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said, `` The price of skins is so low, right now, that you ca n't get all you want. Last year I got 40,000 pounds, and I could have used 140,000.'' He had to supplement with fish and horse, and young alligators do n't grow as quickly on that diet. In addition, too much fish gives alligators gout.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890301-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-89 0036EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Quebec-English     03-01 0710</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quebec-English,0733</SECOND>
<HEAD>English Speakers Resigned To Loss On Bilingual Issue</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SOLL SUSSMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MONTREAL (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It appeared the French and English languages could live together in <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION> after separatist fervor abated nearly a decade ago, but the struggle resumed in December and French appears to have won. New issues arise constantly, such as whether the inside of a bus is really outside for sign purposes, and the answer almost every time is that the signs must be only in French. The English-speaking minority, although disgruntled, appears to accept that the fight is lost. `` Resigned is probably the right catchword,'' said <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, a psychology professor at <ORGANIZATION> McGill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. Language is `` a symbol of identity and it also is a resource that has associated power, and status, and success and access,'' he said. `` So these apparently minor events evoke very primary feelings.'' <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION> was a battleground of culture and language in the 1970s between the 81 percent with <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> heritage and a minority with a cultural kinship to <LOCATION> Ontario </LOCATION> and the other English-speaking provinces. Power shifted to the French-speaking majority in those years but the separatist tide ebbed after 1980, and with it the dispute over language, when <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION> voters rejected a sovereignty referendum. Then came a ruling by the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canada </ORGANIZATION> in December that a 1977 Quebec requiring all signs to be in French was unconstitutional. The court said French could be required to predominate on all signs but other languages could not be prohibited. The provincial government, which has broader powers than state governments in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, overrode the decision with new legislation for the language on signs. Bill 178, as it is known, requires that all outdoor signs still be solely in French, but for the first time since 1977 allowed bilingual indoor signs. Premier <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Bourassa </PERSON> described it as a compromise. Rallies by activists of both communities have accompanied the latest round. English signs posted in the street risk being spray-painted and a fire blamed on arson heavily damaged the offices of <LOCATION> Alliance </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION>, the main English-language lobby. Fewer street protests are held now, but the conflict continues as regulations under <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> 178 are interpreted to restrict indoor bilingual signs more than originally believed. `` It's taken 21 years, but the <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION> language war is finally over. And the English have lost,'' political columnist <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> MacPherson </PERSON> wrote in <LOCATION> Montreal </LOCATION>'s English-language daily <ORGANIZATION> Gazette </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Quebec </ORGANIZATION> said in an interview: `` My concern about Bill 178 is its silliness. You do n't like a law to be silly.'' As an example, he cited the <PERSON> Bourassa </PERSON> government's determination that the inside of a bus is really an outside location and thus not a proper site for bilingual signs. `` A lot of people in both communities were spoiling for a fight,'' <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> said. `` The signs became symbols. Certainly the signs themselves are not what's at play.'' A prevailing view in <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION> is that the vigorous political fight of the 1970s spawned a new entrepeneurial spirit in the French community, as seen in the province's support for the new free trade agreement with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Business administration became the major of choice at French-language universities. <PERSON> Bourassa </PERSON>'s provincial <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> trounced the nationalist <LOCATION> Parti </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Quebecois </LOCATION> in 1985 elections. Many English speakers opposed to learning French left the province and, expecially among the young, bilingualism is becoming the norm. Alliance Quebec figures put the rate of bilingualism among the English community, which is centered in <LOCATION> Montreal </LOCATION>, at 60 percent in 1986 compared with 37 percent in 1971. Until December, the issue of signs was portrayed as being no longer controversial. Since then, however, English speakers have described the denial of bilingual signs as a major violation of individual rights and the French say the restriction is necessary to preserve their culture in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. `` The language is the essence of culture,'' said <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Filion </PERSON>, a Party Quebecois member of the <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION> legislature. `` This compromise -LRB- Bill 178 -RRB- is unacceptable to both the Francophone and the Anglophone.'' <PERSON> Filion </PERSON> said any relaxation of the sign law erodes <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> as the main language of the province. `` Our position is that Mr. <PERSON> Bourassa </PERSON> should have maintained the status quo,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890301-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-89 0013EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Sakharov     03-01 0269</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Sakharov,0279</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sakharov Says Soviets Shot Own Troops In Afghanistan</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT W. TROTT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet activist <PERSON> Andrei </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> has been told that Russian helicopter gunships fired on their own ground troops to prevent their capture by Afgan rebels, his son-in-law said Tuesday night. In the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> Gromov </PERSON>, who led the last contingent of Soviet troops out of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> on Feb. 14, said the allegation was `` monstrous.'' <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> has no evidence that Soviet airmen fired on their own soldiers, `` but he has heard it and he believes it,'' said his son-in-law, <PERSON> Efrem </PERSON> <PERSON> Yankelevich </PERSON>. <PERSON> Yankelevich </PERSON> refused to allow The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> to speak directly with <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON>, who with his wife, <PERSON> Yelena </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonner </PERSON>, is staying with his in-laws in suburban <LOCATION> Newton </LOCATION>. `` He did n't specify from whom -LRB- he heard -RRB- this kind of accusation,'' <PERSON> Yankelevich </PERSON> said. `` He's not the first to make these accusations.'' <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> first made the charge in an interview with a Canadian radio station during a recent visit, according to an article in the Soviet military newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Gromov </PERSON> told the newspaper Tuesday that he had never seen a Soviet unit attack another to prevent capture and interrogation by the <ORGANIZATION> Mujahadeen </ORGANIZATION> rebels. `` I state definitely that there had not been nor could have been facts so monstrous,'' <PERSON> Gromov </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Yankelevich </PERSON> responded, `` On the basis of the facts -LRB- available to <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> -RRB-, he has no reason to retract his statement.'' <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> and Mrs. <PERSON> Bonner </PERSON> arrived in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> on Feb. 18 on their first such visit together. It is not known how long their visit will last.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890301-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-89 0153EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     03-01 0660</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0737</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's TV Shows Ratings</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of Feb. 20-26. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with full season-to-date ranking in parentheses, rating for the week, and total homes. An `` X'' in parentheses denotes one-time-only presentation. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 90.4 million TV homes. 1. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 27.2 rating, 24.5 million homes. 2. -LRB- 3 -RRB- `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 24.9, 22.5 million homes. 3. -LRB- 2 -RRB- `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 24.2, 21.8 million homes. 4. -LRB- 5 -RRB- `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 23.8, 21.5 million homes. 5. -LRB- 4 -RRB- `` Cheers,'', <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 23.3, 21.0 million homes. 6. -LRB- 8 -RRB- `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 22.8, 20.6 million homes. 7. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 22.5, 20.3 million homes. 8. -LRB- 7 -RRB- `` Who's The Boss?'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 21.9, 19.7 million homes. 9. -LRB- 20 -RRB- `` Naked Lie,'' _ `` CBS Sunday Night Movie,'' 21.2, 19.1 million homes. 10. -LRB- 11 -RRB- `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.8, 17.9 million homes. 11. -LRB- 9 -RRB- `` Empty Nest,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.7, 17.8 million homes. 12. -LRB- 12 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.6, 17.7 million homes. 13. -LRB- 15 -RRB- `` In the Heat of the Night,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.2, 17.3 million homes. 14. -LRB- 13 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.6, 16.8 million homes. 15. -LRB- 17 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.5, 16.7 million homes. 16. -LRB- 14 -RRB- `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.4, 16.6 million homes. 17. -LRB- 28 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 17.9, 16.2 million homes. 18. -LRB- 17 -RRB- `` Unsolved Mysteries,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.5, 15.8 million homes. 18. -LRB- 29 -RRB- `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.5, 15.8 million homes. 20. -LRB- 22 -RRB- `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.2, 15.5 million homes. 20. -LRB- 26 -RRB- `` Knots Landing,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 17.2, 15.5 million homes. 22. -LRB- 25 -RRB- `` Original Sin,'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movie,'' 16.8. 23. -LRB- 37 -RRB- `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.7. 24. -LRB- 26 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.5. 25. -LRB- 20 -RRB- `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.1. 26. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Grammy Awards,'' CBS, 16.0. 26. -LRB- 10 -RRB- `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.0. 28. -LRB- 33 -RRB- `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.6. 29. -LRB- 17 -RRB- `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.8. 30. -LRB- 50 -RRB- `` Bridesmaids,'' _ `` CBS Tuesday Movie,'' 14.6. 30. -LRB- 47 -RRB- `` Macgyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.6. 32. -LRB- 38 -RRB- `` Midnight Caller,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.4. 33. -LRB- 45 -RRB- `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.3. 34. -LRB- 32 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>,'' CBS, 14.0. 34. -LRB- 22 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Gideon </PERSON> <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON>,'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Mystery Movie,'' 14.0. 36. -LRB- 24 -RRB- `` The Revenge of <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Capone </PERSON>,'' _ `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 13.9. 36. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` My Two Dads,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.9. 38. -LRB- 42 -RRB- `` Get Smart, Again,'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' 13.7. 39. -LRB- 30 -RRB- `` Designing Women,'' CBS, 13.4. 40. -LRB- 35 -RRB- `` Family Ties,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.3. 41. -LRB- 45 -RRB- `` Nightingales,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.1. 41. -LRB- 51 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' CBS, 13.1. 43. -LRB- 43 -RRB- `` Kate & amp; <PERSON> Allie </PERSON>,'' CBS, 13.0. 43. -LRB- 51 -RRB- `` Just the Ten of Us,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.0. 45. -LRB- 39 -RRB- `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.8. 46. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 12.5. 46. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Passion and Paradise, Part 2,'' _ `` ABC Movie Special-Tuesday,'' 12.5. 48. -LRB- 43 -RRB- `` Father Dowling,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.8. 49. -LRB- 48 -RRB- `` Day by Day,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.5. 49. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 11.5. 49. -LRB- 62 -RRB- `` Paradise,'' CBS, 11.5. 52. -LRB- X -RRB- `` The Karate Kid, Part 2,'' _ `` NBC Movie of the Week-Friday,'' 11.3. 53. -LRB- 63 -RRB- `` Beauty and the <LOCATION> Beast </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 11.1. 54. -LRB- 36 -RRB- `` Wonder Years,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.6. 55. -LRB- 67 -RRB- `` 48 Hours: <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 10.5. 56. -LRB- 64 -RRB- `` Dynasty,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.3. 57. -LRB- 55 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.9. 58. -LRB- 54 -RRB- `` Hooperman,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.8. 59. -LRB- 68 -RRB- `` Man Called Hawk,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.5. 60. -LRB- 66 -RRB- `` Magical World of Disney: The Absent Minded Professor,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.2. 60. -LRB- 69 -RRB- `` Tour of Duty,'' CBS, 9.2. 62. -LRB- 69 -RRB- `` Mission: Impossible,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.0. 63. -LRB- 73 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Dolphin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cove </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 8.3. 64. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 8.1. 65. -LRB- 79 -RRB- `` West 57th,'' CBS, 8.0. 66. -LRB- 64 -RRB- `` Almost Grown,'' CBS, 7.9. 67. -LRB- X -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> 75th Anniversary,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.8. 68. -LRB- 84 -RRB- `` Great Circus of the World,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.3. 69. -LRB- 88 -RRB- `` TV 101,'' CBS, 6.8. 70. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shandling </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.6. 71. -LRB- 85 -RRB- `` Heartbeat'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.4. 72. -LRB- 91 -RRB- `` Fine Romance,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.2. 73. -LRB- 88 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>'s Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 4.7. 74. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.6. 75. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` The Reporters,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.5. 76. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Duet,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.4. 77. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Beyond Tomorrow,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.2.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890301-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-89 0141EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     03-01 0350</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0361</SECOND>
<HEAD>CBS Comes on Strong, But NBC Extends Its Nielsen Streak</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Even <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Capone </PERSON> and <PERSON> Maxwell </PERSON> <PERSON> Smart </PERSON> were no match for <LOCATION> Victoria </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Principal </LOCATION> in a TV movie called `` Naked Lie,'' whose strong performance helped <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> remain out of last place for the fourth time in five weeks. `` The 31st Annual Grammy Awards'' also helped <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> take second place last week. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> has won every week except for one tie with CBS. Never mind that the <ORGANIZATION> Grammys </ORGANIZATION> had its lowest rating ever, 16.0, and ranked 26th. It still did better than <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> usually does on Wednesday nights. Another strong performer for <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> was a special two-hour `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>'' that wound up with the highest-rated episode of the durable night-time soap so far this season. It had a 17.9 and was ranked 17th. Principal's thriller `` Naked Lie'' vanquished <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Revenge of Al Capone'' and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s reunion movie `` Get Smart, Again!'' to win Sunday night and finish ninth in the weekly <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> ratings. Otherwise, the usual suspects rounded up the top 10: `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>; `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>; `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>; `` 60 Minutes,'' CBS; `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>; `` Murder, She Wrote,'' CBS; `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>; `` Who's the Boss?'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Dear John'' finished 10th, behind `` Naked Lie.'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, which at 36 straight weeks is creeping up on <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' record 40-week victory streak from 1962-63, won the week that ended Sunday with an average, prime-time rating of 16.2. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> had a 14.6. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> had 11.7. Each rating point represents 904,000 households with televisions. The share is a percentage of sets in use. Taking the three network news anchors to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> for Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s funeral did n't seem to produce extra ratings. The `` CBS Evening News'' had a rating of 11.7 and a 20 share. `` ABC World News Tonight'' had an 11.5 and 20 share. `` NBC Nightly News'' had an 11.0 and 20 share. The lowest-rated prime-time network shows of the week were: `` Mission Impossible,'' `` Dolphin Cove,'' `` West 57th,'' `` Almost Grown,'' `` <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> 75th Anniversary,'' `` Great Circuses of the World,'' `` TV 101,'' `` HeartBeat,'' `` A Fine Romance'' and `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>'s Law.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890301-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-89 0156EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SpeechDemons     03-01 0506</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Speech Demons,0525</SECOND>
<HEAD>Does Da Mayah Want Good English? You Betcha!</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BILL STIEG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 If youse talk like dis and do n't know nuttin' about grammah and good English, do n't let <PERSON> Mayah </PERSON> <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> know Yup, you be axin' for it. This spring, the mayor and schools chancellor <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON> are beginning a program to exorcise what <PERSON> Green </PERSON> calls `` speech demons'' from the lexicons of young New Yorkers who do n't know or use standard English usage. `` Axe'' instead of `` ask,'' for example. And `` pitcher'' instead of `` picture,'' `` brang'' for `` brought'' and `` meetcha'' for `` meet you.'' And, as <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> himself used to say, `` liberry'' instead of `` library.'' `` It was brought to my attention that I was saying ` liberry.' I was n't aware of it,'' <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> admitted Tuesday. The program grew out of <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>'s conversations with some of the nearly 1 million students in the city school system. `` It's <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yorkese </LOCATION> _ it's white, Hispanic, black,'' <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> said, responding to suggestions that the new language program was aimed at ethnic or racial groups. `` The language in some cases was un-understandable,'' <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> said, coining a word of his own. The mayor had asked <PERSON> Green </PERSON> to come up with a program to tackle the problem, and last week <PERSON> Green </PERSON> outlined it for <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> and provided a list of the most commonly mispronounced and misused words and phrases. The effort starts this spring with a one-day `` Putting Your Best Speech Forward Day,'' during which teachers in all grades will focus on the list of speech demons. A poster contest will produce graphics that will be circulated throughout the system. The long-term plan includes more debating, oral reports, public service announcements and a booklet of classroom activities aimed at improving English. All this, <PERSON> Green </PERSON> wrote, should lead to `` substantive improvement of oral communication skills.'' -LRB- Say what? Better speaking, you betcha -RRB-. <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> said for young New Yorkers to compete with the best students across the nation and get good jobs, they must be able to speak English properly and `` at the same time maintain your own heritage and wherever possible to learn the language of your ancestors.'' Some linguistic experts say such `` non-standard English'' is a kind of dialect that is n't considered incorrect in the students' social setting Professor <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Mayer </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> English </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said the effort could stigmatize some students. The chancellor's list, he said, included many phrases used by blacks and Hispanics. In his memo, <PERSON> Green </PERSON> pointed out that the program will make clear that `` our purpose is not to devalue anyone's home language. We will encourage students to recognize that to be successful in school and in the workplace, they must be able to use formal English effectively.'' `` This has nothing to do with accents,'' <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> said, although the list shows `` cau-nuh'' for `` corner.'' `` It has nothing to do with diction, it has to do with syntax, grammar. And the expressions they're going to concentrate on are effectively <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yorkese </LOCATION>, and they cut across economics and race and ethnicity.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890301-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-89 0156EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SpeechDemons-Example     03-01 0274</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Speech Demons-Example,0276</SECOND>
<HEAD>This Be Talkin' Terrible? Yup, You Betcha</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Speech Demons</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An example of the `` speech demons'' targeted for extinction in the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> schools: `` <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> says he was n't doin' nuttin'. So, I says to him, ` I'm goin' to da liberry, I'll meetcha there. But he did n't know where da liberry was at. I axe him, ` Are youse foolin' round? It's like, in midtown, you know. Pacifically, at da cau-nuh of 41st and Fifth.' He axes me if I was on' y goin' to da liberry. No, I says. ` What-cha doin' next?' he axed. ` First,' I says, ` I'm goin' to da museum to see some pitchers. Then, I'm goin' to see <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON> _ he be sick, and he ai n't got no food. I brang some soup for him.' I says I think this is da right thing to do. ` Yup, you betcha,' <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> says.'' Now, the same encounter rendered in proper English. `` <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> said he was n't doing anything. I told him, ` I'm going to the library. I'll meet you there.' He did n't know where the library was. I asked him, ` Are you fooling around? It's in midtown. Specifically, it's at the corner of 41st Street and Fifth Avenue.' He asked me if I was going only to the library. No, I said. ` What are you doing next?' he asked. ` First,' I said, I'm going to the museum to see some pictures. Then, I'm going to see <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON> _ he's sick and he has no food I brought some soup for him.' I said I thought this was the right thing to do. ` Yes, you're right,' <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890301-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-89 0206EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-MoneyorTime     03-01 0202</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Money or Time,0205</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Orders Drug Smuggler To Hand Over Millions or Face An Extra
10 Year</HEAD>
<DATELINE>READING, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A judge gave a convicted drug smuggler this choice: hand over nearly $ 2.95 million or have another decade added to your 8 -LCB- - year jail sentence <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> French </PERSON>, 37, did not say in court Tuesday whether he would pay up _ the law gives him a year to come up with the cash _ or serve the extra time. The seizure, ordered by Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Murchie </PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION> Reading </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, was the heaviest so far under <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s new Drug Trafficking Act, which allows courts to confiscate the proceeds of illegal drug smuggling. The court convicted French in August of plotting to smuggle 790 pounds of marijuana into <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> with the help of an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> France </ORGANIZATION> employee. His sentencing was postponed until Tuesday for an inquiry into his assets. During a hearing on the assets, <PERSON> Murchie </PERSON> was told of <LOCATION> French </LOCATION>'s various aliases, his 21 bank accounts in <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> and his companies or other interests in <LOCATION> Luxembourg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Liberia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> The judge said Tuesday that he assessed French's assets from drug smuggling at $ 4.3 million, with $ 2.95 million recoverable.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890301-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-89 0208EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Dance     03-01 0363</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Dance,0375</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cunningham Dance Company Opens</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: No PMs Planned</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Merce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cunningham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION> opened its season at the City Center on Tuesday with the premiere of `` Five Stone Wind,'' and the choreographer himself was among the dancers. For much of this 55-minute work, the stage is full of dancers but all are motionless except one or two. The primary motif consists of standing on one foot while stretching, bending and rotating the other leg. This is not a dance that flows. There are many entrances and exits, from five different points. Only occasionally do dancers move in unison or as duet partners. <PERSON> Cunningham </PERSON>, who will turn 70 in April, does arm stretches, bends and turns, usually in the back of the group, once on stage alone. One would expect him to look silly among his trim, young dancers. But he fits the tone of the dance and makes one think about the effectiveness of one or two more mature dancers in the bunch. <PERSON> Cunningham </PERSON> is inventive enough, even pursuing one choreographic idea, to keep one interested throughout. Also, we like long dances so the evening is n't spent mainly in intermissions between short dances. Still, we became restless before the end. Costumes are leotard tops and skirts or pants, later leotards only for the women, in varying colors chosen by <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Lancaster </PERSON>. The score was created by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Cage </PERSON>, <PERSON> Takehisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Kosugi </PERSON> and <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Tudor </PERSON> and has a few painfully loud bursts of sound. The first part of `` Five Stone Wind'' had its premier in <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> last June. The complete work bowed at the Festival d'Avignon in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> in July. The evening began with <PERSON> Cunningham </PERSON>'s 1968 `` RainForest.'' The company's <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> season runs through March 12, and two other premieres are scheduled: `` Cargo X'' and `` Field and Figures.'' The company will perform at the <ORGANIZATION> Leicester </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Festival </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> March 16 to 18, at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION> in Tempe April 1 and 2, <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> May 1 through 7 and C.W. <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> on <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> May 12. During July and August the company will dance in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890301-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-89 0052EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-Names     03-01 0984</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1031</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ANNAPOLIS, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Donovan </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Baltimore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Colts </ORGANIZATION> football player and perpetual jokester, tried a joke out on an anti-abortion crowd but no one thought it funny. Noting that he weighed 17 pounds at birth, <PERSON> Donovan </PERSON> said, `` If anybody should have thought about having an abortion, it was my mother.'' When no one laughed, <PERSON> Donovan </PERSON>, the rally's keynote speaker, quickly turned serious, saying he was against abortion because he is Irish Catholic and `` my church told me'' abortion is wrong. Thousands of demonstrators rallied Monday night at <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to protest legalized abortion <PERSON> Donovan </PERSON> is author of a biography entitled `` Fatso'' and appears frequently as a guest on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Late Night with <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Letterman </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It was n't exactly `` God Is My Copilot,'' but only because that seat was taken by an instructor as Archbishop <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahony </PERSON> took off in a $ 400,000 helicopter given to the Archdiocese of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mahony </PERSON>, 53, will use the helicopter to drop in on the 275 parishes in the nation's most populous Roman Catholic archdiocese, which covers an area larger than <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. `` It's part of the <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> scene now. Traffic is really a problem,'' said the archbishop, who took the gift out for a spin Tuesday. The helicopter, blessed by the archbishop and sporting a St. Christopher medal on the instrument panel, was donated by a group of businessmen. The helicopter has generated criticism from some advocates for the poor who say the money could have been better spent in the archdiocese, but <PERSON> Mahoney </PERSON> said the gift wo n't cost the archdiocese anything.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Aspiring actor <PERSON> Rob </PERSON> <PERSON> Camilletti </PERSON> has pleaded no contest to two counts of vandalism for smashing a photographer's camera equipment outside the home of his girlfriend, <PERSON> Cher </PERSON>, a prosecutor said His attorney entered the plea Tuesday. <PERSON> Camilletti </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> bagel maker, pizza chef and bartender, faces up to one year in jail and a $ 2,000 fine when he is sentenced March 14. <PERSON> Camilletti </PERSON>'s run-in with free-lance photographers who were staking out <PERSON> Cher </PERSON>'s home occurred last July. He was accused of trying to run photographer <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Brandt </PERSON> down in a Ferrari and damaging his camera equipment. A prosecutor said she will move to dismiss a reckless driving charge. <PERSON> Cher </PERSON>, 42, and <PERSON> Camilletti </PERSON>, 24, have been companions since meeting at a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> nightclub on her 40th birthday.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 No more just The Material Girl, <PERSON> Madonna </PERSON> is The Collector. The singer-actress has joined <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Cosby </PERSON>, Barbra Streisand and other celebrities on a list of the top 100 collectors in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Antiques magazine said Tuesday. <PERSON> Madonna </PERSON>, who earned $ 46 million in 1988, is a newcomer to the annual list _ cited for her `` top-notch collection of vintage photographs, particularly female nudes and boxers, and paintings by European masters.'' <PERSON> Cosby </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Camille </PERSON>, fill their home with American furniture and art, especially <PERSON> Shaker </PERSON>, and are the premier collectors of black folk art, the magazine said. Streisand favors <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> furniture and recently paid a record $ 363,000 for a 1903 sideboard that once graced designer <PERSON> Gustav </PERSON> <PERSON> Stickley </PERSON>'s dining room.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> has a vision of `` Disneyland in <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'' and `` the most spectacular building'' in the country _ his casino. The 1,250-room <ORGANIZATION> Trump </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Taj </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mahal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Casino </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resort </ORGANIZATION> _ compete with Arabic-style domes, an amusement park and a heliport _ will be the biggest gambling casino in the world, <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> said Tuesday. <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, casino will be worth $ 1 billion when about 4,000 workers finish building it in early 1990. Construction began in 1983. <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> bought the property several months ago. His plans: a 3,000-seat fast food restaurant, a 5,000-car garage, a 42-story hotel, and a sports arena with enough space to park eight blimps. `` I want people to walk in and freak out,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Cast member <PERSON> Sinbad </PERSON> of the critically praised TV sit-com `` A Different World'' said the show's shortcomings are tempting him to leave `` Sometimes my role gets expanded but sometimes they do n't use me for two or three weeks,'' said <PERSON> Sinbad </PERSON>. `` I have to be all the way in or all the way out. I ca n't straddle the fence. It's hard for me emotionally because I want to give something to the show.'' The comedian plays dormitory director and gym coach <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Oakes </PERSON> at fictional <ORGANIZATION> Hillman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> on the <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> show, a spin-off of `` The Cosby Show.'' This season the sit-com has held the No. 2 spot on the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> ratings and some critics have called it TV's most improved show.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prince <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> will visit the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION> next month, Buckingham palace said. The husband of Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> will be in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> from March 12-15 for several engagements, and travels to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> on March 15 to attend a fund-raising event for the English-speaking Union of the Commonwealth. The next day, he flies to the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION>, the palace said Tuesday.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: Longer version moved on sports wire.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>PHOENIX (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A judge convicted <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lakers </ORGANIZATION> center <PERSON> Kareem </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdul-Jabbar </PERSON> of two misdemeanor offenses stemming from an April shoving incident in a shopping mall. <PERSON> Abdul-Jabbar </PERSON>, 41, the <ORGANIZATION> NBA </ORGANIZATION>'s all-time leading scorer, brushed away a camera held by an Italian tourist, who was following <PERSON> Abdul-Jabbar </PERSON> around a mall. The tourist said he suffered a bruised eye and a scratched ear from the force of the shove by the 7-foot-2, 265-pound athlete. <PERSON> Abdul-Jabbar </PERSON> told police the tourist was bothering him. Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wiehn </PERSON> on Tuesday set sentencing for March 29. <PERSON> Abdul-Jabbar </PERSON> could be fined up to $ 1,750, sentenced to 10 months in jail and put on five years' probation. <PERSON> Abdul-Jabbar </PERSON>, in his 20th and last season, did not appear at the court proceeding.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890301-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-89 0103EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Obit-Lorenz 2ndLd-Writehthru a0778 03-01 0710</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Lorenz, 2nd Ld-Writehthru, a0778,0730</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nobel Laureate Lorenz Dies Age 85</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS last graf and LEADS with 4 grafs to CORRECT title of book
and move up first reference to it. Picks up 5th graf, a0697, `Chancellor
Franz ...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALISON SMALE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VIENNA, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Konrad </PERSON> <PERSON> Lorenz </PERSON>, the world-renowned scientist and author who won a Nobel prize for his pioneering work in the field of human and animal behavior, has died at age 85, the <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> said Tuesday. <PERSON> Lorenz </PERSON>, who died of kidney failure Monday night, was famous both for his research and for the best-selling works on behavior that won him a worldwide reputation as a great humanist. Among his best-known books is `` On Aggression.'' In 1973, <PERSON> Lorenz </PERSON>' behavioral research won him the Nobel Prize for Medicine along with the scientists <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Frisch </PERSON> and <PERSON> Nikolaas </PERSON> <PERSON> Tinbergen </PERSON>. Chancellor <PERSON> Franz </PERSON> <PERSON> Vranitzky </PERSON> said Tuesday the nation had lost a `` pioneering researcher and a humanistic thinker.'' In science, <PERSON> Lorenz </PERSON> was known above all for his discovery of a process known as imprinting, or the rapid and almost irreversible learning process that occurs in early childhood, bonding animals to their biological mothers. But he showed the process could be changed, demonstrating that mallard ducklings, for example, would happily follow a human who greeted them shortly after birth and imitated quacking. To millions, <PERSON> Lorenz </PERSON> was famed as the `` father of the gray geese,'' a man whose detailed studies of geese and other birds and animals led him to some penetrating and often gloomy conclusions about humanity and its future. His most controversial findings suggested that innate and instinctive behavior in animals, such as aggression, might be instinctive in humans as well. `` He was a man of genius, the founding father of ethology,'' said <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> behavioral scientist <PERSON> Remy </PERSON> <PERSON> Chauvin </PERSON>, who was close to <PERSON> Loren </PERSON>. `` For me, he was a father figure,'' said Austrian scientist <PERSON> Bernd </PERSON> <PERSON> Loetsch </PERSON>, a student of <PERSON> Lorenz </PERSON>. `` The thrust that this tiny land made in science and environmental thinking owes much to him.'' Born Nov. 7, 1903 in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>, the son of a well-known surgeon, <PERSON> Lorenz </PERSON> gained his first doctorate in medicine in his native city at the age of 25. Five years later, after studies in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, he held a doctorate in zoology and psychology on the basis of a thesis on the flight of birds. Between 1923 and 1939, <PERSON> Lorenz </PERSON> devoted months to learning the `` language'' of the many birds he kept in his home. <PERSON> Chauvin </PERSON> said <PERSON> Lorenz </PERSON> was prompted to work with animals in nature after his studies in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, where he noticed that the behavior of caged white rats he studied there differed from that of wild rats he had observed in <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>. `` He slept with geese, lying down beside them, to put their behavior in perspective, but also for observations on man and the child, without prejudices,'' <PERSON> Chauvin </PERSON> said. In 1939, <PERSON> Lorenz </PERSON> was given a professorship in the German town of <LOCATION> Koenigsberg </LOCATION>, today the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> port of <LOCATION> Kaliningrad </LOCATION>. While there, he wrote papers considered to reflect Nazi views of science, making him the target of criticism years afterwards. In 1973, accepting the Nobel prize, <PERSON> Lorenz </PERSON> apologized `` most deeply.'' `` Many highly decent scientists hoped, as I did, for a short time for good from National Socialism, and many quickly turned away from it with the same horror as I,'' he said then. In 1941, <PERSON> Lorenz </PERSON> was drafted. Captured by the Russians in 1944, he spent four years as a prisoner of war, a time he later described as `` midway between being a teacher, a joker, a clown and a soul-soother.'' Returning home in 1948 with a manuscript written on sacks of cement and published years later as `` The Back Side of The Mirror,'' <PERSON> Lorenz </PERSON> founded a center for behavioral research in <LOCATION> Altenberg </LOCATION>. In the 1950s, he worked mostly in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, where he headed the <ORGANIZATION> Max </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Planck </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Behavioral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Physiology </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Bavaria </LOCATION> from 1961 to 1973. Beginning in the 1960s, <PERSON> Lorenz </PERSON> authored a series of best-selling books including `` On Aggression,'' which was put out in German in 1963 and in English in 1966, `` The Eight Deadly Sins of the Civilized World,'' `` Comparative Behavioral Studies,'' `` The Decay of the Humane,'' and `` The Evolution of Thought.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890301-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-89 0223EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SenateTrip Bjt   03-01 0728</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Senate Trip, Bjt,710</SECOND>
<HEAD>Most Senators Spurn Inviting Offer from Inouye</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Most of Sen. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON>'s colleagues on a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> panel have spurned his invitation to join him on a six-nation tour, despite his promise that the taxpayer-paid trip will mix pleasure with business. <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Hawaii </LOCATION>, the new chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appropriations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> subcommittee </ORGANIZATION>, has invited 17 panel members to accompany him to the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> for an `` on-the-scene evaluation of the changes which are occurring in several areas of significance to our nation's defense requirements.'' But <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON>'s letter of invitation also notes other attractions in <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>. `` I also intend to make a special effort to allow time for visits to museums, art galleries, and religious and historical sites in the capitals and the countryside of these countries,'' <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON> wrote. Citing protocol demands, he suggested that the senators bring along their spouses on `` what I know will be a most enjoyable and productive trip.'' `` Far from being a ` congressional junket,' this trip will take us to areas which I believe we need to visit to understand the dimensions of the problems confronting <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> national security and to meet the responsibilities we face as members of the subcommittee on defense,'' he said. The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> obtained a copy of the letter, which proposes the trip for the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s Easter vacation the last two weeks of March. Only Sen. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Lautenberg </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, has definitely signed up, although three senators, <PERSON> Arlen </PERSON> <PERSON> Specter </PERSON>, R-Pa.; <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>, D-La; and <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> <PERSON> Garn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Utah </LOCATION>, are undecided, according to an informal head count. The rest say they have no plans to go. Sen. <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Alaska </LOCATION>, said Tuesday that he has declined because `` I took those trips when I was chairman'' of the subcommittee. The itinerary calls for three nights in <LOCATION> Munich </LOCATION>, three in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, two in <LOCATION> Istanbul </LOCATION>, three in <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION>, three in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> and one in <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION>. The route was designed to allow members to see `` fracture zones'' of the geopolitical world, said <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON>, whose subcommittee oversees spending for the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION>. Along the way, the senators would share Easter services with American forces aboard a ship in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> and review fundamental changes under way in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> peace process. The congressional party will fly on an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> jet `` to ensure that we accomplish the objectives of our trip and to add a measure of security,'' <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON> said. The government picks up all expenses for members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. They receive daily per diem at the same rate as <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomats abroad. For example, the daily rate is $ 163 in <LOCATION> Munich </LOCATION> and $ 98 in <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION>. Congressional spouses travel free with their mates on military aircraft, but they must pay their own expenses. A <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official familiar with the trip, speaking on condition of anonymity, said arrangements such as the exact dates are not yet firm. In the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, foreign trips on behalf of a committee must be approved by the full committee chairman, while those on behalf of the full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> must have the approval of the chamber's majority and minority leaders. <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON> has yet to request formal approval of the trip from Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, chairman of the appropriations committee, according to <PERSON> Marsha </PERSON> <PERSON> Berry </PERSON>, the committee <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, also a member of the defense panel, will not accompany <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON>. <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, said spokeswoman <PERSON> Tina </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, `` plans to travel to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>; that's the only traveling he'll do in March.'' <PERSON> Lautenberg </PERSON> wants to accompany <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON> because `` he's new on the committee and he wants to see all the installations,'' said his spokesman, <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Schlein </PERSON>. At least 13 subcommittee members said they have no plans to go, most of them citing prior commitments and more pressing business at home. Sen. <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Rudman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, is n't going in part because he does n't like being in a `` large delegation. ... He tends to prefer trips that are more focused,'' said his spokesman, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobson </PERSON>. Sen. <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON>, D-Vt., declined because he recently returned from the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, an aide said Senators have other plans for the recess, according to the members or their aides: <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hollings </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-S.C. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON>, D-Tenn.; <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ariz </LOCATION>.; <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Bumpers </PERSON>,; <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Harkin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Iowa </LOCATION>; <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McClure </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Idaho </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Kasten </PERSON>, R-Wis.; <PERSON> Alfonse </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Thad </PERSON> <PERSON> Cochran </PERSON>, R-Miss
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890301-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-89 0127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     03-01 0026</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0025</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Down In Tokyo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 31,964.30, down 21.30 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Wednesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890301-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-89 0232EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DrugDilemma Bjt   03-01 0617</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drug Dilemma, Bjt,0634</SECOND>
<HEAD>Murder Trial Avoided By Unusual Tactic</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ARLENE LEVINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Gena </PERSON> <PERSON> Spero </PERSON> might be legally insane. But if she takes the medication that calms her, she could be in prison for the rest of her life. The drug dilemma has kept the 25-year-old <PERSON> Spero </PERSON> shuttling between jail, mental institutions and courtrooms since Jan. 10, 1983, the day she allegedly strangled 21-year-old <PERSON> Gina </PERSON> <PERSON> Sindoni </PERSON>, whose nude body was found in a bathtub. After <PERSON> Spero </PERSON> was charged in the slaying, she was diagnosed as a paranoid schizophrenic and placed on antipsychotic medication. She was found competent to stand trial if she relied on such drugs. <PERSON> Spero </PERSON>, now a psychiatric patient at <ORGANIZATION> Medfield </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, is taking her lawyer's advice to refuse the drugs he calls a `` chemical straitjacket'' that would give her the equilibrium to face her accusers in court. Attorney <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Colella </PERSON> said that only without the drugs would a jury see her insanity unmasked, accurately reflecting his client's condition the day <PERSON> Sindoni </PERSON> was killed Several forensic psychiatrists questioned the ethics of <PERSON> Colella </PERSON>'s advice, including Dr. <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Katz </PERSON>, who teaches at <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> He called the medication <PERSON> Spero </PERSON> would take `` mind-restoring, not mind-altering'' and said he wondered about the welfare of such patients. `` I feel it's a bad investment on the part of any attorney who recommends this to a patient. ... Mental illness can be a very painful and troubling and extremely uncomfortable condition for many people,'' he said. In a recent interview, <PERSON> Colella </PERSON> said: `` They argue that if she's not yelling and screaming, therefore she's cured ... If the criminal charges were to go away, she would still be a person who should be committed because she's a danger to herself and society.'' <PERSON> Colella </PERSON> backs his legal tactic with a 1981 decision by the state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judicial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> that a psychiatric patient could refuse medication. District Attorney <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Burke </PERSON> disagrees with <PERSON> Colella </PERSON>, and persists in hoping a judge will find <PERSON> Spero </PERSON> competent to stand trial so he can try her for murder. But she ca n't be ordered to take antipsychotic drugs, and at her annual reviews for mental competency, a judge has continued hospitalization. `` It's in the best interest of justice to have this case tried,'' <PERSON> Burke </PERSON> said. `` Either this is a case of murder, which we allege, or we have a defendant who would be found not guilty by reason of insanity. And the only way that will be resolved is through a trial.'' For three years, <PERSON> Spero </PERSON> was incarcerated at the state prison for women at <LOCATION> Framingham </LOCATION> until a judge ordered her moved to <ORGANIZATION> Medfield </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Spero </PERSON> was a student at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Amherst </LOCATION> when the killing occurred. <PERSON> Sindoni </PERSON> was attending <ORGANIZATION> Hampshire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>. The two women had been friends about seven months and had shared a house with other women in <LOCATION> Northampton </LOCATION> for a time. <PERSON> Spero </PERSON> had a history of mental troubles and checked into psychiatric hospitals on several occasions, <PERSON> Colella </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Spero </PERSON>'s arms are scarred with self-inflicted razor cuts and cigarette burns, <PERSON> Collela </PERSON> said. She hears voices and hallucinates. Since her hospitalization at <LOCATION> Medfield </LOCATION>, doctors there said she also suffers from temporal lobe epilepsy, <PERSON> Colella </PERSON> said. Temporal lobe epilepsy, for which <PERSON> Spero </PERSON> takes medication, is a psychologically debilitating illness that can cause sufferers to become suddenly angry or to exhibit other erratic behavior. Such attacks themselves would justify a defense of innocent by reason of insanity, <PERSON> Colella </PERSON> said. But nobody knows the extent of <PERSON> Spero </PERSON>'s problems. Over the years, she has been diagnosed with a variety of mental illnesses. A week before the slaying she sought psychiatric treatment, but she left before being admitted to the center.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890301-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-89 0247EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Brite-GadhafiLookalike     03-01 0144</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Brite-Gadhafi Lookalike,0149</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: Retransmits a0409 to change spelling to Gadhafi to conform AP
style</HEAD>
<HEAD>Gadhafi Lookalike at Denny's Prompts Call to 911</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MERRITT ISLAND, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sheriff's Deputy <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> responded skeptically when someone phoned 911 to report that <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Moammar </PERSON> <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> was dining at <PERSON> Denny </PERSON>'s. But when White and another deputy arrived at the restaurant Sunday night, he quickly spotted the customer that had prompted the call. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Belman </PERSON>, 34, was eating quietly with his 3-year-old son. `` We sat down beside him, and we were just laughing about the whole situation,'' <PERSON> White </PERSON> said. `` He favors him.'' <PERSON> Belman </PERSON>, a jeweler from <ORGANIZATION> Cocoa </ORGANIZATION>, said his face has gotten him into trouble before. `` At times it's fun and at times it's fearful,'' he said. `` I've seen -LRB- <PERSON> Gadhafy </PERSON> -RRB- on TV just a few times We do favor each other quite a bit.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890301-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-89 0311EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CurranRuling     03-01 0494</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Curran Ruling,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dissident Priest Gives up Fight for Academic Freedom after Court
Defeat</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LISA M. HAMM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Rev. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> will not appeal a judge's ruling that the <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> may bar him from teaching <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> theology because of his dissenting views on sexual ethics. `` I have lost, but the university, its faculty and students may have lost more than I,'' <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> said after <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Weisberg </PERSON> ruled in <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION>'s favor on all issues raised by <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> in his landmark breach of contract lawsuit. The District of <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> judge said the school has the right to make its own decisions in its struggle to balance its commitment to academic freedom with obedience to the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> was strongly criticized by <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> officials for his positions on abortion, homosexuality and other matters of sexual ethics during more than two decades teaching at <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION>. `` The court's opinion confirms what the university itself has asserted in this case _ that full academic freedom, as understood in American higher education, does not now exist at <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> said. `` I have fought for academic freedom at <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> for more than 20 years,'' he said. `` I have lost. As far as I am concerned, this was the last battle.'' <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> maintained the university violated his contract when last April it stripped him of his canonical mission, which the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> requires to teach Catholic theology. That action came two years after the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> declared <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> was no longer suitable or eligible to teach Catholic theology. <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> contended that the canonical mission requirement had fallen into disuse when he began teaching at <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> in 1965. He said a 1981 church rule making them mandatory did n't apply to him because it was n't in effect when he joined the faculty. The judge ruled that <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> should have understood that his contract changed at that time, requiring him to maintain a canonical mission. <PERSON> Weisberg </PERSON> also said the CUA faculty handbook, which by <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> law constitutes a contract, does not specify that professors have full academic freedom. <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> said he feared the ruling would place limits on academic freedom in other Catholic universities in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. But university officials said they felt vindicated. `` It does n't surprise me, to tell you the truth,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Byron </PERSON>, president of the university. `` This is really what I expected, because we never breached his contract. `` I regret that this ever came to litigation, but it's nice not to lose.'' <PERSON> Curran </PERSON>, who remains a tenured professor at <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> but can not teach there, has taught as a visiting professor at <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and is currently at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Byron </PERSON> said the offer remains open for <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> to teach at <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> if he will accept an alternative assignment. But <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> said that will never happen. `` It's a matter of principle,'' he said. `` I could not do that.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890301-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-89 0317EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     03-01 0786</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>Farm Prices Dip Since January, But Still Higher than Last Year</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Agriculture Department's preliminary figures for February show that prices farmers get for raw products declined 0.7 percent from their January average but still were 14 percent above a year ago. Lower prices for soybeans, lettuce, milk and corn were mostly responsible for the decline from January, the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> said Tuesday Higher prices for tomatoes, strawberries, potatoes and hay partly offset the decline in the other commodities. `` Prices of food grains increased from January to February while feed grains and oilseed prices decreased,'' the report said. `` The all-wheat price moved to the highest level since April of 1981, but the average corn and soybean prices dropped from January to February.'' Tomato prices moved up sharply during the month, and the February average for cattle and calves was the highest since May 1979. The report also included revisions showing that prices received by farmers actually rose 2.8 percent from December to January instead of the 1.4 percent gain reported a month ago. Agriculture Secretary <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, meanwhile, that the farm economy as a whole `` is continuing to make real progress in recovering'' from the hard times of the early and mid-1980s. Last year's drought helped reduce supplies of major crops, including corn, soybeans and wheat, which has resulted in higher prices. `` The higher prices have helped maintain a high cash income level for those farmers with supplies to sell and for the sector as a whole,'' <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. `` However,'' he added, `` the drought dealt a severe blow to many producers in drought areas who lost much of their crop and who did not have prior-year crops to sell. It also placed a heavy burden on livestock, poultry and dairy producers who were faced with higher feed costs.'' According to the preliminary February price figures, based mostly on midmonth averages, the index for livestock and livestock products as a group declined 0.6 percent from their January average but still were up 5.4 percent from February 1988. The department's all-crops price index for February was down 1.4 percent from January but averaged 27 percent above a year ago. No new price figures for farm production costs were included in the February report. Those have been confined to quarterly averages because of budget cutbacks. Although the projections are subject to change, <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> economists say that net cash income of farmers may be in the range of $ 48 billion to $ 52 billion this year, compared with a near-record of $ 57 billion in 1988. That is the difference between cash receipts and cash expenses during the calendar year. Department economists say cash expenses are expected to rise moderately in 1989 with expanded crop acreages and costlier production items. Food prices in 1988 rose an average of about 3.7 percent, and <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> analysts say another increase of 3 percent to 5 percent is likely in 1989.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has announced his intention to appoint a Californian, <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Parnell </PERSON>, to the No. 2 post at the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Parnell </PERSON>, 53, has been director of the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> state department of food and agriculture since 1987 and has been high on the preference list of <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> to be deputy secretary. Reports had circulated last week that although <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> favored <PERSON> Parnell </PERSON> some officials at the White House were leaning toward former <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> governor <PERSON> Louie </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>. <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>, however, branded as `` totally untrue'' reports of him bickering with the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> over the appointment. <PERSON> Parnell </PERSON>, whose appointment is subject to <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> confirmation, would succeed <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> in the $ 89,500-a-year <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> job. The announcement on Tuesday said that before <PERSON> Parnell </PERSON> became <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> state director of food and agriculture he was head of the state's department of fish and game, 1984-87, and that from 1966 to 1983 he was a pedigree livestock auctioneer. <PERSON> Parnell </PERSON> also was owner and publisher of the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cattlemen </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Magazine </ORGANIZATION>, 1966-72, and field editor for <PERSON> Pacific </PERSON> <PERSON> Stockman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Stockman </PERSON> Weekly, 1964-66. The announcement said <PERSON> Parnell </PERSON> `` has also managed and operated diversified agricultural operations.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Agriculture Secretary <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> has named <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> <PERSON> Winkler </PERSON> <PERSON> Shipp </PERSON> as his press secretary, a job she had when <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> was <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade representative during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. <PERSON> Shipp </PERSON>, 29, previously worked at the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> where she was press secretary to Rep. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> McDade </PERSON>, R-Pa. The <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> press job pays $ 57,158 a year. <PERSON> Shipp </PERSON> was reared on a farm in <LOCATION> Alexis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, where her parents still raise corn, soybeans and hogs. She is a communications and fine arts graduate of <ORGANIZATION> Bradley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Peoria </LOCATION>, Ill.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890301-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-89 0319EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FBI-Discrimination     03-01 0485</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-FBI-Discrimination,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>FBI Chief Promises Action to End Job Bias Within Bureau</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> efforts to end discrimination against blacks, Hispanics and women within the bureau will produce measurable results within a year, Director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sessions </PERSON> says. `` I have made it clear throughout the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> _ not just to top management _ that all forms of discrimination are repulsive and will not be tolerated,'' Sessions told a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Judiciary panel Tuesday. He told the subcommittee that he would fight not only hiring discrimination but racial harassment and a practice that Hispanic <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents say has repeatedly blocked them from advancement within the bureau. The Hispanics say they are often thrown into stopgap roles for which Spanish-speaking agents are needed and as a result miss out on in-depth investigative experience that leads to promotion. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>, responsible for enforcing the nation's civil rights laws, has 8,723 special agents, of whom 419 are black, 453 are Hispanic, 119 are of Asian background and 40 are American Indians. Sessions told the panel that represents an increase of 27 black agents and 54 Hispanics since October 1987. Trainees not yet in the field are included, however, and <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> officials were unable to say immediately how many employees have been added overall since 1987, thus leaving unclear the percentage increase in minorities if any, noted Rep. <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Fla </LOCATION>. `` We may have lost ground as far as agents in the field and may need to catch up,'' <PERSON> James </PERSON> said `` We have a catch-up program,'' Sessions said. He said, however, that he would be able to present the lawmakers with measurable improvement over the current situation within a year. Discrimination suits against the bureau, one brought by 238 Hispanic agents, have resulted in disclosures of bias. Bureau recruiters have been barred from using the facilities at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> law school because of findings in the Hispanic agents' suit, although Sessions still plans to deliver the commencement address at the school this year. Members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> are urging the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> to settle the lawsuits quickly. `` They have in my opinion been embarrassing,'' said Rep. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sensenbrenner </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Wis </LOCATION>. He urged Sessions to get `` these problems behind us because, in my opinion, we all have more important things to do.'' Sessions said he would increase the authority of the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s Equal Employment Opportunity chief and give the official `` direct personal access to me upon request.'' If managers balk at proposed changes, he said, `` the <ORGANIZATION> EEO </ORGANIZATION> officer will be instructed to come directly to me.'' `` There will be no ambiguity about the role of this new office in the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>,'' Sessions said. Problems in local offices should be directed to resident <ORGANIZATION> EEO </ORGANIZATION> counselors swiftly, Sessions said. He promised steps to make these counselors, some of whom have come under criticism, `` more responsive to the needs of their peers.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890301-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-89 0321EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PersianGulf-Ships     03-01 0598</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Persian Gulf-Ships,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gulf Minesweeping Force Cut in Half</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NORMAN BLACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
