<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890831-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-89 2354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ChemicalWeapons     08-31 0382</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Chemical Weapons,0392</SECOND>
<HEAD>Army Decides Tooele Army Depot Will Dispose Of Chemical Arsenal On-Site</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT MIMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SALT LAKE CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Tooele </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Depot </ORGANIZATION>'s aging stockpile of nerve and mustard gas, 42 percent of the nation's chemical arsenal, will be destroyed on-site in a new $ 138 million incineration plant, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday. In a report to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, the Office of the Secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> said none of the chemical munitions at the remote western <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> desert installation would be moved elsewhere for destruction. While the decision did not address other sites where chemical weaponry is stored, it was considered a victory for advocates on-site disposal at <LOCATION> Tooele </LOCATION>, 35 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, and seven other <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bases. The Army had considered disposing of the weapons at regional plants or one national site, which would have required potentially risky transport by air, rail, truck and barge. <PERSON> Cindy </PERSON> <PERSON> Vaughn </PERSON>, spokeswoman for <ORGANIZATION> Aberdeen </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, Proving Ground, the program manager for the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s chemical demilitarization effort, said similar announcements are expected for the other sites where chemical weapons are stored, once environmental studies are completed. The <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s decision followed recommendations contained in an environmental impact statement released in July. The new plant will employ a construction work force of about 350, and once operational in December 1992, will have 400 employees. <PERSON> Vaughn </PERSON> said site-specific <ORGANIZATION> EIS </ORGANIZATION> studies, such as the one conducted at <LOCATION> Tooele </LOCATION>, also are planned for <ORGANIZATION> Aberdeen </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Anniston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Depot </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Lexington-Blue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grass </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Depot </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Newport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ammunition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plant </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Ind </LOCATION>.; Pine Bluff Arsenal, Ark; Pueblo Depot Activity, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Umatilla </LOCATION> Depot Activity, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>. Further on-site disposal decisions are expected to be made `` down the line,'' as each <ORGANIZATION> EIS </ORGANIZATION> is finished, she said None of the studies has been completed. Tooele's stockpile, some of which dates back to World War II, includes nerve, mustard and other blistering agents contained in rockets, artillery projectiles, mortar rounds and bombs. In all, the depot has nearly 800 such munitions, some of which are leaking, stored in earth-covered igloos. <PERSON> Vaughn </PERSON> said the new plant will use disassembly and incineration technology studied at <LOCATION> Tooele </LOCATION>'s Chemical Agent Munitions Disposal System pilot plant and the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Johnston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atoll </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> Agent Disposal System facility. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has ordered the old chemical arsenal destroyed by 1997.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890831-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-89 2337EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-FosterHomeFire     08-31 0562</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Foster Home Fire,0580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Four Children Die in Early Morning Fire at Foster Home</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A predawn arson fire in a foster home killed four children and injured 12 other people, with two adults and four children hospitalized in critical condition, fire officials said. The fire was the work of an arsonist, said fire Lt. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Christmas </PERSON>, who added that smoke detectors were found in the house but nothing indicated they had been installed. He would not elaborate. Neighbors said they woke up shortly before 3 a.m. smelling smoke and hearing the cries of children. `` I heard the kids and they were screaming, ` Help me! Help me!' It was horrible,'' said <PERSON> Gloria </PERSON> <PERSON> Page </PERSON>, who lives next door. When firefighters arrived at the three-story, stone-and-frame house, they found heavy fire in the first floor and people trapped upstairs. Neighbor <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> said he woke up hearing a car in the street honking its horn. `` Then I looked out the window and I saw all this fire raging in the front of the house,'' he said. <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> said he ran behind the house and found three or four children who had jumped from second - and third-story windows He said he looked up and saw `` five or six more'' standing at the windows. `` They were crying and shaking and screaming,'' he said. <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> said he tried to build a platform out of wood so the children could have a shorter distance to jump. `` They would n't jump on it, so I told them to jump and I'd catch them. So they jumped and I tried to catch them or break their fall,'' <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> said. The fire was under control by 3:20 a.m., firefighters said. Seventeen people lived in the house, firefighters said. The children who died were found on the second floor. Police identified the dead children as <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Moye </PERSON>, 7, and his brother, <PERSON> Preston </PERSON> <PERSON> Moye </PERSON>, 5; <PERSON> Anwar </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartwell </PERSON>, 9, and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Lavenhouse </PERSON>, 15. The house belonged to <PERSON> Hubert </PERSON> and <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> <PERSON> Artis </PERSON>, a couple who took in foster children and had lived on tree-lined Park Avenue for about 13 years. Mrs. <PERSON> Artis </PERSON>, 65, was in critical condition at <ORGANIZATION> Albert </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Einstein </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> with multiple fractures and smoke inhalation. Also in critical condition at <LOCATION> Einstein </LOCATION> were <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Seymour </PERSON>, 20, <PERSON> Victoria </PERSON> <PERSON> Palmer </PERSON>, 15, and <PERSON> Christine </PERSON> <PERSON> Knight </PERSON>, 3, all suffering burns and smoke inhalation. <PERSON> Pauline </PERSON> <PERSON> Palmer </PERSON>, 17, was in critical condition at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agnes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> with burns, and <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Mills </PERSON>, 12, was in critical condition at <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Christopher </LOCATION><LOCATION> 's </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> for Children. In addition, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Bullock </PERSON>, 28, was in stable condition at <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> with a fractured wrist and smoke inhalation. Three others, <PERSON> Hubert </PERSON> <PERSON> Artis </PERSON>, 65; <PERSON> Michelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>, 20; and <PERSON> Latasha </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodgers </PERSON>, 18, were being evaluated at Temple for burns and smoke inhalation. <PERSON> Jarvis </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, 2, was treated at Temple for smoke inhalation. Neighbor <PERSON> Sylvia </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> described the Artises as a good-hearted couple who took in so many children because they had plenty of room in their spacious house. The Artises had been foster parents since 1972, according to <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Olanoff </PERSON> of the city's <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>. State law prohibits more than six children in a foster home, but police counted 11 children living among the 17 residents of the house when the fire broke out. <PERSON> Olanoff </PERSON> said the department granted the Artises a waiver to care for eight children about a year ago.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890831-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-89 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-PuertoRico-Shooting 1stLd-Writethru   08-31 0473</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Puerto Rico-Shooting, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0716,0486</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gunmen Kill Five in Insurance Office</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS throughout to UPDATE with silencers apparently used, claim
Medellin cartel sympathizers behind shooting; no pickup.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN JUAN, Puerto Rico (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three gunmen apparently using silencers opened fire in a medical insurance office Thursday, killing five people and wounding a sixth before fleeing, police said. Police spokeswoman <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON> said the gunmen opened fire without warning in the third-story Medical Collection Services office in suburban <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Piedras </LOCATION>. She said police suspected robbery was the motive. The office was ransacked, but it was not immediately known if any money was taken. An anonymous caller, saying he represented the <ORGANIZATION> Medellin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cartel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, telephoned the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> late Thursday and claimed the shooting was retribution for `` the decision taken by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his allies'' to help the <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> government's war against drug lords. It was impossible to verify the authenticity of the caller's claims Police Superintendent <PERSON> Ismael </PERSON> <PERSON> Betancourt </PERSON> said he never heard of the group, and did not speculate on whether it could be responsible for the shooting. <PERSON> Betancourt </PERSON> said police were investigating. The five killed were <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>, both 36, the couple who owned <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Collection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, and three employees, said <PERSON> Jorge </PERSON> <PERSON> Valentin </PERSON>, who manages the building where the agency is located. A fourth employee, <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Cerra </PERSON>, in his 50s, was seriously injured by a gunshot wound in the back of the head. <PERSON> Cerra </PERSON> told police and reporters that the gunman knocked at the office door and immediately began shooting when he opened it. He said he was hit and then fell to the ground unconscious. He was hospitalized at the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Juan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. No other people were in the office at the time, police said. Since no one else in the building heard the shots, police said they believed the gunmen used silencers. Ms. <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON>, the police spokeswoman, said officials did not know whether the gunmen stole any money from the agency, which mailed clients' claims forms to insurance companies and received payment through checks. The anonymous caller said six people jailed in <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> and allegedly linked to the <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> drug cartel `` are not alone and we are ready to fight to the end because the money we obtain -LRB- from drugs -RRB- is used exclusively for the proletariat.'' The anonymous caller said the shooting `` constitutes a clear, precise and final message that we know the government will wisely understand.'' Several weeks ago the <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION>, on the east side of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Juan </LOCATION>, began hearings for six peopel allegedly linked to the <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> drug cartel. Prosecutors claim the six dealt in $ 10 million worth of cocaine every week and were responsible for the March 7 shooting death of a man in <LOCATION> Trujillo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alto </LOCATION>, in northeast <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>. Their trial is expected to begin in September.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890831-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-89 0003EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-PopFest     08-31 0437</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Pop Fest,0453</SECOND>
<HEAD>Music Festival or Spectacle: The 20-Year Difference</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LEWISVILLE, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Twenty years after a pop festival took over this <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> suburb, a beer company is sponsoring a rock fest that shows the <LOCATION> Woodstock </LOCATION> era is long past. Organizers put together the 1969 <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pop </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Festival </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Lewisville </LOCATION> in seven weeks with a shoestring budget, but <ORGANIZATION> Miller </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brewing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> has pushed this weekend's concert series for more than a year with television ads and other promotions. At the shows, the psychedelic drugs of yesteryear will give way to drinking arrangements for designated drivers. `` The whole tone of the two shows 20 years apart is remarkably different,'' <PERSON> Angus </PERSON> <PERSON> Wynne </PERSON>, who promoted the <LOCATION> Lewisville </LOCATION> festival, said Tuesday. Just three weeks after the <LOCATION> Woodstock </LOCATION> rock festival in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> state </LOCATION>, about 120,000 people spent three days on a field outside <LOCATION> Lewisville </LOCATION> to hear the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Janis </PERSON> <PERSON> Joplin </PERSON>, <PERSON> Santana </PERSON>, Sly and the Family Stone, B.B. King, Grand Funk Railway, Led Zeppelin and others. This weekend, <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> hopes to draw 500,000 people to concerts in six <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> cities, including performances by the Who in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>. The concerts culminate a 16-month campaign by the company. In addition to the Who, performances by <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kool </PERSON> and the Gang, <PERSON> Natalie </PERSON> <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> and many others are planned in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Corpus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Christi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> McAllen </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Midland-Odessa </LOCATION>. It took <PERSON> Wynne </PERSON> seven weeks and $ 120,000 to line up all 30 acts. Promoters of the <LOCATION> Lewisville </LOCATION> festival said they lost $ 100,000. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> has n't disclosed its budget, but the Who grossed $ 1.04 million at a concert before 47,000 fans in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> three weeks ago. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> has pledged to give at least $ 1 million in proceeds to the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Special Olympics. The company and promoters have made elaborate security arrangements. People will need wristbands to gain access to the concerts. Designated drivers will receive different colored bands entitling them to free soft drinks and baring them from buying beer. Twenty years ago, drugs were common, but the crowd behaved. There were only 36 arrests, most for public intoxication. `` Psychedelics and pot, I believe, were the prevalent stimulants of choice,'' said <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Houston </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Denton </LOCATION> judge who was mayor of <LOCATION> Lewisville </LOCATION> from 1969 to 1973. When it was over, residents were surprised by the long-haired, easygoing rock fans. Some concertgoers mowed lawns and babysat for residents during their stay. `` That was part of the mind-blow thing that went on here,'' <PERSON> Wynne </PERSON> said. `` People expected all these folks to be real nasty, and here they were handing them flowers, just as polite as they could be. It disarmed them totally.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890831-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-89 0532EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--BostonHarbor     08-31 0169</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Boston Harbor,0172</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study Shows Fish Defects Down but Pollution Still a Threat</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A recent study of <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> found fewer fish with bent fins, dwarfism or liver abnormalities associated with pollution, but researchers say the inlet is far from environmentally sound. `` We do n't conclude from the study that in fact things are getting better,'' said <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, senior scientist at the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> England </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aquarium </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Edgerton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION>. Nearly 200 winter flounder caught one day in mid-May showed fewer instances of cancerous lesions as well as other defects, compared to studies in the early 1980s. However, <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said Wednesday, defects were markedly higher than the numbers found in cleaner environments further out in the sea. `` No changes have gone on in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> yet,'' he said, adding that partially treated sewage still is being dumped there. The state plans to spend $ 6.1 billion to clean up the pollution, which then-candidate <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> frequently cited in running against Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in last year's presidential campaign.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890831-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-89 0007EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Reagans     08-31 0211</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Reagans,0217</SECOND>
<HEAD>Greet Soviet Children at Camp for Kids with Cancer</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MALIBU, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON>, greeted four Soviet girls recovering from cancer during a tour of a camp for children with the disease. The <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> came to this seaside town outside <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> on Wednesday to visit Camp <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON> for Good Times. The girls, whose cancer is in remission, are spending a week at the camp with their doctors. Speaking through an interpreter, 13-year-old <PERSON> Angella </PERSON> <PERSON> Mihay </PERSON> said she was impressed with the warmth and openness of the former first couple. She joined <PERSON> Tanja </PERSON> <PERSON> Shmorgoner </PERSON>, 13, and 11-year-olds <PERSON> Alina </PERSON> <PERSON> Ivanova </PERSON> and <PERSON> Nina </PERSON> <PERSON> Dgenda </PERSON> in serenading the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> in Russian. The Reagans ate macaroni and cheese with 100 children. Soviet doctors <PERSON> Lev </PERSON> <PERSON> Durnov </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ilana </PERSON> <PERSON> Mikelova </PERSON> gave the couple hand-carved wooden bowls and spoons, and children gave them pillows made of quilt patches depicting camp life. `` The whole idea behind the camp is to give children with cancer a camp experience like any other child,'' said <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON>'s spokesman <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>. `` There's swimming, frisbee, basketball, just like any normal camp. The kids are encouraged to participate in all they can.'' `` We would like to organize a camp like this one, maybe near <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Mikelova </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890831-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-89 0017EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Abortion-CourtOrder     08-31 0411</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Abortion-Court Order,0424</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Drops Suit Seeking to Prevent An Abortion By Former Girlfriend</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TRIP DuBARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COLUMBIA, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man who sued his ex-girlfriend to prevent her from having an abortion dropped his lawsuit Wednesday, saying he believed she was n't pregnant. <PERSON> Elton </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> dropped his lawsuit after learning through a variety of sources, though not from a medical examination, that the 23-year-old woman known as `` <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Doe </PERSON>'' was not pregnant, said his attorney, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Whiting </PERSON>. However, the woman's attorney said <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> knew no more about her client's condition Wednesday than when he began his court fight last week. `` They've dropped the case. ... We take the position that that is a victory,'' said attorney <PERSON> Victoria </PERSON> <PERSON> Eslinger </PERSON>. The withdrawal nullified a court order barring the woman from seeking an abortion, canceled a <ORGANIZATION> Lexington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Family </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> hearing on the lawsuit scheduled for Thursday and left Ms. <PERSON> Eslinger </PERSON>'s client free to do what she wished. Ms. <PERSON> Eslinger </PERSON> said the woman `` was extremely relieved'' by <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s decision. The woman still refuses to say whether she is pregnant or not, her attorney said. <PERSON> Whiting </PERSON> asked the woman to take a pregnancy test, but she refused. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> and the woman had a three-month relationship that ended a month ago, but <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> had wanted her to carry the fetus to term if she was pregnant, Ms. <PERSON> Eslinger </PERSON> said. On Aug. 23, <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> won the temporary restraining order, which had been set to expire next Monday. Ms. <PERSON> Eslinger </PERSON> said the withdrawal of the lawsuit vindicated her belief that the <ORGANIZATION> Family </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> did not have jurisdiction in the case and affirmed what she said was a woman's right to terminate a pregnancy in the first three months. <PERSON> Whiting </PERSON> countered that the case did not need to proceed once <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> became convinced the woman was not pregnant. `` I do n't think this particular case ended up being a test on any issue because it was stopped,'' he said. <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Bates </PERSON>, executive director of the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> chapter of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, said the lawsuit appeared to be part of a concerted effort by anti-abortion activists to alter the law. `` This is guerilla warfare by the right-to-lifers,'' <PERSON> Bates </PERSON> said. `` There is no legal basis for bringing these actions.'' <PERSON> Whiting </PERSON> said <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s motives were sincere. `` This case was not brought for publicity reasons,'' he said, predicting the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s July decision expanding the states' right to limit abortion could spark similar cases.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890831-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-89 0020EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-KnotNews     08-31 0669</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Knot News,0687</SECOND>
<HEAD>Inside-Out Knot Adds New Twist on Men's Ties</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT DVORCHAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP National Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For men who think fumbling with a tie each morning is a pain in the neck, here comes a new wrinkle in the quest for a firm, symmetrical knot. It's an inside-out style called the Shelby. Touted as the `` first new knot for men in over 50 years'' by a <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> clothier, the knot was introduced to a <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION> TV anchorman by a viewer who chafed at his lumpy, twisted neckwear. `` I got sick and tired of looking at his tie every night. He always had a big knot in it,'' said <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Pratt </PERSON>, 92, a retired manager for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> who lives in <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>. So in 1986, <PERSON> Pratt </PERSON> collared <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Shelby </PERSON> in the lobby of <ORGANIZATION> WCCO </ORGANIZATION> and, quick as you can say clip-on, shared a formula he had used for at least 40 years. The secret is to start with the seams out. With a bit of sartorial sleight-of-hand, the knot forms securely and the broad part flows down the shirt, finished side out. The shorter blade underneath still has the seams and the label facing out, although it can be clasped with a pin or twisted so the seams will turn in. It's simple to tie and works best with wider collars. <PERSON> Pratt </PERSON>, as humble as he is meticulous, said he stumbled across the knot by accident and never thought of it giving it a name through decades of secure wear. `` One morning I put my tie on inside out, I tied it and it worked. That was it,'' he said in a telephone interview Wednesday. `` The beauty of it is the knot wo n't twist to one side or the other. A tie sets the whole theme of dress. If it's twisted, that's the first thing people notice.'' <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> M </PERSON>, a custom men's clothier in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paul </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, learned of the knot, refined it and established the tie-in with <PERSON> Shelby </PERSON>. It printed a five-step diagram for customers seeking alternatives to the bulbous Windsor knot or the tightly tapered four-in-hand, the most common knot among American men. `` You're getting a balanced knot, but it's small and precise, not big and bulky like the <LOCATION> Windsor </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Kingford </PERSON> <PERSON> Bavender </PERSON>, an executive with <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> `` I made up the cards because I had so many customers ask me, ` Why does your tie hang so much better than mine?''' But because the knotting begins with wrongside out, purists may not like it. `` It's not for everybody. You'll never see one of the Kennedys wearing it,'' <PERSON> Bavender </PERSON> said. The knot's newness apparently is legitimate. The method of creating the Shelby does n't appear in `` Getting Knotted _ 188 Knots for Necks,'' a reference guide for ties, scarves, ascots and cravats distributed by <ORGANIZATION> Ratti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Silk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mills </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Como </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, and used by the <ORGANIZATION> Neckwear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>. However, it does resemble a knot called the <PERSON> Nicky </PERSON>, invented by a Milanese restaurateur and said to have been the favorite knot of former Soviet leader <PERSON> Nikita </PERSON> <PERSON> Krushchev </PERSON>. `` It's a variation of the <PERSON> Nicky </PERSON>, but it was not documented anywhere I've seen,'' said <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Neckwear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, who notes that 100 million ties are sold each year in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and American men own an average of 20 ties. `` Personally, it leaves a little too soft a knot for my taste. I prefer a knot that has more body to it,'' <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> said. For his part, <PERSON> Shelby </PERSON> is a bit red-faced at all the fuss. `` I really think people notice the knot in your tie about as much as the knot in your shoes,'' <PERSON> Shelby </PERSON> said. `` I do it because it's easy to tie, you can do it in your sleep, and it puts that little dimple in the tie automatically `` Now I'm known for the knot. People come up to me and say, ` Hi, <PERSON> Don </PERSON>. How are you? Nice knot you got there.'''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890831-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-89 0023EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-KnotNews-Steps     08-31 0076</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Knot News-Steps,0080</SECOND>
<HEAD>With Knot News</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are five steps involved in tying the Shelby knot. 1. Start with the tie seamside out, with the wide end under the narrow end. 2. Loop the wide end over and under the narrow end. 3. Tighten to take up slack. 4. Take wide end across to the right and under the neck loop. 5. Thread wide end down through the knot and tighten.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890831-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-89 0023EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Helmsley-Glance     08-31 0257</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Helmsley-Glance,0274</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Look at the Helmsley Empire</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Helmsley Trial</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Real estate mogul <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Leona </PERSON>, who was convicted Wednesday of tax evasion, head a real estate and hotel empire worth $ 5 billion and are personally worth an estimated $ 1 billion. Their <ORGANIZATION> Helmsley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprises </ORGANIZATION> is the holding company for the <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> businesses which include the following:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>HELMSLEY-SPEAR INC.</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Annual revenues of $ 1.1 billion. Manages or owns 50,000 residential apartments and 50 million square feet of commercial space in over 600 buildings nationwide, ranging from ordinary office towers to middle-class residential projects. Prominent holdings include the Empire State Building, the Flatiron Building, and One Penn Plaza.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>HELMSLEY HOTELS INC.</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Operates six luxury hotels in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> _ the <LOCATION> Helmsley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palace </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Carlton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lane </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Helmsley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Windsor </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> and the <LOCATION> Middletowne </LOCATION>. The Cleveland-based chain, <ORGANIZATION> Harley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hotels </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, named after <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> and <PERSON> Leona </PERSON>, operates 17 budget hotels and motor inns in 10 states.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>DECO PURCHASING AND DISTRIBUTING CO.</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Purchases supplies for hotels. This company was operated by <PERSON> Leona </PERSON> <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON>'s son, <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Panzirer </PERSON>, who died in 1982. Panzirer, who was in poor health, dropped his other hotel clients and re-established his firm as a subsidiary of the Helmsley hotel empire.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>OWNERS MAINTENANCE</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Cleaning services company that holds contracts with many buildings managed by <ORGANIZATION> Helmsley-Spear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>OTHERS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Other <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> companies provide insurance, purchasing and advertising services to buildings that <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> owns or manages in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and across the country.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890831-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-89 0128EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-GunsN'Roses     08-31 0268</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Guns N' Roses,0272</SECOND>
<HEAD>Guns N' Roses Member Released After Arrest for Airline Incident</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Note contents</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PHOENIX (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The rhythm guitarist for the rock group <ORGANIZATION> Guns </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> N </ORGANIZATION>' Roses has been released on $ 5,000 bail after being arrested for urinating in a jetliner's galley area, the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Izzy </PERSON> <PERSON> Stradlin </PERSON> was arrested Sunday at <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> Sky Harbor International Airport during a scheduled stop of <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION> Flight 350, en route from <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Geffen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION> publicist <PERSON> Bryn </PERSON> <PERSON> Bridenthal </PERSON> said <PERSON> Stradlin </PERSON> was angry at having to wait to use the plane's restroom and `` relieving himself in the galley was just his way of expressing himself.'' <PERSON> Stradlin </PERSON>, whose real name is <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Isbell </PERSON>, was arrested and charged by the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> with interfering with the duties of the plane's crew _ a felony. He spent Sunday night behind bars and was released Tuesday after posting bail. <PERSON> Bridenthal </PERSON> said the incident capped a bad day for <PERSON> Stradlin </PERSON>. `` He'd been bitten in the face by a dog in <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> and he was still a little bit shocked by that,'' said the publicist for the band's record label. `` And when he got on the plane, he was bumped from first-class into coach. It was just sort of one bad thing piling up on another.'' In a court statement, <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivas </PERSON> said <PERSON> Stradlin </PERSON> `` went to use one of the restrooms. When he got to the restroom, it was apparently occupied and he stated, ` I'm not waiting any ... longer' and unzipped his pants and urinated in the galley area'' in front of several passengers and a flight attendant.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890831-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-89 0023EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     08-31 0048</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0050</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Wednesday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 01; 03; 13; 21; 26; 36.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto Game: 03; 11; 20; 36; 40; 47. Supplementary 46.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 4-3-4; 0-4-4-1; 9-7-3-1-7; 9-7-6-0-0-0.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890831-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-89 0041EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-PalestinianEconomy     08-31 0683</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Palestinian Economy,0706</SECOND>
<HEAD>Economic Pressure Mounts on Palestinians in West Bank</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN RICE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In days past, weddings in <PERSON> Hamad </PERSON> <PERSON> Badr </PERSON>'s family called for the slaughter of 20 sheep. But when a brother got married three months ago, two were sacrifice enough. The wedding was a victim of the 20-month intefadeh, or uprising against <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> occupation, which has squeezed livelihoods and altered lives for Palestinians throughout the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. Repeated strikes by Palestinian workers, curfews imposed by the Israeli army and a drop in tourism have slashed incomes. As the economy has declined, the Jordanian dinar _ the key currency in the occupied lands _ has plunged in value by 50 percent, further ravaging savings and paychecks. Badr, whose family has owned a four-table restaurant in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>'s walled <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> for 25 years, said his business has been devastated. `` Before, if you wanted to get food, you'd have to wait outside for half an hour,'' said <PERSON> Badr </PERSON>, who now closes for the day at noon to comply with the orders of clandestine uprising leaders. `` Today you see: in a half an hour, we sold only two Coca-Colas.'' Nearly all Palestinians insist that the struggle for daily bread has not weakened their will to resist Israeli occupation. But the dinar's recent plunge coincided with a seeming drop of intensity in the uprising and an increase in factional squabbling in <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> ranks. `` If you are angry and hungry, you have to satisfy your hunger first,'' explained <PERSON> Tarik </PERSON> <PERSON> Said </PERSON>, who owns a photo shop near <LOCATION> Badr </LOCATION>'s restaurant But he said that rather than forcing an end to resistance, more violence is the likely result. An official of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s military government in the occupied lands said economic hardship was beginning to be felt in a widespread way for the first time but that it was too early to say it would mean an end to the uprising. <PERSON> Samir </PERSON> <PERSON> Saleh </PERSON>, an economist at the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Bir </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zeit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, said Palestinian incomes have fallen and buying power is probably half what it was when the uprising began in December 1987. Average incomes per capita declined by 25 percent from a pre-uprising level of $ 1,000 a month. <PERSON> Saleh </PERSON> said the falling value of the dinar `` has disastrous effects.'' The currency has been a major means of payment and savings for Palestinians since <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> lost the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> in 1967. `` Here people only believed in God and the dinar,'' said <PERSON> Nabil </PERSON> <PERSON> Feidy </PERSON>, a money changer on <PERSON> Salah </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Din </PERSON> <PERSON> St. </PERSON> in east <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>. The dinar was worth $ 3 early last year, but fell to less than $ 1 in July before recovering recently to about $ 1.50. Hospital workers, college teachers, Islamic preachers and tens of thousands of private employees still earn wages in dinars, and most paychecks have not risen as the dinar's purchasing power declined. <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Hassan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON>, an Islamic preacher who dropped by to visit <PERSON> Badr </PERSON>, said he was forced to move his wife and two children out of their apartment and into a single room of his father's house. `` My salary is 160 dinars,'' said <PERSON> Ali </PERSON>, noting that it used to be worth about $ 480 but now is worth $ 200. `` The impact on people here is devastating,'' said <PERSON> Feidy </PERSON>, the money changer. `` The worst part is that people have their dinars in Jordanian banks and they ca n't bring them.'' In an effort to stem the flow of orders and money from the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> sharply curtailed travel and financial transfers across the <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. Palestinians can now bring in only 200 dinars a person per month. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has countered a tax boycott by Palestinians with increased fees on vehicles. <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Jafaar </PERSON>, a teacher who has seen his salary cut in half because of the frequent strikes and school closures, said fees on his car have risen to the equivalent of about $ 700 a year from $ 80. He has opened a small grocery store in his home. `` The shop is not a way of living but it helps.'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890831-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-89 0046EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Aunties     08-31 0768</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Aunties,0790</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Old Aunties' Rule Neighborhoods for the Party</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Gao </PERSON> <PERSON> Yugui </PERSON> and her seven `` old aunties'' preside over Shady Willow Street like boarding school headmistresses, poking their noses into everyone's business with government blessing. Did someone park their winter coal supply in front of someone else's door? Is a mother-in-law quarrelling with her daughter-in-law? Is a student playing hookey? Is anyone marrying, pregnant or getting divorced? All this and more the 72-year-old Mrs. <PERSON> Gao </PERSON> regards as her business. Her eight-member committee of retired women _ and committees just like it in every neighborhood of every city in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> _ are the very backbone of the Communist government's public control system, the grassroots link in the chain of supervision. The committees, appointed by local authorities, are unpaid. `` Everyone knows me,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Gao </PERSON> said of her 1,085-family neighborhood, made up of one main street and seven small alleys. `` When people hear ` old aunty' has come, it's ` Please come in.''' Many urban Chinese are less warm in their descriptions of the `` lao dama'' _ `` old aunties'' _ of the neighborhood committees, regarding them as nuisances at best, and dangerous snoops at worst. During the spring democracy movement, when hundreds of thousands of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> students and ordinary citizens poured into the streets to march for reform, the committees came into their own. On many streets, the old aunties went door to door urging residents not to join the protests. Their armies of political activists in red armbands, also all retired, stepped up patrols of the neighborhoods for unusual activity. After the army used force to clear away the protesters on June 3-4, the committees helped search homes for any weapons stolen from the army and reported on residents suspected of `` counterrevolutionary'' activities. Mrs. <PERSON> Gao </PERSON> kept such good order in her domain that <LOCATION> Shady </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Willow </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION> has been named a model `` People-Army Cooperation Street.'' A circular issued by the party <ORGANIZATION> Propaganda </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> declared the neighborhood an example of building `` socialist spiritual civilization'' and said Mrs. <PERSON> Gao </PERSON>'s committee showed `` a firm political stand, a high degree of socialist consciousness and a lofty patriotism.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Gao </PERSON> said she had no sympathy for the protesters, not even for the students whose weeklong hunger strike brought 1 million concerned residents into the streets. `` It's hard to get into college and the government spends money to train them,'' she said. `` If their health is ruined how can they make contributions to the country?'' Not one of the neighborhood's 3,750 residents, not even its 34 college students, took part in the protests, she vowed. Two students went to have a look _ but just once, to see the excitement, she said. Then they went back to their books, checked on daily by her and the other old aunties. Some older residents also went to look, she conceded, but `` very few, very few.'' `` Mrs. <PERSON> Gao </PERSON> has lived here many years and all the students know her ... and love her,'' said <PERSON> Fan </PERSON> <PERSON> Shuyun </PERSON>, an official from the local subdistrict office. `` So they listen to what she says.'' If they do n't love her, they might well fear her and her fellow aunties. Each day after getting together to read the official newspapers and study the latest government order, the eight graying women split into pairs and divide up the neighborhood, visiting stay-at-homes, inquring about their health and other news. Mrs. <PERSON> Gao </PERSON> said it would be impossible for any fugitive student leaders to hide in her domain. As soon as a stranger hits the neighborhood, she said, `` we will know right away.'' Questions are raised: `` Is he a friend? Where is he from? Did he register with police?'' Chinese law requires travelers to notify the local police station when staying away from home. The houses on Shady Willow Street are ancient one-story buildings built around small courtyards, sometimes with a dozen families per unit. Each courtyard has a chief who knows what the families in his unit do, where they go and who their friends and relatives are, Mrs. <PERSON> Gao </PERSON> said. During the spring turmoil, she said, the chiefs checked up: Was so-and-so at home today? Where did he go? When did he get back? `` If someone took part in the protests the courtyard chief would know right away,'' she said. `` We ca n't guarantee everyone tells what they do,'' said district official <PERSON> Feng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaomin </PERSON>, gently correcting Mrs. Gao. `` It's possible someone went out for a stroll and did n't say anything.'' `` But nothing happened or they would have been arrested,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Gao </PERSON> shot back.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890831-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-89 0137EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MannytheRobot     08-31 0680</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Manny the Robot,0699</SECOND>
<HEAD>Robot to Ensure Protection for Soldiers</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto SK3</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PEG McENTEE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DUGWAY PROVING GROUND, Utah (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Manny'' looks a bit the worse for wear, suspended in an Army warehouse with his stainless steel joints and plastic sensors exposed and a dusty black rubber mask on his head. But <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soldiers will someday have the mechanical man to thank for the effectiveness of their protective clothing. `` What we are hoping to achieve is to give the soldier greater confidence in the protective materiel he has available to him,'' said <PERSON> Lothar </PERSON> <PERSON> Salomon </PERSON>, scientific director at this remote post in <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>'s western desert. <PERSON> Salomon </PERSON> said he realized in 1985 that static mannequins and simulated chemicals were n't realistic enough to gauge clothing's protective capacity `` It just occurred to me, through various tests and results, that we should be able to do a better job in the testing of protective gear,'' he said. The idea was born for <PERSON> Manny </PERSON>, a $ 2.8 million robot <ORGANIZATION> Salomon </ORGANIZATION> calls `` the closest thing to a human being possible.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> sent its specifications to <PERSON> Battelle </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratories </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Richland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, which had devised robotics for the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> to handle radioactive materials. Last November, <PERSON> Battelle </PERSON> delivered the 5-foot-11, 187-pound robot, which is attached by a mechanical arm at the small of the back to a stainless steel control unit housing hydraulics and electrical systems. Later this year, <PERSON> Battelle </PERSON> will ship a hermetically sealed test chamber capable of containing such agents as chemical vapors and nerve gas, said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, technical group leader for mechanical systems and robotics. <PERSON> Manny </PERSON> will operate within the chamber in an undisclosed building on the 840,000-acre base, where the Army tests defenses against chemical warfare in the event it becomes a reality despite treaties banning it, <PERSON> Salomon </PERSON> said. The base obtained permission for such tests in 1982, said spokeswoman <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitaker </PERSON>. Tests involving biological agents are n't planned for the near future, but they are `` within the realm of possibility,'' <PERSON> Salomon </PERSON> said. A clear plastic molded on forms sculpted in aluminum gives <PERSON> Manny </PERSON> human shape, and electrical heaters keep a `` skin'' temperature at an even 98.6 degrees. Even without the outer skin of butyl rubber, <PERSON> Manny </PERSON> cuts an eerily human figure. His 38 joints are powered by rotary and linear actuators that enable him to walk at 3 mph, crouch, wave, sit, stand and crawl as guided by a computer program. The skin is fitted with sensors that can detect penetration of up to one-billionth of an ounce of a chemical or nerve agent. Perspiration is achieved by water coursing through capillary tubes on the surface of the rubber, and moist air is injected at the nose and mouth as air bladders in the chest expand and contract. Such realism is necessary to ensure that the stresses of human movement, particularly on seams, wo n't compromise protective material that might be subtly altered by a soldier's breath, said program manager <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> DeWitt </PERSON>. While toxic substance protection is <PERSON> Manny </PERSON>'s prime mission, the robot also is likely to be used to test the spectrum of military garb from firefighting gear and flight suits to field uniforms. <PERSON> DeWitt </PERSON> and computer operator <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON> have spent well over 500 hours testing <PERSON> Manny </PERSON>'s systems and writing movement programs, including a performance the robot gave during a six-week display at <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industry </ORGANIZATION> last winter. <PERSON> DeWitt </PERSON> said <PERSON> Manny </PERSON> drew crowds every time he ran through a 10-minute routine of drop-kicking a ball, walking, crouching, duckwalking and explaining his actions in a clipped electronic voice before folding into the pose of <PERSON> Auguste </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodin </PERSON>'s sculpture, `` The Thinker.'' In more than 500 hours of testing, <PERSON> Manny </PERSON> has been damaged only once, losing a knee-joint shear pin in a collision of his limbs, said <PERSON> DeWitt </PERSON>. Replacing the pin took 15 minutes. The Army has no plans for a second robot, although <PERSON> DeWitt </PERSON> said the possibility remains open. `` I think a lot of it will be based on his performance,'' <PERSON> DeWitt </PERSON> said. `` Personally, I think he'll do very well, but only time will tell.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890831-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-89 0200EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Colombia-Gacha     08-31 0852</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Colombia-Gacha,0877</SECOND>
<HEAD>Drug Kingpin Was Generous One Day, Murderous the Next</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Colombia, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HAROLD OLMOS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PACHO, Colombia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Gonzalo </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> <PERSON> Gacha </PERSON>, the drug lord who owned this town, was generous one day and evil the next. He gave money to adults and toys to children, killed people who displeased him and had a gallows in his yard. Few residents of Pacho would talk with a reporter about the billionaire former pig farmer, who would pass out $ 7,500 or so when he felt good and, when he did n't, might kill a motorist who got in his way. Last week, the crackdown on drug traffickers led the army to his hometown of 20,000 people 50 miles north of the capital <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Jaime </PERSON> <PERSON> Uscategui </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON>, the army colonel who led the raiding soldiers, said <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> <PERSON> Gacha </PERSON> was so feared in Pacho that, when his 18-year-old son went into a bar, the doors were closed to everyone else until he left. The son, <PERSON> Freddy </PERSON>, was arrested last week, but his father is still at large. At the main ranch, soldiers found 500 dolls wrapped for next Christmas inside the house and a wooden gallows outside. The government has confiscated the ranches and other property belonging to <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> <PERSON> Gacha </PERSON>. President <PERSON> Virgilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> ordered the raids and arrests after <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s cocaine barons killed Sen. <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Galan </PERSON>, the leading presidential candidate and a foe of the drug trade, on Aug. 18. Leaders of the drug cartels are said to own major office buildings and hundreds of ranches, and their importance to towns like <PERSON> Pacho </PERSON> is enormous. `` The people here will resent it, but in the end they will adapt to the new situation. We had no alternative,'' <PERSON> Uscategui </PERSON> said of the raids. He was interviewed at his headquarters office in one of the houses on a horse-breeding ranch <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> <PERSON> Gacha </PERSON> owned. Resentment is clear in Pacho, but whether the townspeople will adapt is not. They make little effort to disguise their hostility to outsiders. `` This town boomed on Saturday nights and restaurants like this one were packed,'' said <PERSON> Blanca </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>, a restaurant manager, speaking to a reporter and a photographer. `` Now look. You are my only customers. This town is dead.'' For years <PERSON> Pacho </PERSON> was owned almost entirely by <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> <PERSON> Gacha </PERSON>. Most people's jobs depended on him, directly or indirectly. `` His word was the real law here,'' said <PERSON> Uscategui </PERSON>, of the 13th <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brigade </ORGANIZATION>, which seized 20 ranches in the Pacho area in less than a week. He said <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> <PERSON> Gacha </PERSON> owned 18 of the ranches and `` at least 80 percent of the town was his.'' `` He is barely 41 or 42, but he was Pacho's master and he demanded respect for his status,'' <PERSON> Uscategui </PERSON> said. `` If a car got in his way and the driver did not apologize, he was a dead man. Nobody here had the right to protest without putting his own life at stake.'' Government officials say the property seized in the anti-narcotics campaign _ which includes 300 ranches, houses and apartments _ is worth more than $ 200 million. Newspapers value the traffickers' total property holdings in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> at $ 5.5 billion. <PERSON> Uscategui </PERSON> said <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> <PERSON> Gacha </PERSON> once tried to change <PERSON> Pacho </PERSON>'s name to <LOCATION> Chihuahua </LOCATION>, which he also chose for his main estate, or hacienda, `` but he could n't get enough support for it'' from government officials. <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> <PERSON> Gacha </PERSON>'s choice of the name <LOCATION> Chihuahua </LOCATION>, a state in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, reflected a passion for Mexican culture that led friends to call him <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexicano </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Pistolacho </PERSON>, the hacienda canteen, was done in Mexican and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> western decor, but former employees said it served more scotch, gin, French champagne, Chilean wine and German beer than tequila or mescal. Beside the canteen is a wooden gallows, complete with noose. It does not seem strong enough for a hanging, and the colonel said it appeared to be a symbol for the owner's bandit culture. `` Whatever it was for, it is macabre,'' he said. Pacho soon may feel the pinch of <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> <PERSON> Gacha </PERSON>'s absence, because he distributed money lavishly, <PERSON> Uscategui </PERSON> said. `` We know he gave away some 3 million pesos -LRB- $ 7,500 -RRB- daily,'' the colonel said. `` He was seen as a benefactor. Everybody had a job and everybody was happy. ... What he gave let him control the population.'' <PERSON> El </PERSON> <PERSON> Mexicano </PERSON> left <PERSON> Pacho </PERSON> as a pig farmer in the 1970s and returned as a rich man in 1982. He bought up ranches, frequently `` making offers nobody could reasonably refuse,'' which <PERSON> Uscategui </PERSON> translated as `` sell or die.'' `` He always paid well,'' the colonel said. `` If somebody was working elsewhere for, say, 40,000 pesos a month -LRB- $ 100 -RRB-, he doubled it.'' <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> <PERSON> Gacha </PERSON> even monopolized bus transportation in the region. His company and its buses also have been seized, and `` people in town will complain about bad transportation,'' <PERSON> Uscategui </PERSON> said. Soldiers found hundreds of Christmas gifts in the main house, including the 500 dolls and dozens of pairs of U.S.-made jeans and sneakers. <PERSON> Uscategui </PERSON> said of <PERSON> Freddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>, who was arrested along with seven bodyguards: `` The population thought no one would dare capture him. Well, we did it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890831-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-89 0228EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AIDSSpending Bjt   08-31 0762</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS Spending, Bjt,760</SECOND>
<HEAD>Spread of AIDS Will Test State Resources, Study Finds</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 State and local governments face increasingly difficult budget choices as the growing AIDS epidemic siphons more of their resources, according to a privately financed survey. Most states continue to rely heavily on federal money to support AIDS programs, but nine _ including <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> _ are spending more of their own funds this year than they are getting in federal grants. Additionally, states further down in the ranking of cumulative AIDS cases are increasing their spending to battle the disease by 10-fold or more, said the survey by the AIDS Policy Center at the <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` AIDS is going to increase the budgetary tradeoffs the states must make,'' said <PERSON> Mona </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowe </PERSON>, who helped conduct the survey paid for by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> for AIDS Research. In fiscal year 1989, states spent about $ 495 million in non-Medicaid funds on AIDS education, prevention, testing, care, research and other related activities. Of the total, states contributed $ 252 million from their own resources and received $ 233 million from the federal government to spend through state programs. The rest came from private sources. Overall, the bulk of federal AIDS spending is handled directly by the federal government or is funneled through the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> to private researchers. The House of Representatives has approved $ 1.6 billion for AIDS prevention, education and research during the fiscal year that begins Oct. 1. That is the level requested by the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration. However, there is growing emphasis on money for treatment _ especially now that the expensive drug AZT has been recommended for hundreds of thousands of people who carry the AIDS virus but do n't show symptoms of the disease Patient care `` is the next frontier'' for state spending on AIDS, especially with new government recommendations encouraging early intervention with expensive drug therapies and patient follow-up, the survey said. Currently, 64 percent of all non-Medicaid funds for AIDS-related patient care come from state coffers, the survey said. In a related development, 14 activist organizations wrote <ORGANIZATION> Burroughs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wellcome </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday to ask for a reduction in the price of AZT, sold only by the North Carolina-based drug manufacturer. The letter said that the $ 8,000 annual cost per patient of AZT will make it difficult to persuade <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to renew a program that subsidizes the cost of the medicine for patients who can not afford it. <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bartlett </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Burroughs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wellcome </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman, said the letter springs from `` a failure to recognize how pharmaceutical companies operate.'' `` It is marketed drugs that help pay for all of your research,'' she said. Costs for development, marketing and research, she added, `` are very, very high.'' She said <ORGANIZATION> Burroughs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wellcome </ORGANIZATION> gave 30 million capsules, wholesale priced at $ 1.50 each, to the federal government for the AZT trials. Also, she said, the company continues to conduct studies of the drug. Public health officials believe that up to 1.5 million people in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> are infected with the AIDS virus. As of July 31, AIDS had been diagnosed in 102,621 Americans, of whom 59,391 have died since June 1, 1981, according to the federal <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION>. Federal officials estimate that by the end of 1992, the number of reported AIDS cases in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will total 365,000. In that year alone, more than 80,000 new cases are expected to be reported and 65,000 people with AIDS are expected to die. Most state funds are spent on education, testing and counseling and patient care. Spending this fiscal year in these categories for the states overall more than doubled from last year, the survey found. Besides <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, the states spending more than they received in federal funds this year are: <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. On the other end of the spectrum, eight states are relying solely on federal funds for AIDS activities: <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>. The survey did not include AIDS spending growth rates for individual states because of differences in the data collected from year to year. But <PERSON> Rowe </PERSON> said the general trend shows that states with lower prevalence rates are increasing their AIDS spending the fastest. While <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> increased its state AIDS spending by 35 percent and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> by 31 percent, <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, ranked 8th in prevalence, boosted its state spending 10-fold, and <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, ranked 7th, and No. 13 <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state each increased their spending 12-fold, she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890831-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-89 0102EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-Names     08-31 0993</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1037</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Composer <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON> said he is deeply moved to be in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> in the wake of the continuing political transition toward democracy. `` I feel in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> a very great future,'' he said. <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON>, 71, will recite lines from W.H. <PERSON> Auden </PERSON>'s poem, `` September 1, 1939,'' at the start of a concert on Friday to commemorate the 50th anniversary of the outbreak of World War II. It will be transmitted live to more than 20 countries. Among the other international performers to participate in the concert: actress <PERSON> Liv </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullmann </PERSON>, soprano <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Hendricks </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s most famous contemporary composer, <PERSON> Krzystof </PERSON> <PERSON> Penderecki </PERSON> The concert will be held in <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION>'s Grand Theater where <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON> held a news conference Wednesday `` Today, like 30 years ago when I was here for the first time, I feel deeply moved by the visit to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>,'' he said. Part of the <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON> family came from a village very near present-day <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, he said. Asked to comment on the anti-war nature of the concert, <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON> replied: `` I have long felt war is obsolete. It is stupid and old-fashioned. As a Jewish person I have a very strong feeling about the need for peaceful understanding.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Playboy </ORGANIZATION> founder <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON> and his new wife, <PERSON> Kimberley </PERSON> <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON>, are expecting a child in April, a spokesman says. <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON>, 63, had hinted recently that he and his bride were going to have a child. `` If anybody wants to know what we did on our honeymoon, they'll find out in April,'' <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON> said, according to <ORGANIZATION> Playboy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Farley </PERSON> <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON> and the 26-year-old former Playmate of the Year were married July 1. <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON> has two children from a previous marriage: daughter <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>, the head of <ORGANIZATION> Playboy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprises </ORGANIZATION>, and son <PERSON> David </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>HIGHLAND PARK, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The high heels are there, as are the short skirt and the wild hair. Singer <PERSON> Tina </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> of high-energy rock' n' roll fame takes over center stage for <ORGANIZATION> Plymouth </ORGANIZATION>'s new advertising campaign with an uncharacteristically subdued performance. She talks in a straight-forward manner about <ORGANIZATION> Plymouth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Acclaim </ORGANIZATION>, Laser and Sundance cars and the Voyager minivan. She ends each spot with a soft-spoken `` That's right, <ORGANIZATION> Plymouth </ORGANIZATION>.'' But <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> fans expecting her throaty, hard-driving singing are going to be disappointed. In none of the commercials does she sing a note. The voices of actors <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Plummer </PERSON> and <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON>, a reappearance by <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON> and the absence of actor <PERSON> Ricardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Montalban </PERSON> extolling `` rich Corinthian leather'' also are highlights of <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>'s 1990 advertising campaign, unveiled Wednesday. <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> formally introduces its 1990 cars and trucks Sept. 18-19, and as part of the corporate advertising, <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON> will appear again in a commercial, airing Sept. 5. It will be <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON>'s 58th for <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Steenburgen </PERSON> and actor <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> McDowell </PERSON> have filed for divorce, the actress' publicist said. Miss <PERSON> Steenburgen </PERSON> and <PERSON> McDowell </PERSON> met while making the 1979 movie `` Time After Time.'' They have been married nine years, said <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, a publicist for Miss <PERSON> Steenburgen </PERSON>. The couple had been separated for 18 months, <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> said Wednesday. They have filed for joint custody of their children, <PERSON> Lilly </PERSON>, 8, and <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON>, 6. Miss <PERSON> Steenburgen </PERSON> and <PERSON> McDowell </PERSON> said they will continue to be `` close friends.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BATH, Maine (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Multimillionaire publisher <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Forbes </PERSON> is stumped. He's unsure how to celebrate his 71st birthday next year. `` We're busy recovering from the last one,'' <PERSON> Forbes </PERSON> said Wednesday of the extravagant bash earlier this month in <LOCATION> Tangier </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION>, with 700 of his rich and famous friends. After getting off his 151-foot yacht, Highlander, and anchoring it in the <LOCATION> Kennebec </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Forbes </PERSON> came to shore wearing a pink shirt and cranberry-colored pants for a tour of the <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> Maritime Museum. <PERSON> Forbes </PERSON> takes a voyage to <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> every summer. `` We always stop in <LOCATION> Camden </LOCATION> for lunch and we always wander the <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> coast before Labor Day,'' <PERSON> Forbes </PERSON> said. `` It's a state of mind, the state of <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>. Everybody likes to come here.'' Asked about his relationship with actress <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, <PERSON> Forbes </PERSON> said the two are `` good friends, and we're not going to jeopardize it by getting married.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fans tried to find ways to get close and scalpers offered tickets to an officially sold-out concert as the Rolling Stones prepared for tonight's opening of their Steel Wheels tour. A lawyer for the promoters, meanwhile, said she had a court order allowing the seizure of Rolling Stones posters, T-shirts and other items from vendors who had not paid royalties to the rock group. The Stones, who have not toured the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> since 1981, will open a 29-city North American tour with concerts at Veterans Stadium. On Tuesday, their practice session at <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> F. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stadium </ORGANIZATION> was already drawing fans, scheming to sneak in for a glimpse. Most of the 50 fans outside the stadium listened to the group rehearsing inside, applauding as the Stones finished rehearsing each number.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LAWRENCE, Kan. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Television star <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Landon </PERSON> is scouting locations around <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> and <PERSON> Baldwin </PERSON> for a made-for-TV movie he has written. <PERSON> Landon </PERSON>, who appeared on the TV series `` Bonanza,'' `` Little House on the Prairie'' and `` Highway to Heaven,'' said Tuesday there's been no final decision where the <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> movie will be filmed, but he liked the area `` Everything has worked out very well here,'' he said. `` I hope to come back.'' <PERSON> Landon </PERSON> is scheduled to begin shooting the movie `` Where Pigeons Go to Die'' in October. The script, an adaptation that <PERSON> Landon </PERSON> wrote from a book by <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, is about a grandfather, his grandson and a pigeon. `` It's about people caring for each other and about loving,'' he said. `` It's about an incident that happened to someone when they were very small and that they'll never forget.'' Casting has not been completed, but one thing is for sure, <PERSON> Landon </PERSON> said: `` I'll be in it because the writer-director loves me.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890831-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-89 0213EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AZTPrice     08-31 0529</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AZT Price,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>AIDS Activists Call for Price Reduction for Anti-Viral Drug AZT</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-AIDS Spending, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fourteen activist AIDS organizations are urging the company that makes AZT to cut the $ 8,000-a-year cost of the only drug approved for use by AIDS patients. In a letter Wednesday to <ORGANIZATION> Burroughs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wellcome </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, the groups said lowering the cost not only would benefit those patients and their insurers already paying for it, but would make it easier to persuade <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to come up with the millions of dollars needed to supply AZT to those who can not afford it. `` Without a price reduction, it is politically more difficult, if not impossible, to secure reauthorization and new funding to finance the program needed to provide treatment for all those who need it,'' the letter said. AZT is marketed by <ORGANIZATION> Burroughs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wellcome </ORGANIZATION> under the brand name Retrovir. Company spokeswoman <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bartlett </PERSON> said the letter reflects `` a failure to recognize how pharmaceutical companies operate.'' `` It is marketed drugs that help pay for all of your research,'' she said, adding that development, marketing and research costs `` are very, very high.'' She said <ORGANIZATION> Burroughs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wellcome </ORGANIZATION> gave 30 million capsules, wholesale priced at $ 1.50 each, to the federal government for the AZT trials and continues to conduct research on the drug. The activist groups said they were heartened by recent trials that suggest hundreds of thousands of people infected with the AIDS virus but not yet showing symptoms can benefit from taking AZT. `` Now that the evidence suggests a vastly expanded need for the drug,'' the letter said, the problems of finding a way to pay for it are `` greatly amplified.'' It maintained that `` a large portion'' of the total cost in researching, developing and producing AZT was paid by taxpayers. `` In effect, we have been asked to pay for this drug three times: first in its initial development, next in financing many of the studies needed to permit its marketing, and finally to buy it from you,'' the letter said. The 14 groups endorsing the letter identified themselves as organizations `` devoted to the welfare of people with HIV.'' Among the groups were the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, AIDS Project; the Gay Men's Health Crisis; the <ORGANIZATION> AIDS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>; the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gay </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advocates </ORGANIZATION>; the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gay </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Lesbian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Task </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>; and the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Physicians </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION>. Copies of the letter were distributed to <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>, the secretary of <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, and to other <ORGANIZATION> HHS </ORGANIZATION> officials, along with some members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, and to the news media. <ORGANIZATION> Burroughs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wellcome </ORGANIZATION> officials have said the company has had to invest heavily to test and manufacture the drug, but have declined to make their precise costs public. AZT was first synthesized under a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cancer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> grant in 1964. In 1984, some <ORGANIZATION> Burroughs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wellcome </ORGANIZATION> lab tests showed it to be effective against some animal retroviruses and the company offered it for testing by federal laboratories. <ORGANIZATION> NCI </ORGANIZATION> scientists proved in 1985 that it was active against the AIDS virus. <ORGANIZATION> Burroughs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wellcome </ORGANIZATION> then was granted a license to manufacture and test the drug. The clinical trials were directed by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890831-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-89 0229EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Smells     08-31 0472</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Smells,470</SECOND>
<HEAD>Removal of Bad Odors Seen as Prime Need in Third World</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CARL HARTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> wants to improve Third World cities _ by making them smell better. Not only are odors from bad sanitation and bad fuel for cooking and heating offensive to the nose, they're unhealthy, says <ORGANIZATION> Campbell </ORGANIZATION>, a senior urban planner for the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>. People in <LOCATION> Karachi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s biggest city, burn a lot of dung and wood. In <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, it's wood and charcoal. That pollutes indoor air in a way that may be related to a range of lung diseases, tuberculosis and cancer, <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> says. The pollution comes from poor ventilation, regardless of the kind of fuel. <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>'s study, `` Environmental Dilemmas and the Urban Poor,'' was made public Wednesday as part of a more general report called `` Environment and the Poor: Development Strategies for a Common Agenda.'' Women and children, who spend more time at home, are probably affected more than men, he said. `` The adverse effects of household airborne and water-carried wastes on child mortality and female life expectancy are of no less global proportions than, say, the destruction of tropical forests, and in immediate human terms may be the most urgent of all worldwide environmental problems,'' <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> wrote. The bank is the biggest source of aid loans to Third World countries, lending more than $ 19 billion a year. `` Dealing with bad smells _ human waste and indoor air pollution _ will get you a bigger immediate return in human well-being than many other things we do,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sewell </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Overseas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, which published the report. The council is a private research group, financed by foundations. <ORGANIZATION> Campbell </ORGANIZATION> reported that new kinds of cooking stoves designed for Third World use have run into trouble because they are n't what people are accustomed to. But he added that they are a good idea because a 10 percent improvement of cooking efficiency could save millions of tons of wood a year and help solve the health problem. `` Contain the heat, vent the exhausts,'' he advised. Ventilated pit latrines cut down costs by two-thirds and standard specifications can be reduced to make them cheaper and to use more local labor, he said. He called for more research not only on stoves, but also on toilets that flush when water is poured into them and small, maneuverable pumps for latrine systems. Such things may seem second class, but the people who use them and the donors who provide them will learn to appreciate them, he said. `` Short-term gains in health may come to be valued by the poor as much as or more than the loss of status they perceive for having a second-class _ that is, less than standard _ system for cooking and waste disposal,'' he wrote.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890831-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-89 0212EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CreditCards-List     08-31 0264</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Credit Cards-List,260</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Credit Cards, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a list of 10 banks and savings institutions offering credit cards with interest rates below 16 percent in August, according to <ORGANIZATION> RAM </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION>'s Bankcard List. RAM Research, based in <LOCATION> Frederick </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, surveys 350 banks, representing 90 percent of the bank card market, according to editor and publisher <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> McKinley </PERSON>. Nationally in August, rates averaged 18.28 percent and annual fees $ 16.97. 1. <ORGANIZATION> Arkansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION>, Little Rock, Ark. 11.88 percent annual interest, variable. $ 35 annual fee. No grace period. Interest charged from date of purchase. 2. <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Bridgeport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION> 13.5 percent, but a higher rate charged for cash advances. $ 25 annual fee. Twenty-five-day grace period. 3. <ORGANIZATION> NCNB </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>. 13.9 percent, variable. No annual fee. Twenty-five-day grace period. 4. Republic Savings, <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION>. 13.92 percent. $ 10 annual fee. No grace period. Interest charged from date of posting. 5. Horizon Savings, <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. 14 percent. No annual fee. Twenty-five-day grace period. 6. First <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wilmington </LOCATION>, Del. 14.88 percent. $ 24 annual fee. Twenty-eight-day grace period. 7. <ORGANIZATION> Connecticut </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> and Trust, <LOCATION> Fairfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION> 15 percent, but a higher rate for cash advances. $ 25 annual fee. Twenty-five-day grace period. 8. <ORGANIZATION> USAA </ORGANIZATION> Federal, <LOCATION> Tulsa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION> 15.32 percent, variable. No annual fee. Twenty-five-day grace period. 9. Mercantile, <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>. 15.9 percent. $ 20 annual fee. Twenty-five-day grace period. 10. Champion Federal, <LOCATION> Bloomington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION> 15.9 percent. $ 20 annual fee. Thirty-day grace period. Consumers should check with the credit card issuers to see whether any of the rates or fees shown here have changed and to obtain information about other terms.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890831-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-89 0251EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MethanolDispute     08-31 0339</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Methanol Dispute,350</SECOND>
<HEAD>Oil Companies Step up Campaign Against President's Methanol Plan</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The oil industry is intensifying its attack on a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration plan requiring the use of methanol in some cars by 1995 to control the growing smog problem in the nation's most polluted cities The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, which represents the major oil companies, has hired consultant <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Austin </PERSON> to speak against replacing gasoline-burning engines with those capable of running on methanol, or wood alcohol. <PERSON> Austin </PERSON>, a mechanical engineer and former <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> official, told reporters Wednesday that his research showed methanol is no less environmentally harmful than gasoline. He also contends it is more costly and less safe. `` Methanol is not an inherently clean fuel,'' he said. `` It is just as dirty as gasoline.'' The oil industry has voiced strong doubts about methanol since <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> proposed in June that 500,000 cars capable of burning methanol be sold by 1995 in cities with the most serious air pollution problems, and that 1 million be sold each year starting in 1997. The administration contends that methanol-burning cars will help reduce the formation of smog because they emit fewer hydrocarbons. It also says increased use of methanol will reduce the nation's growing reliance on foreign oil used to make gasoline The oil industry, which produces about 100 billion gallons of gasoline a year, has a powerful interest in keeping it the predominant transportation fuel. <PERSON> Austin </PERSON> acknowledged that tests show cars running on methanol emit fewer poisonous hydrocarbons than those burning gasoline. But he said the administration has overlooked or discounted research that indicates methanol-burning engines emit far more formaldehyde, a chemical that helps form smog. The major oil companies say they have been researching possible uses of methanol as a transportation fuel for years and will continue to do so. But, through their trade association, they have strongly criticized the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> proposal as too ambitious. They say more emphasis should be put on researching cleaner formulations of gasoline.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890831-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-89 0300EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     08-31 0888</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,890</SECOND>
<HEAD>Infectious Swine Disease Found in U.S.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An infectious swine disease previously found only in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> has been confirmed by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and is being viewed as a possible contributor to recent losses suffered by Corn Belt hog producers. The disease is a type of leptospirosis, caused by corkscrew-shaped bacteria called leptospires. About 180 types of leptospires cause disease in livestock, said <PERSON> Carole </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bolin </PERSON>, veterinary medical officer with <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Ames </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bolin </PERSON> said in a report released here Wednesday that the disease, caused by an organism called bratislava, was found in an <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> herd. The name resulted after the bacterium was isolated in 1953 from a hedgehog in <LOCATION> Bratislava </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>. Leptospirosis is transmitted primarily by infected urine, but the leptospires also can pass through the pregnant female's placenta to the fetus. Another probable cause of infection is thought to be venereal transmission from infected boars. Humans in contact with infected animals or urine can develop leptospirosis, the report said. Outbreaks of a mysterious syndrome causing stillbirths, abortions and pre-weaning death in pigs that began a year ago throughout the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> have prompted <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> scientists to look into several possible causes, including bacterial and viral infection, and moldy corn, <PERSON> Bolin </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Bratislava </LOCATION> infection `` is being studied as one possible contributing factor to this syndrome,'' she said. The study was undertaken five months ago at the agency's animal disease center in Ames under a `` technology transfer'' agreement with <ORGANIZATION> Norden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratories </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Neb </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bolin </PERSON> said the next step is to inoculate pregnant sows with bratislava to `` establish absolute proof'' that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> version causes reproductive disease. Also, laboratory tests must be conducted to determine the effectiveness of vaccines in pregnant sows. <PERSON> Norden </PERSON> is marketing two vaccines under conditional <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> licenses and is applying for permanent licensing, she said. Company scientist <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Frantz </PERSON> said vaccination with the conditionally licensed vaccine protects the animal against `` clinical signs caused by bratislava'' through one pregnancy. He recommended vaccination prior to each breeding. Leptospirosis in both animals and humans can be mild or severe, and is often misdiagnosed, the agency said. The disease in humans has been confused with influenza, hepatitis, yellow fever, pneumonia, polio, meningitis and encephalitis.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A partial list of changes in <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> regulations affecting the care and handling of animals for laboratory experiments and other purposes will go into effect Oct. 30. Among the changes will be a requirement that research facilities create special committees to assure humane care and treatment of animals. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Glosser </PERSON>, administrator of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Animal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inspection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, said Wednesday that the revisions `` will partially implement'' amendments to the federal Animal Welfare Act passed by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> almost four years ago. The amendments provide new and stricter requirements to protect laboratory animals from undue pain and stress, tighten enforcement of rules already on the books, and revise the list of definitions needed to carry out the law. Current regulations define standards for animal use, including minimum requirements for handling, housing, feeding, watering, sanitation, ventilation, shelter and veterinary care. <PERSON> Glosser </PERSON> said the revisions will make the rules for dogs, cats and non-human primates, including monkeys, more complete and easier to understand. Besides requiring research facilities to create special animal care committees, the new regulations include provisions for veterinary care, and holding facilities and handling. The Animal Welfare Act covers most businesses that buy or sell warm-blooded animals, exhibit them and transport them commercially. Rats, mice, birds, horses and farm animals are not covered by the regulations. An agency spokeswoman, <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> El-Hinnawy </PERSON>, said there are three parts to the package of regulatory changes. The final decisions announced Wednesday affect only the first and second parts. Part One includes a definition of terms used in carrying out the 1985 amendments, she said. Part Two relates to the identification methods, records, licensing requirements and other details. Part Three, which is still under study by the agency, will include details of the actual standards for federal regulation of animal care _ the space each must have, access to food and water, and other details that affect their routines. <PERSON> El-Hinnawy </PERSON> said she did n't know when <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> might decide on final rules for Part Three. Federal animal welfare legislation was passed by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1966 and covered animal dealers who raised dogs and cats for research and laboratories conducting research on these animals. The coverage was broadened in 1970 to include most other warm-blooded animals used in research, exhibited or sold in the wholesale pet trade. An amendment in 1976 extended to law to include the transportation of live animals.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Agriculture Secretary <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> plans to be in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> for meetings and trade talks Sept. 6-9. <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>'s office said the discussions with European leaders will center on agriculture negotiations under the <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION> Round of the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade. The trip will include meetings Sept. 6 in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> on Sept. 7 with officials of the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION>. On Sept. 8 he will speak in <LOCATION> Burgenstock </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>, to the Swiss Commodities, Futures and <ORGANIZATION> Options </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>'s talk is expected to focus on the need for reform in world trade. <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> will be in <LOCATION> Stuttgart </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, on Sept. 9.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890831-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-89 0304EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Abortion-Election     08-31 0401</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Abortion-Election,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>Florida House Race Shows Pro-Life Movement Thriving, Group Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
