<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891019-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-19-89 2350EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SmithDinner     10-19 0417</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Smith Dinner,0431</SECOND>
<HEAD>First Lady Addresses Annual Fund-Raiser</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARBARA ROSEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 First lady <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Thursday night contradicted a published report that she weighs 135 pounds. `` <PERSON> George </PERSON> said the press never gets anything right,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` Just for starters, I was born weighing 135 pounds.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> addressed the 44th annual <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> Memorial Dinner, a fund-raiser that has been called the city's most famous non-political political event. Approximately 1,350 guests gathered in the <LOCATION> Waldorf-Astoria </LOCATION> hotel's <LOCATION> Grand </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ballroom </LOCATION>, where they dined on filet mignon and chocolate hazelnut torte at $ 500 a plate. After straightening out the weight question, Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> paused, then handed outgoing Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>, who was also on the dais, one of his own lines. `` How'm I doing, <PERSON> Ed </PERSON>?'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, wearing a black and purple gown with her characteristic pearl choker, said she welcomed the chance `` to prove I'm more than just a pretty face.'' The glittering and often controversial <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> dinner always draws an array of politicians and other notables, often held shortly before a major election, though political hatchets are supposed to be buried for the night. The first lady said she loved <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolfe </PERSON>'s satirical look at <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> politics and race relations, `` The Bonfire of the Vanities.'' `` But I never dreamed I'd get to address some of the characters in person,'' she said to cheers. This year's event drew the top contenders for <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION>, Democrat <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> and Republican <PERSON> Rudolph </PERSON> <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON>, who sat two seats apart on the dais and who, according to <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON>, shook hands. At last year's dinner, then-Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his presidential opponent, Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, traded witticisms just weeks before <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> won the race for the White House. Also in attendance Thursday were <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> IV, the master of ceremonies; Gov. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Kean </PERSON>; state Attorney General <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON>; Fire Commissioner <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruno </PERSON>; outgoing Police Commissioner <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> and Cardinal <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>. The Roman Catholic Archdiocese of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> has sponsored the annual event since its inception in 1945, a year after <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> died. The proceeds always go to health care causes. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, governor of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> from 1923-1928, in 1928 became the first Catholic to be nominated for president. Past speakers have included <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, the first Catholic elected president. Other speakers have been <PERSON> Winston </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON>, <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hope </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON> <PERSON> Waldheim </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891019-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-19-89 2354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-LaScalaScare     10-19 0287</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-La Scala Scare,0292</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gate Crashers Threaten Dilapidated Hall With Collapse</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A throng of gate crashers trampled spectators and nearly brought the roof of the dilapidated <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> Conservatory crashing down in their desperation to hear the Italian opera company <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scala </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION> reported. The government newspaper gave no account of casualties, however. <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> police refused comment Thursday evening, and managers of the concert hall did not answer the telephone. In an article headlined, `` Requiem _ One Moment From Tragedy,'' <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION> said in its Thursday editions that thousands of fans, yearning to hear the <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scala </ORGANIZATION> orchestra and chorus perform <PERSON> Verdi </PERSON>'s Requiem, `` broke through a small cordon of police and rushed past the old women ushers into the hall, trampling the bodies of fallen spectators. `` A brawl erupted between the ticket-holders and those without tickets claiming their seats _ pirate connoisseurs of bel canto,'' it said. The newspaper blamed the crowd of unruly spectators for the near-tragedy, but also noted that the downtown <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> conservatory had been closed for 1 -LCB- years as dangerously unstable. `` Under pressure of the public, taking into account the fact that the capital happened to have no concert hall worthy of celebrities, it was reopened on condition of careful use,'' the newspaper said. On Wednesday night, `` the most terrible minutes came when the hall exploded into chanting and the roof beams began to shake,'' <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION> said. Every time maestro <PERSON> Riccardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Muti </PERSON> and the ensemble came out for an encore, `` the new storm of applause was one more turn of the deadly roulette wheel,'' it said. The newspaper noted that <PERSON> Mstislav </PERSON> <PERSON> Rostropovich </PERSON> and <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Ashkenazy </PERSON>, world-famous former students of the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> Conservatory, are scheduled to play the hall in the future.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891019-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-19-89 2354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--TeacherBeating     10-19 0168</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Teacher Beating,0169</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Exonerates Teacher In Beating of Pupil</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A court dismissed charges against a teacher who whipped a 12-year-old boy so badly he had to be hospitalized for six weeks, saying she did it help him improve his grades, a newspaper reported today. The <ORGANIZATION> Korea </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said a court in the southern city of <LOCATION> Taegu </LOCATION> dismissed assault charges this week against <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Mi-kyong </PERSON>, 24, who had been arrested for injuring the pupil. The teacher beat <PERSON> Park </PERSON> <PERSON> Kyong-jin </PERSON> with a stick because he had not done well on a science test, the report said. The boy's back was dislocated by the beating and was in the hospital for six weeks, it said. The court ruled that corporal punishment was a necessary form of discipline in schools and Miss <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> could not be charged with a crime, the report said. The court also ruled the teacher was trying to help the boy improve his grades and her actions were reasonable, it said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891019-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-19-89 2354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APAppointment     10-19 0098</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Appointment,0099</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bradley-Steck Named Pittsburgh Correspondent</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Tara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley-Steck </PERSON>, a newswoman in the <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> bureau of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> since 1984, has been named correspondent in charge. The appointment was announced Thursday by <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> Chief of Bureau <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Zucker </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bradley-Steck </PERSON> succeeds <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mattiace </PERSON>, who recently was named <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s bureau chief in <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bradley-Steck </PERSON>, 34, joined the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, her She is a graduate of <ORGANIZATION> Bryn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mawr </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> and previously worked for <ORGANIZATION> VISTA </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, where she edited an Indian reservation newspaper, and for the <ORGANIZATION> Beaver </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Beaver </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891019-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-19-89 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AstaireSuit     10-19 0185</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Astaire Suit,0190</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fred Astaire's Widow Sues Columbia Over Film Distribution</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The widow of actor <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Astaire </PERSON> has filed suit against <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pictures </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION> over distribution of royalties from two of his films. In a suit filed Wednesday in <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Robyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Astaire </PERSON> claims <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> owes her at least $ 25,000 in receipts from the films `` You'll Never Get Rich'' and `` You Were Never Lovelier,'' in which the famous dancer starred. She also seeks <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>'s accounting records regarding the films' distribution. Mrs. <PERSON> Astaire </PERSON> alleges that since at least 1987, <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> has breached a contract under which <PERSON> Astaire </PERSON> was to receive 5 percent of all net receipts in excess of $ 100,000 up to $ 5,000 and 10 percent of all net receipts in excess of $ 200,000. Mrs. <PERSON> Astaire </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, said Thursday his client does not know exactly how much money she is owed because <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> has refused to provide accounting records to her. He said the amount <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> owes Mrs. <PERSON> Astaire </PERSON> may be significantly higher than $ 25,000. <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> officials could not be reached for comment after business hours late Thursday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891019-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-19-89 0004EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Boeing 1stLd-Writethru a0826 10-19 0449</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Boeing, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0826,0457</SECOND>
<HEAD>Renewed Negotiations Fizzle Between Boeing and Machinists</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: New throughout to UPDATE with talks called off. Edits to conform,
tighten and delete outdated material. No pick up. A longer version moving
on financial wire</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM KLASS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The first negotiations between the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and union officials since nearly 60,000 workers went on strike fizzled Wednesday after only four hours, and no new talks were scheduled, both sides said. <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> negotiators told the union through a federal mediator that they would not expand the economic package rejected by union members Oct. 3 but were willing `` to make adjustments within the framework of the original wage offer,'' <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> said in a news release. `` Sounds like doubletalk,'' said union spokesman <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Daniels </PERSON> after the talks ended. `` Our people want more money and less overtime.'' The talks were the first since Oct. 2, two days before the strike by members of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aerospace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> began. <PERSON> Daniels </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lodge </ORGANIZATION> 751 members were n't surprised by the lack of movement Wednesday `` We figured after a couple of weeks of strike that the first meeting would have to serve as a door opener to successive meetings,'' <PERSON> Daniels </PERSON> said. `` Today the company was kind of doing its tough guy act.'' The Machinists represent about 57,800 <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> workers nationwide, including 43,300 covered by <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lodge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> 751 </ORGANIZATION> in the Puget Sound area, 12,000 in <LOCATION> Wichita </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>, 1,700 in <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, and a few hundred others at scattered sites in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> and other states. Asked if union members were feeling financial pressure, <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lodge </ORGANIZATION> 71, replied, `` I would think the company's feeling the pressure pretty good since nobody's in there -LRB- the airplane factories -RRB-.'' For <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION>, there have been growing reports of concern about delayed aircraft deliveries to <ORGANIZATION> Malaysia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION>, the world's largest commercial airplane builder, has delivered seven planes during the strike. The company has refused to say how many planes it would have delivered normally. Eighty-five percent of the <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION> voted to strike rather than take a three-year contract with wage increases of 4 percent, 3 percent and 3 percent; bonuses of 8 percent of gross pay in the first year and 3 percent the second; cost-of-living boosts virtually matching inflation; a cut in mandatory overtime to 160 hours a quarter from 200 hours; and higher benefits. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said a new offer would have to provide more money, benefits and cuts in mandatory overtime. An agreement would set a pattern for other labor negotiations at <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION>, and traditionally sets the standard for the nation's aerospace industry
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891019-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-19-89 0032EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-PoliceLooter     10-19 0193</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Police Looter,0196</SECOND>
<HEAD>Policeman at Air Crash Scene Jailed for Looting</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LEICESTER, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A policeman who stole a life jacket from the wreckage of a <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 737 jet that crashed in central <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> in January was given a three-month prison sentence. Police Constable <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> had been sent to guard against looters after the British <LOCATION> Midland </LOCATION> aircraft crashed short of <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Midlands </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> on Jan. 8, killing 47 of the 126 people on board. Prosecutor <PERSON> Nigel </PERSON> <PERSON> Rumfitt </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Leicester </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> that <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> took a life jacket from the wreckage and told colleagues, `` I've got my souvenir. After a three-day trial, the jury issued a 10-2 majority guilty verdict. In handing down the sentence, Judge <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said the public expected the police to uphold `` the highest standards of honesty and integrity.'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, a village policeman for nine years, denied stealing. He claimed he took the life jacket and a safety instruction card as a joke and intended to return them. `` We were trying to be lighthearted among ourselves,'' he testified. `` Some were cracking jokes, which is not easy at a time like that, but it needs to be done.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891019-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-19-89 0032EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Amnesty-EastTimor     10-19 0317</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Amnesty-East Timor,0327</SECOND>
<HEAD>Amnesty Concerned About East Timor Arrests</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> says it's concerned over the fate of about 40 East Timorese reportedly arrested after a pro-independence protest while Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> was visiting the former <LOCATION> Portuguese </LOCATION> colony last week. `` According to reports, some of those detained have been subjected to ill-treatment, including electrical shocks, by members of the -LRB- <LOCATION> Indonesian </LOCATION> -RRB- security forces,'' <PERSON> Amnesty </PERSON> said in a statement issued in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> on Wednesday. `` <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> believes that in view of the consistent and recurrent pattern of torture and ill-treatment of political detainees in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Timor </LOCATION>, those now in detention may be in serious danger of ill-treatment.'' The London-based human rights organization said the reports came from previously reliable church and journalism sources in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Timor </LOCATION>, an <LOCATION> Indonesian </LOCATION> territory, and <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>. On Oct. 12, as the <PERSON> pope </PERSON> was finishing his blessing to a crowd of 100,000 people in <LOCATION> Dili </LOCATION>, capital of <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Timor </LOCATION>, about 20 young men shouting `` Viva independence!'' and `` Viva il papa!,'' unfurled banners in front of the altar. One banner read `` FRETILIN Welcomes You'' in <LOCATION> Portuguese </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> FRETILIN </ORGANIZATION> is the independence movement that has fought <LOCATION> Indonesian </LOCATION> rule since annexation of <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Timor </LOCATION> in 1976. Plainclothesmen flogged the demonstrators and seized their banners. The crowd scattered and about 100 more young men joined the fray, hurling chairs at policemen. <LOCATION> Indonesian </LOCATION> authorities made no announcement about arrests. According to Amnesty, five East Timorese who feared arrest reportedly took refuge at the home of Roman Catholic Bishop <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Belo </PERSON>, apostolic administrator of <LOCATION> Dili </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Belo </PERSON> has criticized <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>'s human rights record in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Timor </LOCATION> and called for a referendum to decide its political future. The <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> was closed for the day and the chief spokesman, <PERSON> Joaquin </PERSON> <PERSON> Navarro </PERSON>, was not available for comment on the Amnesty statement. He expressed skepticism this week about a report in a <LOCATION> Portuguese </LOCATION> weekly that some of those arrested had been executed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891019-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-19-89 0015EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SFQuake-Highway 2ndLd-Writethru a0873 10-19 0809</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-SF Quake-Highway, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0873,0831</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hope Diminishes for More Survivors on Flattened Interstate 880</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 9 grafs to UPDATE with police saying report of survivor
was in error. Picks up 11th graf, `A helicopter...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-SF Quake, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE CARPENTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OAKLAND, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police said rescuers using dogs, jackhammers and muscle found no survivors Wednesday in the rubble of Interstate 880, the elevated road turned into a giant concrete pancake and gnarled girders by the earthquake. More than 250 rush-hour commuters were feared buried in the section of the Nimitz Freeway, which collapsed during Tuesday evening's devestating 6.9-magnitude quake. Seven bodies were recovered by midday, and police said at least 86 people still were reported missing. At about 6 p.m., Mayor <PERSON> Lionel </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> was telling reporters that a search had found no survivors when police Lt. <PERSON> Kristina </PERSON> <PERSON> Wraa </PERSON> interrupted to say one had been discovered. `` We have confirmed that there is one person alive, apparently in a car underneath the top level,'' <PERSON> Wraa </PERSON> said, adding that rescue workers had heard a voice and established physical contact with the victim. That report was later dismissed as erroneous by <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION> police Capt. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON>, who attributed it to a garbled communication between officers. `` There were noises coming from the area. ... We have located several individuals, none of whom are alive so there are no survivors at this point,'' <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON> said. Gov. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Deumejian </PERSON> claimed the collapse of I-880 was the result of substandard construction, although state transportation officials said the freeway, one of the oldest in the area, had been reinforced and was considered earthquake-safe. However, they said further upgrading had been planned. Rescue workers searched for victims in the twisted metal and concrete, and used a concrete saw to cut throug cement to each automobile. Search dogs covered all but two sections of the collapsed freeway and found no survivors, <PERSON> Wraa </PERSON> said. A helicopter brought in a remote-control backhoe late Wednesday afternoon. Officials planned to shore up the freeway with steel and wood piles to protect workers from a possible aftershock. The search was moving `` slowly and meticulously'' because the collapsed highway was like `` a house of cards'' that could crash down at any time, <PERSON> Kyle </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> said earlier. Shortly before dawn, a hook-and-ladder truck moved alongside the flattened section of I-880. It stopped periodically to allow firefighters to shine bright lights into gaps between the northbound upper deck and the southbound lower deck. Screams and the crash of metal brought bystanders to the scene on Tuesday. `` You could hear it crunching down _ but you could n't see anything. It was just a big white cloud,'' said witness <PERSON> Leroy </PERSON> <PERSON> FitzGerald </PERSON>. `` You could hear people screaming for help.'' When the 18-block stretch of highway caved in, workers from businesses in the heavily industrial area ran to help, many bringing tall ladders and forklifts. Rescuers were able to pull one man alive from a car that was crushed to a height of 18 inches, said passer-by <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> MacIntyre </PERSON>. Emergency workers pulled a girl from the wreckage of another automobile. The fate of her parents and brother was unknown. A three-member surgical team had to amputate the right leg of a 7-year-old boy who was trapped in a car for seven hours. At 12:15 a.m., he finally was carried down a 20-foot ladder and taken to an ambulance. There were many heroes. <PERSON> Darius </PERSON> <PERSON> Brewer </PERSON>, a 26-year-old cook, joined an impromptu rescue party. The group crawled as far as possible under the crushed road to help injured motorists. They used crowbars to pry open one car and tied ropes around an elderly man to lower him 20 feet to safety. `` Then we went on top of the second deck and just mostly got everybody down we could,'' he said. `` People were yelling and screaming.'' I-880 was built in 1957, and was reinforced in 1977 in the first phase of a three-phase anti-earthquake program, <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> officials said. In the work, the road deck was tied to its supporting columns. The columns themselves collapsed, and the deck did not slip off the columns, transportation department chief engineer <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION>. Further work to strengthen the road against earthquakes had been deferred pending an engineering study, <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON> said. Asked whether the freeway had been considered safe from earthquakes, <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON> said, `` there's no such thing as an earthquake-proof structure,'' but added he was shocked by the collapse. `` We thought it would withstand the maximum credible earthquake we could have in this area, anything that would happen in this area,'' he told reporters. <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON> called for an investigation of the collapse. `` I had assumed that the freeways were ... constructed with adequate standards so that they would be able to withstand a quake of this severity,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891019-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-19-89 0041EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Superstitions     10-19 0226</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Superstitions,0235</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dictionary Of Superstitions Published</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Just in time for Halloween, the <ORGANIZATION> Oxford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> is publishing a `` Dictionary of Superstitions'' with 1,500 entries including stepping on cracks and knocking on wood. <PERSON> Moira </PERSON> <PERSON> Tatum </PERSON> said she and co-author <PERSON> Iona </PERSON> <PERSON> Opie </PERSON> found in seven years of research that many of today's superstitions are universal and harken back thousands of years beyond written history. `` Although we know it goes back 4,000 years to nature worship, the earliest written reference to knocking on wood is a 19th-century children's game,'' Ms. <PERSON> Tatum </PERSON> said. `` But the actual knocking on wood, or ` touch wood' as the British say, to save oneself after saying a boastful thing, originated in <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> where they always knocked the underside of a table and said, ` May I not be bewitched.''' Ms. <PERSON> Tatum </PERSON> said putting together 494 pages of superstitions cured any fears she had of bad omens: `` After all that work, I am totally converted from those pagan ways.'' The superstition to avoid stepping on cracks dates back to the ancient Greek mythological character Persephone who was taken to the underworld by Hades, she said. Ms. <PERSON> Tatum </PERSON> said superstitions are especially common in tightly knit communities. `` The small communities of seamen or miners in <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> are full of superstitions,'' she said. `` That's where you find the more obscure or arcane superstitions.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891019-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-19-89 0048EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Haiti-Drugs     10-19 0221</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Haiti-Drugs,0228</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Seize 2,000 Pounds Of Cocaine</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> PORT-AU-PRINCE </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ Tipped off by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> drug agents, authorities raided a suburban home and seized more than 2,000 pounds of cocaine in <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>'s biggest drug haul of the year, a news report said. Police carried out the raid in the northern suburb of <LOCATION> Delmas </LOCATION> on Tuesday and discovered the drugs Wednesday. A Colombian and a Venezuelan who rented the house were absent and not detained, <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Metropole </ORGANIZATION> said. Authorities seized 2,024 pounds of cocaine, the privately-owned radio said. It gave no value for the drug. The station, quoting police, said Haitian authorities were tipped off by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> has been identified by the <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> as a major conduit for U.S.-bound Colombian cocaine. There has been testimony in a Cuban drug-smuggling case linking ousted <LOCATION> Haitian </LOCATION> military leader Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Henri </PERSON> <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> to drug-running. On Oct. 9, <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> and Interior Minister Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Acedius </PERSON> <PERSON> Saint-Louis </PERSON> said drug seizures have increased by 200 percent this year compared with 1988. He said the <ORGANIZATION> Haitian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Narcotics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> had handed over 4,000 pounds of cocaine to the <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> for destruction. <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> was ousted in September 1988 in a coup led by junior officers who said they were disgusted by government corruption and state-sponsored killings and put Lt. Gen. Prosper Avril in power.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891019-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-19-89 0049EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SFQuake-USList     10-19 0358</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SF Quake-US List,0388</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Deadliest U.S. Quakes</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-SF Quake Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Tuesday's earthquake was the second deadliest in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> history. Here is a list of major quakes as recorded by the U. S. Geological Survey:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>SAN FRANCISCO, APRIL 18-19, 1906</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Rated at 8.3 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale. Ruptured gas lines, overturned stoves, started fires that destroyed much of the city, killing hundreds. Traditional estimates put the death toll at 500 to 700, but the city archivist recently established that at least 2,500, and possibly 5,000 people were killed.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>SAN FRANCISCO BAY AREA, OCT. 17, 1989</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> reading 6.9. Collapsed a mile of double-deck highway, inflicted widespread damage to buildings. Struck at evening rush hour. At least 272 people dead and 650 injured, according to early official reports.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>PRINCE WILLIAM SOUND, ALASKA, MARCH 27, 1964</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> reading 8.4. The infamous Good Friday Earthquake. There were 131 deaths and extensive damage in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MONA PASSAGE, PUERTO RICO, OCT. 11, 1918</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> reading 7.5. Shook the Mona Passage between <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> and the island of <LOCATION> Hispaniola </LOCATION>. Some 116 people died, many in the giant wave generated by the quake.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>LONG BEACH, CALIF., MARCH 10, 1933</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> reading 6.2. Hit a heavily populated area. Many buildings collapsed, including schools, and 115 people died. Brought about wide revision of building codes, including standards requiring new buildings to withstand lateral forces from earthquakes.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>SAN FERNANDO VALLEY, CALIF., FEB. 9, 1971</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> reading of 6.4. Killed 65 people, 45 of them in the collapse of a Veterans Administration hospital at <LOCATION> Sylmar </LOCATION>. Total damage unofficially estimated at $ 600 million, with at least $ 37 million to highways, streets and bridges. Outside of areas nearest the epicenter, principal damage involved buildings erected 40 or more years earlier.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CHARLESTON, S.C., AUG. 31, 1886</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> reading of 6.6. Killed 60 people. Was felt for a radius of 1,000 miles, as far away as <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>HEBGEN LAKE, MONT., AUG. 17, 1959</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> reading of 7.3. Was felt from <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>. Extensive damage was reported and 28 people died.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891019-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-19-89 0052EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-HUDIndictments     10-19 0287</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-HUD Indictments,0295</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Men Indicted on Charges of Defrauding HUD</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUG RICHARDSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>INDIANAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two men were indicted Wednesday on charges they defrauded federal housing programs under investigation in a nationwide probe of waste and mismanagement at the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>. `` I would say these two cases are symptomatic of the types of cases you will see across the country in fraud on the government in <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> programs,'' said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Daniels </PERSON>. Named in separate indictments were <LOCATION> Zionsville </LOCATION> real estate agent <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cirillo </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> businessman <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> official. <PERSON> Daniels </PERSON> said <PERSON> Cirillo </PERSON>, 37, made false statements to help applicants for low-income housing assistance obtain HUD-insured mortgages for properties for which <PERSON> Cirillo </PERSON> was the broker. Once the loans were approved, <PERSON> Cirillo </PERSON>'s company received profits from the sale of the properties and brokerage fees, the indictment said. In each of seven cases, the loans went into default, costing the government about $ 200,000, <PERSON> Daniels </PERSON> said. If convicted, <PERSON> Cirillo </PERSON> could face up to 19 years in prison and a fine of $ 2 million. <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>, 36, is charged with embezzling $ 54,425 from February until April when his company, <ORGANIZATION> Closing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, acted as a closing agent at the sale of HUD-repossessed properties. If convicted, <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> could face up to 10 years in prison and a $ 250,000 fine. A reporter's telephone calls to <PERSON> Cirillo </PERSON>'s home were not answered Wednesday and his business is no longer listed. The telephone at <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>'s office was disconnected and his home number is unlisted. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and congressional committees began investigating the federal housing agency after reports of widespread fraud and mismanagement that is expected to cost the government $ 6 billion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891019-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-19-89 0028EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SpaceShuttle 5thLd-Writethru a0852 10-19 1021</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Space Shuttle, 5th Ld-Writethru, a0852,1047</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shuttle Atlantis Launches Galileo Probe into Space</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 22nd graf,`Scientists hope...,' to CORRECT that Jupiter's
diameter, sted radius, is 11 times size of earth.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Space shuttle Atlantis soared into orbit Wednesday and its astronauts started the <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION> probe on a six-year, roundabout journey to Jupiter for the closest look yet at the colossus of the solar system. `` Galileo is on its way to another world; it's in the hands of the best flight controllers in this world,'' said Atlantis commander <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>. Earlier, concerns about <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION>'s nuclear power supply were left behind as Atlantis lifted off flawlessly on its mission to carry the $ 1.5 billion space probe into orbit on the first leg of its trip. After Atlantis had made five trips around the world, <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION> was ejected from the cargo bay by springs at 7:15 p.m. EDT, precisely on schedule, over the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> east of <LOCATION> Brownsville </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Tex </PERSON>. The shuttle quickly moved away to put distance between itself and the space probe's rocket. The `` burn'' was an hour later over <LOCATION> Borneo </LOCATION> _ first for 2 -LCB- minutes, then for a minute, 45 seconds _ giving the 6,700-pound <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION> the initial push toward <PERSON> Venus </PERSON>, its first planetary port-of-call. `` On time and on schedule,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Mission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION>. `` It achieved earth-escape velocity and is now heading outbound toward the sun,'' said <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Welch </PERSON>, spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Johnson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>. A spacecraft can escape the Earth's gravity when traveling faster than 25,000 mph. The five astronauts spent their first hours in space giving a final electronic checkout to <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION>, a probe so sophisticated that one <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> official dubbed it `` the Rolls-Royce of spacecraft.'' `` Everything looks real good,'' said astronaut <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> <PERSON> Lucid </PERSON>, a one-flight veteran from <LOCATION> Bethany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION>, who had charge of the probe deployment. The crew members reported a few problems with their own ship as it orbited 184 miles above the <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>. One was with a cooling system that might cause them to have to return slightly earlier than planned in what a flight director called `` a worst-case scenario.'' `` You looked marvelous going up,'' <ORGANIZATION> Mission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> told <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> as the winged spacecraft reached orbit after two launch postponements. `` I feel a lot better,'' said <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION>, named after the 17th century discoverer of <ORGANIZATION> Jupiter </ORGANIZATION>'s moons, will use the laws of physics to get to <ORGANIZATION> Jupiter </ORGANIZATION>, the largest planet in the solar system, in 1995 Flying by <PERSON> Venus </PERSON> will cause it to gain momentum and so will two subsequent close encounters with Earth. Although concern over the <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION>'s 49.4-pound plutonium power supply was argued in court, it drew no protesters to the Kennedy Space Center on launch day. Environmentalists had argued that a Challenger-like accident could scatter deadly plutonium-238 over <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. Nothing like that happened Wednesday, and even the weather cooperated. Clouds and rain threatened to halt the launch until the last minutes of the countdown, but the clouds suddenly dissipated and the shuttle darted into a bright blue sky, trailing a 700-foot geyser of fire. The 132-ton Atlantis has a crew of five for the mission that ends Monday with a landing at <ORGANIZATION> Edwards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> at 2:38 p.m. EDT. The $ 1.5 billion mission already was seven years behind schedule when <PERSON> Atlantis </PERSON> was grounded by rain at the last minute Tuesday and by a faulty engine computer last week. `` It feels great,'' said <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> chief scientist <PERSON> Lennard </PERSON> <PERSON> Fisk </PERSON> after liftoff. `` It's been a long time.'' Apart from <PERSON> Lucid </PERSON>, <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>' crew consists of pilot <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> McCulley </PERSON> and mission specialists <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> and <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> Chang-Diaz </PERSON>. The liftoff was the start of a voyage that will take the probe on a looping path past <PERSON> Venus </PERSON> in February, back to within 620 miles of <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> in December 1990 and past <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> again at a 200-mile altitude two years later. The craft will arrive at <ORGANIZATION> Jupiter </ORGANIZATION> in Deceber 1995 for a two-year orbit. As part of the mission, a robot will separate from the <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION> spacecraft and plunge through Jupiter's gaseous atmosphere. Scientists hope to gain insight into the birth of the solar system by studying Jupiter, which holds original material from that event 14 billion years ago. The planet's diameter is about 11 times that of <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> and its mass 318 times greater. The mission originally was to have started in 1982, but money ran out. Then came the Challenger explosion in January 1986, delaying all shuttle flights for three years and prompting a change in the rocket to propel the Galileo. The mission originally was budgeted at $ 425 million. It will climb to $ 1.9 billion by the time <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION> finishes a 10-orbit trip around Jupiter in 1997. The sweeps past <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Venus </PERSON> will take advantage of the planets' gravity to accelerate the spacecraft to the proper speed to reach its distant target. Small onboard motors will fine-tune the flight path. The Galileo's electricity will be generated by decaying radioactive pellets of plutonium-238, which causes cancer and death in humans if inhaled in minuscule amounts. Environmental activists feared not only a launch accident but also mishaps during the two flybys. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> convinced a federal judge that the plutonium containers could withstand such pressures and that even if there were a release of radioactivity there would be no appreciable health effects. The government had hundreds of experts in the launch area _ just in case _ to monitor any radioactive release. More than 200 guards on foot, in helicopters and boats patrolled the launch center for protesters who said they might try to stop the launch by infiltrating the launch zone and sitting on the launch pad. `` We've succeeded in a small way calling attention to the escalating plan to put nuclear energy into space, including in Star Wars,'' said <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Gagnon </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>. `` The real fundamental point is that people have n't been doing much more than ooo-ing and ahhh-ing at the launches. They have n't been considering the moral and ethical issues of what is in these things, where they are going and what they are doing.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891019-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-19-89 0056EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     10-19 0490</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0509</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FORT PAYNE, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 100-year-old man sliced into the world's biggest cake to mark this town's 100th anniversary. The 128,238-pound, 12-layer cake _ 32 feet wide, 80 feet long and shaped like the state of <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> _ was unveiled Wednesday at the local fairgrounds before 6,000 people. The country band <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, who hail from <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Payne </LOCATION>, sang `` Happy Birthday.'' <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Henderson </PERSON> cut the cake with a sword and helped serve pieces. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Gengozian </PERSON>, editor and publisher of the local newspaper, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION>, came up with the idea of baking the birthday cake because the <ORGANIZATION> EarthGrains </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> bakery is the town's largest employer, with 750 workers. He set a goal of topping a 90,000-pound cake baked in <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, for the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Sesquicentennial in 1986. The Guinness Book of World Records lists that cake as the heaviest ever made. Guinness approved construction plans for the Fort Payne cake but still must verify it as a record. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>, who supervised the baking of cake by <ORGANIZATION> EarthGrains </ORGANIZATION>, said it contained 33,238 pounds of cake flour, 21,980 pounds of sugar, 11,799 pounds of corn syrup, 608 pounds of vegetable oil, 161 pounds of vanilla flavoring, 1,206 pounds of baking powder, 568 gallons of powdered milk, 19,250 pounds of water and 429 pounds of salt. The icing added another 33,354 pounds of ingredients, mostly sugar. A local metal company provided the steel supports to keep the cake from collapsing under its own weight. The <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> in the town of 12,000 said the cake required $ 25,000 in ingredients, paid for with donations.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>STOCKBRIDGE, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After 35 years, <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> McCormick </PERSON> still gets teased about being replaced by a dog in <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Rockwell </PERSON>'s famous picture `` Breaking Home Ties. `` I've been razzed about this quite a bit,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> McCormick </PERSON>, 84. `` I knew that he changed the faces of the people in his portraits, but this was a little drastic.'' According to a <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION> exhibit at the <ORGANIZATION> Old </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, the artist had initially envisioned both a grieving mother and a father in his 1954 painting of a young boy leaving home for the first time. But only the father and son made the final version. Mrs. <PERSON> McCormick </PERSON> said was delighted when her late husband, <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON>, a groundskeeper at the <ORGANIZATION> Stockbridge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Country </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, came home and told her that the artist wanted both of them to sit for the painting. `` I was so excited,'' Mrs. <PERSON> McCormick </PERSON> recalled. `` I made a dress for the picture. I told everybody we were going to be on the cover of the magazine.'' The couple sat for several photos in <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION>'s studio with the artist himself playing the anxious son. But when <PERSON> Rockwell </PERSON> finally got around to painting, he replaced Mrs. <PERSON> McCormick </PERSON> with a big collie. She said one of her friends attempted to console her with the advice, `` Do n't feel so badly, dear. It's a beautiful dog.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891019-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-19-89 0121EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Quake-DejaVu     10-19 0480</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quake-Deja Vu,0492</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman, 91, Remembers Worse Jolt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BOB EGELKO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area was slammed this week by a catastrophic earthquake, <PERSON> Elsie </PERSON> <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> was one of the few who remembered one even more terrible. `` This was a really heavy one ... -LRB- but -RRB- 1906 was the worst one,'' the 91-year-old woman said Wednesday from her daughter's house in suburban <LOCATION> Concord </LOCATION>, where she was recovering from injuries suffered in Tuesday's quake `` The city was in flames. We were all sitting on the sidewalk. ... There was no water, no medical care. We are all advised to go to higher ground. I was 7. You did n't know where to run.'' The memory of a stronger jolt did n't make Tuesday any less terrifying, Mrs. <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> said. `` I was sitting in a rocking chair. It started to swing and sway. Finally it gave a big jolt ... like a ship on the sea,'' she said. She fell from the chair, hurting her wrist, fingers, knee and leg. Her screams alerted the manager of the senior citizen's apartment complex, who helped carry her to her bed She spent the night without electricity in a dark, frightening city. `` It was horrifying,'' she said. `` Every two hours, an aftershock. A fear, a terrible feeling, to think everything will be destroyed.'' On Wednesday morning, her daughter, <PERSON> Jeanette </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, and Mrs. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>' husband took her into their home, 30 miles northeast of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, to recover. The daughter of immigrants from <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, she was 1 when her family moved from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. Her father, who spoke little English, did maintenance work in theaters here. Six years after her family arrived, the mightiest earthquake in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> history struck. The 1906 quake, estimated at 8.3 on the open-ended <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale, was followed by an even more destructive fire. The temblor was more than 10 times as powerful as Tuesday's quake, which registered 6.9 `` The buildings sunk into the ground,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> recalled. `` My mother and I were walking around, going to Twin Peaks with a blanket,'' she said of the scenic area. Her father went down into the fire area with another relative to clean and stack bricks, she said. Their Mission District house was the only one on the block to survive, but they had to seek higher ground to escape the smoke, she said. They moved to another neighborhood, and she has remained in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> all her life, working at times as a typist and taking part in dog shows. She also has attended some of the annual commemorations of the April 18, 1906, quake. Like most Californians, she lives near active fault lines in the earth and has gotten used to periodic earthquakes. But when Tuesday's quake began, she said, `` I said to myself, ` This has gone too far.'''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891019-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-19-89 0115EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PeddlingWeapons Bjt   10-19 0660</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Peddling Weapons, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>One-Stop Shopping, Military Style</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONNA CASSATA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Need to pick up some helicopters, light armored vehicles and tank ammunition for your country's defense? The easy answer is one-stop shopping _ military style _ with the <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. With the blessing of the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, the association is holding its annual meeting this week featuring the customary big-name speakers such as former <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> and information panels on topics like Soviet forces and national security. The main attraction, however, is the approximately 200 defense industry and <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> exhibits on every imaginable aspect of weaponry. `` The exhibits ... reflect the latest in military doctrine, technological advances and hardware improvements,'' says the association, which has held what it touts as `` the largest landpower forum in the free world'' for the past 35 years. Among the items on exhibit in the bowels of a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> hotel were a full-scale light armored vehicle, a handful of howitzers and several high-tech videos promoting helicopters, M-16 machine guns and night-vision goggles. Beribboned officers, fresh-faced cadets and defense industry officials created traffic jams as they grabbed glossy brochures, closely examined the rifles and handguns and questioned the hundreds of company representatives. Some sat transfixed as they watched a sophisticated video on the LHX helicopter displayed on 16 television monitors. It was a combination of <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Bond </PERSON> and Top Gun. `` Time to smell the coffee, sucker,'' said the helicopter pilot as he maneuvered his aircraft through mountain ranges and green valleys and located his target with the help of a British-sounding female voice. `` Have a nice walk home, <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON>,'' the pilot said after a successful hit. But beyond all the glitz, there was serious business as officials from <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> McDonnell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> ITT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Deere </PERSON> briefed representatives from foreign countries and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on their latest wares. For the buyer who ca n't afford to fly from one company to the next, the meeting provides a `` great place for networking in a marketing environment,'' said <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON>, an official with <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION>, as he stood in front of the company's 14 1 @ 2-ton light armored vehicle equipped with a 25mm gun. The meeting, according to <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON>, is strictly for the buyer who wants to browse. `` No contracts. We do n't even talk about contracts. If we did the <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION> secretary could not endorse it,'' he said. `` Those types of things are verboten.'' Instead, the companies tout the advantages and successes of their products with the hope that a telephone call or meeting at a later date will result in a sale. General Motors' light armored vehicle is ideal for low-intensity conflicts and in fact, 14 of them were flown into <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> when the rebel forces led a failed coup against leader <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, according to the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> official. The vehicle has `` great acceleration, a low silhouette, when it's smaller it's harder to hit, great mobility,'' <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON> said. Like in a car showroom where prospective buyers kick the tires, people have come up and knocked their knuckles on the vehicle and said, `` Oh boy, this is it,'' he said. On the other side of the room, in front of a large video screen, representatives of <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Helicopter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Textron </ORGANIZATION> praised the V-22 Osprey, the aircraft that takes off like a helicopter but flies like a plane. Defense Secretary <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON>, in his budget for the fiscal year that began Oct. 1, proposed killing the program. The move was met with opposition on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> where the <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> aircraft enjoys a great deal of popularity. House and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> conferees hammering out a final defense bill have not yet reached a decision on the aircraft. But <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Spivey </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Helicopter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Textron </ORGANIZATION> is convinced the Osprey is key to the nation's defense. `` <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> may be here in jail now if we had the V-22,'' the company official said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891019-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-19-89 0130EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r e BC-CarnegieCabaret     10-19 0426</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Carnegie Cabaret,0442</SECOND>
<HEAD>Elisabeth Welch Opens `Cabaret Comes to Carnegie'</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: No PMs Planned</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Elisabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Welch </PERSON>'s first song, `` One Life To Life,'' contained the line `` If I'm in town, I want to be the toast of it.'' On Wednesday and Thursday she can claim to be the toast of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, where she has come from <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> to sing the first two nights of `` Cabaret Comes to Carnegie'' in Weill Recital Hall. Miss <PERSON> Welch </PERSON>'s biography does n't include her age but it says that she made her Broadway debut in 1923, in `` Runnin' Wild.'' The sweet but distinctive timbre of her voice is n't a great deal different from her vintage recordings and she sings with remarkable control. But a long time lived infused at least two songs with a special glow. They were <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Herman </PERSON>'s `` Song on the Sand,'' a mellow looking back at falling in love, and <PERSON> Noel </PERSON> <PERSON> Coward </PERSON>'s `` I'll Follow My Secret Heart,'' sung in a soft, reminiscent mode. Miss <PERSON> Welch </PERSON> recounted how, in 1930, she was singing in cabaret here when three friends of <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> came to hear her sing `` Love for Sale.'' They recommended that she sing it in the Broadway show `` The New Yorkers,'' which she did. Later, when she was singing in cabaret in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> sent for her and said he had a song for her in a new <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> show to star <PERSON> Gertrude </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON>. `` Let's face it, who stays in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>?'', Miss <PERSON> Welch </PERSON> asked. She sang <PERSON> Porter </PERSON>'s `` Solomon'' in `` Nymph Errant'' in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> in 1933 and sang it at Weill Recital Hall on Wednesday. Her voice wavered on the title word, which is held long, and on the exposed long lines of `` September Song'' her voice wavered again, somehow in an endearing way. The singer made the cabaret staple `` Miss Otis Regrets'' unusually amusing. She said of <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, `` Songs seemed to come from her inner depths. She had a great sadness about her.'' She sang a <PERSON> Jerome </PERSON> <PERSON> Kern </PERSON> specialty of Miss <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>'s, `` Why Was I Born?'', and made it strong but not very sad. A trio, <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Samuels </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Keller </PERSON>, accompanied Miss <PERSON> Welch </PERSON>. Toward the end of her more than an hour show, they were swinging. On those songs Miss <PERSON> Welch </PERSON> danced a bit as she sang, including on her encore, `` Bye, Bye, Blackbird.'' Her appearance here coincides with the release of an RCA album, `` This Thing Called Love,'' and her Weill Recital Hall evenings are being taped for a follow-up, live album.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891019-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-19-89 0132EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     10-19 0925</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0964</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Audrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON> observed life in <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION>'s largest slum on a mission to publicize the plight of the hungry, downtrodden children of the world. <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON>, representing the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Children's Fund, also met Wednesday with <PERSON> Prateep </PERSON> <PERSON> Hata </PERSON>, known as the `` Slum Angel of <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION>.'' `` I am full of admiration for this marvelous angel as she is called. I've seen many of these people. They are the ones that make a big, big difference,'' <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON> said. The star of `` My Fair Lady,'' `` Breakfast at <ORGANIZATION> Tiffany </ORGANIZATION>'s'' and `` Roman Holiday'' said she hoped to make some difference in the lives of the world's downtrodden when she left her Swiss villa and became a <ORGANIZATION> UNICEF </ORGANIZATION> fund-raiser and goodwill ambassador two years ago. `` I put off growing tomatoes for a while,'' she said. <PERSON> Prateep </PERSON>, a slum child herself, started a foundation to care for and educate neglected children. The foundation's seed money was the $ 20,000 grant <PERSON> Prateep </PERSON> got with the 1978 Magsaysay Award, the equivalent of the Nobel Peace Prize in <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Prateep </PERSON> had begun a kindergarten when she was 16 years old to care for the children she saw abandoned in the streets. `` She is proof that where there is determination and love there is a way,'' said <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON>, 60. <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON> said she has little time for acting. In August, however, she flew to <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> to spend two weeks filming a part in <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON>'s `` Always,'' which stars <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Dreyfus </PERSON> and <PERSON> Holly </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>. The movie is scheduled for December release.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PHOENIX (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Guns N' Roses guitarist <PERSON> Izzy </PERSON> <PERSON> Stradlin </PERSON> pleaded guilty to urinating in the galley of an airborne jet and agreed to pay $ 1,000 cleanup costs. <PERSON> Stradlin </PERSON>, 27, said he urinated outside the restroom of the <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION> flight on Aug. 27 because he was frustrated at being kept waiting outside. Originally he was charged with interfering with the duty of a flight crew, a felony, but the charge was dropped Tuesday when <PERSON> Stradlin </PERSON> pled guilty to four misdemeanor charges. He was ordered to pay a $ 2,000 fine, $ 1,000 toward cleanup costs and write a letter of apology to the <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION> crew. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Magistrate <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Mignella </PERSON> also placed <PERSON> Stradlin </PERSON> on six months' probation, which includes counseling. <PERSON> Stradlin </PERSON>, whose real name is <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Isbell </PERSON>, was arrested at <LOCATION> Sky </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> during a scheduled stop in <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> of an Indianapolis-Los Angeles flight. He spent one night in jail.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 40 country music stars including <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Daniels </PERSON> and <PERSON> Waylon </PERSON> <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> will participate in a 12-hour radio show to raise money for a <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> hospital, organizers announced. `` Because of our visibility, we have an opportunity to do a tremendous amount of good for organizations like <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jude </ORGANIZATION> that really need help,'' said <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> Owen </PERSON>, lead singer and guitarist for the group <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>. `` For me, it's more than an opportunity, it's an obligation.'' More than 750 radio stations will carry the Nov. 19 broadcast, `` Country Cares for <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jude </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kids </ORGANIZATION>,'' to raise money for <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jude </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Children </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. Other performers include <PERSON> Glen </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Crystal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gayle </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenwood </PERSON>, Highway 101, <PERSON> Emmylou </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Judds </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandrell </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Mattea </PERSON>, <PERSON> Reba </PERSON> <PERSON> McEntire </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Oak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ridge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boys </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Buck </PERSON> <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kenny </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>, <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> Travis </PERSON>, <PERSON> Conway </PERSON> <PERSON> Twitty </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ricky </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON>. <PERSON> Owen </PERSON> organized the show; the performances will be taped rather than live. The hospital, which opened 27 years ago, specializes in leukemia treatment.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 First lady <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> head <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> and Soviet author <PERSON> Chingiz </PERSON> <PERSON> Aitmatov </PERSON> were honored by a foundation that promotes religious freedom throughout the world. `` Who would have thought, even two years ago, that we would be gathering honoring the first lady of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the chairman of the largest corporation in the world and honoring a Soviet author,'' said Rabbi <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Schneier </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Appeal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conscience </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>. The three each were presented Steuben crystal stars at a press conference Wednesday night. <PERSON> Schneier </PERSON> said Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was being honored as a `` woman of faith'' and `` for her own leadership in and commitment to improving the quality of life in the American family.'' Asked whether she thought it symbolic that she and <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> were being honored along with a Soviet author, Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said: `` It's just another sign of the friendship between our two countries. In honoring <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> for his philanthropic contributions, <PERSON> Schneier </PERSON> said: `` There is a perception that a successful corporation head has no soul and no sensitivity. That's not <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Aitmatov </PERSON> was honored `` as a writer who has probed deeply into the soul of the Russian people and mankind's struggle for human dignity.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 French designer <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Montana </PERSON> will be <PERSON> Lanvin </PERSON>'s new creator of haute couture, the fashion house announced. <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> is the latest ready-to-wear designer to join the world of couture after several other shakeups in the heady high fashion scene this past year. <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> _ the creator of hulking, linebacker shoulders and strong, aggressive fashion _ will be expected to turn out the refined clothes expected by customers of the venerable old house of <LOCATION> Lanvin </LOCATION>, started by <PERSON> Jeanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Lanvin </PERSON> in the 1920s. `` I'll be showing my first collection for 1990 next January,'' <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> said at a news conference Wednesday. He ducked questions about his salary. The Paris-born <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> went to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> when he was 20, and nearly starved before he created papier-mache jewelry that was noticed by <ORGANIZATION> Vogue </ORGANIZATION> magazine. He returned to <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> and designed for several leather companies before turning out his own collections starting in 1977.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891019-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-19-89 0138EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-KidneyTransplants     10-19 0388</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Kidney Transplants,0397</SECOND>
<HEAD>Drug Makes Transplants Cheaper, More Successful</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A drug that improves the success of kidney transplants also helps reduce medical bills by shortening the length of hospital stays, according to a study published today. Among patients receiving new kidneys, hospital bills totaled an average of $ 28,649 for those receiving the anti-rejection drug cyclosporine and $ 37,895 for those who did not, a 24 percent difference, according to the study. Patients receiving the drug were discharged from the hospital in three weeks rather than five, according to research directed by <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Showstack </PERSON> at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. The drug keeps the body from rejecting the foreign organ. The study said the medicine improved the chances of a successful kidney transplant from 60 percent to 80 percent. The research, published in the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> England </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION>, was based on studies of 702 patients who received transplants between 1982 and 1986, the period during which cyclosporine became widely available. Doctors from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pittsburgh </ORGANIZATION>, meanwhile, said Wednesday a new drug code named FK-506 appears to be even more effective and less toxic than cyclosporine. Dr. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Starzl </PERSON>, who pioneered the use of cyclosporine, said the new drug could make transplants cheaper still by speeding recovery and reducing the need for tests. In a separate report in the journal, Dr. <PERSON> Catherine </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cowie </PERSON> of Social & amp; <ORGANIZATION> Scientific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Bethesda </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, directed a study showing that black people with diabetes are more likely than whites with the disease to suffer kidney failure. Diabetes is the underlying cause of about one-quarter of all cases of kidney failure in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, and blacks are about three times more likely than whites to have diabetic kidney failure. However, it was unclear whether this was simply because blacks are more likely to get diabetes. The new study, based on 470 blacks and 861 whites in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, found that the incidence of diabetic kidney failure was 2.6 times higher among blacks, even when their higher prevalence of diabetes was taken into account. An accompanying editorial by Dr. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rostand </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alabama </ORGANIZATION> said the increased risk may result in part from racial differences in kidney function. However, better control of blood sugar and blood pressure could improve blacks' chances of escaping kidney failure.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891019-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-19-89 0142EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Ethics-Bates     10-19 0420</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ethics-Bates,420</SECOND>
<HEAD>Panel Finds Bates Sexually Harassed Workers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee says Rep. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bates </PERSON>, D-Calif., could face <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> disciplinary action if he repeats harassment of female staffers or permits any more campaign activities in his office <PERSON> Bates </PERSON> was informed by the committee Wednesday that he violated a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> rule prohibiting sexual harassment and an ethics guideline barring campaign work in a congressional office. `` Your improper conduct and concurrent violations of relevant standards deserve reproval,'' the four-term <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Diego </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrat </ORGANIZATION> was told in a letter from <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Julian </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, D-Calif. and ranking Republican <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> The panel declined to recommend disciplinary action by the full <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, which could range from a reprimand to expulsion in the most extreme cases. But the committee warned <PERSON> Bates </PERSON> that `` any further violation by you in the areas which were the subject of the ... inquiry may result in a recommendation that disciplinary action be considered by the House.'' The panel began a preliminary inquiry against <PERSON> Bates </PERSON> after a complaint last October by two women who had worked in his congressional office. The women, who had left <PERSON> Bates </PERSON>' office before filing their complaint, said he sexually harassed them while they were employees and pressured congressional staffers to do campaign work. The committee acknowledged <PERSON> Bates </PERSON> has apologized to `` anyone who may have been offended'' by his personal conduct, but deemed that action insufficient. <PERSON> Bates </PERSON> was directed to write the women, <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Dryden </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dorena </PERSON> <PERSON> Bertussi </PERSON> `` apologizing for behavior which was sexual harassment, copies of which should be provided to this committee.'' <PERSON> Bates </PERSON> told reporters he allowed a campaign employee to make fund-raising calls from his office and later hired the worker for the congressional staff. <PERSON> Bates </PERSON> told reporters, `` I accept the committee's judgment,'' he said, adding, `` Times are changing. Members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> are going to be scrutinized for their personal and professional behavior. `` Sexual harassment is very serious and not to be taken lightly. I did not know what sexual harassment meant until this came up.'' The rule cited by the committee states: `` A member, officer or employee of the House of Representatives shall not discharge or refuse to hire any individual, or otherwise discriminate against any individual with respect to compensation, terms, conditions or privileges of employment, because of such individual's race, color, religion, sex or national origin.'' The ethics committee's manual for members states, `` Official allowances may not be used to defray any personal, political, or campaign-related expenses.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891019-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-19-89 0156EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     10-19 0883</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>Trade Agreement With Canada Will Help Vegetable Sales, Expert Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The new long-range trade pact with <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> should help boost consumer demand for fresh vegetables on both sides of the border, perhaps by 25 percent overall, says <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> economist <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> <PERSON> Sparks </PERSON>. The U.S.-Canada Free Trade Agreement, which took effect last Jan. 1, removes many trade restrictions between the two countries. A major benefit down the road will be the elimination of all agricultural tariffs within 10 years. <PERSON> Sparks </PERSON>, who works for the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, took a look at the trade agreement's impact on vegetables. Her findings are reported in a forthcoming issue of Farmline magazine. Why focus on vegetables, when there are other larger and more glamorous export commodities such as grains and meat to study? `` Everybody asks that question,'' <PERSON> Sparks </PERSON> said Wednesday in a telephone interview. `` Do n't feel that I take it personally.'' But something `` totally different'' had to be found for her doctoral dissertation, and vegetables were it, she said. `` Also, international trade in vegetables is growing quite a bit,'' <PERSON> Sparks </PERSON> said. `` While it's not one of our major crops like soybeans or corn, it's growing in importance and is something that needs to be looked at.'' The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> are each other's largest export markets, overall, the report said. More than 18 percent of last year's total <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> imports were from <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, while almost 22 percent of all <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> exports went to <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. But agriculture makes up only a small portion of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade with <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, the report said. And of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agricultural export total, only about 5 percent went to <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> in the 1980s. According to the department's <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> imports around $ 3 billion in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agricultural products annually, including an average of about $ 450 million worth of vegetables and $ 650 million worth of fruit. The <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> forecasts 1989-90 agricultural exports to <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> at a value of $ 2.2 billion but adds that in recent years these figures `` have been under-reported by an estimated $ 1 billion annually'' and is officially recognized by both governments. Agricultural imports from <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> in 1989-90 are forecast at about $ 2.8 billion, according to current <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> figures. The department's official estimate of total <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agricultural export value in the year that began Oct. 1 is $ 40 billion. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> is the biggest single-country market at $ 8.1 billion, followed by the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, $ 3.5 billion; <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, $ 2.5 billion; <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, $ 2.4 billion; and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, $ 2.2 billion. With the complete elimination of tariffs, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> demand for Canadian vegetables would increase about 80 percent from today's levels, and Canadian demand for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> vegetable would go up 30 percent, according to <PERSON> Sparks </PERSON>' study
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The share of commodity marketings by farm cooperatives has declined from levels of the early 1980s, according to an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> report. In 1987, the most recent year examined, co-ops accounted for 25 percent of farm marketings, down from 27 percent in 1985 and 28 percent in 1982. Grain marketings by cooperatives were reported at 29 percent of the total, down from 33 percent in 1985 and 36 percent in 1982. That includes sales of oilseeds except for cottonseed. `` Much of the decline has been the result of less cooperative involvement in grain and oilseeds marketing,'' the report by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cooperative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday. The co-op share of milk marketed was 76 percent in 1987, compared with 78 percent in 1985 and 77 percent in 1982. Cotton marketings were 38 percent, 33 percent and 36 percent, respectively, and livestock at 7 percent, 8 percent and 11 percent. Fruit and vegetable marketings by co-ops accounted for 23 percent of the total in 1987, up from 8 percent in 1985 and 11 percent in 1982. Cooperative shares of production supplies sold to farmers also dropped by similar percentages, to 25 percent in 1987 from 27 percent in 1985 and 28 percent in 1982, the report said. However, not all items declined accordingly. Supplies included: fertilizer, 43 percent of the total in 1987, 44 percent in 1985 and 42 percent in 1982; petroleum, 37 percent, 44 percent and 36 percent; farm chemicals, 28 percent; 29 percent and 34 percent; seed, 19 percent, 15 percent and 17 percent; and feed, 17 percent, 16 percent and 18 percent.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> trade report says <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> exports of solid wood products were valued at $ 2.95 billion in the first six months of this year, up 11 percent from the first half of 1988. Softwood products rose 4 percent to $ 1.9 billion, the report by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday. That included about $ 1.09 billion in the value of logs, $ 648.1 million for lumber, and $ 104.9 million for plywood. Hardwood products increased 29 percent to $ 661 million, including a 62 percent jump in hardwood logs to $ 147.8 million. `` Exports to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, the leading purchaser of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wood products, increased by 25 percent in the first half to $ 1.4 billion,'' the report said. `` The other growth markets include <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, 11 percent; <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, 140 percent; and <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, 39 percent.'' But exports to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION>, two other top markets, were down 38 percent and 50 percent, respectively, from a year earlier, the report said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891019-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-19-89 0200EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Quake-Scene     10-19 0730</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quake-Scene,0749</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thousands Pour Into Streets</HEAD>
<HEAD>With LaserPhotos</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-SF Quake, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICH CARTIERE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The powerful earthquake that jolted the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area forced a holiday on tens of thousands of people, who poured into the rubble-littered streets to gawk at nature's might Amid the balmy weather that encouraged throngs clad mostly in shorts and T-shirts, there were scenes of devastation and others _ like the soup line of 1,000 outside Glide Memorial Church in the seedy <LOCATION> Tenderloin </LOCATION> district _ emblematic of more permanent misfortunes. The disaster brought out the spectator in many, but others pitched in to help the homeless and distraught. `` This is an incredible coming together; an act of the brotherly love that <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Franciscans </LOCATION> were famous for in the'60s,'' self-described `` ex-hippie'' <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosen </PERSON> said as he helped people clear rubble from a collapsed building. The dawn of a flaming sun, colored through wisps of fog in the hills east of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, painted streets in rose tones as residents and hundreds of stranded visitors awoke a day after the quake, unsure of what awaited them. Thousands arose from a night in emergency shelters, hundreds more from makeshift tents in city parks and rural lots. Most had spent more than 12 hours without heat or light. But the vast majority of the region's 6 million residents made it through the night in largely undisturbed comfort. As they mingled on the streets by the hundreds in cities ranging from the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> coastal community of <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>, they became a portrait of contrasts. In <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>'s Golden Gate Park, joggers huffed in the bright high-noon sun. Temperatures reached the high 70s by late afternoon. A couple walked their two dogs. A lone man sunbathed on a knoll near the towering band shell. While sprinklers in the well-to-do <LOCATION> Marina </LOCATION> district saturated expansive, manicured lawns, many residents of collapsed sections of the neighborhood were forced into a <LOCATION> Red </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cross </LOCATION> shelter, where they quickly ran out of water. A Mendocino water company donated a truckload of bottled water. The traditional daily crowd of tattered homeless people at Tenderloin churches was swelled by hundreds of elderly hotel dwellers and Southeast Asian refugee families. They came to the church hoping to eat their first meal since the quake. The Marina, at the northern end of the city inside the Golden Gate, is renowned for its narrow, curving streets, with such names as <LOCATION> Alhambra </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Cervantes </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Mallorca </LOCATION>. The streets are lined with neat, handsome homes and apartments, most finished with light-colored stucco and many with tile roofs. But the area, built on fill land, was the hardest hit of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>'s neighborhoods. On Wednesday, it contained scenes like this: Next to the crumpled, charred rubble of a three-story apartment complex, an elderly woman gingerly dusted a delicate crystal lamp. A helicopter tour of the Bay Area beginning at daybreak revealed billowing smoke pouring from a block of the Marina nearly flattened by a fire that broke out after the quake. Two joggers ran by, trying to step over firehoses without breaking stride. The grand sandstone structure of the Palace of Fine Arts, built for the 1915 Panama-Pacific International Exposition, was draped in smoke from the devastated buildings two blocks away. The neighborhood of bungalows and Victorians looked as if a giant invading creature had taken two steps and then turned back. The silver strand of the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco-Oakland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bridge </LOCATION> gracefully cut through the foggy haze, marred only by lines of orange hazard cones blocking traffic. A collapsed 50-foot section of the upper level looked like nothing more than one pasteboard in a fallen house of cards. On either side of the bridge, the green-and-yellow pennants of the <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Athletics </ORGANIZATION> and the black-and-orange of the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Giants </ORGANIZATION> flapped at each other in the light morning breeze, with no motorists to cheer them on. On the <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> side of the bridge, a collapsed section of Interstate 880 looked like it had melted in a scorching sun. On the nearby beaches of <LOCATION> Alameda </LOCATION>, scores of sun bathers took advantage of canceled school or work. At <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION>, the historic Boardwalk amusement park was spotless but without visitors, while hundreds of people stood in block-long lines at the few supermarkets open to the public in a city largely devoid of power and potable water.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891019-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-19-89 0447EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--DeadlineClub     10-19 0151</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Deadline Club,0159</SECOND>
<HEAD>Seven Journalists Chosen for Hall of Fame</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Seven journalists have been chosen for admission into the Hall of Fame of the <ORGANIZATION> Deadline </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, the local chapter of the <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Professional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journalists </ORGANIZATION>. Two of the seven were named posthumously: <PERSON> DeWitt </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lila </PERSON> <PERSON> Acheson </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON>, who founded Reader's Digest in 1922. The others chosen are: _ <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Hewitt </PERSON>, executive producer of <ORGANIZATION> CBS-TV </ORGANIZATION>'s `` 60 Minutes''; _ <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerr </PERSON>, the Pulitzer Prize-winning drama critic for the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>; _ <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, chairman and chief executive officer of <ORGANIZATION> Dow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jones </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>; _ <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> <PERSON> Salisbury </PERSON>, Pulitzer Prize-winning foreign correspondent for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> and author; _ <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Shawn </PERSON>, who retired as editor of The New Yorker in 1987; The chapter will recognize the selections Nov. They will join 66 others in the Hall of Fame, which was established in 1975.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891019-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-19-89 0203EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NorthPension     10-19 0456</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-North Pension,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>North Supporters Fighting to Restore His Pension</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Some lawmakers are vowing to restore <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s $ 23,000 military retirement pay, saying <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> never intended for its anti-shredding law to deprive the convicted Iran-Contra figure his pension. `` Regardless of what happened in the Iran-Contra affair, people have a difficult time understanding why he is being denied the pension that he earned,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Orrin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Utah </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is scheduled to vote Nov. 3 on a bill that would exempt North from the penalty which was imposed after he was convicted July 5 on charges of shredding government documents and two other felonies. North is appealing the convictions. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Biden </PERSON>, D-Del., said he will draft a report for the full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> that outlines the arguments on both sides of the politically divisive issue `` We've got to solve this thing. We've got to make this thing square for everybody,'' <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> told reporters after a hearing on Wednesday on the matter. <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> suggested lawmakers should deal not just with <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s case, but with the pension rights of any federal official _ including members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> _ convicted of a felony North's retirement pay was $ 23,000 a year. He is reportedly getting $ 25,000 for each speech he gets on the lecture circuit. The law under which the pay was revoked provides that anyone convicted of shredding protected government documents `` shall forfeit his office.'' The <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, which has jurisdiction over federal pay matters, ruled <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s status as a retired military officer came under that provision of the law and that forfeiting his office meant he no longer qualified for retirement pay. Some conservatives who view <PERSON> North </PERSON> as a hero who bore the brunt of blame for the Iran-Contra scandal were outraged at the decision. <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON>, Sen. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Grassley </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Iowa </LOCATION>, and Sen. <PERSON> Strom </PERSON> <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-S.C. </LOCATION>, have said the retirement pay should be restored. But Sen. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s sentence was too lenient and the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> was right to deny him retirement pay. `` We are sending the wrong message when people violate the public trust and get off with only a slap on the wrist,'' he said. Legal scholars told the Judiciary panel <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> should answer whether the law meant for `` office'' to include military positions. Technically, military retirement pay is not a pension based on past service but a reduced salary for an officer who continues to hold a commission and remains subject to recall to active duty. North `` very well may be entitled to his pension,'' <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> said. `` Whatever we do, there should be a basic equity'' with other cases. But he acknowledged, `` It's not going to be divorced from politics.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891019-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-19-89 0206EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SlopeSentencing     10-19 0558</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Slope Sentencing,0575</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pair Sentenced to Jail in Alaska's Longest, Costliest Criminal Trial</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL JENKINS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ANCHORAGE, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
