<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891207-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-07-89 2333EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Cuba-US 1stLd-Writethru a0786 12-07 0260</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cuba-US, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0786,0264</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Soldiers Fire at Cuban Guardpost, Prensa Latina Says</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS throughout to UPDATE with details, quotes, U.S. comment.
No pickup</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soldiers at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> base at <LOCATION> Guantanamo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, fired two shots Thursday at <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> sentry posts, breaking glass but causing no injuries, the official news agency <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Latina </ORGANIZATION> said. The news agency quoted a ministry statement as saying one shot was fired at 10 a.m. EST at sentry post 17, and a second at 1 p.m. at post 18. Lt. Cmdr. <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Satterfield </PERSON>, a spokesman in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> for the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` We received no reports of any such incident.'' Both shots shattered glass in the posts, the agency said in the dispatch, monitored in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. The direction indicated the shots were fired from <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> post 13, the agency quoted the note as saying. `` These actions are even more serious and of unpredictable consequences because the two shots hit the guardposts and could have wounded and even assassinated any of the soldiers who were on guard duty,'' the agency quoted the note as saying. The note said the last similar incident was Aug. 21, 1987, when shots were fired from <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> post 18 on a <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> observation post. It noted the incident occurred as the country was holding funerals for more than 2,000 Cuban soldiers and civilian technicians killed in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> and other foreign conflicts the past 14 years. The ministry said it was not an accident that `` these vulgar and dangerous provocations by <ORGANIZATION> Yankee </ORGANIZATION> soldiers occurred precisely today.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891207-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-07-89 0755EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     12-07 0517</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0536</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHARLESTON, W.Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 State game officials are no dummies, but the same ca n't be said for the deer they used to nab poachers. For the second straight year, officers from the state's Division of Natural Resources used fake deer against hunters who stop along highways to shoot at deer illegally. Last year, one bogus buck in <LOCATION> Braxton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> bamboozled 30 would-be hunters into taking potshots. This year, conservation officers caught 82 shooters at two locations. `` We were hoping that the publicity would act as a deterrent to those hunters who like to cruise the roads looking for deer,'' said Maj. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> of the agency's law enforcement division. `` I think it worked. I'm sure it saved some real deer.'' Most of the arrests were for shooting from the road or for trespassing on private property. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> said one decoy was set up in a privately owned field marked with `` No Hunting'' signs. `` We had some guys who would jump out of their cars, run over to the fence and use the signs as gun rests,'' <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> said. Such antics often left conservation officers laughing so hard that they had to pause to compose themselves before moving in to make arrests. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> still chuckles about one incident. `` One car pulled up and four guys came rolling out of it with their guns,'' he said. `` Three of them took up positions outside the fence while the other one sneaked in toward the decoy. `` Finally, the guy got within 30 yards or so of the deer, stood up and fired. He looked at the decoy, still just standing there, and I think he began to get the idea that something was wrong. `` He walked over to the decoy and just reached out and touched it. About that time, we hit the siren and moved in. You've never seen a more dejected or more hang-dog expression on anyone in your life. His buddies were laughing their brains out.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>COGGON, Iowa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Your run-of-the-mill lounge lizard will still be roaming bars, but the <ORGANIZATION> Coggon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> intends to decide whether an undersized alligator can frequent a tavern. A hearing will be held next month to discuss whether <LOCATION> Crosby </LOCATION> the alligator can be the mascot of <PERSON> Crosby </PERSON>'s Cove, a tavern recently purchased by <PERSON> Crosby </PERSON>'s best friend and feeder, <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Schebler </PERSON> of Cedar Rapids. Tuesday night, <PERSON> Schebler </PERSON> lobbied the <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> to amend the city's dangerous animal ordinance, which prohibits bobcats, polar bears, alligators and other wild critters within the city limits. Council discussion showed a general reluctance to amend the ordinance to allow alligators less than 3 -LCB- feet long if in a secured container. But Councilman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Foye </PERSON> supported the change, agreeing with Schebler that dogs could be more dangerous than a locked-up alligator. `` I'm not worried about his alligator snipping off my kids' toes,'' <PERSON> Foye </PERSON> said `` They should n't be in the tavern anyway.'' Mayor <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Trumbull </PERSON> encouraged drafting the amendment and having a hearing Jan. 2. <PERSON> Schebler </PERSON> wants to keep the alligator, now 2 feet long, in the bar to attract customers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891207-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-07-89 0808EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Cocaine-Heart     12-07 0512</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cocaine-Heart,0525</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study: Even Tiny Amount of Cocaine Cuts Blood Flow to Heart</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANIEL Q. HANEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Even minuscule amounts of cocaine can constrict the arteries and reduce the flow of blood to the heart, and this may explain how larger doses trigger heart attacks and death, researchers report today. Young, seemingly healthy cocaine abusers sometimes suffer chest pain or heart attacks even though their heart arteries appear to be perfectly normal. Doctors have speculated that the drug causes spasms in blood vessels and temporarily chokes off the flow of blood to heart muscle. `` The importance of our findings was showing that this indeed happens,'' said Dr. <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Hillis </PERSON>. `` No one has shown it in man before.'' Cotton strips soaked in a cocaine solution are routinely used as a local anesthetic in an estimated 185,000 medical procedures in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> each year. It is especially common during minor nose operations, since it limits bleeding as well as deadens pain. In their experiment on 45 people, doctors tested cocaine's effects on the heart when volunteers received doses that were about two-thirds the amount used for anesthesia They got between 150 and 180 milligrams of cocaine. By contrast, people who abuse cocaine typically take one gram, or six times this much. `` Even that small dose caused coronary blood flow to fall by about 15 to 20 percent,'' said <PERSON> Hillis </PERSON>. `` One can extrapolate from that to say that in all probability a much larger dose would in some people cause a very profound fall in blood flow.'' The study, conducted by <PERSON> Hillis </PERSON> and colleagues at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, was published in the New England Journal of Medicine. <PERSON> Hillis </PERSON> said that despite the finding, the medical use of cocaine as a painkiller is safe. The volunteers showed no sign in their hearts of ischemia, or oxygen starvation. <PERSON> Hillis </PERSON> said that some people's heart arteries respond much more dramatically than others' to the potential hazards of cocaine. In his study, he said, the reduction in blood flow ranged from 5 percent to about 40 percent. He said these individual differences may explain why some people have heart attacks or die from cocaine abuse, while most do not. In an accompanying editorial, Drs. <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Isner </PERSON> and <PERSON> Saurabh </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Chokshi </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elizabeth </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> noted that during the past year, the number of emergency room visits for cocaine-related problems has increased fivefold. `` While laboratory studies offer increase insight into the fundamental effects of cocaine,'' they wrote, `` the history of this ancient drug grows progressively more depressing.'' They said that at least 58 cases of cocaine-related heart attacks have been described in medical journals. Among highly publicized cases was the 1986 death of college basketball star <PERSON> Len </PERSON> <PERSON> Bias </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hillis </PERSON> said cocaine stimulates the body's production of adrenaline and other hormones. These trigger the blood vessels to narrow so that less oxygen-carrying blood can get through. At the same time, the drug increases the heart's need for oxygen by boosting the heart rate.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891207-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-07-89 0808EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Publishing     12-07 0243</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Publishing,0249</SECOND>
<UNK>Ten Percent Of Publishers To Be Closed</UNK>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> plans to shut down 10 percent of its newspapers and publishing houses, targeting for closure those printing pornography or material critical of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, the official <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> news agency said today. The agency quoted the current issue of <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> as saying newspaper and magazine offices that publish pornographic stories or articles running counter to the party line will lose their licenses. The Press and <ORGANIZATION> Publications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> will also merge newspapers and periodicals that are similar in content, it said. The report said <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has 1,600 newspapers, 3,000 social science periodicals and 500 publishing houses. Many are similar in nature and have few readers. In the past year, particularly after <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> leaders used troops to crush the pro-democracy movement in June, the government has moved to consolidate and exert greater control over the publishing industry. Millions of publications have been confiscated and destroyed in a nationwide anti-pornography campaign and a number of publications that sympathized with the pro-democracy movement, such as <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION>, have been shut down or revamped. <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruihuan </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Politburo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Standing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> member in charge of propaganda and cultural affairs, said recently that many publications were being turned out that advocated `` bourgeois liberalization'', or Western ideas. He said such publications were `` full of seductive and poisonous material especially harmful to young people'' and `` it was high time to solve all these problems.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891207-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-07-89 0755EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--HonestThief     12-07 0124</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Honest Thief,0127</SECOND>
<HEAD>Returns Stolen Loot</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KEENE, N.H. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A thief apparently troubled by a guilty conscience returned $ 4,500 to a bank after taking the money to buy Christmas gifts, police said. Fleet Bank-N.H. reported this week that two bags containing the cash and checks were missing. The next day, the bank received a large envelope in the mail containing the cash bags, the cash and a note saying the sender had found the bags outside the post offce, opened them and decided to return them. Police said the package was traced to a 19-year-old <PERSON> Keene </PERSON> man, who was to have put the money in a night deposit box for his employer. The business has decided not to press charges, police said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891207-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-07-89 0241EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PapSmears Bjt   12-07 0631</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pap Smears, Bjt,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study Shows Higher Cancer Risk With Infrequent Pap Smears</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Cervical cancer risks increase dramatically for women who fail to get Pap smear tests at least every two years, <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> scientists report in a study released today. Women who get Pap smears only every three years run a risk that is 3.9 times greater that cervical cancer will go undetected than women who have the test annually, according to the study published in the professional journal Obstetrics and Gynecology. The study said the risks increase as the between-test interval increases and that for women who have no Pap tests for 10 years or longer, the risk increases by 12.3 times. `` The study shows that women should get Pap smears more frequently than every three years,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Chu </PERSON>, one of five physicians who conducted the study at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION>. `` The risk of having advanced disease goes way down if the tests are conducted every two years or less.'' <PERSON> Chu </PERSON> said that the more frequent Pap tests lower the cancer risk for all women, no matter what other risk factors, such as smoking or multiple sexual partners, they have in their life. The Pap smear is used in gynecological screening to detect the presence of squamous cell cancer, the most common form of cervical cancer. It can also detect changes in cells that could lead to invasive cancer if not treated _ thus the test can result in therapy that prevents the cancer from developing. To perform a Pap test, doctors collect cells from the mucous membrane of the cervix during a pelvic examination. The cells are stained for laboratory analysis. The procedure, known formally as the <PERSON> Papanicolaou </PERSON> stain test, is named for <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicolas </PERSON> <PERSON> Papanicolaou </PERSON>, the physician who developed it. Just how frequently such tests should be performed to afford maximum protection has long been a matter of controversy. Some studies have found that significantly elevated risks for cancer occur at test intervals of four years or more. But the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> State researchers said in their study that they found three years seemed to be the critical interval. `` Women with three-year screening intervals had over three times the risk of squamous cells cervical cancer at did other women with annual screening intervals.'' It noted, however, that there was little risk difference between annual and biannual Pap tests. `` We found no difference in the risk of cervical cancer between women screened every year and those screened every two years, suggesting that two-year screening intervals offer the same protection as annual smears,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> <PERSON> Shy </PERSON>, lead author of the study. The findings are based on interviews and medical histories of 92 women with advanced cervical cancer, compared with similar data from 178 women without cancer and selected randomly. The ages ranged from 31 to 75. Annual Pap tests are recommended by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cancer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Obstetricians </ORGANIZATION> and Gynecologists for women ages 18 and over who are sexually active. After three consecutive tests with normal findings, however, the test often is done at the discretion of the physician. `` There are really no firm guidelines,'' <PERSON> Chu </PERSON> said. `` Our study, though, shows that three years is certainly not the right number of years'' between tests. The study showed that although the Pap test frequency, along with appropriate follow-up treatment, can reduce the risk of squamous cell cancer, the test interval had no effect on other types of cervical cancer. Squamous cell, however, accounts for about 85 percent of all cervical cancers, <PERSON> Chu </PERSON> said. Other researchers conducting the study were Drs. <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandelson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Greer </PERSON> and <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Figge </PERSON>. Obstetrics and Gynecology is the professional journal of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Obstetricians </ORGANIZATION> and Gynecologists.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891207-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-07-89 0239EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Summit-Naval Bjt   12-07 0714</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-Naval, Bjt,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tougher Soviet Stance Could Delay Arms Treaty</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s toughened stance on submarine-launched cruise missiles could delay completion of a strategic weapons treaty past the summit planned for June, says a senior <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and his foreign minister, <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>, appeared at the <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> summit last weekend to `` walk back'' from a concession they made in September concerning the submarine-launched cruise missiles, or SLCMs, said a second official. Both sources spoke on condition of anonymity. At a September meeting in <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> with Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> withdrew Soviet demands that SLCM limits be included in the proposed Strategic Arms Reduction Treaty. <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> said the Soviets would settle for a separate deal, but did not specify whether it must be signed at the same time as the START treaty. At <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>, however, the Soviets spelled out new, more stringent conditions for the proposed SLCM accord, and they have been indicating that they want the two deals concluded simultaneously, said the sources. `` In September, they said SLCMs could be dealt with outside the START treaty. But <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said ` how can we agree to all these kinds of reductions when SLCMs are out there running free?''' said the official. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> also pressed President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to hold naval arms control talks to ban short-range nuclear weapons in the superpower navies, said <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> rejected <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s suggestion as `` unacceptable to us because the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is a naval power. We depend upon the seas for contact with all of our allies and with other continents of the world,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> concentrated on the issue of tactical nuclear weapons, while <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> dealt in greater detail with the SLCM question in a separate meeting with <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, said one of the sources. The senior <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official said that as a result of the conflicting signals from <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>: `` I do n't know where we are. But SLCMs is a major issue.'' The new Soviet position helps explain the sudden pessimism of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials who went to <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> hoping to conclude START in time for the summit scheduled for the last two weeks of June in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, but left the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> saying it could take longer. Both leaders said before the summit that a START deal was possible by September, and at <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> they announced that <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> would travel to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> next month to continue work on the treaty, which would cut long-range superpower arsenals by 30 percent to 50 percent, to 6,000 warheads apiece. So far, the Soviets have not put forward a comprehensive proposal linking SLCMs and tactical nuclear weapons, or spelling out the scope of the issues they want covered in naval arms control talks. But at <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Baker </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Soviets </ORGANIZATION> wanted the SLCM issue included in a naval arms control treaty, that they wanted tough verification rules and they wanted to curb conventional and nuclear warheads, said one source. The Soviets have been pushing similar conditions at the START talks in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>, and also have given `` indications that they want START and a naval treaty at the same time. They did n't say that specifically at <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>,'' said the source. One official described <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>'s statements at <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> as a `` hardening of the Soviet position.'' Another called it a `` walk back.'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> illustrated his concern over the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> by giving <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a map of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> naval bases, deployments and maneuvers around the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. In rejecting <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s argument, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> maintained that `` the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is a land-based power. But the navy is crucial to us in terms of maintaining all of our commitments around the world, maintaining open sea lanes and commercial lanes around the world.'' In Pentagon and other assessments, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> is considered to be mightier than its Soviet counterpart, having for example more aircraft carriers. At the joint presidential news conference concluding the summit, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> staked out their basic positions on naval arms control, although neither went into detail. `` The time has come when we should begin discussing naval forces,'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> replied, `` I'm disinclined to think that this is an area where we will have immediate progress.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891207-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-07-89 0238EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ConservativeThaw Bjt   12-07 0843</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Conservative Thaw, Bjt,820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cold War Drying Up Conservative Coffers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With the Cold War thaw, the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s right wing is having a tougher time attracting troops and money to its conservative causes _ prompting a search for new issues to replace the Soviet menace `` Saber rattling and the sort of hard-line anti-communism that have held our coalition together are not going to be as convincing arguments with the voters, not when you have a majority of the voters thinking the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> merely seeks peace like we do,'' said <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON>, a Republican political consultant. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Viguerie </PERSON>, who built a political and financial empire based on mail-order fund-raising among conservatives, says he's replacing anti-communism with attacks on <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> as the centerpiece of his new appeals for dollars `` I plan to make the imperial <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> my No. 1 issue for the foreseeable future,'' <PERSON> Viguerie </PERSON> said. `` Whether it's going to catch on as the No. 1 issue, I do n't know.'' Not all conservatives have begun such wholesale rethinking, however. Most prominent among them was Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, who offered a highly skeptical assessment of the Soviets in an interview published after last weekend's summit between President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. `` I do n't think they've changed much in foreign policy,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. In a subsequent interview with <ORGANIZATION> Knight-Ridder </ORGANIZATION> newspaper editors, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> tempered his earlier comments by saying he should have referred to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> as an authoritarian rather than totalitarian state. National security adviser <PERSON> Brent </PERSON> <PERSON> Scowcroft </PERSON> rejected suggestions there was a marked difference in the views of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>. He said that there may be a `` difference of perspective, but there's no difference in the substance of the policies we're pursuing. Sen. <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallop </PERSON>, R-Wyo., a leading <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> hawk, disputed the notion that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s `` perestroika'' reforms and the moves toward democracy in the Soviet bloc nations of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> have resulted in a lessening of Cold War concerns by American voters `` I do n't think the millennia has arrived, and I do n't think the polls show the public thinks the millennia has arrived,'' <PERSON> Wallop </PERSON> said. He is a leader of conservative efforts to oppose defense cuts attributable to the lessening of superpower tensions. He is opposing <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration acceptance of modest cuts in defense spending. But Wallop acknowledges that in the wake of changes in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> summit, `` it's going to require some leadership to maintain some perspective in the public mind'' in support of the conservative agenda. The opening of the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall and other rapid, revolutionary changes in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> are only the latest blows to conservatives' ability to rally around Cold War worries. As conservatives have seen their presidential candidates win three consecutive elections and much of their agenda enacted by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, some of their leading organizations have faced a decline in fund-raising and dues-paying membership. As they succeed, some of the fire goes out of the fight. `` Our members came on because of defense and foreign policy issues _ anti-communism issues,'' said <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>. `` The fear and loathing is just not at the same level of intensity it was in recent years. ... You do n't expand your membership pool by just declaring victory.'' Most of the conservative leaders say they believe there is still a good case to be made for maintaining tough defense and anti-communism positions. Their problem is most voters are n't as concerned as before. `` I find this all a very sorry state of affairs,'' laments Stone. The <ORGANIZATION> ACU </ORGANIZATION> illustrates the problem encountered by many conservative groups. Its donor list has fallen from a high of 750,000 donors a decade ago to about 60,000 today. Others, such as the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, have sold assets and cut back programs. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Keene </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> ACU </ORGANIZATION>, said his group is `` in an assessment phase,'' and considering other issues. And conservative leaders say there are many other ones, including opposing `` Latin communism,'' as <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> calls it, in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, and even that favorite from 11 years ago, maintaining control of the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION>. `` I do n't see any perestroika south of the border,'' <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> said. Other potential fighting issues eyed by conservative fund-raisers are opposing abortion, pushing conservative social issues before the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, fighting taxes, and opposing liberals on the spending at home of any savings accruing from peace abroad. `` The center of gravity of the conservative movement will shift,'' said <PERSON> Casey </PERSON>. `` I think the tax issue is a critical issue, and the disposition of the ` peace dividend' will ignite the usual liberal-conservative fight.'' Wallop, while insisting the Cold War causes will still work, acknowledges that rapid changes in the face of communism will force conservatives _ and liberals _ to change their methods. `` It's made it different. It's made it different for the other side, too,'' Wallop said. `` The will begin to find ways to spend the defense savings. They've got a pile of new thinking to do also. All of us do.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891207-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-07-89 0239EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     12-07 0693</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0721</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Another mystery has been solved. <PERSON> Angela </PERSON> <PERSON> Lansbury </PERSON> has agreed to return for a seventh season in <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>'s highest-rated entertainment show `` Murder, She Wrote.'' Miss <PERSON> Lansbury </PERSON> had not planned to return for 1990-91, but <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> reached an agreement for next season, said <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Stringer </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>. `` Murder, She Wrote,'' in which Miss <PERSON> Lansbury </PERSON> plays a mystery novelist who keeps happening upon murders, is CBS' only hit entertainment show. Usually, Miss <PERSON> Lansbury </PERSON>'s show and `` 60 Minutes'' are the only <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> shows to make the 20 top shows in the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> ratings. Her return is so important to <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> that the network has granted her enormous concessions. The agreement calls for Miss <PERSON> Lansbury </PERSON>'s production company to develop a series for next season that she would not appear in To get her to return for the current season, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> financed the establishment of her production company and said she only had to appear in 13 episodes. She makes brief appearances in nine other episodes, which are essentially pilots for other series. That contract also calls for her company to produce several TV movies and 13 episodes of a half-hour series starring Miss <PERSON> Lansbury </PERSON> after `` Murder, She Wrote'' ends its network run.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MILAN, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Maurizio </PERSON> <PERSON> Gucci </PERSON>, chairman of the Italian luxury goods company <ORGANIZATION> Guccio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gucci </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> SPA </ORGANIZATION>, has been found innocent of attempted fraud by a <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION> appeals court. In November 1988, <ORGANIZATION> Gucci </ORGANIZATION> was given a one-year suspended prison term and a fine of $ 760 after being convicted of tax fraud. He also was ordered to pay inheritance tax on shares of <ORGANIZATION> Gucci </ORGANIZATION> he had received from his father, <PERSON> Rodolfo </PERSON>. The <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION> court had ruled that <PERSON> Maurizio </PERSON> <PERSON> Gucci </PERSON> arranged the forgery of his father's signature on the documents giving him the shares, to make it appear that the transfer took place before <PERSON> Rodolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Gucci </PERSON>'s death in 1983. The lower court said <ORGANIZATION> Gucci </ORGANIZATION> was trying to evade inheritance taxes. But the appeals court ruled Wednesday that <ORGANIZATION> Gucci </ORGANIZATION> and six others accused with him did n't commit the crime. <ORGANIZATION> Gucci </ORGANIZATION> was named company chairman in May after the lower court had handed back his 50 percent shareholding despite his conviction. He is the great-grandson of <ORGANIZATION> Guccio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gucci </ORGANIZATION>, who founded the company in 1922.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comedian <PERSON> Milton </PERSON> <PERSON> Berle </PERSON> had dental surgery at <ORGANIZATION> Cedars-Sinai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> and was in good shape, a spokesman said. <PERSON> Berle </PERSON>, 81, underwent surgery on Tuesday and remained hospitalized Wednesday, said hospital spokesman <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Wise </PERSON>. `` He felt he wanted to stay overnight,'' said Wise. <PERSON> Berle </PERSON>, known to millions as `` Mr. Television'' as the star of his own variety show during the medium's Golden Age, had quadruple bypass heart surgery in 1985.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former first lady <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had tea with Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> at the British leader's official 10 Downing St. residence. The wife of former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> promoting her book, `` My Turn.'' A spokesman for Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> said Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s 45-minute visit Wednesday was `` a private call.'' He gave no details on their conversation.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: Longer version moving on sports wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Dr. J is ready to operate again _ but this time as an owner. <PERSON> Julius </PERSON> <PERSON> Erving </PERSON>, who dazzled <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Basketball </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> fans for 16 years with his high-flying dunk shots, has notified league Commissioner <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Stern </PERSON> that if a franchise becomes available, he would like to be considered for ownership. <PERSON> Erving </PERSON> and business partner <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Llewellyn </PERSON> purchased a <ORGANIZATION> Coca-Cola </ORGANIZATION> bottling plant in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> shortly after <PERSON> Erving </PERSON> retired from the 76ers. The two have several other business interests. `` I would be interested in being part of a good situation,'' <PERSON> Erving </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> at an athletic forum Tuesday. `` My partner and I are interested in owning a basketball team, but the timing has to be right, and the deal has to be right. ... `` I never intended to coach or be the general manager or work for an owner. Not that there are bad owners in the league. But I would rather be in the position to hire rather than be hired.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891207-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-07-89 0927EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BrainGene     12-07 0545</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Brain Gene,0563</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gene for Brain Protein Found, Could Lead to Better Stroke Treatment</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MALCOLM RITTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Scientists reported today they have discovered a gene for a protein that helps govern brain cell communication, a potential step toward new treatments for stroke and severe head injury. Further work also may help explain how the brain learns and remembers, scientists said. `` This discovery is extremely important,'' commented <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, whose editorial appears with the study in the British journal Nature. The work is the first finding of a gene that tells brain cells how to make a protein called a glutamate receptor. When this receptor senses a natural substance called glutamate outside a brain cell, it makes the cell more prone to fire off messages to neighboring brain cells. In this way, the receptor acts as a fundamental regulator of brain cell communication. The newfound gene is for one type of glutamate receptor, but it can be used to find genes for the other types, said study co-author <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Heinemann </PERSON>. Finding the gene is a first step toward studying a receptor's structure and behavior. Eventually, glutamate receptor studies may lead to development of drugs that limit brain damage from strokes, head injury or repeated seizures, and to new understanding about learning and memory, the scientists said. <PERSON> Heinemann </PERSON> and colleagues at the <ORGANIZATION> Salk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Biological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> report that they isolated key portions of a rat glutamate receptor gene. The same issue of Nature carries reports of similar findings in frogs and chicks by scientists at <LOCATION> Salk </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Bethesda </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, and the <ORGANIZATION> Weizmann </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Rehovot </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. In a telephone interview, <PERSON> Heinemann </PERSON> said his group went on to isolate the entire gene. Finding the human counterparts of rat glutamate receptor genes for further research should be relatively easy, he said. He said he hopes the work will lead to finding the gene for another type of glutamate receptor, called the <ORGANIZATION> NMDA </ORGANIZATION> receptor because it binds to a man-made chemical called N-methyl-D-aspartate. The NMDA receptor plays a role in a phenomenon called excitotoxicity, in which brain cells are fatally overstimulated after a stroke, repeated epileptic seizures or a severe blow to the head, <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> said. By analyzing and experimenting with the NMDA receptor, researchers may be able to develop drugs that block the process and so limit brain damage, he said. The NMDA receptor also triggers a process called long-term potentiation, a strengthening of communication links between certain brain cells that is thought to underlie some forms of memory and learning. So studying the receptor may illuminate brain function in those tasks, <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> said. Such studies might one day lead to treatments for people with learning or memory disorders, <PERSON> Heinemann </PERSON> speculated. Scientists have been unable to study details of the <ORGANIZATION> NMDA </ORGANIZATION> receptor because, until now, they had not found any glutamate receptor gene to guide the search for the NMDA receptor gene, <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> said. The new work `` gives us the right gene family, we think,'' he said. <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Cotman </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Irvine </LOCATION>, cautioned that the study does not guarantee discovery of a gene for the <ORGANIZATION> NMDA </ORGANIZATION> receptor, although it probably increases the chances.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891207-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-07-89 0354EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-EasternEurope     12-07 0891</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Eastern Europe,0922</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nationalism, Ethnic Tensions and Racism Released by Reforms</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-East Germany, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE JAHN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VIENNA, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sometimes overlooked in the excitement of the political upheaval in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> is an increase in nationalism and racism along with the new climate of freedom. In the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, there are signs of nationalism and anti-Semitism that suggest the four decades of Communist rule suppressed traditional hatreds instead of eradicating them. Since <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> allowed more openess and lifted iron controls on dissent, ethnic and racial hatreds have resurfaced in Moslem Central <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> and in the <LOCATION> Caucasus </LOCATION> republics of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Ethnic violence there has killed more than 300 people. <LOCATION> Azerbaijan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION> are in conflict over the <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION> region and the Baltic republics are gripped by growing nationalist sentiment. Writing in the current issue of Foreign Affairs, <PERSON> Zbigniew </PERSON> <PERSON> Brzezinski </PERSON> says that although communism `` proclaimed itself to be a doctrine of internationalism, communism in fact intensified popular nationalist passions.'' The former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> national security adviser noted that while <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> are the most ethnically cohesive countries in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> are diverse societies and both <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION> have substantial national minorities. `` Moreover, all these states have borders that are potentially subject to revisionist aspirations on the part of their neighbors,'' he wrote. In the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, activity by <PERSON> Pamyat </PERSON>, a nationalist Russian society, also has picked up in this new era. Pamyat, with its extremist, xenophobic outlook, is operating openly in a number of major <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> cities. In <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>, Soviet artist <PERSON> Tanya </PERSON> <PERSON> Loskutova </PERSON> said in a recent interview that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s campaign of openness had succeeded in unearthing hatreds that had lurked under the surface for decades. `` Anti-Semitism has become much more obvious, because there is now a great opportunity to spit out the dirt that people had inside,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Loskutova </PERSON>, a Jew who emigrated in October and hopes to settle in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The sudden removal of constraints on freedom of expression has permitted organizations like Pamyat to step up anti-Jewish campaigns. In <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> too, overt anti-Semitism appears to be more pronounced since the country initiated reforms about two years ago that are meant to transform it into a full democracy. But representatives of <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s Jewish community of 60,000 seem to feel the racist sentiment _ expressed through the desecration of synagogues and in anti-Semitic outbursts at soccer matches _ is not on the rise. They say it's just becoming more visible. `` Anti-Semitism has been with us all these four decades, but it was forbidden to discuss it openly,'' Chief <PERSON> Rabbvi </PERSON> <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Schoener </PERSON> said in an interview. More worrying to Jews is that political reforms have been accompanied by the kind of growing nationalism that in the past has been linked to the persecution of Jews. The popularity of the Hungarian Democratic Forum, a main opposition party that has gained support by exploiting tensions with <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> over <LOCATION> Transylvania </LOCATION> and the fate of ethnic Hungarians in the Romanian territory, is therefore a cause of worry for some Jews. <PERSON> Gyoergy </PERSON> <PERSON> Konrad </PERSON>, a writer of Jewish origin, likes to relate how his mother once told him: `` My boy, be careful, because once they start talking about <LOCATION> Transylvania </LOCATION>, they'll be deporting Jews soon.'' Government figures and the Hungarian media have also raised nationalist themes in an attempt to gain popularity. The result is embarassing some members of Hungarian minority groups living in neighboring countries. `` The media in <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION> are hurting us here with false reports of a mass autonomy movement in <LOCATION> Slovakia </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Andras </PERSON> <PERSON> Szemere </PERSON>, a member of <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>'s 500,000-strong Hungarian minority told a Western visitor to <LOCATION> Bratislava </LOCATION> recently. `` Sure, we have our problems _ all minorities do everywhere _ but right now we're more interested in working with the Czechs and Slovaks and getting rid of the Communists.'' In <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, there have been scattered incidents of anti-Semitism preceding elections that gave the country its first government in four decades not dominated by the Communists. People scribbled the word `` Jew'' on campaign posters of Solidarity activist <PERSON> Jacek </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuron </PERSON>, who is not Jewish. There are also reports that prominent Solidarity activist and intellectural <PERSON> Bronislaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Geremek </PERSON> was passed over for the Polish premiership because he is Jewish. In <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, where decades of isolation have fallen away with the opening of the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall, fears focus on the importation of racist sentiments. At a meeting with Jewish community leaders Nov. 27, East German security officials contended that leaflets distributed by <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s ultra-rightist <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> have appeared with increasing frequence in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> since border controls were loosened Nov. 9. `` Since the opening of the borders to the West, a rise in activities of neo-Nazi groups in the direction of <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> can be noticed,'' the official <ORGANIZATION> ADN </ORGANIZATION> news agency said in a report on the meeting. Even <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>, the last bastion of Stalinism in the Soviet bloc, is exploiting some of the unsolved ethnic problems. In an apparent attempt to deflect attention from his own country's economic and human rights record, President <PERSON> Nicolae </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> recently suggested the return of the former <LOCATION> Bessarabia </LOCATION>, now <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Moldavia </LOCATION>, which <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> lost during World War II.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Jahn </PERSON> has covered <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> European </LOCATION> affairs for the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> since 1982 and is now stationed in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891207-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-07-89 0355EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     12-07 0856</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>World Beef Trade Undergoing Changes</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The world's beef trade is undergoing rapid changes as production declines in 1989 and production falters in some major countries. One result, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday, is that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is edging ahead of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> as a world-class beef exporter. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> exports are estimated at 450,000 metric tons, up from 313,000 tons in 1988, the department's <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> reported. Exports are expected to rise to about 508,000 tons in 1990. Most of the increase is the result of larger sales to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> under last year's trade liberalization by <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> to open the door to more beef and citrus. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>'s total beef and veal exports, meanwhile, are estimated at 439,000 tons in 1989 and 368,000 tons in 1990. Production rose this year as drought forced more cattle to slaughter. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> imports of beef, which reached 1.1 million tons in 1988, are expected to decline this year to around 990,000 tons, the report said. The decrease is the result of smaller shipments from <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, where production is down and more meat was diverted to the lucrative Japanese market. The report said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> beef imports in 1990 are likely to decline slightly, to around 970,000 tons, as <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> continues exporting to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. `` <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> beef exports grew at a faster rate than those of the other five countries during the 1980s, rising from sixth to fourth position by 1988,'' the report said. `` In 1989, it is expected that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will surpass <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> to become the third largest beef exporter in the world.'' The top six beef exporters in 1989 are: <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, 823,000 tons; the 12-nation <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION>, 759,000; <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, 450,000; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>, 439,000; <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, 370,000; and <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, 350,000. Overall, global beef and veal production is expected to decline this year to about 45.2 million metric tons from 45.3 million tons in 1988, the report said. Much of the decease occurred in the <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>. The situation in the major beef producing countries is watched closely by <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> trade analysts and livestock producers, particularly conditions in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>. Cattle herds are expected to increase in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> to about 25.3 million head by 1991 from 24.3 million at the beginning of 1989, the report said. `` Dampening a more rapid increase in the herd size is an attractive wool market and expansion in the sheep industry,'' the report said. `` Without this competition for resources, total cattle numbers could increase more rapidly.'' In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>, drought forced cattle slaughter to about 3.3 million head this year from 3.1 million in 1988. But slaughter may decline to around 2.8 million head in 1990, the report said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says it will soon pay wheat and barley producers about $ 175 million in `` deficiency'' payments for participating in the government's 1989 acreage program. <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Bjerke </PERSON>, executive vice president of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Commodity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Credit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, said Wednesday that the payments to wheat and barley farmers will be made in cash through local offices of the <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stabilization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> Wheat payments will total about $ 168 million and barley $ 7 million. No payments will be made for 1989 oats. The payments will include a deduction for advance payments earlier this year. Deficiency payments are made to help make up the difference between a target price and the higher of the price support loan rate or a five-month market price average. For example, the target price for wheat this year is $ 4.10 per bushel and the basic loan rate is $ 2.57 per bushel. The market price average for five months was $ 3.78 per bushel. Thus, the deficiency payment rate would be 32 cents per bushel, the difference between the target and the market price. An advance of 25 cents per bushel was made, so farmers will get 7 cents per bushel at final settlement.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A reduction in the use of wheat as animal feed is partly responsible for a sharp jump in global corn trade, says the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. In the last four years, world corn shipments have increased an estimated 28 percent, the largest increase since the late 1970s, the department's <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday in a report. `` There has been some worldwide step-up in animal feeding, particularly in the -LRB- <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> -RRB- and major East Asian markets,'' the report said. `` But, in the last two years, an additional reason for the sharp expansion ... is the reduced use of wheat for feed, caused by relatively low global wheat supplies.'' As a result, wheat has become more expensive in relation to the livestock feeding value of corn. Further, the report said, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> corn exports have nearly doubled in the last few years, while exports of other foreign suppliers have dropped by one-third, due to `` shifts to more profitable crops like oilseeds, increased domestic utilization'' and poor crops. `` The net result is that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> now provides nearly 80 percent of the world's corn export needs, up dramatically from just a few years ago,'' the report said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891207-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-07-89 0416EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Coleman     12-07 0399</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Coleman,0413</SECOND>
<HEAD>Actor Says Mother's Attempt to Control His Estate is Vindictive</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> called his mother's attempt to wrest control of his estate vindictive, and his lawyer said allegations in her court request may damage the actor's career. <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>, 21, and attorney <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Wake </PERSON> responded Wednesday to <PERSON> Edmonia </PERSON> <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>'s statements in court documents asserting her son was incapable of handling his $ 6 million fortune. `` My mother's latest legal action obviously stems from her frustration at not being able to control my life,'' said <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>, star of the old `` Diff ` rent Strokes'' TV Mrs. <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>'s conservatorship petition, filed Monday, said his deteriorating physical and mental condition puts him at `` significant risk of financial exploitation.'' `` The allegations upon which <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>'s petition is based are simply not true,'' said Wake. `` This sort of tactic will only backfire because it will expose <PERSON> Gary </PERSON>'s parents to additional liability for malicious prosecution. `` The potential damage to <PERSON> Gary </PERSON>'s career is enormous, and this sort of accusation can be extremely harmful even though it has no foundation whatsoever.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> asked that a conservator be appointed for her son and that <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> be placed in control of assets that include $ 6 million in property and annual income of $ 750,000. A <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> hearing on the request was scheduled for Jan. 3. It was latest action in the continuing legal wrangle between <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> and his parents. In February, <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> filed suit in <PERSON> Santa </PERSON> <PERSON> Monica </PERSON> against his parents and former business adviser <PERSON> Anita </PERSON> <PERSON> DeThomas </PERSON>, alleging they improperly profited from his financial success. The lawsuit alleges the Colemans and <PERSON> DeThomas </PERSON> diverted his profits and assets to themselves. <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> said in his suit that he felt his parents were unduly influenced by <PERSON> DeThomas </PERSON>. `` I was very hurt by the vindictive response it caused,'' <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> said Wednesday. <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> was born with an atrophied right kidney and has undergone two transplants during a childhood that required frequent dialysis and medications, the court documents said. Mrs. <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> said she was concerned about her son's business manager, <PERSON> Dion </PERSON> <PERSON> Mial </PERSON>, whom she described as a 25-year-old unemployed <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> impersonator. <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> was 10 when `` Diff ` rent Strokes'' made it debut in November 1978 and his character <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, opposite co-star <PERSON> Todd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bridges </PERSON>, became a hit with young His twinkling eyes, pudgy cheeks and flawless timing helped make the TV situation comedy a ratings winner.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891207-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-07-89 0113EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Shooting-Chronology     12-07 0365</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Shooting-Chronology,0380</SECOND>
<HEAD>How Canada's Worst Mass Murder Unfolded</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Canada-Shooting</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MONTREAL (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The first call from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Montreal </ORGANIZATION> came into the city's emergency 911 phone line in late afternoon. `` There is a hostage-taking, there is gunfire and there are lots of people wounded,'' police quoted the caller as saying. It was the beginning of what may be the worst mass shooting in Canadian history. When it was over, 14 women had been killed, the gunman had committed suicide, and a dozen other people had been rushed to hospital operating rooms. Based on police and eyewitness accounts, the drama began as students were ending their last classes of the term. About 4:30 p.m., a man thought to be in his twenties and dressed in hunting garb entered the cafeteria on the first floor of the university's engineering building and opened fire with what police believe was a .22 - caliber rifle, killing three The gunman then went up to the second floor and walked into a packed classroom, where he ordered the men into one corner of the room and the women into another. Several of the students, who had been making oral presentations on the final day of classes before exams, said later they thought it was a joke. But the gunman fired a shot into the wall, and they quickly followed his instructions. He told the men to leave. They did so, and police said the gunman screamed before opening fire on the women: `` You're all a bunch of feminists.'' Six slain women were later found in the classroom. On the same floor, he killed a woman in an administration office. Then he climbed to the third floor, where he shot four more women in the corridor. `` It was a human hunt and we were the quarry,'' said one witness quoted by Canadian Press. `` He was clearly gunning for the women,'' said another student. He continued up to the fourth and fifth floors, shooting and wounding both men and women. Then, police say, he returned to the third floor and turned the gun on himself. One police officer who was called to the scene discovered his daughter was among the dead.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891207-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-07-89 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i Bc-Japan-Stocks     12-07 0026</FIRST>
<SECOND>Bc-Japan-Stocks,0026</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Up In Tokyo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 37,858.11, up 203.82 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Thursday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891207-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-07-89 0936EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MillionaireBenefactor     12-07 0650</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Millionaire Benefactor,0670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Benefactor `Out of Money,' But Appeals for Help Still Roll in</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto AD1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY HARKAVY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PORTLAND, Maine (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> wants the world know he's broke. But appeals for money, like the one containing pieces of the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall, keep streaming in. The package was delivered even though it was addressed to `` The Millionaire <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON>'' in `` <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> <LOCATION> U.S.A. </LOCATION>'' It came from a young <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> woman who had read news reports about the 32-year-old benefactor's efforts to help residents in his adopted city of <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION> start their own businesses. `` As a sign that a new time begins, I send you a little part of the original <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall _ a sign that people should come together and help each other in peace, love and harmony,'' the woman wrote in asking <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> to finance her health-related studies. Appeals have poured in by the thousands, said <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON>. He says his life has changed dramatically in the six weeks since he placed a classified ad in local newspapers offering to bankroll first-time entrepreneurs and provide them with office space and business advice. Enthusiasm and hard work were the traits the community college dropout from a blue-collar <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> suburb sought in examining the flood of applicants before selecting 15 beneficiaries of his interest-free loans. `` These were people who did n't need a push,'' he said. `` They had the enthusiasm. They just needed the guidance.'' After writing checks totaling more than $ 220,000 and wondering aloud how he will pay his next mortgage payment on the apartment house where he lives and works, <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> has a standard reply to the unending pleas: `` I'm broke. I'm out of money.'' Undaunted, applicants often ask <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> to put their names on a waiting list for any future largesse. <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> acknowledged that, though he may be strapped for cash, he probably remains a millionaire on paper. That's because of the appreciation in value of real estate he accumulated in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> as his career as a computer salesman blossomed. He resigned his lucrative sales job last spring out of boredom and invested in a computer company in <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>. He then looked at job possibilities in the area, found nothing of interest, and decided to use his business talents to help others. <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> insists he was `` just an average guy'' before his newspaper ad made him an international celebrity and propelled him into 16-hour workdays. Recipients of <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON>'s seed money include several welfare recipients, a recently discharged serviceman and an ex-convict trying to earn a living as an artist. The start-up money has ranged from as little as $ 200 for supplies and equipment to help a young woman begin a cleaning business to $ 100,000 to publish the comic book artist's work. Form months, 23-year-old <PERSON> Bonnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> wanted to open the cleaning business to get off welfare, but could n't afford a vacuum cleaner or other supplies. So she answered <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON>'s ad and he helped her buy the equipment. But she admits to being leery after first reading the ad: `` I thought maybe it was a guy who wanted to kidnap people and sell children, so I made sure not to bring my daughter.'' <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON>, who embarked on the project three months after his arrival in <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, said the role of benefactor is a weighty burden. `` A lot of people do n't realize this but it's a big responsibility when you're dealing with people's dreams,'' he said. `` They're looking up to you as an answer. It's frightening.'' <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Branscomb </PERSON>, associate director of the <ORGANIZATION> Small </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maine </ORGANIZATION>, said people applying to <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> should be cautious because they are vulnerable when they start a business, even if it is with someone else's money. `` They could put in the time and effort and blood, sweat and tears and lose the whole kit and caboodle,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891207-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-07-89 0245EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WhiteHouseTree     12-07 0359</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-White House Tree,360</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pennsylvania-grown Fir Arrives at White House</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The first family's Christmas tree, a Pennsylvania-grown Fraser Fir, is at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, arriving in a carriage drawn by two Clydesdale horses. The 18-foot tree will sit in the <LOCATION> Blue </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Room </LOCATION>, decorated with `` soft sculptures depicting well-known characters from literature,'' <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Becker </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the first lady, said Wednesday. The tree's theme is family literacy, <PERSON> Becker </PERSON> said, adding that it will be decorated by Monday. With first lady <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> looking on, the tree was hauled from the White House gate to the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Portico </LOCATION> in a wreath-adorned carriage pulled by Clydesdales. Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> stroked the tree admiringly, but the horses made <PERSON> Millie </PERSON>, the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> family dog, nervous. `` Stay right where you are,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said in a commanding tone to the horses as <PERSON> Millie </PERSON> cowered nearby. Finally, the first lady scooped up <PERSON> Millie </PERSON> in her arms as photographers frantically maneuvered to get the shot. `` It's just because she's never seen a horse before,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` Millie can not steal this show, please.'' Growers <PERSON> Duane </PERSON>, <PERSON> Meade </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> <PERSON> Berkey </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Spartansburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, won a contest sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christmas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tree </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> for the right to have one of their trees displayed at the nation's most prominent residence A White House delegation traveled to the family's 140-acre farm, selecting a 21-foot tree sturdy enough to support 100 dolls. The tree will be cut down to 18 feet. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> <PERSON> Berkey </PERSON> brought his two children, <PERSON> Melissa </PERSON>, 4, and <PERSON> Jaime </PERSON>, 6, to Wednesday's ceremony, and they were invited to sit in the carriage as it rolled past reporters and guests. The growers wondered how the tree would fit through the White House door. `` Miracles happen every year here. Do n't worry, it'll get in,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. The White House tree is different from the National Christmas Tree, a 35-foot blue spruce, also from <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, transplanted here in 1977 to be the centerpiece of an annual holiday pageant. That tree, which sits on the grassy Ellipse south of the <LOCATION> White </LOCATION> <LOCATION> House </LOCATION>, will be lighted at a Dec. 14 ceremony.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891207-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-07-89 0936EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Frank     12-07 0325</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Frank,320</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prostitute Testifies in Barney Frank Ethics Case</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DIAMOND</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A male prostitute who testified before the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee on his relationship with Rep. <PERSON> Barney </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> remains under subpoena and may be called back for additional testimony, the panel's chairman says. <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON>, who claims to have run a male prostitution ring out of <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> apartment, testified for four hours Wednesday at a closed meeting of the ethics committee. In past comments, <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON> had suggested that he had information embarrassing to other members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> besides <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, D-Mass. But after the hearing, the ethics panel's chairman, Rep. <PERSON> Julian </PERSON> <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, D-Calif., said <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON>'s testimony did not expand the scope of the investigation <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> said <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON> may be called back for additional testimony, but that the investigation `` is n't any broader'' as a result of the information he provided Wednesday. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> has said he had a brief sexual relationship with <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON> after meeting him and paying him $ 80 for sex in 1985. He said he later hired <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON> with personal funds to serve as a housekeeper and driver from July 1985 through August 1987. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> has acknowledged that he intervened with <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> probation authorities on <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON>'s behalf. But he denies other allegations by <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON>, including that he knew <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON> was running a prostitution ring from his apartment, and that <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON> evidently took advantage of him. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> had acknowledged his homosexuality before <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON>'s allegations were made Leaving the session, <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON> said he was not out to destroy <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s reputation and career. `` I think he's a very fine person. I always have and I always will. I think he's one of the best people up on the hill,'' <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> has not yet testified to the committee. Neither <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> nor his attorney, <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Sachs </PERSON>, attended Wednesday's session. <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> said the committee will continue its investigation through the current congressional recess, which is scheduled to end Jan. 23.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891207-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-07-89 0417EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Cuba-Dead     12-07 0400</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cuba-Dead,380</SECOND>
<HEAD>Castro to Honor Cuban Casualties in Foreign Lands</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, ending a prolonged silence, says 2,016 military and other <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> personnel have died in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> since President <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> began his commitment there 14 years ago. <PERSON> Angel </PERSON> <PERSON> Pino </PERSON>, a spokesman for the Cuban diplomatic mission here, gave that figure Wednesday in announcing that the remains of all Cubans who died carrying out international missions in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> and elsewhere have been returned to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> in recent days. The Cuban casualty toll had never before been discussed officially. The dead were being honored at a ceremony today outside <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION> at which <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> was due to participate along with Angolan President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Eduardo </PERSON> <PERSON> dos </PERSON> <PERSON> Santos </PERSON> and Ethiopian Vice President <PERSON> Fisseha </PERSON> <PERSON> Desta </PERSON>. <PERSON> Pino </PERSON> said 2,289 Cubans, including troops and civilian technical advisers, have died abroad over the years. More than 400,000 have participated in such missions, mostly in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Pino </PERSON> said 160 Cubans died in <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>, where thousands of Cuban troops were sent in 1977, two years after <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>'s involvement in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> began. The number of Cuban dead in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> has been the subject of considerable speculation over the years, but <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> has always regarded the figure as a state secret. Three years ago, Angolan anti-communist rebel leader <PERSON> Jonas </PERSON> <PERSON> Savimbi </PERSON>, whose forces have been fighting the Cuban-backed government for years, put the Cuban death toll at more than 6,000. Of the 2,289 casualties, <PERSON> Pino </PERSON> said 863 were killed in combat, 595 died of illness and 829 were accident fatalities. The remains of 36 Cubans could not be recovered; several others disappeared. The remains were returned to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> between Nov. 27 and Dec. 4 and have been sent to their hometowns. Over the years, some families have complained that the remains of relatives who died while serving the revolution abroad had not been brought back to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> for burial. At its peak, <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> involvement in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> reached 50,000 personnel but <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> agreed last December to withdraw all its forces by early 1991 as part of an accord brokered by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Assistant Secretary of State <PERSON> Chester </PERSON> <PERSON> Crocker </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>'s troop commitment to <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> declined over the years, ending several months ago. <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> also has been involved in internationalist missions of either a civilian or military nature in a number of other countries, including <LOCATION> Equatorial </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Guinea </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION>, and in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> as well.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891207-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-07-89 0231EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Scotus-RighttoDie     12-07 0586</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus-Right to Die,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Supreme Court Considers `Right to Die' Issue</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY MASSEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Cruzan </PERSON> has watched with anguish for nearly seven years as his daughter lies unconscious in a <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> hospital and he says listening to the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> consider her fate was yet another sad event. It `` certainly was a very painful thing to sit through,'' <PERSON> Cruzan </PERSON> said after the the justices heard arguments on whether his daughter's feeding tube should be removed. `` I would like to be able to express my feelings to them why we are very comfortable with our decision, why we feel that we are doing what <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> would want us to do,'' he said. <PERSON> Cruzan </PERSON>, a 55-year-old sheet metal worker from southwestern <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, and his wife, want the nation's highest court to grant their request for removal of a feeding tube sustaining their brain-damaged daughter, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON>. On Wednesday, justices for the first time took up the `` right-to-die'' issue as they heard oral arguments by attorneys in the case of the 32-year-old woman, who has been in what doctors call a persistent vegetative state since a 1983 automobile accident. The <ORGANIZATION> Missouri </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> has ruled that doctors can not remove the tube that supplies food and water keeping Ms. <PERSON> Cruzan </PERSON> alive. The family's attorney, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Colby </PERSON>, told the justices that if Ms. <PERSON> Cruzan </PERSON> were `` lucid for a moment and could come before this court,'' she would `` choose liberty'' and ask for removal of the feeding tube. But she will never recover to do that, he said. Assistant Attorney General <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Presson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> maintained that Ms. <PERSON> Cruzan </PERSON>'s parents have no right to permit their daughter's death, especially without `` clear and convincing evidence'' she would choose to die Letting her die `` goes against the state's interest in preventing suicide,'' he said. Solicitor General <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Starr </PERSON>, the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's top courtroom lawyer, supported the state's position. A ruling by the court is expected by July. The justices recently have been reluctant to expand individual rights, but they gave no clear sign on the outcome of the case as they questioned the lawyers during arguments. <PERSON> Colby </PERSON> said after the case that he did n't expect the court to issue a broad ruling on the the right-to-die question. An estimated 10,000 people in this country are being kept alive in a manner similar to that used for Ms. <PERSON> Cruzan </PERSON>. Legal and medical officials say the court's ruling could set a precedent in determining the limits of life-sustaining care. Doctors say Ms. <PERSON> Cruzan </PERSON> could live for 30 years or more in her current condition unless the feeding tube is removed. Her body is rigid, her hands and feet constricted and bent into claw shapes. She can breathe on her own and at times her eyes are open and move randomly. <PERSON> Cruzan </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON>, an older daughter and two grandchildren watched the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> proceedings. Afterward, he expressed concerns about the possible effects on other families if the high court denies his daughter a right to die. He contended it would force people to consider initially not ordering life-sustaining treatment for fear that it could not later be stopped. `` This puts families in a terrible situation of being faced with making a decision about life support when there is still hope, when it still might do some good,'' he said. Asked how he thought the oral arguments played out to the justices, <PERSON> Cruzan </PERSON> replied, `` I have no idea. I'm not an attorney. I'm just a spectator.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891207-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-07-89 0252EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DrugVerdict     12-07 0555</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drug Verdict,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Appeal Planned in Big D.C. Drug Case</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD KEIL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Lawyers for a man convicted of operating a drug ring that took in $ 2 million a week in the nation's capital say they will appeal the verdict, while <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stephens </PERSON> says the convicted dealer will now face other charges. <PERSON> Rayful </PERSON> <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, 24, was convicted Wednesday of operating a cocaine distribution network that prosecutors said was responsible for up to 30 percent of the cocaine sold in the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>. A 12-member <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> jury found <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON> guilty of all seven charges against him after more than four days of deliberations, capping a 12-week trial held amid extremely tight security. The verdict means <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON> faces a mandatory life prison sentence. Ten other defendants were convicted of assisting him. `` Everyone on the defense team is upset by the verdict,'' said <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, one of <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON>'s attorneys. `` We had the cards stacked against us from the beginning ... and we are going to appeal.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Court Judge <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Richey </PERSON> has not yet set a sentencing date for <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON> or his associates. <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON> faces additional charges, including three counts of first-degree murder and conspiracy. <PERSON> Stephens </PERSON> said he plans to try <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON> on those charges, despite the mandatory life sentence in the drug distribution case. `` Our immediate plan is to proceed,'' <PERSON> Stephens </PERSON> said. `` The primary goal ... is to bring this organization to a halt.'' Prosecutors had described <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON>'s drug network as a blend of family members and close friends who conducted their operations with a sophisticated _ and deadly _ entrepreneurial flare. The charges against <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON> included conspiracy to violate drug laws, employing minors to possess and distribute cocaine, traveling across state lines to sell drugs and using a telephone to set up illegal drug deals. Convictions on those counts satisfy a definition of a continuing criminal enterprise, a crime that carries a mandatory life sentence. <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON>'s 10 co-defendants, including an aunt, a sister, a brother and several close friends, were found guilty of conspiracy to deal drugs. That crime carries a penalty of 10 years to life in prison. At its peak last summer, the prosecutors charged, the Edmond network was pumping up to 440 pounds of cocaine per week into the streets of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` The message should be clear _ if you deal death and destruction, you will pay with your life,'' <PERSON> Stephens </PERSON> said. After noting that <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON> had been perceived by some friends and neighbors as a hero for his ability to make money, the prosecutor said <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON> should be seen instead as a `` purveyor of human destruction.'' The trial featured extremely strict security measures. At the outset, <PERSON> Richey </PERSON> ruled that jurors' names be kept secret even from himself and lawyers to protect the jury from reprisals. The home of one witness' mother was firebombed during the trial and an informant was shot after his name was accidentally divulged by the prosecution. Defense lawyer <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> suggested that the unusual security provisions _ including a 1 -LCB- - inch bullet-proof shield around the courtroom _ made it impossible for the defendants to receive a fair trial `` No matter what happened in that courtroom, it was going to make it very difficult to give Mr. <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON> the benefit of the doubt,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891207-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-07-89 0204EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-Poll-Communism Bjt   12-07 0694</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poll-Communism, Bjt,0710</SECOND>
<HEAD>Poll: More Americans See Communism on the Wane</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GARY LANGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Half of all Americans believe communism is dying, twice the number who thought so nine months ago, a <ORGANIZATION> Media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General-Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> poll has found. The survey found views of communism shifting radically as reform sweeps <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, with far fewer Americans now seeing the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and its <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pact </ORGANIZATION> allies as a threat. But more Americans feel threatened by <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, where authorities in June suppressed pro-democracy demonstrators. And the poll found no change in the relatively high level of concern about communism in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. The survey tracked opinion by repeating questions that first were asked in a Media General-Associated Press poll in March, a few months before the <ORGANIZATION> democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> reform </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> movement </ORGANIZATION> gained full force in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. The change in opinion was striking. Then, for example, only 19 percent said communism was on the decline around the world. In the new poll, 54 percent said communism was declining worldwide _ a nearly threefold increase. Similarly, 52 percent regarded communism in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> as less of a threat to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> security now than in the past; in March, just 28 percent held that view. And 51 percent in the new poll saw Soviet communism as less of a threat to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, up from 38 percent nine months ago. In one of their broadest measures, the surveys asked respondents: `` In your view, is communism dying, or not?'' In March, 25 percent said yes. In the new poll, 52 percent said yes. The new survey was conducted Nov. 17-25, as many of the changes reshaping <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> were still evolving. The changes, some of which culminated after the poll was done, include establishment of a partially non-communist government in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and the fall of Communist leaderships in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>. Optimism was the greatest for <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, where on Nov. 9 the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wall </LOCATION> was opened after 28 years of division from the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>. Sixty percent in the survey expected that within their lifetimes East Germans will enjoy the same freedoms Americans have now. By contrast, only 26 percent expected American-style freedoms to come within their lifetimes to residents of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, where reforms are progressing more slowly and the Communist party retains supremacy. And only 14 percent expected such freedoms in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, where soldiers staged a bloody crackdown on dissidents near <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> on June 3-4. Indeed, during the past nine months more Americans have come to see <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> as an increasing threat to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, while those seeing <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> as less of a threat fell from 34 percent in March to 20 percent now. While fewer Americans now believe <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> is moving away from communist political and economic systems, the opposite was true for <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and for the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Seventy-five percent believed some of the Eastern European countries are moving away from communist economies, up from 47 percent in March. And 70 percent believed some of <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> was dropping the communist system, more than double the number in March. The movement of opinion about the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, like the change there, was less abrupt. Sixty-seven percent believed the Soviets are leaving their communist economic system, up from 58 percent; and 48 percent believed the Soviets are changing their political structure, up from 31 percent. As in the earlier poll, concern was greatest about communism in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>: Forty-six percent called it an increasing threat to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, virtually unchanged from March. Men and more highly educated respondents in the new poll were likeliest to believe that communism is declining or even dying, and that the threat to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> posed by the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> is decreasing. The survey, conducted by telephone, had a margin of sampling error of plus or minus 3 percentage points. <ORGANIZATION> Media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a communications company based in <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, publishes the Richmond Times-Dispatch, the Richmond News Leader, the <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> Winston-Salem </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- Journal, and operates TV stations <ORGANIZATION> WXFL </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION>, WCBD in <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> WJKS </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891207-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-07-89 0215EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Japan-Markets     12-07 0343</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Markets,0353</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dollar Rises, Stocks Hit Another New High</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The dollar rose against the Japanese yen in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> Thursday, while the key index on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> set another new high. The dollar closed at 144.13 yen, up 0.38 yen from Wednesday's close of 143.75 yen After opening at 143.95 yen, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> currency ranged between 143.94 and 144.33 yen. On the stock market, the <ORGANIZATION> Nikkei </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Average </ORGANIZATION> of 225 selected issues, which rose 160.12 points for a record closing of 37,654.29 Wednesday, added another 203.82 points, or 0.54 percent, to close at 37,858.11, another new high. Currency dealers said the dollar's bullish opening in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> was largely due to the currency's gains on overseas markets overnight. The dollar-buying was triggered by warnings issued by the East German military that it would not tolerate attempts by citizens to seize munitions from security installations, according to dealers. A fleeting fear that the military might take action to block the country's reform movement led some to sell the West German currency for dollars, they said. The dollar's decline against the mark in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> was accelerated overnight by comments from <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Undersecretary of the Treasury <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulford </PERSON>, who said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was `` not alarmed'' about the dollar's recent steep 10 percent decline against the mark. He also noted the dollar has only slipped 2 percent against the yen. The <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> market took <PERSON> Mulford </PERSON>'s comments to mean that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> central bank has not been intervening to shore up the sagging dollar, as many had thought. Securities dealers said the Nikkei index rose as market players were reassured by an <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Planning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> announcement of 2.9 percent growth in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s real gross national product in the July-September quarter over the previous quarter. The rise in inflation-adjusted GNP was equivalent to an annual 12.2 percent growth, the largest since 1973, according to the agency. `` Trading is becoming more active and broader,'' said a dealer at <ORGANIZATION> Nikko </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, requesting anonymity. `` I expect the bullish trend to continue for some time.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891207-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-07-89 0321EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BusCrashTrial     12-07 0561</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bus Crash Trial,0581</SECOND>
<HEAD>Anguished Father Speaks of Losing His Family in Bus Crash</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Testimony to resume at 11 a.m. EST</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROB WELLS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CARROLLTON, Ky. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
