<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891226-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-26-89 2346EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-LiverTransplants     12-26 0303</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Liver Transplants,0312</SECOND>
<HEAD>Living Donor Recipient Has Follow-up Operation</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nation's second recipient of a liver from a living donor underwent another operation Tuesday to remove a pocket of infection from her abdomen, officials at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospitals </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Sarina </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, a 16-month-old liver defect victim from <LOCATION> Millington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, received part of a liver Dec. 8 from her father, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, a dry-wall installer. Hospital spokeswoman <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> said Dr. <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Emond </PERSON>, a member of the original transplant team, decided the best way to deal with the small abcess was to reopen the operation incision to drain and clear the area of infection. `` She tolerated the procedure very well, and was out of the operating room in about two hours,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, adding the infection had not been life-threatening. The spokeswoman said <PERSON> Sarina </PERSON> was listed in critical but stable condition after the two-hour operation, and was expected to be transferred out of the intensive care ward within several days. Also Tuesday, <PERSON> Alyssa </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, who preceded <PERSON> Sarina </PERSON> as the nation's first living-donor liver transplant recipient, had her condition upgraded to serious `` She continues to progress well,'' Ms. <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Alyssa </PERSON> was given a `` day pass'' from the hospital to visit with her parents on Christmas Day at a <ORGANIZATION> Ronald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> McDonald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> for relatives of ailing children. <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, 29, an elementary school teacher who donated part of her liver to her daughter for the Nov. 27 transplant, was released from the hospital two weeks ago. The Smiths are from <LOCATION> Schertz </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Alyssa </PERSON> is expected to leave the hospital sometime after the first of the year if all continues to go well, according to Ms. <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>. <PERSON> Sarina </PERSON> and <PERSON> Alyssa </PERSON> suffer from biliary atresia, a usually fatal congenital defect which is the leading cause of liver transplants in children.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891226-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-26-89 0001EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--Smoking-Death     12-26 0092</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Smoking-Death,0094</SECOND>
<HEAD>Emphysema Victim Dies After Igniting Fire While Smoking</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOLEDO, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An emphysema victim died after igniting a fire after he tried to light a cigarette while taking oxygen through his nose, firefighters said. <PERSON> Clare </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON>, 59, of <LOCATION> Toledo </LOCATION>, had been warned not to smoke in bed in his private room at the <ORGANIZATION> Monclova </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Care </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, fire investigators said. Early Monday's fire was limited to <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON>'s bed area, but 15 other residents were moved as a precaution to the dining area for a couple of hours, authorities said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891226-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-26-89 0000EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-EastBloc-Christmas Bjt   12-25 0793</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-East Bloc-Christmas, Bjt,0813</SECOND>
<HEAD>Christians Jam Churches Around East Europe, Remember Romania</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NESHA STARCEVIC</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>EAST BERLIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Millions of Christians jammed churches in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> to celebrate their first Christmas in freedom after four decades of Communist rule, but their thoughts also went to the brave Romanian people. In <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> and even in battle-ravaged <LOCATION> Bucharest </LOCATION>, the spirit of defiance that had guided Eastern Europeans to their remarkable revolutions turned into hope for a brighter future. The change was striking in <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> as people from both sides of the technically still divided city mingled freely, attending joint church services for the first time since the Berlin Wall was built 28 years ago. <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> on Sunday began allowing visa-free travel by West Germans and thousands used the opportunity to cross to <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> to join relatives for a Christmas service. `` We had very good attendance this year. Many people from <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> came. Now we really have a feeling of freedom,'' said <PERSON> Christiana </PERSON> <PERSON> Winter </PERSON>, an East Berliner who was showing West Berliners around the <ORGANIZATION> Lutheran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mary </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>. `` The church gave hope during all those years when there was no hope and now we are full of hope. `` This year it was important to speak of God's message of love so that there are no acts of revenge. The church was on the side of the weak for years and now its is important not to hate those who treated us unjustly,'' she said. The pope's midnight Mass was broadcast live for the first time by East German television. In <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION>, the cradle of <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s pro-democracy movement, pastor <PERSON> Friedrich </PERSON> <PERSON> Magerius </PERSON> began the service in <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nicholas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> by commemorating the thousands of Romanians killed and wounded in their struggle to overthrow Communist dictator <PERSON> Nicolae </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>. In <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION>, like in many other towns in East Europe, the church had sheltered dissidents during the years of oppressive Communist rule. In <LOCATION> Bucharest </LOCATION>, hundreds of faithful came to the Mitropolia Cathedral to hear the Patriarch of the <ORGANIZATION> Romanian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orthodox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Teocitist </PERSON> <PERSON> Arapas </PERSON>, and Christmas carols played on radio for the first time in more than 40 years. The patriarch thanked about 500 believers for coming to the service despite battles raging in the city between popular forces and die-hard <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> loyalists. `` We must thank <PERSON> God </PERSON>, who gave us freedom after 25 years of terror,'' the patriarch said, referring to the length of <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>'s dictatorship. `` I have been waiting 40 years for this. Now I can openly go to church,'' said <PERSON> Ion </PERSON> <PERSON> Ganescu </PERSON>, a dissident who spent 10 years in prison for his opposition to <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>. In <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, where the <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> had enjoyed much more freedom than churches in other Communist countries, many people stayed by television sets Sunday night to watch Polish-born Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> celebrate Midnight Mass at the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION>. Thousands attended the midnight service at their local parishes and crowds filled churches to capacity on Christmas Day to pray and see traditional nativity scenes, which at some churches comment on the changes in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. One, at <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION>'s St. <PERSON> Ann </PERSON>'s church, showed the Holy Infant resting upon the fallen <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall. In most of the vast <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, Christmas will be celebrated Jan. 7 according to the Russian Orthodox calendar. But in the three Baltic republics, where there are large populations of Roman Catholics and Protestants, Christmas was a holiday for the first time under Soviet rule. In <LOCATION> Vilnius </LOCATION>, the capital of <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> activist <PERSON> Antanas </PERSON> <PERSON> Terleskas </PERSON> said many people attended church as usual. But he said people were not especially happy, because `` the freedom of expressing religious beliefs is just an illusion we are permitted to toy with,'' he said. In <LOCATION> Riga </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Latvia </LOCATION>, radio and television broadcast the pope's mass and activists said church attendance was up. In <LOCATION> Tallinn </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Estonia </LOCATION>, people were able to watch the pope's mass on Finnish television, which they receive easily, and for 12 hours Estonian television broadcast Christmas carols. On Christmas Eve, millions of Czechoslovaks watched Christmas Mass on an unprecedented live television broadcast. The Mass from <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>'s 13th century Strahov Monastery was said by the Rev. <PERSON> Vaclav </PERSON> <PERSON> Maly </PERSON>, who the government had banned from the priesthood for 11 years because of his human rights activities. Millions of believers jammed into churches and Cathedrals throughout the country for midnight Mass. On Christmas Day, 90-year-old Cardinal <PERSON> Frantisek </PERSON> <PERSON> Tomasek </PERSON> said Mass at the gothic <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vitus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cathedral </ORGANIZATION> overlooking the city, delivering a sermon on the responsibility that freedom brings. In central <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>, on the site where mass pro-democracy rallies turned the tide of Czechoslovak history last month, crowds of students gathered to sing and share the holiday at the statue of <LOCATION> Bohemia </LOCATION>'s patron saint _ good King Wenceslas.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891226-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-26-89 0003EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SouthAfrica     12-26 0788</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-South Africa,0807</SECOND>
<HEAD>100 Days Into de Klerk Presidency, Optimism Seems Contagious</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID CRARY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 There's still doubt whether President F.W. <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> will personally oversee the end of apartheid, but his performance since his inauguration has raised hopes higher than ever for peaceful change. Even the white-run government's most militant opponents acknowledge a dramatic shift in mood since P.W. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> quit the presidency. They say <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON>'s conciliatory moves resulted from pressure rather than conviction, but many anti-apartheid leaders now believe _ for the first time _ that the government sincerely wants to negotiate with them. `` Exit a president named <PERSON> P.W. </PERSON>, to be replaced by one named F.W. Remarkable what a difference that one letter made,'' wrote The Weekly Mail, an anti-apartheid newspaper, in its year-end issue. `` Suddenly the logjam seemed to break. Good intentions twinkled around the country. ... For the first time, people of widely differing views agreed: there is hope in our land.'' <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Sisulu </PERSON>, a leader of the outlawed <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> freed by <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> in October, said in a remarkably optimistic Christmas message that he had reason to hope for `` relaxation of tension'' throughout <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> in the coming year. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> took over as acting president in mid-August after winning a power struggle with <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>. Even before his inauguration Sept. 20, two weeks after general elections, <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> made his mark by approving the first mass anti-government marches in decades. He marks 100 days from the inauguration on Thursday. Since his inauguration, in the words of <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION> political writer <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Fabricius </PERSON>, <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> `` has been a blur of movement, making a major announcement almost every other day, unraveling the security establishment, going some way to unbanning the <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION>, consulting a vast spectrum of political figures.'' Among those consulted was the world's best-known political prisoner: <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>. The Dec. 13 meeting at de Klerk's <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Town </LOCATION> office was seen as further proof that <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>'s release is inevitable, probably before de Klerk opens the new Parliament on Feb. 1. During <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>'s 11 years in power, the <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> was depicted as a communist-led terrorist group that had no right to enter negotiations unless it formally renounced violence. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON>, by meeting <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> and unconditionally freeing <PERSON> Sisulu </PERSON>, has begun the process of acknowledging the guerrilla movement's legitimacy The government now says it will talk with any group committed to peaceful solutions _ the demand for renunciation of violence has been dropped. Seeking to remove obstacles to negotiations, <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> has ordered the abolition of whites-only beaches, proposed repeal of the law that allows segregated local facilities, and hinted that the state of emergency imposed in 1986 will be lifted. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Selfe </PERSON>, an official of the anti-apartheid <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> _ despite a past reputation as a conservative _ has proven vastly different from previous <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leaders. `` It might even be that the man had an ideological change of heart after coming into office,'' <PERSON> Selfe </PERSON> said. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> has vowed to end discrimination and negotiate a new constitution that would extend political rights to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s 28 million blacks But he remains wedded to the concept of racial groups, and his critics believe he will balk at any steps that jeopardize the power held by the 5 million whites. `` In the process -LRB- of defending white control -RRB-, <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> is even prepared to put apartheid in jeopardy,'' said <PERSON> Fikile </PERSON> <PERSON> Bam </PERSON>, a legal aid director in Port <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON>. Wrote The Weekly Mail's editor, <PERSON> Anton </PERSON> <PERSON> Harber </PERSON>: `` By now, <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> has done enough to convince most people that he is sincere in wanting some form of change. ... However, few of these people are certain he has the strength or the vision to carry through even this limited vision.'' The country's most powerful black moderate, Zulu leader <PERSON> Mangosuthu </PERSON> <PERSON> Buthelezi </PERSON>, is less skeptical. `` There are now few who do not take the state president seriously when he talks about bringing reform,'' <PERSON> Buthelezi </PERSON> said. `` 1990 is probably the year in which the government is going to strike out in the direction of establishing justice and equality for all.'' Perhaps <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON>'s most significant move was curbing the influence of police and army commanders. He halved mandatory military service for white men from two years to one, proposed defense spending cuts, and scrapped a bureaucratic network through which security force officers controlled black townships. `` His achievement has been to go a long way to civilianizing the country again and creating a spirit of glasnost ... as a prelude to the real challenge of thrashing out a true democracy,'' wrote <PERSON> Fabricius </PERSON>, political correspondent for The Star newspaper.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891226-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-26-89 0006EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Panama-Chorrillo     12-26 0709</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Panama-Chorrillo,0730</SECOND>
<HEAD>Panamanians Accept Loss as Price for Noriega's Ouster</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS GRANT MINE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Blanco </PERSON> rummaged through the ashes that had been his home and salvaged a balpeen hammer with a charred handle and a blackened pair of pliers. The two tools and the clothes on his back are what remains of his earthly possessions. Even so, the 70-year-old retired auto mechanic says he is glad <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces invaded <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> and overthrew the dictatorship of Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. `` It hurts that I've lost everything, but what are you going to do? The gringos had to do it like they did. I only wish they would have done it long ago,'' he said. He stood on blackened sheets of corrugated zinc that had been the roof of the two-story wooden apartment building, where he lived with his wife and their granddaughter. The only remnans of the building are two masonry columns that supported the communal bathrooms. <PERSON> Blanco </PERSON> and his neighbors had the misfortune to live a block from the headquarters of the Panamanian <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s command center <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> tanks and rocket-firing helicopters destroyed the military headquarters before dawn Wednesday. The barrage sparked fires that raced through housing in the working class <LOCATION> Chorrillo </LOCATION> neighborhood, creating at least 20,000 refugees. `` No one has more right to speak than we do, the ones hurt most by the attack,'' said <PERSON> Ruben </PERSON> <PERSON> Camargo </PERSON>, 37, standing in front of his ruined home. <PERSON> Camargo </PERSON>, a goldsmith, is luckier than <PERSON> Blanco </PERSON> in that he lived with his wife and two children in a more substantial cinderblock structure. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces evacuated the area at daybreak Wednesday, hours after the assault began. <PERSON> Camargo </PERSON> said his 4-year-old daughter was traumatized by the hours of fire and bombing, and she wakes up crying during the night. `` One single person is guilty of all this. So much death because of one man, and that man's name is <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Camargo </PERSON> when asked if he resents the invaders. Of a dozen Chorrillo residents inteviewed by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, all applauded the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> action. The closest thing to criticism was voiced by taxi driver <PERSON> Bolivar </PERSON> <PERSON> Escobar </PERSON>, 32, standing in his flooded home on the ground floor of the destroyed housing block. Most of his family's possessions were wrecked or looted. He had salvaged a red cape embroidered with silver trim _ a costume that his 11-year-old daughter had worn. `` The invasion itself was correct, the form no,'' he said. `` They should have come with much more personnel to establish positions corner by corner, to prevent looting. And they could have used less shelling. A lot of people died in their sleep. Now we have to start from zero,'' he said. Hospital authorities estimated between 200 and 300 people were killed in the invasion, at least half of them civilians. Hundreds more were injured. `` It was the only way to get him -LRB- <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> -RRB- out,'' said <PERSON> Camargo </PERSON>. `` He could have quit and given us all the gift of a happy Christmas, not this bitter Christmas we're having.'' The perception of the Americans as liberators underscores the relationship the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> have enjoyed since <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> was created, through seccession from <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, by President <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON>'s gunboat diplomacy in 1903. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s currency is the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dollar and its economy has always been closely linked to the U.S.-built and jointly administered canal. The national pastime is baseball and virtually all males over 8 years old follow the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> big leagues. `` Not only are we happy with the invasion. Most people here would like <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> to be the 51st star on the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> flag,'' said a middle-aged woman. <PERSON> Camargo </PERSON>, <PERSON> Blanco </PERSON> and about 9,000 Chorrillo refugees are being sheltered and fed by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops at <ORGANIZATION> Balboa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, two miles away. They, like a dozen others interviewed in the wasteland around the Defense Forces headquarters, appealed for reconstruction aid from the U.S.-installed government of President <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> and from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Sergio </PERSON> <PERSON> Delgado </PERSON> loaded some soggy sofa cushions from his house onto his brother-in-law's pickup. `` We've suffered, but finally that corruption is ended,'' he said. `` The Panamanian people have been asking for a long time for the North Americans to intervene.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891226-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-26-89 0014EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ChristmasMiracle     12-26 0347</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Christmas Miracle,0359</SECOND>
<HEAD>Teen-ager Emerges From Coma in Time For Christmas</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SPOKANE, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Just last week, doctors thought 18-year-old <PERSON> Melissa </PERSON> `` Missy'' <PERSON> Goebel </PERSON> would remain in a coma for years. On Christmas Day, the <ORGANIZATION> Mead </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> honors student was talking and watching as family members opened presents for her at Sacred Heart Medical Center. `` I thought the very best Christmas present I could ever get was to hear my daughter talk again,'' said <PERSON> Missy </PERSON>'s father, <PERSON> Steve </PERSON>. `` She gave me that gift with a week to spare. And each day she gets a little bit better.'' <PERSON> Missy </PERSON> was injured Nov. 25 in a head-on collision on Interstate 90, just west of <ORGANIZATION> Coeur </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> d'Alene </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>. Ms. <PERSON> Goebel </PERSON> and her 16-year-old boyfriend were in her car when they collided with a pickup truck traveling the wrong way. <PERSON> Ian </PERSON> <PERSON> McElfish </PERSON>, the boyfriend, was treated and released. The 79-year-old driver of the pickup is now in a nursing home. A month ago, doctors, family members and friends thought <PERSON> Melissa </PERSON> would die. <PERSON> Missy </PERSON> was in a coma, largely unresponsive to talking and touching by family members. On Day 19, doctors said <PERSON> Goebel </PERSON> most likely would be comatose for years. But just a few hours after doctors left her room that day, <PERSON> Missy </PERSON> spoke to her mother. Then, she asked to telephone her brother, despite her head injuries and a broken neck, clavicle, right arm and left leg. `` She's a little miracle,'' said <PERSON> Victoria </PERSON> <PERSON> Goebel </PERSON>, <PERSON> Missy </PERSON>'s mother `` She's quite an amazing girl.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Goebel </PERSON> said she welcomed the sound of <PERSON> Missy </PERSON> bickering with her younger brother, <PERSON> Brian </PERSON>. `` She calls her brother a dweeb a lot,'' the mother said, adding that the siblings were close friends. `` I could n't believe it when they were in there arguing the other day. It was great.'' <PERSON> Missy </PERSON>'s struggle is far from over. The left side of her body remains paralyzed. <PERSON> Goebel </PERSON> said his daughter often slips into a `` kind of dream state'' and gets confused easily. `` She's pretty much like a rag doll,'' he said. `` But she's further along than anyone ever thought she would be.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891226-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-26-89 0041EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     12-26 0979</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1019</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ELDERSBURG, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former burlesque queen <PERSON> Blaze </PERSON> <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> is still seeing stars after a whirlwind trip to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> for the premiere of `` Blaze,'' a film based on her love affair with former <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Long </PERSON>. `` I felt like <PERSON> Cinderella </PERSON> after the ball when I got out of the limousine and boarded the plane home,'' <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> said. `` Unlike Cinderella, though, I am very glad to be here.'' <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> is back selling her homemade jewelry in a <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> mall, but she said she loved her five-day stay last week in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. `` Every time we stepped out of the hotel, we stepped into a stretch,'' she said. `` Nobody calls them limos.'' <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> did all she could in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to promote the movie, from which she will earn 4 percent of the profits. She participated in 14 straight hours of interviews along with actors <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lolita </PERSON> <PERSON> Davidovitch </PERSON> and director <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON>. Many critics have praised the movie, but decried its historic inaccuracies. For one, the movie has Long dying on <PERSON> Starr </PERSON>'s lap, when he actually suffered a fatal heart attack nowhere near his sweetheart. <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> said she flew to <LOCATION> Baton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rouge </LOCATION> where his body lay in state. `` I walked into the Capitol with a single red rose in my breasts. I did n't look right or left as I walked to the casket,'' she said. `` Then, I pulled out the rose and said ` This is for you, <PERSON> Earl </PERSON>.' I knew that's what he would like.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: Single name Costa-Gavras cq.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Lange </PERSON> has become accustomed to working in movies that are not commercial films. `` So if one of them does become that, it would be a real surprise to me,'' she said. `` It's just because I'm attracted to things that are somewhat out of the mainstream,'' she said in an interview in the January issue of Premiere magazine. The 40-year-old <PERSON> Lange </PERSON>'s latest roles are in Costa-Gavras' `` Music Box,'' in which she plays a <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> lawyer contesting charges that her father is a Nazi war criminal She's also in <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Brickman </PERSON>'s `` Men Do n't Leave,'' in which she plays a newly widowed mother. `` The roles and the stories that make it interesting for me to spend six months or three months of my life involved in the playing of are maybe not what's going to appeal to the majority, which is fine,'' she said. Langes lives with actor-playwright <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Shepard </PERSON> and they have two children. She has a third child by dancer <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Baryshnikov </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>EAST BERLIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON> conducted an orchestra of international musicians to celebrate the struggle for freedom throughout <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, and then appealed for brotherhood in East and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. `` I am experiencing a historical moment _ incomparable with others in my long, long life,'' the American conductor said during the performance, which was broadcast live in more than 20 countries. The Christmas performance of <PERSON> Beethoven </PERSON>'s `` Ninth Symphony'' capped three days of concerts. The symphony was inspired by 18th century German writer <PERSON> Friedrich </PERSON> <PERSON> Schiller </PERSON>'s poem `` Ode to Joy.'' In the concert, <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON> substituted the word `` freedom'' for `` joy'' in the chorus to reflect his personal message. The 71-year-old musician conducted the same symphony in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> in a performance timed to end at midnight Saturday, when West Germans were allowed to travel without visas into <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> for the first time. The musicians were from East and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> as well as the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> _ the four victorious World War II allies still technically responsible for governing <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>. The East German government presented <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON> the `` Star of People's Friendship.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Alyssa </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, the 22-month-old girl who underwent the nation's first liver transplant from a living donor, played with Christmas gifts sent by well-wishers from strangers including <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON>. `` She's received a lot of cards and gifts from everywhere,'' her father <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said Monday. `` People from all walks of life have given things like dolls and stuff. `` <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON> sent her a doll,'' added the father. `` I thought that was real neat. People sent cards and money. That made us feel very loved.'' <PERSON> Alyssa </PERSON> and 16-month-old <PERSON> Sarina </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, who received the nation's second living-donor liver transplant, were recovering remarkably well at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, though both girls remained in critical but stable condition, spokeswoman <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> said The girls suffered from biliary atresia, a usually fatal congenital defect. <PERSON> Alyssa </PERSON> received her transplant from her 29-year-old mother, <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON>, an elementary school teacher who was released from the hospital two weeks ago. Since her Nov. 27 transplant, <PERSON> Alyssa </PERSON> has undergone three operations to stop bleeding on the liver's surface, but doctors say she still is expected to be able to leave the hospital sometime after Jan. 1. Said the girl's father, `` If the surgery had not been good, we'd not be having the Christmas we're having.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: Version moved on sports wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>FORT WAYNE, Ind. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Indianapolis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Colts </ORGANIZATION> rookie wide receiver <PERSON> Andre </PERSON> <PERSON> Rison </PERSON> was in too much of a hurry to get home for Christmas. <PERSON> Rison </PERSON> was charged with reckless driving early Monday after police clocked him at driving his 1989 Mercedes at 128 mph on Interstate 69 near <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wayne </LOCATION>, authorities said. The speed limit is 55 mph. He was taken to the <LOCATION> Allen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lockup </LOCATION> where he posted $ 500 bond and was released. `` He told the officer he thought he was driving between 95 and 100 miles per hour because he said that's what it feels like when you're driving 55 miles per hour in a regular car,'' said Sgt. <PERSON> Dallard </PERSON> <PERSON> Tackett </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> post at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wayne </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Rison </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Colts </ORGANIZATION>' top draft pick out of <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION>, was headed to <LOCATION> Flint </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, for Christmas. The <ORGANIZATION> Colts </ORGANIZATION>' season ended Sunday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891226-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-26-89 0109EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BiologicalWeapons Bjt   12-26 0641</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Biological Weapons, Bjt,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Anti-Biological Weapons Legislation Making Progress</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONNA CASSATA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Twenty years after President <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> ordered the destruction of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> stockpile of biological weapons, the federal government is on the verge of making development and possession of the weapons illegal. Although <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s directive met with little resistance and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> joined the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and 109 other countries in signing a 1972 pact to prohibit production and possession of the weapons, efforts to incorporate the treaty's provisions into <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> law have failed _ until this year. Scientists, defense analysts and lawmakers credit the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration, the changing atmosphere for arms control agreements and the work of a freshman senator from <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> who has little foreign policy background. `` If I had to pick any of the 100 senators, it would not be him, even the top 80,'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Isaacs </PERSON> of the liberal Council for a <ORGANIZATION> Livable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> said in a recent interview. `` He was the new kid on the block.'' The kid is Democratic Sen. <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>, who with the help of a longtime opponent of biological and chemical weapons, Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON>, D-Ark., convinced the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and the full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> to support the Biological Weapons Anti-Terrorism Act of 1989 In the waning hours of the congressional session on Nov. 21, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approved the legislatio by voice vote. House passage and presidential approval appear likely early next year. `` By approving the legislation, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> has signaled the world that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is serious about controlling these abominable creations,'' <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> said on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> floor. By definition, biological weapons are a form of bacteria, virus, fungus or naturally occurring toxin. A biological weapon could be unleashed on an unsuspecting public by using it in a liquid to contaminate water or in an aerosol that is dropped by bomb. In 1925, the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> Protocol banned the first use in war of biological and chemical weapons, but did not address the development, production, possession or transfer of the weapons. Forty-four years later, <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> ordered the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to destroy its arsenal of biological weapons. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> then spearheaded the fight for an international ban on production and possession of the weapons. On April 10, 1972, in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, 111 countries signed the Biological Weapons Convention. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> ratified the treaty two years later. According to the pact, each nation must take `` any necessary measures'' to prohibit biological weapons at home. Legislation was introduced in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> over the years to include the prohibition in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> law, but the measures never got far. Among the problems during the 1980s, according to the legislation's <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> sponsor, Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kastenmeier </PERSON>, D-Wis., was the view of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration `` This administration is somewhat different,'' <PERSON> Kastenmeier </PERSON> said in an interview. `` During eight years of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, candidly speaking, they were not really for this legislation. ... They felt we did n't need this.'' But with the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's support for the bill and the `` tenor of the times'' for arms control legislation, said <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>, the biological weapons bill won easy <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approval after just a handful of hearings. `` It was the right time, the right place, the right bill,'' <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> said. The measure's purpose is twofold. It implements the 1972 Biological Weapons Convention and seeks to protect the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> against the threat of biological terrorism. `` The legislation would prohibit the possession or development of germ warfare devices and authorize the punishment of those who attempt to help foreign nations acquire such weapons,'' the bill says. <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> believes final congressional approval and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s signature would strengthen the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' hand in demanding that all countries comply with the 1972 treaty. The administration is concerned about countries with the capability to produce biological weapons, including <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. The official list remains classified.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891226-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-26-89 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reporter'sNotebook     12-26 0705</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reporter's Notebook,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Pool Reporters in Panama: Late for the Story</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COLON, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Under cloak of darkness, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> army helicopter flew the length of the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> taking a pair of reporters, a photographer and a television crew to this port city. But soon after they arrived, members of the group realized that they'd missed the story. Again. Soldiers told of entering the city on Friday afternoon to the cheers of citizens who draped <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> flags from their balconies. They told how the local groups helped the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soldiers round up <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> loyalists, and how deeply moving the scene had been. But more than two days after the invasion began, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military still was keeping the media away from its operations until they were over. The Pentagon news pool, created to cover American military actions in a way that would protect important operational secrecy, was still on its way to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> last Wednesday when the invasion began. Arriving in the country, the pool had to cool its heels for hours inside a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> army base and found out the details of the attack the same way everyone else in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> did _ on television, based on reports from other news people already in the city. The group arrived at the battle area around Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s headquarters after the battle was over. They viewed <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s private retreats after they'd been disturbed by military investigators, and saw people who had been rescued, but not the rescue itself. After a while, the pool members decided their motto should be `` semper tardis,'' or `` always late.'' The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> showed reporters the spoils of war but not the war itself, which was, of course, the reason for the pool in the first place. Exposure to ongoing events was almost an accident for the pool, but it happened. For example: _ An alert photographer yelling `` Whoa! got the press bus to stop at a makeshift prisoner-of-war camp. _ Reporters heading to a pre-set downtown site received an extraordinary view of looting and mayhem when their driver got lost _ The press corps could n't help but witness a surprise attack on Southern Command headquarters, the site of the press center _ On a trip to interview <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commanders west of the city, reporters happened upon an extraordinary scene: more than a thousand people cheering wildly as <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> loyalists surrendered their weapons to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soldiers All around the country, <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> GIs and local citizens were more than happy to tell their stories. But, not being witnesses themselves, reporters were forced to piece things together and deal with difficult contradictions. At <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hato </LOCATION>, a Panamanian army base west of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> rangers fresh from their first real combat told of parachuting into an intense firefight. Several <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> lives were lost, and one paratrooper was shot in the doorway of his C-130 aircraft as he prepared to jump, they said. His Ranger comrades had to pull him back to save his life. But back in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, the brass was saying how the attack on <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hato </LOCATION> had been cleared of resistance thanks to new Stealth fighter planes which evaded radar for a bombing run which distracted the defenders. At <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Amador </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> was the `` Witch House,'' a modest residence where <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> was said to have kept his four Brazilian voodoo witches. Reporters were shown the evidence of strange ritual: a bucket of blood, animal entrails, and a variety of religious artifacts carefully arranged on a desk that apparently served as an altar. But before reporters were allowed in, the military removed what soldiers said were packets of cocaine wrapped in tropical leaves. Soldiers who confiscated the stockpile described their haul as about 50 pounds of cocaine. At headquarters and in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, the generals said it was 50 kilograms, which, at 2.2 pounds per kilo, would better back up the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> claim that <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> was involved heavily in the drug trade. It was possible the generals were referring to cocaine also recovered elsewhere, but reporters never were able to reconcile the figures.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Komarow </PERSON> was a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> press pool in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> during the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> invasion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891226-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-26-89 0121EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RiotTrial-Police Bjt   12-26 0764</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Riot Trial-Police, Bjt,0791</SECOND>
<HEAD>Officer's Conviction Drives Ethnic Wedge Into Police Force</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: McMillian cq.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD COLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The manslaughter conviction of a Hispanic officer in the deaths of two blacks had raised hopes for healing a decade of racial tension. Instead, the verdict has spread tensions within police ranks. Talk of a work slowdown by the police and an allegation that a Hispanic policeman hesitated before responding to a backup request from a black officer have embroiled the force in recent weeks. The local branch of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advancement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Colored </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION> even asked Gov. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> on Friday to have <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guardsmen </ORGANIZATION> patrol <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>'s black neighborhoods. `` If I needed police protection, I would not feel comfortable calling the police because of the attitude of some of the officers,'' said the <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Johnnie </PERSON> <PERSON> McMillian </PERSON>. <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> rejected <PERSON> McMillian </PERSON>'s request, and Mayor <PERSON> Xavier </PERSON> <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON> and Police Chief <PERSON> Perry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> assured the community that officers of all races would act professionally. Tensions have been evident since a jury found Colombian-born officer <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON> guilty Dec. 7 in the deaths of black motorcyclist <PERSON> Clement </PERSON> <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> and his passenger, <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON>. During the past two weeks, an Hispanic <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> officer and a white <ORGANIZATION> Metro-Dade </ORGANIZATION> policeman have been suspended for wearing black tape on their badges or black wristbands to protest the verdict. <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Benevolent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> has raised funds and presented <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON> with a `` Brotherhood in Blue'' T-shirt _ a mocking reference to the term prosecutors used during the trial to accuse officers of protecting each other. Many black officers, however, agreed with the verdict and see fund-raising, wristbands and clemency petitions as a slap in the face. `` For the very people who uphold law and order, to take exception in such a blatant manner, is extremely insensitive,'' said Officer <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Harlan </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Officers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. But to many other officers, <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON> is seen as a martyr to the community's desperation to avoid a fifth race riot in the 1980s. Two previous disturbances followed acquittals of officers charged with killing blacks, and the Jan. 16 deaths of <LOCATION> Lloyd </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON> ignited three days of riots. `` It would n't have made a difference whether he was Hispanic or black _ he did n't receive a fair trial,'' said <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>, head of the Hispanic Officer's <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> defended officers' action in support of <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON>. He said some black officers cheered and gave each other high-fives when the conviction was announced. `` If the blacks were permitted to celebrate, then we have the right to protest,'' <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> said. Some community leaders have blamed past racial violence on a feeling by blacks that they are being left behind while the Hispanic population grows in size, wealth and influence. Hispanic gains in the community have been reflected in the <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> police force during the past decade. Today, 44 percent of the force's 1,100 officers are <PERSON> Hispanic </PERSON>, 19 percent are black and 37 percent non-Hispanic white. The changes have created divisions that did n't exist before, when <PERSON> Hispanics </PERSON> joined blacks in challenging `` Anglos'' for jobs and promotions, <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> said. `` Before, we probably had better working relations with black officers than we did with <ORGANIZATION> Anglo </ORGANIZATION> officers _ but not now,'' <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> said. In the week following <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON>'s conviction, a Hispanic officer was accused of stalling on the way to the aid of a black officer who had called for assistance. The incident prompted a meeting of the Hispanic and black officers associations with police officials to soothe the tension. `` This used to be a war between the police and the criminal,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Hialeah </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Rolando </PERSON> <PERSON> Bolanos </PERSON>, who mediated the meeting. `` We do not need to have a war between police and police.'' The mayor also met with <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> and police unions. `` They showed a lot of sensitivity,'' <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON> said. Nevertheless, police unions continue to fight the suspensions of the two officers punished for the black bands and raise money for <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON>'s appeal. Members of the Fraternal Order of Police each have agreed to donate $ 260 to defray <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON>'s legal expenses. The Hispanic Officers Association is selling its own T-shirts and distributing black wristbands to departments around the state, said <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>. Although police chiefs have banned in-uniform displays of support, many Miami-area officers wear black wristbands off-duty. <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Black </PERSON>, <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON>'s defense attorney, said he has n't been surprised by the support. `` A lot of people did n't take it seriously until he was convicted,'' <PERSON> Black </PERSON> said. `` I get more calls all the time from people, many of them police officers, who want to know what they can do.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891226-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-26-89 0123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CivilRights Bjt   12-26 0869</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Civil Rights, Bjt,860</SECOND>
<HEAD>Employment Rights Bill Tops Civil Rights Shopping List on Capitol
Hill</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Civil rights forces, stunned by what they see as a wave of setbacks in the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> last June, are putting a congressional agenda forward for next year. `` We'll have a fight but we'll win because civil rights is looked upon with favor these days,'' declares Rep. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, D-Calif. A civil rights bill, set to be unveiled soon after lawmakers return from the holidays, could focus political pressure on the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration Opposition would risk alienating the black community while support would mean repudiation of court decisions that have found favor among conservatives. The sponsors, Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., Rep. <PERSON> Augustus </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>, D-Calif., and bipartisan coalitions in both houses are expected to introduce the bill soon after the 1990 congressional session gets under Thus far, <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials have been saying they see no problem with recent rulings on the employment discrimination front. They have said they would monitor the results to determine whether legislation is needed. Civil rights forces say it is needed now. While details are not available, proponents say the measure will be designed in large part to counter three decisions by the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> last June: _ The court held in a June 5 decision involving two salmon canneries that plaintiffs in hiring bias suits have the burden of proving the practices at issue have no legitimate business purpose Prior to the so-called Wards Cove decision _ named for a packing company that figured in the case _ it was the employer who had to prove that there was a legitimate business reason. _ The justices on June 12 cleared the way for challenges to longstanding, court-approved agreements giving minorities and women preference in hiring for government jobs The <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Wilke </PERSON> case, involving <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, firefighters, was viewed as a sharp setback for affirmative action plans. _ The court ruled June 15 that a civil rights law does not bar racial harassment in the workplace The <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON> case was brought by a black woman from <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> who said she was mistreated on the job because of her race. In each case, the court was divided 5-4. `` What has happened is that the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, in its mischievousness, in the past year has actually gutted title 7 of the 1964 Civil Rights Act,'' said <PERSON> Althea </PERSON> <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON>, lobbyist for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> for the Advancement of Colored People. Title 7 is the job bias portion of the 1964 Civil Rights Act. Legislation to counter the decisions `` has to pass _ we have no choice but to pass it,'' she said. `` If you ask, ` Is it going to be smooth sailing?,' I think we have to work hard to pass it, but I think it's going to pass.'' Actually, winning approval for the measure might not turn out to be such a formidable task. No longer the embattled underdogs of yesteryear, civil rights forces have been getting most of what they want from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, often by margins as wide as 70 percent in each house. `` We expect very substantial bipartisan majorities in both houses of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to support this vital legislation,'' said <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Neas </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Leadership </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION>, an umbrella group that includes virtually every civil rights organization active in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Both Ms. <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> and <PERSON> Neas </PERSON> described the employment rights measure as far and away the top item on the civil rights agenda for the year ahead. But civil rights forces are pressing for a wide array of other items. They are hoping for legislation to counter a <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decision in a <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, case that struck a severe blow at set-asides that reserve a portion of government contracts for minority-owned business. Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Conyers </PERSON>, D-Mich., is planning hearings Legislation to guarantee civil rights for Americans with disabilities already has been passed by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> following a compromise agreement with the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration. Action in three <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> committees is expected when <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> returns from its break. Pending in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> is House-passed legislation that would order the government to gather statistics on so-called hate crimes, directed against racial, religious and ethnic minorities. Committees in both houses have approved legislation that would guarantee employee rights to medical leave in cases involving birth, adoption and serious illness. A conference committee currently is attempting to resolve differences between <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> versions of legislation to provide federal aid for child care, either through grants to states or tax credits. Leaders in both houses have said the measure will get high priority. Incorporated into legislation to reestablish the death penalty now pending in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is an amendment to bar racial discrimination in imposing it. Civil rights forces also are pressing the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to attach anti-discrimination provisions to pending legislation that would allow voter registration through the mail, provide automatic registration for anyone with a driver's license and require government agencies to register voters. Also pending is Senate-passed legislation that would reauthorize through 1994 discretionary programs to aid handicapped students. Civil rights forces plan to press <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> again for legislation that would guarantee Americans affordable housing.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891226-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-26-89 0119EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     12-26 0026</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0025</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Up In Tokyo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 38,681.31, up 257.69 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Tuesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891226-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-26-89 0137EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TaxMailout Bjt   12-26 0691</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tax Mailout, Bjt,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Federal Tax Forms in the Mail Today</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Economics Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Taxpayers receive their annual holiday greetings from Uncle <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> starting today, as the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> mails out more than 107 million tax forms and instruction packages. The forms, which have been waiting at post offices across the nation for weeks, should be in most taxpayers' hands before Jan. 1. The <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> always times the mailing, which costs $ 26 million for postage and printing, to come right after the crush of Christmas mail but soon enough to give taxpayers as much time as possible to complete their returns before the filing deadline, which falls this year on April 16. For taxpayers still reeling from the sweeping changes wrought by the 1986 <ORGANIZATION> Tax </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reform </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Act </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> has reassuring words: the new forms look very much like last year's forms. But to the chagrin of <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> officials, one of the few changes should not have been made, and it could confuse millions of elderly Americans. The <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> is trying to get the word out to taxpayers eligible for <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> that they should ignore the lines on the tax form covering the supplemental <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> premium. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> did away with the premium along with the catastrophic health program it was designed to fund. But <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> did not vote to repeal the controversial program until late November, long after the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> forms had gone to the printers. The <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> hopes to keep confusion to a minimum through a publicity campaign to get word to the 12 million elderly taxpayers who could be affected. In addition, <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> officials note that the form taxpayers would need to compute their Medicare premium tax liability, Form 8808, does not exist. `` We believe that taxpayers will not want to pay taxes that they do n't have to pay,'' said <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> official <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Altman </PERSON>. But <PERSON> Altman </PERSON> said that if taxpayers still include an amount on the <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> premium line, the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> will refund the money. This year's returns are accompanied by a special pitch from new <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> Commissioner <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, who urges taxpayers to consider filing their returns electronically to cut down on the time it takes to process their refund checks. The <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> is providing a special toll-free telephone number, 1-800-424-1040, for people to call for a list of tax preparers in their area who can file returns electronically. In 1988, two-thirds of all taxpayers qualified for a refund, with the average refund totaling $ 875. All of the changes in this year's forms are explained in the accompanying instruction booklets, which also include a list of other <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> publications that offer further help in preparing taxes. To request additional tax forms and the tax information publications, taxpayers can call the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> at 1-800-424-3676. Among the changes featured in this year's forms: _ The personal exemption, the amount you may exempt from taxation for yourself, your spouse and each dependent, increases to $ 2,000 per person, up from $ 1,950 last year _ The standard deduction, claimed by people who do not itemize, rises to $ 3,100 for a single person, up from $ 3,000 last year The exemption for a couple increases to $ 5,200, up from $ 5,000 last year. _ Tax rates remain the same at 15 percent, 28 percent and 33 percent with about four of every five taxpayers paying only the lowest rate While the rates stay the same, the tax brackets have been widened so that more income will be taxed at lower rates in order to compensate for inflation. _ For the first time, the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> will include two name lines, instead of one, in recognition that more married couples have different last names The <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> is looking for 111.2 million individual tax returns to be filed this year with 65 percent expected to opt for the comprehensive Form 1040, designed for taxpayers who itemize or who have incomes above $ 50,000 annually. Two shorter forms, Form 1040A and the brief nine-line Form 1040EZ, are available for taxpayers who do not itemize and can meet other qualifications. The <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> form each taxpayer receives is based on the form that taxpayer used last year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891226-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-26-89 0142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     12-26 0700</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>China Faces Growing Demand for Imported Wheat</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> is the world's largest wheat producer but is not keeping pace with its own consumer demand for more bread, noodles and dumplings. As a result, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has been buying huge amounts of wheat from other countries, including the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. An <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> analyst says import demand will continue to grow, at least through the turn of the century. `` Even though it is the world's largest producer of wheat, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s domestic demand exceeds supplies,'' says <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Crook </PERSON> of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. `` Wheat output has risen steadily as farmers have boosted yields because of greater irrigation and use of improved varieties.'' Crook, in a report on <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s wheat economy, said population growth and `` consumer preference for wheat products'' such as noodles, steamed dumplings, bread and pastries have spurred demand. As the world's most populous country with 1.1 billion people, even slight changes in per capita use can translate into large numbers. Crook said per capita wheat consumption rose steadily from 29 kilograms in 1960 to 48 kilos in 1978. Then, as supplies increased because of import and production gains, the average jumped to 90 kilograms per person in 1987. A kilogram is about 2.2 pounds. Ninety kilos would be about 198 pounds, or approximately 3.3 bushels of wheat, allowing 60 pounds per bushel. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has been at peaks and valleys as a customer of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat farmers since the early 1970s. Lately, <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> has been a large and consistent buyer of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat, rivaling the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> at times. In the 1988-89 wheat marketing year that ran through last May 31, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> imported almost 8.1 million metric tons of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat and became the largest foreign customer of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> growers. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, by comparison, imported 4.96 million tons in the same period. So far in 1989-90, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has bought about 4.7 million tons against the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s purchases as of Dec. 14 of less than 2 million tons. A metric ton, the unit favored in world grain trade, is about 2,205 pounds and is equal to 36.7 bushels of wheat. It also is equal to 1,000 kilograms. Both <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> have bought large amounts of wheat under a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> price subsidy arrangement, the Export Enhancement Program. Under <ORGANIZATION> EEP </ORGANIZATION>, private exporters can sell to designated foreign countries at reduced prices and then collect USDA-owned commodities as `` bonuses'' or subsidies to make up the price difference. From a production standpoint, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has been the world's largest wheat producer in four of the last five years, according to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> statistics. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s wheat output this year, for example, is estimated at 91 million tons, compared with 89 million for the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and 55.6 million for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Other major producers this year include: <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, 24.4 million tons; <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, 12.5 million; <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, 10.7 million; <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, 53 million; <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, 42.3 million; and the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION>, 79.3 million. Crook said that by world standards <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has achieved `` fairly high wheat yields'' and is surpassing those in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and countries which have large areas of non-irrigated wheat, such as <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. On the other hand, Crook said wheat yields are higher in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. Crook said that Chinese experts predict wheat yields will climb an average of about 1.65 percent a year and that by the year 2000 there will be some decrease in total wheat area. But they claim that total output by then will increase to between 100 million and 105 million tons. `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s population will continue to grow in the next decade, and if per capita income continues to rise, demand for wheat will also increase,'' Crook said. `` However, prospects for rapid gains in domestic wheat output are dim because little arable -LRB- land -RRB- can be shifted to wheat production, and yields are already high.'' As a result, he added, the outlook for wheat exports to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> `` looks promising in the near future.'' But the rate of growth will depend mostly on the ability of the rest of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s economy to earn foreign exchange.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891226-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-26-89 0147EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MercyShooting     12-26 0313</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mercy Shooting,0328</SECOND>
<HEAD>Authorities: Retired Police Officer Shoots Chronically Ill Wife</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHARLES J. GANS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A retired policeman who was facing major heart surgery fatally shot his ailing wife because he was afraid he could n't take care of her and did n't want her to suffer anymore, authorities say. <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, 67, was charged with first-degree murder in the death of his wife, <PERSON> Alice </PERSON>, who suffered from multiple sclerosis, said Police Sgt. <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Palmer </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> was released on personal recognizance into his daughter's custody after a Christmas Day hearing. The prosecutor agreed with a defense lawyer that <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, who retired six years ago, posed no threat to society. `` Good luck and Merry Christmas,'' Circuit Court Judge <PERSON> Sheldon </PERSON> <PERSON> Garber </PERSON> told <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> at the close of the hearing. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> was scheduled to appear for another hearing today. Mrs. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, 64, apparently died instantly Christmas Eve when her husband of 44 years shot her in the head with a .38 - caliber revolver as she sat in her wheelchair, <PERSON> Palmer </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> then called police and handed over the gun when officers arrived at the home, <PERSON> Palmer </PERSON> said. `` It's a sad thing to happen on any day, and it just seems to be embellished by the fact that it's Christmas Eve,'' said <PERSON> Palmer </PERSON>. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> told the officers that `` all his wife did was complain about how much she was suffering and she begged him to end it,'' <PERSON> Palmer </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>' doctor recently told him he needed a second major heart operation and he would n't be able to care for his wife, according to an account given to police by <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>' daughter. Mrs. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> suffered from multiple sclerosis, a degenerative disease of the nervous system, for 20 years, and had heart and kidney problems, <PERSON> Palmer </PERSON> said. `` His health was n't the best and hers was deteriorating,'' <PERSON> Palmer </PERSON> said. `` I'm sure the guy is overwrought.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891226-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-26-89 0155EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-Christmas     12-26 0130</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Christmas,130</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush, Family Spend Christmas at Camp David</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President and Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spent the Christmas holiday with their five children and 11 grandchildren in the splendid isolation of the snow-covered <LOCATION> Catoctin </LOCATION> mountains. Reports of their Christmas Day activities on Monday were scarce, except that the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> let it be known that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had invited National Security Adviser Brent Scowcroft to Camp David, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, to brief the president on the situations in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>. The president is scheduled to stay at Camp David until Wednesday. The children at the presidential retreat, 60 miles from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, were <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and wife <PERSON> Laura </PERSON>; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and wife <PERSON> Columba </PERSON>; <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Mallon </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and wife <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON>; <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and wife <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891226-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-26-89 0156EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Cuba-Salvador     12-26 0570</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cuba-Salvador,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cuba Believed Sending Weapons to Leftists by Remote Mexican Route</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> is believed to be using a remote Mexican land route to send weapons to leftist rebels in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials say. <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> is believed to have started using the alternate route some time ago, and indications are that use of the route _ beginning in the <LOCATION> Yucatan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION> _ has increased recently, said the officials, who asked not to be identified. <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> has traditionally used <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> as its primary transit point for weapons deliveries to its allies in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. It was not clear whether <LOCATION> Mexican </LOCATION> officials have been approached by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomats about the alleged shipments. There was no immediate comment from the Mexican government. Historically, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> has been sympathetic to the Salvadoran rebels but that support has been more muted since President <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON> took office a year ago. Much of the weaponry sent to the Salvadoran insurgents is supplied by the Soviet bloc and delivered via <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, according to officials. Recent administration statements indicate that it sees <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> _ not the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> bloc </LOCATION> _ as the principal villain in these activities. As described by officials, the Cubans ship the weapons across the narrow channel that separates <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> from the <LOCATION> Yucatan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION>. From there, the equipment is sent by truck to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> via <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> although the precise route is not clear. <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s leftist government has been criticized internationally for its alleged collaboration with <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> in supporting the Salvadoran rebels. As <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials see it, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>'s apparent search for new ways to help the Salvadoran rebels _ without relying exclusively on <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> _ may be an effort to limit the chances that the Sandinista role will be exposed more than it has been. <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> has denied that its territory has been used for subversive activities in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. Such interference is a violation of Central American agreements signed by Nicaraguan President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>. The Sandinista government has been in the forefront of the international effort over the past week to have the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration condemned for its invasion of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>'s response also has been indignant The administration views <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>'s purported use of the route through <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> as a supplement to the support the Nicaraguans are providing as a transit point for Cuban-supplied weapons. As evidence that the Sandinista connection has not been abandoned, the administration has cited the discovery of weapons by <LOCATION> Honduran </LOCATION> officials aboard a truck said to have been headed to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. The driver of the truck involved in the Oct. 18 weapons seizure told authorities he had been making the run between <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> monthly since August 1988. According to officials, a more revealing incident occurred on Nov. 25 when a plane carrying surface-to-air missiles crashed in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. The plane had taken off from <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and its destination reportedly was rebel-held territory in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. The officials contend <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> are intent on providing assistance to the Salvadoran rebels during the current period because it may be more difficult in the coming months. One reason: peacekeepers from the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> are being assigned to <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> to ensure that provisions of regional agreements are being kept. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration has been pressing <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> officials to ensure that the peacekeepers, among other duties, are on the lookout for deliveries to the Salvadoran rebels from outside the county's borders.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891226-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-26-89 0228EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Japan-Markets 2ndLd-Writethru   12-26 0414</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Markets, 2nd Ld-Writethru,a0666,0425</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Hit Another Record High, Dollar Lower</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Lead with 3 grafs to UPDATE with closing Nikkei, dollar. Pickup
4th graf ``Share prices...''</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The key index on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> closed at yet another record high Tuesday, while the dollar edged down against the Japanese yen. The 225-issue Nikkei Stock Average gained 257.69 points, or 0.67 percent, ending at 38,681.31. The index had gained 383.25 points Monday as investors welcomed the third discount rate increase by the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> this year. The previous record was 38,586.18 on Dec. 18. The dollar closed at 142.37 yen, down 0.35 yen from its finish of 142.72 yen on Monday, when it fell 0.95 yen. It opened Tuesday at 142.94 yen and ranged between 142.30 yen and 142.95 yen. `` Share prices were higher almost all across the board,'' said <PERSON> Tatsuo </PERSON> <PERSON> Kurokawa </PERSON>, an analyst with <ORGANIZATION> Nomura </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION>. Although stock investors are normally discouraged by a discount rate hike, they boosted buy orders following the Monday announcement by the central bank, mainly because investors were reassured that there would be no more major changes in monetary policy for a while, <PERSON> Kurokawa </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> raised the discount rate to 4.25 percent from its current level at 3.75 percent. The discount rate is the rate the central bank charges on its loans to commercial banks. `` A majority of market players think all the negative factors in the market have disappeared,'' <PERSON> Kurokawa </PERSON> said. In currency dealings, the market was quiet becuase many overseas markets, including those in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, were closed for Christmas holidays, traders said. After the dollar hit a high at 142.95 yen, investors began to sell the currency for profit-taking and small position adjustments, they said. <PERSON> Toru </PERSON> <PERSON> Kanai </PERSON>, a foreign exchange analyst with <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, said the dollar-yen rate remained inactive because the market had already responded to the discount rate hike Monday. `` The market had been well prepared for the hike since the rumor had come out last Tuesday,'' <PERSON> Kanai </PERSON> said. `` Everybody knew there would be a 0.5 percentage point hike, so the hike yesterday had little impact.'' Also, traders said that a mere 0.5 percentage-point raise would not boost yen-buying because <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s discount rate is still substantially lower than those of other industrialized nations. Market players were reluctant to buy the dollar as well, due to uncertainties over whether the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> will cut its discount rate, <PERSON> Kanai </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891226-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-26-89 0247EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Arrests     12-26 0323</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Arrests,0334</SECOND>
<HEAD>China Charges Five With Helping Dissidents Flee</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> says it arrested five <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Macao </LOCATION> residents on charges of trying to smuggle dissidents out of the country and today accused a <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> group of running an `` underground railroad.'' <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> said the <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alliance </LOCATION> for Supporting the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> helped dozens of dissidents flee abroad since the army crackdown on pro-democracy protests in June. Police said the arrests `` dealt a major blow to the overseas reactionary forces who attempted to use <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Macao </LOCATION> as sanctuaries for criminals,'' the official <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said in a report Monday. The five arrests were made over the past three months, and <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> did not say why they were being announced only now. It said <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> will `` punish severely those who dare to plot and ship wanted criminals out of the mainland.'' <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has said repeatedly it will not allow residents of <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Macao </LOCATION> to interfere in mainland affairs, but this was the first time it explicitly accused the <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> alliance of running the underground railroad. The alliance was founded after the June crackdown, which increased anxiety in British-ruled <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> and Portuguese-ruled <LOCATION> Macao </LOCATION> about their return to <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> rule in the coming decade. The official <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> defended the arrests in an editorial in today's editions, saying `` <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Macao </LOCATION> residents must obey Chinese laws when on the mainland.'' In excerpts of the editorial, the paper accused the alliance of smuggling abroad `` important counter-revolutionary criminals. ... The Chinese government will never tolerate such activities.'' <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> considers ethnic Chinese from the two colonies to be <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> citizens and has rejected past efforts by <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> to intervene on behalf of arrested <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> Chinese. The arrests were likely to increase <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> fears about Chinese rule, which already have sent many in search of haven elsewhere.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891226-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-26-89 0349EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Romania-Text     12-26 0164</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Romania-Text,0173</SECOND>
<HEAD>Text of Ceausescu Execution Announcement</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Romania, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BUCHAREST, Romania (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Text of the announcement of the execution of <PERSON> Nicolae </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Elena </PERSON>, as broadcast by <ORGANIZATION> Bucharest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> and translated by The Associated Press:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 On Dec. 25, 1989, the trial of <PERSON> Nicolae </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> and <PERSON> Elena </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> was held before an extraordinary military tribunal. The charges were: 1. Genocide. More than 60,000 victims. 2. Undermining of the state power through organization of armed actions against the people and the state power. 3. Destruction of public property through destruction and damaging of buildings and numerous explosions in cities, etc. 4. The undermining of the national economy. 5. The attempt to flee the country by taking advantage of more than $ 1 billion deposited in foreign banks. For these crimes against the Romanian people and <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>, the culprits <PERSON> Nicolae </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> and <PERSON> Elena </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> were condemned to death and the confiscation of their wealth. The sentence was definitive and was carried out.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891226-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-26-89 0338EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     12-26 0704</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0732</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LAFAYETTE, Ind. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> accepted his teacher's semester challenge, and last week he carried it to school: numbers from one to 1 million listed on 2,400 pages and weighing 50 pounds The project began after <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Randak </PERSON>, who teaches a biology class for gifted students at <ORGANIZATION> Lafayette </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jefferson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, told the class he would give an A for the semester to anyone who wrote out every number from one to a million. Unfortunately, <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> did n't qualify for the A because he generated the numbers on his home computer. `` I just thought it would be really neat to show someone could do it and to prove how large a million is,'' said <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>, who is earning an A in the course anyway. <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> said he first set out to write each number by hand, but lost interest at about 5,000. His interest was renewed when he thought of printing the numbers by computer. He ran the program at least seven hours a day for two weeks. After 2 -LCB- boxes of computer paper and three ink cartridges, he reached the magic number.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CAMBRIDGE, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> may profess to be striving to combat its image as a citadel of the privileged. Sometimes, however, the <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> old </ORGANIZATION>, when titled and untitled royalty paced the ivied campus, peeps through the modern curtain. In a new questionnaire, the school asks its graduates to own up to their proper title. For alumni not content with Mr., Miss, Mrs. or Ms., <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> offers 43 other choices. Admiral? General? <PERSON> Baron </PERSON>? Contess? Chief Justice? The Right Honorable Lord? The Most Reverend Archbishop? His Royal Highness? Please check all that apply. But some titles were left out _ such as president. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> went to <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION>'s archrival, <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION>. The president of the <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alumni </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Egan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, said there was nothing unusual about the survey. `` It's like the census. It's the same principle, when you're trying to determine exactly who is in that population,'' said <PERSON> Egan </PERSON>, who signed a letter accompanying the survey urging alumni to fill it out <PERSON> Egan </PERSON> said at least four chief justices of the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> were graduates of <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. He said he could think of at least two alumni who bore the title `` His royal highness.'' <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Welanetz </PERSON> said the university has many illustrious alumni, but she wondered whether the survey used the right tone. `` Perhaps it was not as well thought through as it might have been,'' she said. The information is to be compiled in a two-volume, $ 85 directory of <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION>'s 200,000-plus graduates.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>KALAMAZOO, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> professor is trying to encourage serious research on extraterrestrials by reviving a professional journal. The Journal of UFO Studies, resurrected this year from a defunct publication of the same name, aims to give researchers something `` they would n't be embarrassed by writing for,'' said its editor, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Swords </PERSON>. `` It's meant to allow the serious people to have an outlet, which does n't really exist right now. This was a hole in UFO publishing that had to be filled,'' the professor of natural sciences said recently. Swords, who is working on the second annual issue, said the $ 15 journal, with a circulation of about 700, is too technical for the general public. For example, one of the first issue's three articles of about 35 pages each discussed chemical analyses of a substance gleaned from the Delphos Case, a supposed 1971 UFO landing site in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>. Another looked at the effect of hypnosis in obtaining information from people who claim they have been abducted by aliens. Swords wrote a third article, about whether other life exists in the universe. He said it is n't a matter of if, but of how many. `` All the laws of nature are the same everywhere, and what happens once is bound to happen twice. Chances of other high-tech extraterrestrial civilizations are equal to how long it could exist after reaching the danger zone of technology. `` Since we're made it 45 years past nuclear weapons, I think people think there are at least dozens if not thousands of high-tech civilizations out there,'' Swords said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891226-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-26-89 0347EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RetirementHomeFire Bjt   12-26 0566</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Retirement Home Fire, Bjt,0583</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sprinklers Had Been Planned for Retirement Home Where 16 Died</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DUNCAN MANSFIELD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JOHNSON CITY, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Owners of a high-rise retirement home where a Christmas Eve fire killed 16 people had planned to install a sprinkler system in the spring, the manager says. `` We did n't feel uncomfortable with the safety of the building. We just had seen fires, basically on TV and other places. The comment was made that the sprinkler system would have been a benefit,'' <ORGANIZATION> Grant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trivett </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> M </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; M Properties, which manages the <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sevier </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Retirement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, said Monday night. <PERSON> Trivett </PERSON> says the <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sevier </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Partnership </ORGANIZATION>, which owns the 11-story building, was going to have sprinklers put in at a cost of $ 100,000. The 5-decade-old building did have water hoses on each floor and met the fire code in effect in 1977, when it was converted from a hotel into apartments for retirees, according to Lt. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON>, fire marshal for this eastern <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> city of 40,000. He said the current fire code requires sprinklers for buildings undergoing renovations. `` We inherit these buildings,'' <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> said. `` They're no more dangerous, it just means they do n't meet the present codes ... Legally they do n't have to.'' The fire broke out Sunday evening on the first or second floor of the building, where about 145 people lived, and sent thick smoke billowing through the upper floors. Officials said the deaths occurred on the upper floors, probably because of smoke inhalation. About 50 people were injured, including about 15 firefighters. The cause of the fire was under investigation, but <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> said it appeared accidental. In October, a resident of the home died when a kerosene heater, apparently mistakenly filled with gasoline, ignited his apartment. After that fire, Assistant Fire Chief <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Souder </PERSON> said, he stepped up pressure on the owners to install sprinklers. `` I feel like if a building is sprinkled and if the sprinkler is working properly then we would n't have had life loss,'' said <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON>. Sunday's disaster might have been worse had so many residents not been away for Christmas, said Mayor P.C. <PERSON> Snapp </PERSON>. `` I ca n't think of a worse time, on Christmas Eve,'' <PERSON> Snapp </PERSON> said. `` On the other hand, it could have been a good time because a number of people had gone to visit relatives.'' Fourteen victims lived in the building and the two others were visiting residents. Residents of upper floors waved flashlights and screamed for help from the windows of their smoke-filled apartments. `` We could hear some people over there screaming, ` We ca n't hold out much longer!' then all at once we did n't hear them anymore,'' said <PERSON> Alex </PERSON> <PERSON> Hambric </PERSON>, whose 77-year-old mother was rescued from her ninth-floor apartment. Up to 250 firefighters fought the blaze, which took about nearly seven hours to control. Some of them suffered frostbite. Most of the injured were treated for smoke inhalation and released. At least one person was seriously burned, said <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Blevins </PERSON>, spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Northside </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. Ten of 11 residents who had been listed as missing Monday have been accounted for. The 11th person is believed to have been away at the time. The fire marshal said he did n't know if owners plan to renovate the building or tear it down. He said it appeared to be structurally sound. <PERSON> Trivett </PERSON>, the building manager, said, `` If it's renovated, it will be renovated to today's codes.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891226-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-26-89 0342EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Romania-Chronology     12-26 0381</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Romania-Chronology,0401</SECOND>
<HEAD>Romania's 11-Day Revolution</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Romania, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BUCHAREST, Romania (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Key events in the <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>'s popular uprising:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
