<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890916-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-89 0203EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-MineAccident     09-16 0517</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mine Accident,0534</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mourners Honor The Dead; Investigation Delayed By Methane</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL DE LA GARZA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MORGANFIELD, Ky. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hundreds of people filled a school auditorium Friday night to remember with prayer and hymns the 10 victims of Wednesday's <ORGANIZATION> Pyro </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mining </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> disaster. Gov. <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilkinson </PERSON> said Kentuckians in general, and the families of <ORGANIZATION> Pyro </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mining </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> miners in particular, `` share in the immense grief.'' `` Tragedies like this one ... make us mindful of the fragile nature of the thread that holds us together,'' <PERSON> Wilkinson </PERSON> said during the service at <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> near this western <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> community. The auditorum, with seating for 700, appeared to be nearly filled. A large wreath with yellow mums and white carnations backed the podium onstage, with more flowers and ferns and a candle for each of the victims in the foreground. An <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> flag was at one side of the stage and the crowd sang `` Amazing Grace.'' In the investigation of <LOCATION> William </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Station </LOCATION> mine, near <LOCATION> Wheatcroft </LOCATION>, was delayed as officials of Pyro and state and federal agencies attempted to clear explosive levels of methane that persisted around the explosion site. Investigators entered the mine Friday afternoon in an attempt to reduce the hazardous methane levels. Officials of the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Mine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> approved, with modifications, a company plan for reducing methane levels, said <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON>, spokeswoman for <ORGANIZATION> MSHA </ORGANIZATION>. If the plan is successful, officials will remain underground and the probe will begin, she said. Earlier Friday, the head of a public-interest law firm said <PERSON> Pyro </PERSON> and federal authorities failed to prevent the disaster, even though there were plenty of warning signs. This year, federal inspectors briefly shut down the William Station Mine because of `` imminent dangers,'' said <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Davitt </PERSON> <PERSON> McAteer </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Occupational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. Pyro reported 267 accidents at the underground mine since 1985, but failed to report several others, <PERSON> McAteer </PERSON> said. Last year, for example, an <ORGANIZATION> MSHA </ORGANIZATION> audit of mine records revealed <PERSON> Pyro </PERSON> did not report eight accidents at <LOCATION> William </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Station </LOCATION>, seven of which forced workers to miss work, <PERSON> McAteer </PERSON> said. Accidents also went unreported the two previous years, he said. <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Calman </PERSON>, a Pyro spokesman, refused to discuss the company's safety record He said <PERSON> Pyro </PERSON> would reserve further comment until company, state and federal officials completed their investigation of the accident, which was expected to take several weeks. <PERSON> McAteer </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> MSHA </ORGANIZATION> was too lenient on Pyro after it discovered blatant safety violations at William Station. He said <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Station </PERSON> had a coal-dust explosion in September 1988, which injured two miners, and a methane ignition three months later, which injured no one. In 1985, one miner was electrocuted at the mine and another died in an explosion, he said. The following year, another miner died at <LOCATION> William </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Station </LOCATION>, although <PERSON> McAteer </PERSON> said the report submitted to <ORGANIZATION> MSHA </ORGANIZATION> by the company did n't specify a cause of death. <ORGANIZATION> MSHA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Gorman </PERSON>, who could not immediately verify that <PERSON> Pyro </PERSON> failed to report some accidents, denied <PERSON> McAteer </PERSON>'s claim that his agency did not properly police <PERSON> Pyro </PERSON> was `` totally false.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890916-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-89 0549EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Germany-FreedomFlight     09-16 0708</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Germany-Freedom Flight,0730</SECOND>
<HEAD>East Germans Say Lack of Freedom and Economic Reforms Forced Them
to Leave</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Refugess</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GIRARD C. STEICHEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TIEFENBACH, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For 12 years, <PERSON> Guenter </PERSON> <PERSON> Bachmann </PERSON> worked as a loading dock supervisor at a state cooperative in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. Then he got tired of not being able to say what he really thought. Last week, <PERSON> Bachmann </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Sabina </PERSON>, packed the family car with a few belongings and headed for <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> to join thousands of their countrymen streaming to the West over <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s border with <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>. `` It just hit me all of a sudden,'' the heavy-set 33-year-old <PERSON> Bachmann </PERSON> said outside a refugee camp in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s picturesque Bavarian countryside. `` I just finally had enough of never being able to say what I really thought, and there was no hint it was ever going to change.'' The estimated 14,000 East Germans who fled to the West via <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> in the past week come from all walks of life, ranging from laborers to tradesmen, from bakers to doctors and lawyers. Their exodus occurred amid increasing pressure for democratic reforms across <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, which has rejected the need for economic and political reforms under way in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> enjoys the best standard of living in the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc, but shortages are an aggravating fact of daily life. Dissent quickly is silenced by security forces. Demonstrators demanding democracy routinely are beaten and jailed. Public dissatisfaction in the hard-line <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> nation of 16 million has mounted steadily. According to the West German Ministry for Inter-German Affairs, 74 percent of East Germans who have come to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> since August left because of a lack of freedom of expression and human rights. The discontent is causing <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> to lose some of its best workers in the country's biggest drain of talent since the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall went up in 1961. A ministry report published Thursday said 55 percent of East German refugees who have come to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> since August are between 18 and 30 years old, and 86 percent have high levels of job training. The survey said the majority enjoyed relatively comfortable lifestyles in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. Nearly all owned a television, more than half of them color. Sixty-one percent owned cars, according to the report. But it was n't enough to keep them in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. `` When you read the state-owned newspapers, you feel like they really must take you for a fool,'' said <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> <PERSON> Dengler </PERSON>, a chemical engineering student from <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION>, who was interviewed after crossing into the West. `` The paper declares one production success after another and <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s commitment to human rights, while in reality you still have to wait 15 years for what passes for a car and land in jail if you show a banner praising Soviet glasnost.'' <PERSON> Hermann </PERSON> <PERSON> Knorr </PERSON>, 25, said he decided to leave out of frustration at not being able to change the system. `` You talk and talk in small groups and nothing ever happens,'' said <PERSON> Knorr </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> member who was close to finishing a law degree in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>. `` When I finally gave up and tried to organize -LRB- illegal -RRB- discussion groups, the state security paid me a visit.'' <PERSON> Knorr </PERSON> said he had wanted to stay in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> but `` lost all hope.'' Many young refugees said the aggravations of daily life became unbearable when added to severe travel restrictions to the West and lack of free expression. `` When I applied for an apartment of my own, I was told that the wait would be 10 years,'' said <PERSON> Heidi </PERSON> <PERSON> Brueckl </PERSON>, who was a medical assistant in <LOCATION> Gera </LOCATION>. `` I get along with my parents all right, but I do n't think I need to live with them until I'm 35. I want to be able to live my own life.'' <PERSON> Anna </PERSON> <PERSON> Schroetter </PERSON>, a 27-year-old textile worker form <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION>, said she was proud of some of the achievements of her country, especially social programs that guaranteed free day care and other services. `` But what good is day care and kindergarten when your children are drilled full of ideological nonsense? What good are guarantees of a job when you have no real say in the work place?'' she asked.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890916-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-89 0218EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-MemphisPyramid 1stLd-Writethru a0735 09-16 0422</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Memphis Pyramid, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0735,0429</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dick Clark Plans Hall of Fame in Pyramid</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: New throughout with party postponed due to rain.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WOODY BAIRD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEMPHIS, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rock' n' roll pioneer <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> said Friday he's donating hundreds of videotapes, films and other memorabilia for a music museum in a 30-story pyramid being built along the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. `` I've got a great collection of stuff to share,'' <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>'s announcement was to have kicked off a night of parades, music and fireworks to mark the start of construction of the $ 56 million pyramid, intended as the centerpiece of a $ 200 million tourist theme park billed as a musical Disneyland. Then it rained, and the party was postponed 24 hours, leaving thousands of would-be revelers wandering aimlessly past soggy beer and souvenir stands, and the empty soundstages set up for street-party bands. Promoters had promised for weeks that the celebration, called The Big Dig, would be the biggest party <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> had ever seen. But <PERSON> Sidney </PERSON> <PERSON> Shlenker </PERSON>, the man who will run the pyramid, said wet electronics made the affair too dangerous. Major events of The Big Dig included a fireworks display with a ton of explosives and a laser-light show outlining the shape of the 321-foot pyramid. Police said they had expected up to 100,000 spectators for the show but were unable to count the sparse crowd that showed up because it was too scattered through downtown. `` We're going to have the whole show tomorrow night,'' <PERSON> Shlenker </PERSON> said. `` It just got to a point tonight that the decision got taken out of our hands. It rained so hard that we've got pools of water. It's just too dangerous with the electrical equipment to risk peoples' lives.'' A late-night rock' n' roll concert featuring comedian <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Aykroyd </PERSON> and his <ORGANIZATION> Blues </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Review </ORGANIZATION> was to go on as scheduled at an amphitheater on the city's <LOCATION> Mud </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> tourist park near the pyramid site. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, who helped usher in rock' n' roll with his TV show `` American Bandstand,'' said the museum will be a hall of fame linked to his annual American Music Awards. The museum will include computerized displays with recordings and videotapes of the nation's musical past `` You'll be able to punch up a date and find out what musically was happening, what world events were happening and what it meant to your life,'' <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> said. The concrete and stainless steel pyramid is scheduled to open in May 1991. It is called `` The Great American Pyramid.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890916-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-89 0600EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-EnrollmentEnticement     09-16 0265</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Enrollment Enticement,0273</SECOND>
<HEAD>Officials Use Prizes To Boost Attendance</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MILWAUKEE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Schools offered free pizza, door prizes and even chauffeured transporation to lure students to class for a head count that will determine the size of state aid payments. At <ORGANIZATION> Parkman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Middle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Principal </PERSON> <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Schumacher </PERSON> gave away portable radios, movie tickets and restaurant certificates. Victory elementary school invited parents to a picnic. The idea was to get as many youngsters as possible in school Friday, the day set by the state for deciding its per-student distribution of financial assistance among districts throughout the state. <ORGANIZATION> Milwaukee </ORGANIZATION> school district spokesman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Begel </PERSON> said Thursday's enrollment figure was about 96,500 Official figures for Friday were to be announced Monday. The <ORGANIZATION> Milwaukee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> expects to get $ 2,300 per student. At <PERSON> Burdick </PERSON> school, principal <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Schleck </PERSON> arranged to have one youngster chauffeured to and from school, saying he was a transfer from another school and had not yet been assigned a bus route. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Peters </PERSON>, principal at <ORGANIZATION> Custer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, urged each student to `` bring a dropout to school.'' `` I told them that it was an excellent way for each of them to help their peers have a better future,'' <PERSON> Peters </PERSON> said. School officials spent the last two weeks tracking students who did not show up on opening day with telephone calls and visits to their homes. On opening day at <ORGANIZATION> Vincent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, 400 fewer students than expected showed up, principal <PERSON> Kery </PERSON> <PERSON> Kafka </PERSON> said. Since then, enrollment has increased by 210, enough to ensure that the school will not lose any teachers, she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890916-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-89 0603EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     09-16 0799</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0833</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Theater critics stung Sting for his stage debut in `` The Threepenny Opera,'' but some in the black-tie audience found the British pop star's performance dazzling. `` Slow and turgid stuff,'' complained <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Richards </PERSON>, who said Sting's `` acting has little resonance and his singing voice is surprisingly thin.'' Sting said that President and Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who watched from box seats above the National Theater stage Thursday night, congratulated him backstage on his performance. Sting played <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> the Knife in the pre-Broadway premiere of <PERSON> Bertolt </PERSON> <PERSON> Brecht </PERSON>'s biting musical satire. Soviet Ambassador <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> Dubinin </PERSON>, who joined <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> backstage during an intermission, said he was delighted with the play. He also seemed to appreciate the chance to talk with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The curtain for the final act was delayed when the two men stepped aside for an animated conversation alone. `` We did n't know if we were going to have a peace treaty ending the Cold War or a third act,'' one cast member said later. The show is scheduled to open at the Lunt-Fontanne Theater in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> on Nov. 5 after a four-week run at the National.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Entertainer <PERSON> Sammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> says he'll fight throat cancer with radiation treatments and without cigarettes. The 63-year-old singer, dancer and actor said he's been a heavy smoker since he was 14. He quit 10 days ago. `` I'm going cold <LOCATION> turkey </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said. When the urge strikes, `` I put something else in my mouth. Candy, Life Savers, anything.'' <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said the prognosis for his recovery is strong. `` It's just radiation, not cutting, so the voice box wo n't come out. Thank God it's localized in one area,'' he said Thursday night from <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tahoe </LOCATION>. A throat abnormality was detected recently during <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>' annual medical examination and was diagnosed as cancer by Dr. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Sugerman </PERSON>, <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Lipsman </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Sugerman </PERSON> expects <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> to recover completely from the cancer, <PERSON> Lipsman </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ORLANDO, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Downey </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, who encouraged abuse from his audience as a television talk show host, will be trying to tickle funny bones in his new role as a country singer on a TV sitcom. <ORGANIZATION> SYS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a newly formed company based in central <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, announced that <PERSON> Downey </PERSON> also will return as a TV talk show host and on a drive-time radio program. SYS President <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> said the company is offering for syndication `` That's My Dad,'' in which <PERSON> Downey </PERSON> will star as a country singer living in <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, with his three daughters. The company also is trying to syndicate the talk show, called `` America Talks with <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Downey </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>'' <PERSON> Downey </PERSON>'s old TV show, canceled in July by <ORGANIZATION> MCA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> after declining ratings, often was trashed by critics. `` I was always a kinder, gentler Mort, but the critics never saw it,'' <PERSON> Downey </PERSON>, 55, said Thursday. `` But the audience always did.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SYRACUSE, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A group of <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> students angered by <ORGANIZATION> NFL </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fame </ORGANIZATION> running back <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>'s comments about women picketed a campus bookstore where he signed copies of his book, `` Out of Bounds.'' The students said <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> had made sexist comments in his book and to a local newspaper columnist. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> met with the students Friday and later appeared with them at a conciliatory news conference. `` I feel very strongly about everything these students stand for and as I travel I will make mention of these things,'' he said. `` All women should be respected. All people should be respected,'' said <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, who played for <LOCATION> Syracuse </LOCATION> between 1954-1956 and retired from the <ORGANIZATION> NFL </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Browns </ORGANIZATION> as the league's all-time leading rusher. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>'s comments `` were things about younger women being better than older women, that women do n't need an education, about women's role in marriage,'' said senior <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> <PERSON> DiGennaro </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> apologized for the remarks, but did not recant them. `` My personal preference is my personal preference,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former heavyweight boxing champion <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Frazier </PERSON> plans to handle the hits with his voice instead of his fists when he returns to the stage next month in <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Frazier </PERSON> is taking his rhythm-and-blues act to the <ORGANIZATION> Claridge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hotel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Casino on Oct. 6 and 7. `` I've been doing it off and on for years and years,'' <PERSON> Frazier </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Frazier </PERSON> recently was in a car accident that caused soreness in his back and legs. He may wear a neck brace for the performance, which also will star friend <PERSON> Sonny </PERSON> <PERSON> Averona </PERSON>. Smokin' <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> said he remembers singing with his family in church and outside his house at Friday and Saturday night barbecues. `` We all sang together,'' <PERSON> Frazier </PERSON> said. `` Mama, if you did n't strike a note right in church, she'd say, ` What's wrong with you? when you'd get home.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890916-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-89 0607EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lite     09-16 0166</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lite,0170</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ashrita Furman bounced 13 miles on a pogo stick to celebrate his 35th birthday, and dedicated the apparently record-breaking hop to his guru. `` I used to be a totally unathletic nerd, but then I got involved in meditation,'' said <PERSON> Furman </PERSON>, whose birthday is today. His guru is Sri Chinmoy. According to the 1988 Guinness Book of World Records, <PERSON> Furman </PERSON> holds the previous record for distance pogo-jumping -LRB- 11.3 miles -RRB- and for pogoing under water -LRB- 3 hours and 40 minutes beneath the <LOCATION> Amazon </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>. -RRB- <PERSON> Furman </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> native, said he bounced 10 miles around a running track in a park Friday, then bopped up Third Avenue three miles to the Empire State Building, wearing out two heavy-duty pogo sticks during the day. The building's managers were unmoved by <PERSON> Furman </PERSON>'s record-breaking plans and refused him permission to hop up the skyscraper's steps. <PERSON> Furman </PERSON> set the earlier distance record by pogo-ing up and down <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fuji </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890916-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-89 0053EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-CaspianEarthquake     09-16 0145</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Caspian Earthquake,130</SECOND>
<HEAD>Strong Earthquake Occurs in Caspian Sea</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A strong earthquake has occurred in the <LOCATION> Caspian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> several hundred miles from the site of a quake that killed thousands in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION> last year, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Geological Survey says. The tremor occurred at 10:05 p.m. EDT Friday about 90 miles east of <LOCATION> Baku </LOCATION>, the capital of <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Azerbaidzhan </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Finley </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> USGS </ORGANIZATION> here, said early today. Monitors at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Earthquake </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Golden </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, measured the quake at 6.6 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale, <PERSON> Finley </PERSON> said. There were no reports of casualties or injuries, although an earthquake of that magnitude has potential to cause severe damage, said <PERSON> Finley </PERSON>. About 400 miles east of the epicenter of the tremor, a quake measuring 6.9 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale killed about 25,000 people in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION> last Dec. 7.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890916-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-89 0231EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Congress-Drugs Bjt   09-16 0566</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress-Drugs, Bjt,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush `Flexible' as Drug Talks Start; Jackson Rips Drug Plan</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, anxious for money to launch the war on drugs, says he is ready to deal with <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Democrats seeking to expand the program by $ 2.2 billion now and enlarge it in the future. `` We're flexible in terms of the funding method,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said at a White House luncheon Friday. `` But I strongly believe we must return the integrated elements of this drug strategy which took more than six months to develop.'' His comment came as a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> bipartisan task force came away from two hours of negotiations Friday with Republicans promising to present a fresh financing plan when talks resume Monday. Meanwhile, the Rev. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> select committee on narcotics the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> plan `` does not match the breadth of this social crisis'' and urged summit-style talks to draw up a new version. In the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, the Democratic plan to generate an additional $ 2.2 billion through a half-percent, across-the-board cut in federal programs remained part of a money bill for transportation programs awaiting final floor action. The administration opposes the idea, offered by <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appropriations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, which would slice $ 1.8 billion from the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s `` We ca n't afford to sacrifice our military preparedness,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said Friday. Democrats were confident following the initial session of the task force made up of nine <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> and nine Democratic senators. `` It was a good step,'' <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> told a news conference. Democrats said, however, that money agreements reached now would be only a start on the drug war and that they have fundamental disagreements with the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration over what its size and scale should be. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, D-Del., said Democrats eventually want to expand the attack on cocaine dealers beyond what has been envisioned thus far by Republicans and provide more treatment and education National drug policy director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, author of the drug plan, says it most likely will be expanded in the future and an updated version is due in February. He also says the administration's request is a sharp increase over a drug-fighting budget that was only $ 2 billion three years ago. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> drew applause and scattered shouts of approval from spectators as he told the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> select committee on narcotics the nation needs `` a new initiative equal to the scope and depth of the problem.'' He criticized the plan for lack of enforcement strength, aid for the poor and input from national and community leaders with experience in fighting drugs. He said a meeting at the Camp David presidential retreat should be convened to redraw the strategy. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was sharply critical of both <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> and the president. `` In April, Mr. <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> announced that he would take comprehensive emergency action to attack the drug crisis in the nation's capital,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said. `` Five months later, we still have the emergency but no action.'' `` President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> announced a drug plan for <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>. Where is his plan for the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> and cities around the nation?'' he said. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, reported to be weighing a race for mayor of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, suggested the nation's capital could be a model for fighting the drug scourge. He was asked what his role in that effort would be. `` A volunteer,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890916-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-89 0233EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-QuickAIDSTest Bjt   09-16 0611</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quick AIDS Test, Bjt,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>New AIDS Test Gives Results, On The Spot, In 10 Minutes</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Patients worried they may be infected with the AIDS virus will be able to get a quick and confidential answer soon with a simple test that takes only 10 minutes. The test, now undergoing trials at nine centers, will enable people to get results quickly in a doctor's office instead of having to wait to hear from a distant laboratory. `` It provides a new means for patients to learn of their AIDS status and still retain anonymity,'' said <PERSON> Jarel </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelsey </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Murex </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> Norcross </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, firm that developed the test. `` Once this method is widely available, it will encourage more people to determine their status.'' Tests for AIDS now require that blood be drawn and sent to a laboratory for complex processing. Patients must wait to find out if they have contracted the human immunodeficiency virus, or HIV, which causes acquired immune deficiency syndrome, or AIDS. `` That can take a number of days sometimes,'' said <PERSON> Kelsey </PERSON>. Concern about whether the test information will be kept confidential and the long wait for results discourage some people from being tested for AIDS, even though they may be at risk for the disease, he said. The new test, called SUDS for single use diagnostic system, takes away some of that anxiety. It consists of a small plastic disk, slightly thicker than a camera lens cap, that is filled with an absorbent material. A cone-shaped indention on top leads down to a small hole that exposes the absorbent material. A SUDS test starts with a blood sample obtained from a simple finger stick. Two drops of serum, the clear fluid in blood, are separated from the sample and then combined with two reactant solutions. The mixture is poured into the cone of the test cartridge. Inside the tester, the sample mixture is absorbed and pulled through a color reactant. If a dot on the bottom of the disk remains white, there is no AIDS virus. A blue dot means an AIDS infection. The whole process takes about 10 minutes. <PERSON> Kelsey </PERSON> said the system works through the use of microscopic latex beads that are coated with proteins that react to AIDS antibodies. An antibody is a molecule in the blood produced by the body's immune system to attack specific invaders, such as bacteria or virus. The proteins used in SUDS react to antibodies created by the immune system in response to both the outer membrane and the core of the HIV virus. SUDS is being tested at selected doctors' offices, sexual disease clinics, hospitals and blood banks. The trials started in July and more than 5,000 tests have been conducted. `` The trials so far have shown an average accuracy rate of 99.8 percent,'' said <PERSON> Kelsey </PERSON>. `` Any specimen that has evidence of AIDS antibody has been detected by the system so we are really achieving levels of 100 percent sensitivity.'' Clinical trials of SUDS end in October and the <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> is expected to approve a license quickly, <PERSON> Kelsey </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Brad </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> said the agency does not announce its intentions ahead of time and will have to study the data. But he noted, `` We recognize the need to get any test for AIDS out as soon as possible.'' Although the SUDS test is very simple to conduct, <PERSON> Kelsey </PERSON> said it will not be sold for home use. `` Everybody is aware that exposure to the HIV is a terminal condition,'' he said. `` Having that information revealed without counseling immediately available could be a traumatic experience.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890916-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-89 0238EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush     09-16 0585</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>President Rules Out Expanding Ban on Assault Rifles</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is standing by his opposition to a federal ban on assault weapons, saying he doubts such a law `` could ever safeguard'' against a tragedy like the shooting rampage in <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION> `` I have seen no evidence that banning a specific weapon is going to guard against it,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said Friday, referring to the shooting spree in a printing plant the day before that left eight dead and 13 wounded. The president, at a news conference, called the shootings the work of a deranged individual and said, `` It is terrible, and the loss of human life is horrible.'' But <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, a life member of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rifle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said instead of enacting new laws, `` we must do everything we can to enforce laws that are already on the books.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was spending the weekend at the presidential retreat in Camp David, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, before heading west on a two-day trip next week. He will participate in bicentennial ceremonies in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> on Monday. At the news conference for out-of-town reporters, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also: _ Repeated his opposition to raising federal taxes to pay for the war against drugs, but said he would not criticize state or local governments that did so _ Said the nation's education system `` is not making the grade'' and hoped his Sept. 27-28 education summit with the nation's governors would lead to national educational goals and objectives for _ Rejected a suggestion that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> divert funds from its contribution to <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> to pay for the drug war `` Let's not let down our alliance guarantees because we are more optimistic about peace,'' he said. _ Indicated he was giving `` serious and active'' consideration to using former military bases to house prisoners from overcrowded prisons <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was asked what he would tell the families of victims of Thursday's shooting spree in a <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION> printing plant in which a worker with several automatic weapons went from floor to floor shooting down former co-workers. `` I'd tell them I feel horrible about the loss of life.'' But, he added, `` I would tell them I do n't think banning weapons is going to be the ultimate answer or could ever safeguard against that kind of tragedy.'' He recalled automatic weapons were not involved in the 1966 shooting spree by <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitman </PERSON>, who climbed to the top of a tower at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION> with three rifles, two pistols and a shotgun. He shot 44 people, killing 14, before being killed himself. He also said that in the 1960s, when he was a member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION>, he went to a police station in the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> to register `` my arsenal'' of a rifle and a shotgun to comply with the law. `` The guy looked at me like I'd lost his mind,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, adding that only a small percentage of gun owners were complying with the law. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he asked the officer if police were `` getting a lot of criminals to turn their guns in? `` He said, ` No. It's just a bunch of suckers like you from <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.' And it made a profound impression on me.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> banned the import of foreign-made assault rifles into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, including the AK-47, the weapon used in <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION>. However, possession of these weapons is not a federal offense, nor does the import ban prevent them from being manufactured domestically.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890916-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-89 0242EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NuclearSatellite     09-16 0480</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nuclear Satellite,470</SECOND>
<HEAD>NASA Gets Go-Ahead For Controversial Probe Launch</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> has White House approval to proceed with its much-debated October launch of a nuclear-powered satellite to <LOCATION> Jupiter </LOCATION>. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s science adviser, <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bromley </PERSON>, signed the authorization Friday which is required before a nuclear device is put into space. <PERSON> Bromley </PERSON> had the president's approval, said <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Alixe </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> Administrator <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Truly </PERSON> was informed, she said. The mission would have been scrubbed had White House approval been withheld. Critics worried about nuclear fallout in case of an accident will ask a court to stop the launch, and promise to try to put their bodies in the way if that does n't work. The Galileo probe will be sent on its eight-year, $ 1.4 billion mission from the cargo bay of the space shuttle <LOCATION> Atlantis </LOCATION> _ the first time nuclear power has been carried on a shuttle. The three men and two women who will be on the Oct. 12 mission were in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> today for a breakfast with Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> at his residence. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, who intends to be at the Kennedy Space Center for the liftoff, heads the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> and was particularly interested in meeting the astronauts because shuttle commander <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> is from <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s home state. Protesters claim a Challenger-like accident could poison Earth's atmosphere with `` the most toxic substance in the universe. They are preparing to file suit in federal court to stop the mission and a protest march is scheduled to begin at <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canaveral </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> on Sunday. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Gagnon </PERSON>, a leader in the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>, said `` we are going to attempt to enter the launch area and sit on the launch pad.'' He has written that `` Plutonium 238 is the most toxic substance in the universe. If ingested, it concentrates in the bone marrow where it can cause leukemia. If inhaled, it sticks to the lungs, where it can lead to cancer.'' The Galileo spacecraft was originally scheduled for launch in January 1982 but was delayed time and again. It is outfitted with two radioisotope thermoelectric generators to produce the electricity for the spacecraft, science instruments and engineering support systems. Of the 22 <ORGANIZATION> RTGs </ORGANIZATION> used on previous missions, three have been involved in accidents _ one releasing 17,000 curies of radioactive material 75 miles high over the <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION>. The generators use the heat from the radioactive decay of plutonium-238 dioxide to generate electricity. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> estimates the probability of having a launch accident that results in the release of plutonium into the atmosphere is one in 2,800. RTGs similar to the ones on Galileo provided the power for Voyager 2, which recently sent back spectacular views of the planet <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION>. Voyager 2, launched in 1977, was the last spacecraft carrying a nuclear power source.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890916-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-89 0243EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MemphisPyramid     09-16 0297</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Memphis Pyramid,0306</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pyramid Celebration Postponed by Rain</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WOODY BAIRD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEMPHIS, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rainshowers canceled a huge shindig to celebrate the construction of a 30-story pyramid, but organizers said they would try again after mopping up flooded beer stands and stages set up for street-party bands. The party will go on tonight, weather permitting. `` It just got to a point tonight that the decision got taken out of our hands. It rained so hard that we've got pools of water,'' developer <PERSON> Sidney </PERSON> <PERSON> Shlenkler </PERSON> said Friday. Promoters had promised for weeks that the event would be the biggest party <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> had ever seen. Police had expected up to 100,000 people, and several thousand would-be revelers showed up despite the downpour. At a luncheon to kick off the celebration, rock' n' roll pioneer <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> announced he will supply hundreds of videotapes, films and other memorabilia for a music museum in the pyramid. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, who helped popularize rock' n' roll with his TV show American Bandstand, said the music hall of fame will be linked to his annual American Music Awards show and include computerized displays with recordings and videotapes of the nation's musical past. The stainless steel pyramid, which is being built along the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, is intended as the centerpiece of a $ 200 million tourist theme park billed as a musical <ORGANIZATION> Disneyland </ORGANIZATION> and scheduled to open in May 1991. The pyramid and music park are being financed largely through public funds and developed primarily by <PERSON> Shlenker </PERSON>, who helped develop the <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> Astrodome, and by international businessman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tigrett </PERSON>. <PERSON> Shlenker </PERSON> likes to compare the pyramid with the Eiffel Tower and the Statue of Liberty and said he expects the music theme park to eventually draw up to 3 million tourists a year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890916-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-89 0244EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HUD-Pierce     09-16 0444</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-HUD-Pierce,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pierce Likely Faces Subpoena; One Lawmaker Wants Special Prosecutor</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The attorney for <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> says he'll try to convince a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee not to subpoena the former housing secretary, but lawmakers say <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s refusal to appear voluntarily leaves them no choice. The chairman of the panel investigating abuses at the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> said Friday he would ask members to approve a subpoena next week. Republicans joined majority Democrats in saying they would support the request. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Perito </PERSON>, said he would try to convince the subcommittee next week to give <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> two weeks to prepare and then allow him to testify voluntarily. In another development, Rep. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Conn </LOCATION>., asked the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Friday to ask Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> to name a special prosecutor and have a grand jury investigate actions at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> during <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s tenure There was no immediate action on the request. The House Government Operations subcommittee on housing and employment subcommittee denied <PERSON> Perito </PERSON>'s request Friday for a two-week extension for <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> to testify. `` I am at a loss to understand why there is such a concern for speed over truth,'' said <PERSON> Perito </PERSON>. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> told the subcommittee Thursday evening he would not appear the next morning, prompting a number of verbal attacks from the panel's members. `` We have no option but to proceed in teaching Mr. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> that while he may run, he may not hide,'' said subcommittee Chairman <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON>, D-Calif. `` Not only is Silent <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> silent, apparently today he's also invisible,'' added Rep. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> `` Buz'' <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> R-Ohio </LOCATION>, using the derogatory nickname <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> acquired for his low-profile demeanor as secretary during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration The subpoena vote is scheduled for Wednesday, but it was unclear when the panel would demand that <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> appear. <PERSON> Perito </PERSON> said <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> most likely would comply with any subpoena but left open the possibility of fighting an order if it gave <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> less than two weeks to prepare. `` You can be assured that I will consider all options,'' <PERSON> Perito </PERSON> said. The panel is investigating allegations that prominent Republicans and former <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> officials got favored treatment from the agency under <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, some making huge profits as consultants obtaining multimillion-dollar federal housing contracts. The department also is still unable to account for millions of dollars in connection with projects and home sales during <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s eight years as secretary Critics blame poor management. <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials have said more than 1,000 HUD-related cases are being reviewed by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorneys around the country, and there have been a handful of criminal and civil cases filed in recent months.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890916-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-89 0247EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AutoDefects     09-16 0534</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Auto Defects,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Agency Upgrades Ford Seat Belt Probe, Opens Others</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN FLESHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government is intensifying its investigations of possibly defective seat belts in <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aerostar </ORGANIZATION> vans and of bus arm rests blamed for injuries to nine people in a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> accident. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> also announced a new investigation Friday of <ORGANIZATION> Mazda </ORGANIZATION> seat belts and 10 other new investigations of cars, mobile homes, utility vehicles and motorcycles made by <PERSON> Chevrolet </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Pontiac </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Yamaha </ORGANIZATION>, Jeep, <ORGANIZATION> Porsche </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Jaguar </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Isuzu </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON>, Mobile and <LOCATION> Kawasaki </LOCATION>. Such investigations are used to determine whether to order a recall of the vehicles. The agency said it had upgraded its examination of Aerostars manufactured between 1986 and 1988 from a paperwork analysis to an engineering analysis, which involves studying the allegedly defective parts. The <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> opened a preliminary evaluation in December 1988 after receiving seven complaints of fraying front-seat, passenger-side seat belts. `` Something sharp is rubbing against the belt, apparently,'' said agency spokesman <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Hurd </PERSON>. The agency conducted a survey and detected other cases of fraying but no injuries resulting from the problem, <PERSON> Hurd </PERSON> said, adding, `` We're always concerned about seat belts. They double your chances of surviving a head-on collision.'' In <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Joy </PERSON> <PERSON> Stinson </PERSON> said 450,000 Aerostars were built between 1986 and 1988. Of those, 338,000 were equipped with a plastic cover that shields the seat belt from contact with the metal hinge, Ms. <PERSON> Stinson </PERSON> said. Belt fraying is believed to be limited to vans without the plastic cover, which the company began installing in 1987 to protect the hinge and improve the seat's appearance, she said. <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> also said it was upgrading to an engineering analysis a probe of 1988 <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coach </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> inter-city buses. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> requested a preliminary evaluation June 5 after a bus crashed in <LOCATION> Tinton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> Nine passengers were hurt when arm rests broke, leaving sharp edges. Also, the agency began a preliminary inquiry into other arm rests made between 1984 and 1989 by <ORGANIZATION> Wakefield </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seating </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, the manufacturer of the <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coach </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> seat rests. The <ORGANIZATION> Mazda </ORGANIZATION> probe is of seat belts in all cars the company manufactured between 1984 and 1989 following 11 complaints of 15 injuries resulting from failure to restrain passengers in accidents. <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> also reported launching preliminary evaluations of: _ Breaking buckles on <ORGANIZATION> Chevrolet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Camaros </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Pontiac </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Firebirds </ORGANIZATION> built in 1984 through 1986 The probe covers an estimated 500,000 cars. _ Malfunctioning throttle grip sticks on 1989 <ORGANIZATION> Yamaha </ORGANIZATION> FZR400 and FZR600 <ORGANIZATION> Yamaha </ORGANIZATION> motorcycles The probe covers 10,000 cycles. _ Malfunctioning rear seat belts in Jeep Cherokees, Wranglers and Wagoneers The probe covers the 1984 through 1988 model years. _ Smoke and fires under the dashboards of 1987 Porsche 924 and Porsche 944 models covering 7,500 cars _ Anti-lock brake system failures in 1987 through 1989 models of the <ORGANIZATION> Jaguar </ORGANIZATION> XJ6 _ Ball-joint failures in 50,000 1988 Isuzu Impulses after three complaints of collapsed front suspensions causing loss of vehicle control _ Power-steering failure in 1988 <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Continentals </ORGANIZATION>, covering 40,000 cars _ Detaching spare tire mounts on Mobile Class A motor homes, covering about 7,000 vehicles from 1988 and 1989 _ Detaching handlebars on 1,000 <ORGANIZATION> Kawasaki </ORGANIZATION> ZX-7 motorcycles from 1989
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890916-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-89 0248EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FishInspections     09-16 0480</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fish Inspections,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tail of a Turf Battle Over Surf Products</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT GREENE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The federal government believes it's time to inspect seafood for safety, but two agencies are arguing over just who should put the final stamp of approval on the fish. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is being asked to resolve the turf battle, which comes down to the question of whether fish are wild animals or should be treated like the chickens and cattle that are raised for food. Almost certain, however, is that the low-fat food source health-conscious Americans have been turning to in large numbers is going to come under closer government scrutiny. `` Currently many consumers are wary about the safety of fish,'' Rep. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, D-Calif. `` They have heard many stories about contamination from toxic industrial and agricultural chemicals, medical waste products and red tides. <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on health and the environment began considering legislation Friday that would have the <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> set up a comprehensive federal inspection program of the seafood industry. Contaminants for regular fish and shellfish include the botulism toxin, ciguatoxin, scombrotroxin, salmonella bacteria and the hepatitis-A virus, not to mention PCBs and other industrial contaminants. Although everyone at the hearing agreed seafood needs to be inspected, but <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>'s plan drew criticism from the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, which wants to bring fish under its meat and poultry inspection program. `` We would not have to start from scratch,'' said <PERSON> Lester </PERSON> <PERSON> Crawford </PERSON>, administrator of the food safety and inspection service at the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, noting the experience with meat and poultry. The `` principles of inspection are the same regardless of the species,'' he said. The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has been named as the inspection agency for fish in legislation since 1986, but <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>'s `` Fish and Fish Products Safety Act of 1989'' would require the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> to set safety standards. <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> Commissioner <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said it's simple: fish are not like chickens and cattle. `` Here we are capturing wild animals,'' he said. `` I do n't do this with any kind of turf comparison, but when one looks at the chicken and beef, these are animals that are raised in standard ways. They are housed and they are brought to the market in a chain that is known.'' Witnesses said that whichever government agency gets the task, consumer education should be improved because many problems deal with errors in handling seafood at home. <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Haas </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION>, a non-profit group dealing with food safety issues, said federal statistics indicate the risk of a food poisoning outbreak from eating seafood is 25 times greater than from beef, and 16 times greater than for either chicken or pork. Seafood consumption has been increasing as a result of efforts to find low-fat sources of protein. <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said there have been signs of a decline, although he said the reason was unclear.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890916-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-89 0251EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Refugees     09-16 0400</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Refugees,390</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Urges Other Nations to Take in Soviet Refugees</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is calling on other nations to ease the burden on the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> by taking in some of the recent surge of emigres from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Deputy Secretary of State <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> issued the call Friday as he defended the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration from criticism that a proposal to allow 50,000 Soviet refugees into the country in the next year is too conservative. `` I resent the implication that we have some heartless, niggardly, conservative approach to this problem,'' <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on immigration. `` But there are limits on the numbers we can take,'' he said, citing budgetary constraints and the press of refugees worldwide seeking to come to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` No budget deficit, however large, should ever induce the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to abandon or compromise in any way its fundamental values and principles'' of granting safe haven to `` oppressed peoples,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Orrin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Utah </LOCATION>. Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., chairman of the subcommittee, said the months of administration deliberations on its Soviet refugees strategy had given the impression that `` you're dealing with cans of beans rather than human beings. Some 150,000 applications for entry _ mostly from Jews and some Pentacostals _ are expected in the 1990 fiscal year. Critics say that leaves the administration's quota figure too low. For nearly 20 years the demand for liberalized Soviet emigration was a cornerstone of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy, but `` never was it said that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> has an obligation to take them all in'' if the gates open, <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> said. He said <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> should also offer entry to the Soviets, although he conceded attempts to enlist the other countries' help over the past few months had not borne fruit. `` I ca n't tell you there will be a massive willingness on the part of other countries,'' he said, `` but we'll continue trying.'' Under existing procedures, most Soviet emigres leave the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> with <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> visas but change course for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> once they reach processing centers in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>. Only about 10 percent to 15 percent go to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. To save money, the administration will shut down the <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> facilities once it clears up the backlog of an estimated 30,000 applicants there, and process all applicants in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> after Oct. 1, <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890916-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-89 0254EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NationalSecurity     09-16 0338</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-National Security,340</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Keeps Alive Suit Over Reagan Computer Files</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal judge's ruling will help ensure that presidential records are preserved for future generations, says a lawyer involved in a suit over <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration computer records. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Richey </PERSON> on Friday rejected a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration motion to dismiss the case, saying private citizens may go to court to keep the government from erasing computer records dealing with the Iran-Contra affair. <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents and congressional investigators delving into the Iran-Contra affair used thousands of messages retrieved from the system, called PROFS, in piecing together the most far-reaching scandal of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. Former White House aide <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> and former national security adviser <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> used the system, which serves as a substitute for the telephone. <PERSON> Richey </PERSON>'s decision `` goes a long way toward ensuring that ... records produced by the president'' are `` preserved for future generations so that chapters of history are not lost,'' said <PERSON> Katherine </PERSON> <PERSON> Meyer </PERSON>, one of the lawyers who filed the case. <PERSON> Richey </PERSON> said the Administrative Procedures Act empowers a private group to seek judicial review of the president's performance under the Presidential Records Act and the Federal Records Act. He gave the government and private groups and individuals filing the suit until Jan. 2 to decide how to proceed. The National Security Archive, a non-profit organization, went to court Jan. 19 after learning the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> White House was about to dispose of the contents of the PROFS computer system. On the eve of the change in administrations, a judge temporarily enjoined the government from destroying the material. It includes computer tapes of the <ORGANIZATION> NSC </ORGANIZATION> and the executive office of the president as well as back-up computer files. <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> lawyers argue most of the notes are n't presidential or agency records, but are like telephone messages The judge questioned that assertion in a 28-page opinion. `` Were telephone conversations in the Executive Branch routinely taped, a good portion would undoubtedly qualify as presidential or agency records,'' the judge said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890916-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-89 0300EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Obit-Warren     09-16 0613</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Obit-Warren,0636</SECOND>
<HEAD>Author Robert Penn Warren Dead At 84</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STRATTON, Vt. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Penn </PERSON> <PERSON> Warren </PERSON>, who won the Pulitzer Prize three times for his novels and poetry and was named the nation's first poet laureate, has died after a three-year battle with cancer. <PERSON> Warren </PERSON>, 84, died early Friday at his summer home. His wife, the author <PERSON> Eleanor </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, and a local doctor were with him, said <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, his longtime friend and <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON>'s town clerk and treasurer. Services will be private, with a public memorial service scheduled later, said a spokesman for the Covey and <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> Funeral Home in <LOCATION> Wilmington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> was the first to win Pulitzer Prizes in both poetry and fiction. The poetry prizes came in 1957 for `` Promises: Poems 1954-1956,'' and in 1979 for `` Now and Then: Poems 1976-1978.'' His novel `` All the King's Men,'' a book about the myth surrounding <PERSON> Huey </PERSON> <PERSON> Long </PERSON>, the swaggering populist governor of <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, won the Pulitzer in 1947 and became an Academy Award-winning motion picture. His other awards include the Presidential Medal of Freedom, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Literature </ORGANIZATION> and the Gold Medal for Poetry from the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> and Letters. He also was among the first recipients of the <ORGANIZATION> MacArthur </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>'s unrestricted `` genius grants. <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> was remembered as a brilliant poet, fiction writer, teacher and critic _ and as a nice man. `` He had such vigor and such love of life. He was such wonderful company _ he was the soul of hilarity,'' said novelist and short story writer <PERSON> Eudora </PERSON> <PERSON> Welty </PERSON>, whose first work was published in the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Review </ORGANIZATION> when <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> was editor in the 1930s. `` He was a good friend to writers _ constantly generous and giving.'' `` He was reticent, ironic, reserved and perfectly charming, and I loved and respected him quite apart from his work,'' said poet <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nemerov </PERSON>, who owns a copy of the first edition of <PERSON> Warren </PERSON>'s first book His fellow writers marveled at his versatility and virtuosity. `` He's astounding,'' said poet <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Bly </PERSON>. `` It's very seldom that someone can write poetry and fiction and do it well. In fiction, you take nine or ten generations and compress them; in poetry, you take 30 seconds and expand it.'' Born in <LOCATION> Guthrie </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, on April 24, 1905, <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> grew up hearing tales of the Civil War from his two grandfathers who had been Confederate soldiers. <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> graduated summa cum laude from <ORGANIZATION> Vanderbilt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in 1925, received a master's degree from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION> and studied at <ORGANIZATION> Oxford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> as a Rhodes Scholar. While teaching at <ORGANIZATION> Louisiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, he was a founder of <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Review </ORGANIZATION>. From 1938 to 1961, he was an editorial adviser to the <ORGANIZATION> Kenyon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Review </ORGANIZATION>. His first full-length novel, published in 1939, was `` Night Rider,'' about the plight of <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> tobacco growers at the turn of the century. Other works included `` At Heaven's Gate,'' `` World Enough and Time,'' `` Band of Angels,'' `` Wilderness: A Tale of the Civil War,'' and `` Flood: A Romance for Our Time.'' In 1986, <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> was appointed poet laureate, a largely ceremonial title created by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. `` The people who create these posts do n't give a damn about poetry,'' <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> said of the appointment. `` They do it because it's a nice thing to do They think ` There's a poet down the road; let's make him a poet laureate.' <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> lived the last three decades of his life in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. Before his second marriage, to Ms. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, she had suggested that they return to the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> so that their children would know his world. `` But I discovered it was n't the same world,'' <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> once said. `` I had been carrying a dream around in my head.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890916-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-89 0306EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RunawayTruck     09-16 0222</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Runaway Truck,0227</SECOND>
<HEAD>Boy In Different Place At Right Time _ Misses Being Hit By Runaway
Truck</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GAINESVILLE, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Makel </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s night away from his usual position in front of the TV set saved him from being hit by a runaway fire truck. The 11-year-old <LOCATION> Gainesville </LOCATION> boy likes to spend each night playing the <ORGANIZATION> Nintendo </ORGANIZATION> game on a television set in his bedroom. But Thursday, his older brother took the television to college with him, interrupting <PERSON> Makel </PERSON>'s nocturnal habit. The boy was in another room when the truck crashed through the bedroom wall Thursday night, his mother said. `` This is a miracle,'' said <PERSON> Clairese </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>. `` It demolished my baby's room. Thank God he was not in bed. I thank you <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> that child was not in that bed.'' Police Capt. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> said the fire truck answered a call on a steep hill near the <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s home in <LOCATION> Gainesville </LOCATION>, about 40 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. Fireman <PERSON> Boone </PERSON> <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> said he was spraying the fire when he felt his fire hose jerk. He and some bystanders chased the vehicle, which rolled down the street, crashed into the Wrights' car, plunged through their front porch and rammed into the house. It was n't the first time a vehicle had smashed into the Wrights' house Last April, a car ran into their porch.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890916-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-89 0311EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ExxonValdez Bjt   09-16 0594</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Exxon Valdez, Bjt,0615</SECOND>
<HEAD>Exxon Halts Spill Cleanup, Governor Praises `Good-Faith Effort'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRIAN S. AKRE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VALDEZ, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 On a sun-drenched day, <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> pulled out its cleanup crews for the winter and the state announced its own plan to protect fish hatcheries and untainted areas from the Exxon Valdez oil spill. `` It's a nice day for the first day of winter, is n't it?'' Gov. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Cowper </PERSON> said Friday before he announced the state's plans for a $ 21 million program `` to continue cleanup work left by <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>.'' But for that bit of sarcasm, and a crack by his spokesman about a `` dirty dozen of soiled beaches'' left by <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Cowper </PERSON> was conciliatory toward the oil company responsible for the March 24 tanker wreck that left 10.9 million gallons of crude oil in Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON>. The governor thanked the thousands of workers who helped scrub the oil-fouled shorelines, proclaiming Friday `` Oil Spill Workers Appreciation Day'' in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> pulled the crews out Friday, saying <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s early winter makes continuing field work too risky. `` I think Exxon has made a good-faith effort to clean up the beaches,'' <PERSON> Cowper </PERSON> said. `` I'm not going to fault Exxon here. They made some mistakes and, frankly, some of the things the state has done were mistakes.'' <PERSON> Cowper </PERSON> said the state should have known how to clean up a major spill. `` At least we should have known no one else knew how to do it,'' he said. <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s winter program, announced on a warm fall day when residents donned T-shirts and shorts, calls for: _ Small-scale cleanups when fish and wildlife resources are threatened by the remaining oil _ Monitoring the oil's movement and changes in its composition during the region's severe winter months _ Research and development of new ways to remove the remaining oil, most of which lies under the surface of rocky shorelines _ Protecting the region's five fish hatcheries with standby equipment and crews _ Forming a strike force of counselors and mental-health professionals to help prevent and treat stress-related problems, such as drug and alcohol abuse, in spill-affected towns Money for the program will come from the state's new 5-cent-a-barrel oil-spill response tax. <PERSON> Cowper </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> eventually will be billed for reimbursement. While <PERSON> Cowper </PERSON> had little negative to say about <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>, he showed reporters a seven-minute, state-produced video that focused on the oiled shores the company has vacated. On a nearby table were oiled rocks taken this week from what a Cowper spokesman said were soiled beaches. <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Beathard </PERSON> said later that the beaches where surface oil remains visible were the last treated with a chemical fertilizer. The fertilizer, which stimulates the oil-eating action of microorganisms, takes up to six weeks to work. State environmental officials are worried about the subsurface oil. They fear winter storms and tidal action will loosen that oil, resulting in small slicks that will pollute other areas. Although <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> has promised to monitor the oil and respond to emergencies during the fall and winter, <PERSON> Cowper </PERSON> said it remained unclear to what extent the company will work with the state. <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> has said it will re-evaluate the shorelines next spring and decide then whether to resume the cleanup on a large scale. The governor noted that some biologists alleged recently that <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>'s cleanup, which employed as many as 12,000 workers, may have done more environmental harm than good. `` That may be,'' <PERSON> Cowper </PERSON> said. `` But what was Exxon going to do? Not only was everyone barking at them to get it done, including us, they had a public relations problem.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890916-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-89 0312EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WashingtoninBrief     09-16 0730</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Washington in Brief,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kelly Urges Arabs To Drop Campaign Against Israel</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A senior <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official is calling on the Arab governments to abandon their efforts to expel <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> from the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>. That `` change in tactics'' could contribute to attempts to arrange negotiations between the Arabs and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON>, assistant secretary of state for the <LOCATION> Near </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, said Friday night. `` It is time for the Arab nations to follow the example of the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> and acknowledge <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s existence as a state. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> is entitled to membership in the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> under the principle of universality,'' <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> said in a speech before a conference on the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> at Wye Plantation in <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>. He referred to the step taken last year by <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>, who also publicly renounced terrorism. That action met <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> conditions for the dialogue opened by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> last December. `` It is time for the Arab governments to stop the anachronistic practice of voting against Israeli credentials,'' <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> said. The Arabs have consistently failed to oust <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> from the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> despite annual attempts.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Library of Congress May Become Computer Accessible</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An improved computer network could make the huge store of information in the Library of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> available to libraries and scholars across the country, says the nation's chief librarian. `` The Library of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the national library community want to help develop a national research and education network,'' <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Billington </PERSON>, the librarian of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, told a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee Friday. `` The major information resources for this nation reside in the Library of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and other research libraries across the country. These collections have been assembled in many cases with federal, state and local revenues. `` Our citizens have a right to expect that these irreplaceable intellectual resources be made ever more widely available through a national information network,'' he said. <PERSON> Billington </PERSON> testified in favor of a bill sponsored by Sen. <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, D-Tenn., which calls for the establishment of national computer-based research network <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> chairs the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> science subcommittee, which held Friday's hearing. The Library of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, with 88 million items, is the largest collection of recorded and printed information ever assembled in a single place, <PERSON> Billington </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Administration Retreats On Plan To Aid Ortega's Foes</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration has bowed to congressional pressure and abandoned its idea of aiding the presidential election campaign of Nicaraguan opposition leader <PERSON> Violetta </PERSON> <PERSON> Chamorro </PERSON> through a U.S.-financed private organization. While the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Endowment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democracy </ORGANIZATION> should play an active role in ensuring a free and fair election, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will not ask the group to go beyond election activities permitted by its charter, <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON> said Friday. <PERSON> Chamorro </PERSON> is campaigning to defeat <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>, the Nicaraguan president, in a national election next February. All <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> efforts, including past weapons shipments to anti-government rebels known as Contras, have failed to unseat the Sandinista leader. Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> ran into stiff opposition when he sounded out members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> earlier this week about providing around $ 2 million in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> funds to <PERSON> Chamorro </PERSON>, the publisher of the leading opposition newspaper, <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION>, through the endowment. <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON> said the group's charter permits it `` to support election activities in a general sense. We do n't intend to ask it to do anything that's beyond its charter.'' The group gets its money from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>League of Cities President Asks for Big Hike in Drug-Fighting</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Budget
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The federal drug-fighting budget for 1990 should be increased by $ 5 billion to $ 6 billion over the administration's proposed $ 7.9 billion and taxes should be raised to pay for it, says <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cities </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Goddard </PERSON>. <PERSON> Goddard </PERSON>, the Democratic mayor of <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>, said Friday he knows of no other way to get the new resources needed. The administration strategy will call on state and local governments to spend $ 10 billion to $ 12 billion for drug testing and prisons next year alone. `` We believe that an equivalent resource from the federal government has got to be committed,'' <PERSON> Goddard </PERSON> said. He said he is asking municipal leaders to lobby <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, where some members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> already are balking at a proposal by Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, to increase the $ 7.9 billion by $ 2.2
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890916-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-89 0226EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-CaspianQuake 1stLd-Writethru a0416 09-16 0264</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Caspian Quake, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0416,0268</SECOND>
<HEAD>Precede WASHINGTON</HEAD>
<HEAD>Quake Rocks Caspian Shore, Cracks Buildings</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: UPDATES thruout with details; no pickup.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A strong earthquake rocked the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Caspian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> area early today, cracking some buildings but apparently causing no serious damage or injuries, seismologists reported The quake occurred at 6:05 a.m. and was centered in the <LOCATION> Caspian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> about 110 miles east of <LOCATION> Baku </LOCATION>, the capital of <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Azerbaijan </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Nadezhda </PERSON> <PERSON> Molchanova </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <LOCATION> Obninsk </LOCATION> Seismic Station near <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. The Caspian Sea separates the <LOCATION> Caucasus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> region and <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>, two active seismic areas. A powerful quake Dec. 7 in western <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>, about 370 miles west of today's quake, killed 25,000 people. Monitors at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Earthquake </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Golden </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, measured the quake at 6.6 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale. The Armenian earthquake registered 6.9 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale, a gauge of the energy released by a temblor, as measured by the ground motion recorded on a seismograph. A quake measuring 6 can cause severe damage and a temblor measuring 7 can cause widespread, heavy damage. Ms. <PERSON> Molchanova </PERSON> said there were no immediate reports of casualties. She said the quake registered 7 on the Soviet earthquake scale in <LOCATION> Krasnovodsk </LOCATION>, a city on the eastern shore of the <LOCATION> Caspian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Turkmenia </LOCATION>. The Soviet scale is based on observable effects of an earthquake. A quake registering 7 is regarded as `` very strong,'' capable of making cracks in stone walls. It registered at 5 in <LOCATION> Baku </LOCATION>, strong enough to wake the sleeping and shake furniture.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890916-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-89 0235EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-BRF--PlaneCrash 1stLd-Writethru a0429 09-16 0177</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Plane Crash, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0429,0176</SECOND>
<HEAD>Six Killed in Plane Crash</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 5th graf to CORRECT hometown of pilot to Georgia sted Florida
and spelling of Sanders' first name to Terry sted Harry</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MAYFIELD, Ky. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A twin-engine plane crashed in an open field in rain and fog Friday night, killing all six people aboard, police said. The Beechcraft BE-10 apparently was headed for a landing at the <LOCATION> Mayfield-Graves </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> airport when it crashed northeast of the site, a state police dispatcher said. She blamed poor weather on the crash. `` This is a real nasty night,'' said the dispatcher, who declined to be identified. She said the plane was arriving from <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, but had no details. The victims were identified as pilot <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Haag </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>; and <PERSON> Mayfield </PERSON> residents <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Yancey </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Belinda </PERSON>; <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanders </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Melissa </PERSON>, and the Rev. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>. The dispatcher did not have ages. Federal investigators were expected to arrive at the site in the southwest corner of <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> on Saturday, the dispatcher said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890916-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-89 0327EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ArtsAwards     09-16 0445</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Arts Awards,0455</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rockefeller: Arts Award to be `Next Nobel'</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Praemium Imperiale is cq in 3rd graf</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KILEY ARMSTRONG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Architect I.M. <PERSON> Pei </PERSON> and painters <PERSON> Willem </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Kooning </PERSON> and <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Hockney </PERSON> were among the first six winners of the Praemium Imperiale, a new award from <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> that a leading philanthropist compared to Nobel prizes. The other winners of the honor, which comes with $ 100,000, were Italian sculptor <PERSON> Umberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Mastroianni </PERSON>, film director <PERSON> Marcel </PERSON> <PERSON> Carne </PERSON> and conductor <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON> <PERSON> Boulez </PERSON>, both of <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. `` These prizes will come to be perceived as a supplement to the Nobel Prize and will soon assume in the arts the stature of the Nobel awards in other fields,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Rockefeller </PERSON>, former chairman and chief executive officer of <ORGANIZATION> Chase </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manhattan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Modern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION> and a member of an advisory panel for the awards. Prince <PERSON> Masahito </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitachi </PERSON>, brother of the emperor and governor of the <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, which gives the awards, will present them in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> on Oct. 27. A luncheon to announce the winners was attended by <PERSON> Pei </PERSON>, a naturalized <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizen born in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Kooning </PERSON>, daughter of the painter, a naturalized <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizen born in <LOCATION> Holland </LOCATION>. `` I'm numb and I really do n't know what to think or how to feel,'' said <PERSON> Pei </PERSON>. `` It has to be ` the' award, as far as I'm concerned ... But it does put a lot of burden on those of us who are nominated.'' <PERSON> Seiji </PERSON> <PERSON> Tanaka </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> coordinator, said about 50 or 60 nominations were received. <PERSON> Tanaka </PERSON> said it was coincidental that all the winners are male and American or European. In addition, he said, the award categories may be changed next year _ to make theater and film separate categories, for instance. The prize is funded primarily by <ORGANIZATION> Fujisankei </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>, a media corporation. Fujisankei founder <PERSON> Nobutaka </PERSON> <PERSON> Shikanai </PERSON> is chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, founded in the 19th Century. The association selected the winners based on recommendations from the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advisers </ORGANIZATION>, which included <ORGANIZATION> Rockefeller </ORGANIZATION>, former prime ministers <PERSON> Jacques </PERSON> <PERSON> Chirac </PERSON> of <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Heath </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Amintore </PERSON> <PERSON> Fanfani </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> and former West German Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Schmidt </PERSON>. Each adviser had his own method of coming up with nominations, said <PERSON> Ned </PERSON> <PERSON> Steele </PERSON>, a publicist for the event. In the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Rockefeller </ORGANIZATION> asked <PERSON> Schuyler </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapin </PERSON>, former dean of the <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION>, to recruit a committee to give him recommendations. That committee included Broadway composer <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Sondheim </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> art critic <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> Dean <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Richards </PERSON>, former <ORGANIZATION> Smithsonian </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dillon </PERSON> <PERSON> Ripley </PERSON> and former CBS President <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Stanton </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890916-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-89 0256EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Canada-Arrests Bjt   09-16 0580</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Canada-Arrests, Bjt,0603</SECOND>
<HEAD>Colombian Suspects Under Tighter Guard After Weapons Case Linked
to Them</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FREDERICTON, New Brunswick (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
