<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890226-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-26-89 0159EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-China-Japan     02-26 0349</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-Japan,0358</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chinese Weekly Accuses Japan of Rewriting War History</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An authoritative Chinese weekly has accused <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> of `` war responsibility phobia'' for trying to gloss over its role in World War II. The <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Review </LOCATION>, in its edition for Tuesday, said attempts by Japanese leaders to deny <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s wartime crimes represent `` a chronic, political disease of an epidemic nature.'' The article was summarized Sunday by the official <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has reacted strongly to recent statements by <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s Prime Minister <PERSON> Noboru </PERSON> <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> that judgement on whether <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> was the aggressor in World War II should be left to future historians. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s Foreign Minister <PERSON> Qian </PERSON> <PERSON> Qichen </PERSON>, in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> to attend the funeral of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s wartime head of state Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>, told <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s Foreign Minister Sousuke Uno that <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> `` should avoid hurting our people's feelings by denying and distorting history.'' A member of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s legislature accused <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> of `` a gross deception which nobody will believe'' and a commentary in the English-language <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>'s `` cynical utterances'' will `` smear the image of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> as a trustworthy member of the world community.'' The <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Review recalled the 1982 furor over Japanese history textbooks which <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and other Asian nations said were attempts to whitewash <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s wartime aggression. It also noted the 1986 controversy caused by Education Minister <PERSON> Masayuki </PERSON> <PERSON> Fujio </PERSON>, and a similar dispute last year involving <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> head <PERSON> Seisuke </PERSON> <PERSON> Okuno </PERSON>. Both were forced to resign their cabinet posts after making statements justifying <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s invasions of <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. `` It is to avoid a repeat of such a historical tragedy that we Chinese pay so much attention to and criticize those irresponsible speeches, which not only whitewash past aggressors, but may also pave the way for militarism,'' the weekly said. It said <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s refusal to recognize its responsibilities in the war could impede its drive to become a major diplomatic power. `` If the statesmen of a country lack the courage to face history and accept its reality, and can not obtain trust from the international community, the country can hardly play a major role in world politics.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890226-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-26-89 0207EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Honduras-Explosives     02-26 0356</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Honduras-Explosives,0368</SECOND>
<HEAD>Brother of Armed Forces Chief Says Confiscated Explosives Were His</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By FREDDY CUEVAS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TEGUCIGALPA, Honduras (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A brother of the armed forces chief said Saturday that the 80 tons of explosives confiscated by the army belongs to the petroleum exploration company for which he works. Military officials had said earlier that the materials belonged to `` leftist subversives'' planning a campaign of terror. But <PERSON> Julio </PERSON> <PERSON> Regalado </PERSON>, brother of armed forces chief Gen. <PERSON> Humberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Regalado </PERSON>, said they were innocent exploration materials. `` These materials were used by the company where I work for petroleum exploration,'' he said. However, the government did not immediately confirm <PERSON> Regalado </PERSON>'s claims. <PERSON> Regalado </PERSON> said the dynamite, detonators and liquid explosives were awaiting delivery to the eastern province of Gracias a Dios near the Nicaraguan border for the U.S.-based exploration company <ORGANIZATION> Geosource </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprises </ORGANIZATION>. `` I'm no subversive,'' he said. <PERSON> Regalado </PERSON>, 40, said his brother had helped him reclaim the dynamite, which was under guard at a military installation to keep it from being stolen `` or used by leftist guerrilla groups.'' Police and soldiers found the dynamite Thursday in an abandoned house near <LOCATION> Hector </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caraccioli </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Air </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Base </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ceiba </LOCATION>, about 250 miles north of the capital of <LOCATION> Tegucigalpa </LOCATION>. Col. <PERSON> Erick </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanchez </PERSON>, chief of the 4th Infantry Batallion, told reporters the dynamite was `` to be used by subversive groups to continue the chain of terrorist acts that lately have unleashed panic in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>.'' He said the military was searching `` intensely'' for the terrorists. On Saturday, <PERSON> Sanchez </PERSON> refused to confirm or deny <PERSON> Regalado </PERSON>'s account of the explosives to reporters Government sources said there would be an official announcement on the matter within the next few days. He said only that `` our guerrilla search operation continues, particularly on the north coast of <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>.'' Four bombs have gone off in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> in a week, the latest in <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ceiba </LOCATION> at the offices of the New York-based <ORGANIZATION> Standard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fruit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. Other targets have included the <LOCATION> Tegucigalpa </LOCATION> city hall, an <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> office in the capital, a national telephone company office in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pedro </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sula </LOCATION> and a bus carrying <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soldiers and Honduran civilians in <LOCATION> Comayagua </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890226-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-26-89 0209EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BoyDrowns     02-26 0209</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Boy Drowns,0216</SECOND>
<HEAD>Boy Drowns While Helping Friend To Safety</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COLUMBUS, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 9-year-old boy who fell through the ice on a lake with another child Saturday drowned after hoisting his playmate to safety, authorities said. The second child, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, also 9, ran for help, but <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Alesio </PERSON> apparently suffered cardiac arrest in the icy water and died two hours later at <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Children </LOCATION><LOCATION> 's </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, officials said. `` Basically, by the time they got back -LRB- to the lake -RRB-, it was a search for the body,'' said police Detective <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Fineran </PERSON>. <PERSON> Fineran </PERSON> said <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> had managed somehow to push <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> out of the water and onto the ice before sliding back in again. <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> had disappeared from sight by the time firefighters and other rescue workers arrived, he said. The accident occurred on a private lake in a <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION> suburb, said Lt. <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Allspaugh </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Reynoldsburg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. `` It was thin ice _ it could n't have been more than a few inches thick,'' <PERSON> Allspaugh </PERSON> said. He estimated <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> had been in the water about 30 minutes before he was pulled out by firefighters who used boats and long poles. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> was treated at <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carmel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION> and released, a nursing supervisor there said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890226-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-26-89 0211EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0638 02-26 0644</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0638,0663</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: ADDS obits on Claypool and Tutt; AMs separates moved as a0615
on Schiotz, a0627 on Warmbold.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Rev. Frederick Schiotz</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BLOOMINGTON, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Rev. <PERSON> Fredrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Axel </PERSON> <PERSON> Schiotz </PERSON>, the first president of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lutheran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, died Saturday. He was 87. Since retiring as head of the 2.5 million-member denomination in 1971, <PERSON> Schiotz </PERSON> had taught at seminaries and colleges and carried out special tasks for the <ORGANIZATION> ALC </ORGANIZATION> and Lutheran World Relief. <PERSON> Schiotz </PERSON>, a native of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, was elected president of the <ORGANIZATION> Evangelical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lutheran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in 1954. He worked in merger negotiations that led to the formation in 1960 of the <ORGANIZATION> ALC </ORGANIZATION> and was elected to a six-year term as its first president. He was re-elected in 1966. The <ORGANIZATION> ALC </ORGANIZATION>, based in <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>, merged with the <ORGANIZATION> Lutheran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Evangelical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lutheran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Churches </ORGANIZATION> in 1987 to form the <ORGANIZATION> Evangelical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lutheran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, which has its headquarters in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Schiotz </PERSON> also helped organize the <ORGANIZATION> Lutheran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Lund </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, in 1947 and served as its president from 1963 to 1970. In addition, <PERSON> Schiotz </PERSON> served on the executive committee of the <ORGANIZATION> Lutheran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and was a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Churches </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Ted Warmbold</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN ANTONIO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Warmbold </PERSON>, editor of the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Light </LOCATION>, died Saturday of cryptococcal meningitis. He was 45. Warmbold, who formerly held executive titles with newspapers in <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, had been the chief news executive at the Light since joining the newspaper in June 1981. A native of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Warmbold </PERSON> received his degree from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Missouri </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journalism </ORGANIZATION> and began as a reporter with the <ORGANIZATION> Rochester </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chronicle </ORGANIZATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> Gannett </ORGANIZATION> newspaper, in 1967. In 1969, <PERSON> Warmbold </PERSON> was named assistant managing editor at the Democrat and Chronicle and in 1972, <ORGANIZATION> Gannett </ORGANIZATION> named him managing editor of the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> Sun-Telegram. He left <ORGANIZATION> Gannett </ORGANIZATION> in 1975 and became assistant managing editor of the <ORGANIZATION> Dallas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> and the following year became executive editor of D magazine, the city magazine of <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>. In 1977, The <ORGANIZATION> Hearst </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> hired him as executive editor of the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Examiner </ORGANIZATION> and in 1981, <ORGANIZATION> Hearst </ORGANIZATION> named him executive editor at the Light. He was promoted to editor in 1986.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Bob Claypool</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOUSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Claypool </PERSON>, music critic for the <ORGANIZATION> Houston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chronicle </ORGANIZATION>, died Saturday in a hospital less than a week after undergoing emergency surgery for an aortic aneurysm. He was 43. He joined the Chronicle in November 1988. After earning a master's degree in journalism at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Missouri </ORGANIZATION> in 1972, he went to work for the <ORGANIZATION> Houston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. He wrote mostly about country and blues music. <PERSON> Claypool </PERSON> contributed to many music magazines and was the author of `` Saturday Night at <PERSON> Gilley </PERSON>'s,'' a book about the giant nightclub featured in the movie `` Urban Cowboy.''
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>William Tutt</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COLORADO SPRINGS, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Thayer </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutt </PERSON>, a major figure in international sports and president of the Broadmoor Hotel for 43 years, died Friday following a long illness. He was 76. <PERSON> Tutt </PERSON> was a member of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hockey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fame </ORGANIZATION>, the Canadian <ORGANIZATION> Hockey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fame </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cowboy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fame </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sports </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fame </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Golf </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fame </ORGANIZATION>. In 1987, he was awarded L'Ordre Olympique, the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Olympic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>'s highest honor. <PERSON> Tutt </PERSON> helped bring the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Olympic Committee and the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> to <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>. He helped start the <ORGANIZATION> NCAA </ORGANIZATION> hockey tournament and bring prestigous golf tournaments to <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, including the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Men's Amateur, the Women's <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Amateur, the Curtis Cup and the Western Amateur. He served for three decades on the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hockey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, and for 29 years with the <ORGANIZATION> Amateur </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hockey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890226-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-26-89 0011EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-BarbaraBush 1stLd-Writethru a0532 02-26 0685</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Barbara Bush, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0532,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mrs. Bush To Tour Scenes From Last Emperor's Life</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Bush Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDs: Top 9 grafs new to update with Mrs. Bush's morning activities;
picks up 7th graf pvs, ``Like dozens xxx'' Subs 9th graf pvs to past-tense,
``However, Mrs. xxx''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 While President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> met Sunday with the leaders of modern <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> sipped tea, watched Chinese dancers and heard a Chinese rendition of `` Yankee Doodle Dandy'' within the walled compound of the last emperor. She then strolled through the royal family garden. `` This is marvelous,'' she said. Although the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> first lady lived in the Chinese capital city when her husband served as <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> liaison officer in the mid-1970s, neither the compound nor the <LOCATION> Forbidden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, which Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also planned to visit, was open to the public at the time. Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> attended services Sunday morning with her husband at the <ORGANIZATION> Chongwenmen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, where they worshipped when they lived in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. She then toured the Mansion of the Regent Prince. The elegant and traditional walled compound was the home of the Xuangtong Emperor, better known as <PERSON> Pu </PERSON> <PERSON> Yi </PERSON>. <PERSON> Pu </PERSON> <PERSON> Yi </PERSON>, whose life was told in the award-winning 1987 movie `` The Last Emperor,'' was enthroned in 1909 at the age of 3, but a revolution three years later forced him to abdicate. Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, wearing a blue wool suit and her trademark pearl necklace, had tea and cookies with Chinese and <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> women in the garden of the compound. A Chinese band clad in blue traditional robes played string instruments while young women performed dances with a traditional flavor. At the close, they gave a rendition of <ORGANIZATION> Yankee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Doodle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dandy </ORGANIZATION>, and Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> stood up and clapped enthusiastically.'' <PERSON> Pu </PERSON> <PERSON> Yi </PERSON>'s family mansion alongside a northern <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> lake is guarded by huge red doors and an ornate gate, and remains off limits to ordinary sightseers. Like dozens of other aristocratic mansions of old <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, it was taken over by the Communists who took power in 1949. Now, it houses the <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>. Its stately halls have been divided into tiny offices where hundreds of bureaucrats work under dim light bulbs. However, Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had tea and watched the music and dance program in a separate reception area with about 30 Chinese women. Among those invited was Premier <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Zhu </PERSON> <PERSON> Lin </PERSON>. In the afternoon, Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was to view a newly opened exhibit on <PERSON> Pu </PERSON> <PERSON> Yi </PERSON>'s life in the imperial palace in the heart of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, known as the <LOCATION> Forbidden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Inside two faded wooden halls in a small inner courtyard of the vast palace complex, the exhibit contains <PERSON> Pu </PERSON> <PERSON> Yi </PERSON>'s English-made bicyle, gramophone, childhood toys, set of Encyclopaedia Britannica and wedding robe, its multicolored silk threads still brilliant 67 years later. It also includes a small piano on which <PERSON> Pu </PERSON> <PERSON> Yi </PERSON> sometimes composed traditional-style tunes, and a taped recording of one, titled `` Generals On A Southern Expedition,'' that is played repeatedly for visitors. `` On the day peace is restored, my gentlemen, I shall bid you return and divest you of your battle robes,'' <PERSON> Pu </PERSON> <PERSON> Yi </PERSON> wrote in the lyrics. For <PERSON> Pu </PERSON> <PERSON> Yi </PERSON> and the feeble forces of monarchial restoration, however, there was no victory, even though he continued to live in the palace for 12 years after abdicating. The exhibit is a poignant testimony to the aimlessness and futile hopes of those 12 years. Pictures show him in full court dress seated on a throne during a brief period when he hoped for restoration, and later taking the throne as the puppet ruler of a Japanese-created kingdom of <LOCATION> Manchukuo </LOCATION> in northeast <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. Finally, he is shown in padded peasant clothing, exercising with other prisoners in a Communist prison for war criminals. Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s itinerary is very different from <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s, who visited the city in 1984. During her two-day tour, Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> toured the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zoo </LOCATION>, a temple where emperors once offered sacrifices for good harvests, an acupuncture clinic and a kindergarten. Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> also had tea at the home of a teacher.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890226-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-26-89 0239EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SleddingFatal     02-26 0310</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Sledding Fatal,0318</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Children, Three Adults Injured As Car Hits People Sledding</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ABSECON, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A car jumped a guard rail and hit a group of sledders Saturday, killing a 4-year-old girl and injuring three other children and three adults, authorities said. A 20-year-old woman lost control of her car around 2:30 p.m. while driving south on the <LOCATION> Garden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Parkway </LOCATION> in southeastern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, said State Police Sgt. <PERSON> Stacy </PERSON> <PERSON> Cranmer </PERSON>. The car went over the guard rail and hit the group, which was standing on top of the embankment, then slid 75 feet to the bottom of the hill, <PERSON> Cranmer </PERSON> said. A 6-year-old boy was in critical condition with head injuries after being airlifted to <ORGANIZATION> Cooper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Camden </LOCATION>, nursing supervisor <PERSON> Helene </PERSON> <PERSON> Zehnder </PERSON> said. The other injured children, a 7-year-old girl and a 9-year-old girl, were treated at <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>'s mainland division and released, <PERSON> Cranmer </PERSON> said. A 31-year-old woman, a 31-year-old man and a 41-year-old man were all in serious but stable condition at the medical center with broken bones and head injuries, the sergeant said. The driver's condition was not immediately known The victims all were from the <LOCATION> Absecon </LOCATION> area. Neither the victims' nor the driver's names were released When the accident occurred, about 50 people were in the area, which is within walking distance of homes, <PERSON> Cranmer </PERSON> said. `` It's a good sledding hill. The thing is they were n't supposed to be there,'' <PERSON> Cranmer </PERSON> said, adding that a trooper had told a group of people to leave the area about 45 minutes before the accident. `` This is an ongoing problem that we've had for years. `` How do you stop it? Do you arrest people for trespassing?'' <PERSON> Cranmer </PERSON> asked. `` I do n't know how you prevent it. `` When there's snow and there's kids, all the reasoning in the world wo n't stop it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890226-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-26-89 0101EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Poll-Bush     02-26 0267</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Poll-Bush,0274</SECOND>
<HEAD>Poll: Majority Of Americans Say Bush Doing Good Job</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A majority of Americans approve of the job President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is doing, according to a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Times-CBS News Poll. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> received a 61 percent approval rating for his first month in office, higher than the 55 percent rating given President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in his first month in office in a 1981 Gallup poll, the Times reported in Sunday's editions. In the new poll of 1,223 adults, only 9 percent of those surveyed disapproved of the young <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration. Thirty percent of the respondents said they did not know enough about <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to venture an opinion. The Feb. 18-19 survey was completed before the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> voted against the nomination of <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON> to be Secretary of <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION>, and did not include any questions about the Tower nomination. But in followup interviews, many respondents expressed relief that the committee had voted against Tower, though they also said that they did not think the vote would hurt the president, the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> scored high in all geographic areas and with all age groups, the Times said. Geographically, he got his highest approval rating, 67 percent, in the South. His lowest, 54 percent, was in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>. Among respondents who said their families earn more than $ 35,000 a year, 73 percent voiced approval of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, while 6 percent voiced disapproval, the Times said. Among those families earning less than $ 12,500, 52 percent of respondents approved of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, while 17 percent disapproved. The poll had a 3 percent margin of error.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890226-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-26-89 0418EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-BushRdp 7thLd-Writethru a0664 02-26 1170</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush Rdp, 7th Ld-Writethru, a0664,1,200</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Reunited With Deng; Attends Protestant Church</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDs: INSERTS 8th graf with Fitzwater quote; INSERTS grafs 22-25,
bgng, Bush later ... etc., to UPDATE with Sihanouk meeting and Fitzwater
description of Bush's meetings with Chinese leaders.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Sunday traded banter with senior <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON>, got `` right down to business'' on a range of topics with Premier <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON> and returned to a church where he and his wife <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> had worshipped in 1974-75. The president was bid a `` hearty welcome'' by <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> as they two began a session at the Great Hall of the People. During a picture-taking opportunity, <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>, 84, thanked <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for visiting <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> `` shortly after you took office'' and said, `` we two have been good friends.'' `` I'm delighted to see you looking so well,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> leader, who appeared healthy. The session followed a meeting between <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Chinese Premier <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s press secretary, <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>, called the meeting with <PERSON> Li </PERSON> `` a remarkable and unprecedented dialogue, covering issues ranging from Kampuchea -LRB- <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> -RRB-, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, trade, <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> and nuclear proliferation.'' `` It was an engaged conversation. We got right down to business. We thought it was an extraordinary conversation,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>, briefing reporters Sunday afternoon, said that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON>, were `` quite pleased with the pace and substance of the trip and with the extraordinarily warm reception'' by the Chinese. During the meeting with <PERSON> Li </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said that `` I come here at an interesting time, both an opportunity and a challenge,'' according to the <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION>, the official <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> news agency. It quoted the president as saying that `` I'm delighted that'' Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> will visit <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in May. `` It's a good thing,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> said that <PERSON> Li </PERSON> told <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> that <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> hopes to establish good-neighborly relations with the Soviets, but not the bond of alliance that existed in the 1950s. In his meeting with <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>, the two talked about sports and cards. <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> told <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>: `` you're an athlete. That's why you're in good shape.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> replied: `` I keep trying.'' <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> agreed that sports were important, and said that the one sport they had in common was `` playing bridge.'' `` I gave up bridge a long time ago, too complicated, too difficult,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> said he expected <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s job as president would make it even harder to find time to play the card game. `` I know it's a hard job to be the president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and you will be the champion of the world in terms of having the busiest work schedule,'' he said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> apologized to <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> that his visit to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> was `` very short,'' just 40 hours. Earlier, the Bushes attended a church that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> called `` our home away from home'' in the heart of the Chinese capital. He told the <ORGANIZATION> Chongwenmen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> congregation that a strong faith in God helps people cope with seemingly insurmountable problems. Just before going into his meetings with top Chinese officials, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> mixed secular and spiritual talk in brief remarks to roughly 1,400 worshippers seated in the sanctuary of the church hidden behind high stone walls. Speaking through an interpreter, he said that while relations between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> are basically sound, `` Sometimes our problems can seem bigger than life itself _ intractable and fearsome. But I am convinced that, with each other, with our faith in God, we can meet any challenge, and we will.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> met later Sunday with <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> resistance leader Prince <PERSON> Norodom </PERSON> <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON>. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said there were no new developments at that meeting, and that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had reiterated his support for a reconcilation government in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> with the prince at the head of it. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> also said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> assured Chinese leaders that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> continues to subscribe to its one-China policy and believes that the problem of <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> is one that should be resolved `` by the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> people'' without pressure from outside. He also said that Chinese leaders assured <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> that the Chinese would not sell missiles to other nations, with the exception of <LOCATION> Saudia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>, with which the Chinese has contractual commitments. `` This relationship is as important as any we have anywhgere in the world,' Fitzwater quoted <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as telling his hosts. `` They will not be affected by rapid changes in other relationships,'' the president said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his wife lived here in 1974-75 when <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was the head of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liaison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> in the period just before the formal restoration of diplomatic relations between the two world giants. During his talk Sunday, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> noted that his daughter, <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON> <PERSON> LeBlond </PERSON>, had been baptized at the <ORGANIZATION> Chongwenmen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> here in 1975, when she was 16. `` That gives us a special feeling of identity and warmth,'' he said. To the predominantly <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> congregation seated in the octagonal brick building with dark wood paneling and a neon cross, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> praised `` our church away from home.'' `` It's a little different, though,'' he said. `` Today we came up with 20 motor cars, with a motorcade, and I used to come to church on my bicycle, a Flying Pigeon,'' he said. At one point he picked up a <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> baby and cuddled it, and the baby said `` grandfather'' in Chinese. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> presented church with a gift Bible, saying `` it comes to you with our heartfelt thanks and our love.'' `` This church, in a sense, was our home away from home,'' he said. On Saturday, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> mingled with people at a downtown landmark, delivered a `` thank you'' in Chinese and presented <PERSON> Li </PERSON> with a pair of black leather boots from <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, here for a two-day working visit, and Chinese President <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> <PERSON> Shangkun </PERSON> toasted each other at the banquet in the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hall </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> the </LOCATION> <LOCATION> People </LOCATION> with vows to strengthen relations, while both hinted at issues that remain sources of friction. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> made veiled references to human rights concerns and weapons proliferation while <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> cautioned that `` twists and turns and relapses may occur in the process of relaxation.'' But <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> told <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> that his visit, coming so soon after his inauguration, was a `` big event'' in U.S.-Chinese relations. `` The Chinese leaders attach great importance to your current visit. ... The Chinese people know you well, and so do you know them,'' <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> returned the praise, claiming `` the world as a whole is watching the larger movement of our two great nations as we build even firmer bonds across the vast ocean that joins us.'' The first lady had a separate schedule for part of the day, visiting the childhood home of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s last emperor, <PERSON> Pu </PERSON> <PERSON> Yi </PERSON>, and touring the <LOCATION> Forbidden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, the sprawling walled residence of the imperial rulers. On Monday, the president and his wife head to <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, for a visit that will conclude their Far East trip. The Korean government has put 120,000 police on alert in anticipation of anti-American protest demonstrations.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890226-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-26-89 0435EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PlaneEmergency 6thLd-Writethru a0663 02-26 1300</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Plane Emergency, 6th Ld-Writethru, a0663,1337</SECOND>
<HEAD>NTSB Officials Say Stress Indicated In Jumbo Jet Accident</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: RETRANSMITTING a0666 for all needing. LEADS with 19 grafs to
UPDATE with officials saying investigation indicates stress responsible
for accident, other details, edit for transition; picks up 11th graf pvs,
``One of ...;''</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserGraphic NY15; LaserPhotos HU2, HU4, HU9, HU10, HU12, NY6, NY12</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVE ELLIOTT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HONOLULU (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A preliminary investigation has raised the possibility that stress, and not a bomb or metal fatigue, ripped open a jumbo jet, hurling nine people to their deaths, federal officials said Saturday. <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> ships, meanwhile, spent the day searching 3,000 square miles of ocean for debris from the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> jet, which made an emergency landing Friday with a 10-foot-wide, 40-foot-high hole in its side. The <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747 had been en route to <LOCATION> Auckland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>, with 336 passengers and 18 crew members aboard. `` Nothing yet gives us any indication of a bomb in the cargo area, but we are not drawing any conclusions yet,'' <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON>, an investigator with the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> told a news conference Saturday night. <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents searched the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747's cargo area with dogs earlier Saturday, but found no evidence of explosives. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Marx </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION>'s senior metallurgist, said there was no evidence that metal fatigue caused the hole. <PERSON> Marx </PERSON> said the condition of the hole's edge indicated that `` overstress'' _ a stress greater than the plane could stand _ had been placed on the aircraft, but did not say what it might have been. However, neither <PERSON> Marx </PERSON> nor <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> would rule out metal fatigue as a possible cause. A key question for investigators is whether the loss of a cargo door was a cause or a result of the plane tearing open. `` If a door opened in flight, it could possibly cause overstress,'' <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> said in response to a reporter's question. <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> added that the condition could be caused by other factors he declined to explain. The government last July ordered airlines to improve cargo door lock systems on older <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747s after one partly opened in flight. <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> followed the directive as far as an initial inspection, but had not added an aluminum and steel part required to be installed on the door by Dec. 31 of this year, spokesman <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. United has completed the addition on six of 25 aircraft it applies to, he said. <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> said the pilot and co-pilot of <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> Flight 811 told investigators Saturday there was no indication of trouble closing the cargo doors. <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> said a warning light in the cockpit would indicate if the doors were not closed properly. The hole follows the dimensions of the cargo door `` exactly'' and flares further up the aircraft, <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> said. Investigators began examining the damaged jet earlier in the day. A dozen people involved in the investigation peered into the exposed cargo hold as workers removed baggage from the jumbo jet and a military police officer armed with an M-16 rifle kept reporters and photographers at least 50 yards away. Aviation experts said earlier the most likely cause was metal fatigue. However, three <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> bomb experts from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> were sent to join the investigation. Between 70 and 100 people are participating in the investigation, including 16 from the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION>, to look into every possible cause, said <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON>. `` The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> is also here working with us because, as I've said earlier all doors are open,'' said <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON>. `` All doors are completely wide open.'' Investigators may make some preliminary findings, but it will take nine to 12 months to determine the cause of the incident, <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> said. One of three <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> cutters searching the ocean south of here Saturday afternoon retrieved part of an overhead compartment, said Lt. Cmdr. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellner </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> also found safety instruction cards with `` <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>'' on them, seat cushions and personal items including shoes and a teddy bear, <PERSON> Ellner </PERSON> said. Six Americans, two Australians and a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealander </LOCATION> aboard <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> Flight 811 were instantly blown through the opening, and at least one was sucked into one of the jet's engines, authorities said. The airplane was at 20,000 feet when the accident happened. <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> hospitals reported treating 27 people, mostly for minor injuries. Officials said three people remained in hospitals Saturday: a 48-year-old flight attendant in fair condition with broken bones in her neck and upper back and abdominal injuries, a flight attendant recovering from surgery on a fractured arm, and a 73-year-old <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> man in fair condition with heart problems. More than 200 people boarded other flights; those who did n't want to fly were put up in hotels. Early Saturday, 110 passengers from Flight 811 arrived in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> aboard a special <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> flight. `` It was a nightmare and I'm glad I got back on that plane today because if I'd waited I do n't know if I would have ever flown again,'' said <PERSON> Cathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Mehan </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, who said she was sitting about 10-12 rows behind the hole in the fuselage of Flight 811. `` I think that the United crew did an excellent, incredible job. The pilot should be recommended, commended _ he was fantastic,'' she said. `` I was afraid, I did n't think we were gon na make it ... I thought that this was the end.'' At dawn, three <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> ships and helicopters resumed their search of the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> about 100 miles south of here for debris from the plane. A vessel Friday found two airline seat cushions and a 4-by-6-foot piece of metal believed to be from the jet, <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Spangler </PERSON> said. Authorities had not decided late Saturday whether the search would continue Sunday, <PERSON> Spangler </PERSON> said. The nine missing passengers were identified as <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> and <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Morristown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> <PERSON> Harley </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Hackensack </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Fallon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Fallon </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Handley </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Wellington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>; and Dr. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Crawford </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Swann </PERSON>, both of <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>. According to <ORGANIZATION> Hawaii </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Kali </PERSON>, the 18-year-old <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747, the oldest in <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION>'s jumbo jet fleet, took off for <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> at 1:34 a.m Pilot <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cronin </PERSON> heard `` a loud thump'' just before the No. 3 engine failed a few minutes into the flight. A short time later, the No. 4 engine fire indicator activated and <PERSON> Cronin </PERSON> shut it down. At 2:16 a.m., <PERSON> Cronin </PERSON> radioed the traffic control tower, asking for emergency vehicles, which were standing by when the plane landed at 2:33 a.m. <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Cronin </PERSON> would have no comment. Investigators recovered small body fragments and pieces of clothing in the jet's No. 3 engine, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Honolulu </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Examiner </ORGANIZATION>'s Office. <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Starrett </PERSON>, a medical examiner investigator, said it was unlikely officials would be able to identify the remains, even as male or female. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Speicher </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Division </ORGANIZATION> vice president, said he hopes to have the plane repaired and returned to service in three or four months. <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nagin </PERSON> said the jet had undergone a complete four-day inspection 88 days before the accident, and a less intensive check Feb. 16. `` It has no history of maintenance problems. This aircraft had a routine maintenance history,'' <PERSON> Nagin </PERSON> told reporters in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bobbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Nardis </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, where safety records are kept, said cracks were once found near the structure that holds the engine to the wing. She said the plane also once had an engine fire. But Ms. <PERSON> Nardis </PERSON> said `` people who work with these reports all the time'' said the plane had nothing on its record that particularly distinguished it from other jumbo jets.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890226-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-26-89 0951EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-BushRdp 2ndLd-Writethru a0670 02-26 1196</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush Rdp, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0670,1,190</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush, Chinese Leader Toast `New Progress' in Relations</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS pvs grafs 7-8 bgng, He also, with 5 new grafs on Fang's
exclusion from Bush's farewell banquet, South Korean security precautions.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERENCE HUNT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP White House Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON> toasted `` new progress'' in Sino-American relations Sunday, and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> assured <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> that their ties would not be weakened by Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s plans to visit <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> this spring. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also raised previously expressed <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> concerns about proliferation of nuclear missiles. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> is one of the world's biggest arms merchants White House press secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said Premier <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON> reaffirmed an earlier commitment by <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> that <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> would not sell missiles to any country other than <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>. Later, however, deputy White House press secretary <PERSON> Roman </PERSON> <PERSON> Popadiuk </PERSON> said <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> had misspoken. <PERSON> Popadiuk </PERSON> said <PERSON> Li </PERSON> did not discuss specifics but merely restated assurances given last October that <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> would act in `` a responsible manner'' regarding missile sales. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has said it is satisfied with that policy. Before heading for <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> en route home to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> appeared on the government-run television network for a live, 15-minute interview by <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> journalists _ an unprecedented event for a foreign visitor here. He also entertained his Chinese hosts at a farewell banquet featuring a Texas-style barbecue and Lone Star beer. But one of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s invited guests, leading Chinese dissident <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> <PERSON> Lizhi </PERSON>, was barred at the front door of the hotel by <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> police, according to an American witness. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had invited <PERSON> Fang </PERSON>, a respected astrophysicist, as a gesture of support for a small group of Chinese intellectuals who have called for greater political freedom. `` This really shows <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s attitude toward human rights,'' <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> said later in a telephone interview `` At the most, I would have been able to say hello to the president.'' White House officials, when asked about the incident, had no immediate comment. It was not known if <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was aware of <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> and his wife's forcible exclusion from the banquet. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> had said earlier it was unlikely that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would have spoken to <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> at the dinner. South Korean authorities meanwhile braced for the threat of violent anti-American demonstrations when <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> flies to <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> on Monday for a three-hour visit that will include talks with government leaders and an address to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>. An estimated 120,000 police, security agents and commandos were put on alert. During the TV interview, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> expressed hope for expanded U.S.-China trade, which he said already had grown from $ 800 million in the mid-1970s to $ 14 billion today. `` We are prepared to go the extra mile in terms of investments, in terms of business, exports and imports,'' he told a questioner. In his toast at the farewell banquet, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he was leaving <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> `` convinced that U.S.-China relations are strong.'' `` We have great responsibilities and also great possibilities,'' the president added, promising to work with <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s leadership to `` help make this world a safer, more peaceful place for us all.'' <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>, 84, the country's senior leader, expressed `` a hearty welcome'' as he greeted <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in the cavernous Great Hall of the People. `` We two have been good friends,'' <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> told his visitor. Throughout the final day of his visit to <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> emphasized a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> desire for warm relations with <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. As his rode around <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> in a black limousine, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> repeatedly used a microphone in the car to say `` thank you, thank you'' to thousands of <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> people who lined the streets. However, the air of cordiality was marred when <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> security guards pushed and shoved people away from <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> when the president's wife toured the <LOCATION> Forbidden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, ancient home of Chinese emperors. <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Powers </PERSON>, a White House photographer accompanying the first lady, was pushed face-first into a door. Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> interrupted the tour to declare, `` This girl's job is to take my picture and she got hit. She works for my husband.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the security guards should `` calm down.'' Later, Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> produced Ms. Powers at a news conference and reported that `` she's fine.'' The president and <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> established a warm relationship during <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s tenure as <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> envoy to <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> in the mid-1970s, before formal diplomatic relations were restored between their two countries. On Sunday, they bantered about playing bridge, one of the Chinese leader's passions. `` I gave up bridge a long time ago _ too complicated, too difficult. You are the expert,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>. `` Now it's even more difficult for you to find time to play bridge,'' <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> responded. `` I know it's a hard job to be the president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and you will be the champion of the world in terms of having the busiest work schedule.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> conferred separately with <PERSON> Li </PERSON> for two hours. `` This relationship is as important as any we have anywhere in the world,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. In the past, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has expressed concern over human rights in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, but the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> did not raise the subject during his two-day visit this time. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, dressed in a Western business suit, and <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>, wearing a gray <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> suit, spent most of their hour-long meeting discussing East-West relations, focusing on <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s scheduled trip to <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> in May. It will be the first Sino-Soviet summit meeting in three decades. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said the president told <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> welcomes <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s trip as an `` important and useful step in providing stability to the region and the world.'' `` He -LRB- <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> -RRB- wanted to assure the chairman that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy with regard to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> would not be affected by the outcome of those discussions,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. The spokesman said <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> spoke at length about the history of Soviet-Chinese relations and `` the difficulties he faces in having this meeting'' with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> as part of a `` normalization process.'' <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> almost never hosts luncheons for foreign leaders, but made an exception for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> said he would n't give a speech but added: `` Let us all raise our glasses to the health of President and Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and other American friends and to the new progress in China-U. relations.'' <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> downed a small glass of mao-tai, a potent sorghum liquor. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> did the same. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was encouraged by developments on the <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> peninsula and hoped <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> would use its influence with <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> to engage in talks with the <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> government. On the delicate issue of <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is committed to a `` one-China'' policy and that the future of <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>, home of the Chinese Nationalist government ousted from the mainland in 1949, must be worked out by <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> government. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> is unhappy about <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> arms sales to <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> and has urged <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to be more aggressive in promoting contacts between <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also met on Sunday with Prince <PERSON> Norodom </PERSON> <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> and said that `` we strongly support'' the exiled resistance leader in his campaign for withdrawal of Vietnamese occupation forces from <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>. Both the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> want <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> to lead a coalition government in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890226-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-26-89 1126EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-HijackingTrial     02-26 0800</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hijacking Trial,820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Trying To Keep Secrets About How It Nabbed Lebanese</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the hijacking trial of <PERSON> Fawaz </PERSON> <PERSON> Younis </PERSON>, under way in federal court, the government is trying to keep secrets about how it nabbed the Lebanese militiaman in an undercover operation in the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Younis </PERSON> is the first suspect arrested overseas and tried under the 1984 Hostage-Taking Act, which gives the government `` long arm'' jurisdiction in cases involving American hostages. <PERSON> Younis </PERSON>, 29, is a relative small fry, said <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Livingstone </PERSON>, an expert on terrorism. `` This is not the <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Dillinger </PERSON> of the terrorist world. He is a relatively low-level terrorist,'' <PERSON> Livingstone </PERSON> said. But to nab him federal authorities cast a multi-million dollar net involving undercover agents, an aircraft carrier, helicopters and a fleet of aircraft, according to court arguments and documents in the case. Four days after his arrest on Sept. 13, 1987, <PERSON> Younis </PERSON> was flown to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in a 13-hour flight aboard a plane that refueled several times in the air, avoiding any contact with foreign governments that might have clouded <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> jurisdiction in the case. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agents used sensitive intelligence methods in making the arrest, and a number of the key players in the case are living under new identities in the federal witness protection program, prosecutors said during a pretrial hearing on Wednesday. At the hearing, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Distrist Chief Judge <PERSON> Aubrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> denied requests by defense attorney <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> for access to classified information in 12 categories, ranging from the names of high-level policymakers who helped plan the arrest to details about <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> and intelligence assets used in the case. <PERSON> Younis </PERSON> is accused of leading a band of men who, armed with AK-47 assault rifles, shot their way past security guards and boarded a Royal Jordanian jetliner in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> on June 11, 1985. <PERSON> Younis </PERSON> was a member of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Amal </ORGANIZATION> militia, a Shiite Moslem faction. He was under orders to fly the plane to <LOCATION> Tunis </LOCATION>, where an <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> meeting was under way, and read a statement demanding the withdrawal of <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> guerrillas from <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, defense counsel <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> said Wednesday. Tunisian authorities denied the plane permission to land and it returned to <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. The evidence against <PERSON> Younis </PERSON> includes a videotape of him on the <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> tarmac, armed with an assault rifle, announcing that the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 727 would be blown up. One of the passengers, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Slade </PERSON>, has also testified that <PERSON> Younis </PERSON> emerged from the plane's cockpit several times during the 39-hour hijacking and ordered other hijackers to stop beating Jordanian skymarshals. The beatings resumed when <PERSON> Younis </PERSON> returned to the cockpit, <PERSON> Slade </PERSON> testified, identifying the defendant in the courtroom. No one was killed in the hijacking. In Septmeber 1987, <PERSON> Younis </PERSON> was lured to the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> island of <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> by a friend, identified by federal authorities as <PERSON> Jamal </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamdan </PERSON>. Court papers contain the transcript of a conversation clandestinely recorded at <PERSON> Hamdan </PERSON>'s apartment on <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>, in which <PERSON> Younis </PERSON> said he was picked for the hijacking by the head of <ORGANIZATION> Amal </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Nabih </PERSON> <PERSON> Berri </PERSON>, who is also <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s justice minister. <PERSON> Berri </PERSON> has denounced the arrest as `` an attack against the honor of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>.'' During pretrial argument, the defense attorney said he would not contend that <PERSON> Berri </PERSON> ordered the hijacking, but that his client would testify that he was under orders to pirate a plane to <LOCATION> Tunis </LOCATION>. According to the defense attorney's arguments in court, <PERSON> Jamal </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamdan </PERSON> and his brother <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> lured <PERSON> Younis </PERSON> from <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> to a two-masted sailboat with the promise of a drug deal and a party. Two <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents, a man and a woman, were aboard the yacht, which was located in international waters to avoid the need for extradition hearings. In the struggle to arrest <PERSON> Younis </PERSON>, both his wrists suffered hairline fractures, federal authorities said when they announced the arrest. <PERSON> Younis </PERSON> was transferred to a naval supply vessel, the USS Butte, which took four days to carry him to the western <LOCATION> Mediterrean </LOCATION>, where he was moved to the carrier <ORGANIZATION> USS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Saratoga </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> said at the hearing. <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> asked to introduce evidence that five doctors were flown by helicopter to the <LOCATION> Saratoga </LOCATION> beforehand in the event that <PERSON> Younis </PERSON> was hurt, but that the defendant was not treated until after he confessed. `` The only medication my client received was a bag of ice,'' the defense attorney said. The court, said the judge, `` will allow the defense to argue that four days is a long time to transport the defendant from the eastern <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> to the western Mediterranean'' and that `` that there was not a normal complement aboard the ship,'' said <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>. The defense, in debating whether the `` confession was free and voluntary,'' will be allowed to argue that there was `` undue delay'' in diagnosing and treating <PERSON> Younis </PERSON>, the judge said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890226-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-26-89 1125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Britain-Plane     02-26 0137</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Britain-Plane,0139</SECOND>
<HEAD>No Fire Found Aboard Plane, Despite Warning Light</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A warning light indicated there was a fire aboard a jumbo jet that landed at <LOCATION> Heathrow </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> on Sunday, but firefighters who rushed to the scene discovered it was a false alarm, <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> said. The light came on after the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747 had landed safely on a flight from <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> and the passengers had disembarked at <LOCATION> Heathrow </LOCATION>'s Terminal 4, said an airline spokesman, speaking anonymously in keeping with British custom `` The emergency services were called as a matter of precaution,'' he said. The warning light on British Airways Flight 292 suggested there was a fire in the plane's auxiliary power unit, located in the tail of the plane. The unit provides power for the aircraft when the main engines are switched off.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890226-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-26-89 1126EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-France-Ariane     02-26 0198</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-France-Ariane,0202</SECOND>
<HEAD>Strike Forces Postponement of Rocket Launch</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A strike at the European space center in <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Guiana </LOCATION> has forced postponement of Tuesday's scheduled launch of a Japanese communications satellite and a European weather satellite, <ORGANIZATION> Arianespace </ORGANIZATION> said Sunday. <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanchez </PERSON>, spokesman for the European consortium, said a new date will be set for launching the Ariane 4 rocket after the strike is settled. He said it was the first time a strike has led to postponement of an Ariane launch. In a statement, <ORGANIZATION> Arianespace </ORGANIZATION> said it was staying in close touch with the <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> company <ORGANIZATION> Thomson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> CSF </ORGANIZATION>, whose 230 workers at the space center in <LOCATION> Kourou </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Guiana </LOCATION>, have been on strike since Wednesday seeking higher pay and better insurance and social benefits. Many of the Thomson employees are technicians manning radar controls, operating computers or performing other tasks vital to the launch, <PERSON> Sanchez </PERSON> said. Negotiations were continuing through the weekend at <LOCATION> Kourou </LOCATION>, on the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> coast of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, but there was no report of progress. The flight scheduled for Tuesday night was to have placed two satellites in orbit: the first Japanese commercial communications satellite JC-SAT, and the European meteorological satellite MOP-1.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890226-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-26-89 1132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--China-Executions     02-26 0161</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--China-Executions,0165</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Executed In China For Drug Smuggling</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three men, including a <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> resident, have been executed for drug smuggling in the southern province of <LOCATION> Yunnan </LOCATION>, the official press reported Sunday. Two others were sentenced to 15 years in prison. The <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Cao </PERSON> <PERSON> Guojun </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, came to <LOCATION> Yunnan </LOCATION> last year and recruited <PERSON> Wu </PERSON> <PERSON> Yinggang </PERSON> and <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> <PERSON> Chunseng </PERSON> for a scheme to buy heroin abroad and transport it to <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> via <LOCATION> Kunming </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Guangzhou </LOCATION>. In June, <PERSON> Cao </PERSON> returned to <LOCATION> Yunnan </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, bringing with him <PERSON> Liang </PERSON> <PERSON> Hongen </PERSON>, from <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> <PERSON> Weitong </PERSON>, from <LOCATION> Guangzhou </LOCATION>, to work on the scheme. Police cracked the case when they found <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> with about 10 pounds of heroin on July 4, it said. <PERSON> Cao </PERSON> and the three others were picked up later. The report only said that <PERSON> Cao </PERSON> was executed. It did not identify which two of the remaining four men also died.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890226-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-26-89 1132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--BusPlunge     02-26 0120</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Bus Plunge,0122</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bus Accident Kills 12 In Northern Taiwan</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TAIPEI, Taiwan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A bus packed with tourists plunged off a mountain highway in northern <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> on Sunday and fell 330 feet into a valley, killing 12 people and injuring 24, police reported. Those killed in the accident in <LOCATION> Taoyuan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, 30 miles west of <LOCATION> Taipei </LOCATION>, included the driver, <PERSON> Liu </PERSON> <PERSON> Pi-kuang </PERSON>, and a British woman identified as <LOCATION> Daisy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Finchley </LOCATION>, police said. Her hometown was not known. All the other passengers aboard the bus, which was heading for a miniature garden in the county, were Taiwanese, police said. The bus apparently went out of control when the driver tried to pass a vehicle in front of it, police said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890226-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-26-89 1132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Bush-Sihanouk     02-26 0481</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush-Sihanouk,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Meets Sihanouk, Voices Support</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Bush Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM ABRAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> met with Prince <PERSON> Norodom </PERSON> <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> on Sunday and expressed support for the resistance leader's efforts to end <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s 10-year occupation of his country `` We wish you well and respect the resistance you represent,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told the 66-year-old <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> during their 20-minute meeting at the <ORGANIZATION> Diaoyutai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, where both were residing. White House press secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> made no new commitments to the prince. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> provides non-lethal aid to the <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> faction and a second non-Communist group seeking the withdrawal of Vietnamese occupation forces from <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>. The third resistance force is the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>, which took power in 1975 and killed an estimated 1 million of their countrymen with fanatic agrarian policies before <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> invaded and drove them into the jungles in late 1978. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> is the main supplier of arms to the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>, which receives no <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> support. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told Chinese Premier <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON> on Sunday that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> rejects a dominant role for the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> in any future Cambodian government. <PERSON> Li </PERSON> repeated <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s position that <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> should withdraw all its troops and that <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> should head a four-party coalition government, which would include the three resistance groups and the Vietnam-backed Phnom Penh government. <PERSON> Li </PERSON> said no single party should dominate the coalition. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said he could not recall any discussion between <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Li </PERSON> on the question of <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> arms supplies to the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> tentatively has agreed to end arms shipments to the guerrillas if <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> fulfills a pledge to withdraw all its troops by September. The mercurial <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON>, who is noted for his frequent quarrels with his resistance partners, arrived at <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s villa after a limousine ride from his own residence about 100 yards away. The prince was greeted by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy officials and Assistant Secretary of State <PERSON> Gaston </PERSON> <PERSON> Sigur </PERSON>, but stood outside <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s villa for about 10 minutes, apparently reluctant to enter until the president appeared at the door. When <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> showed up, <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> greeted him warmly and they went inside together. <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> was driven from the <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> throne in 1970 in a coup he claimed was engineered by the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. Then strongly anti-American, he returned to his homeland in 1975 when the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> gained power but was immediately placed under house arrest. <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> fled <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> when <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> invaded and has spent the past decade wandering in exile in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. He has been living at the <LOCATION> Diaoyutai </LOCATION> guest house here for more than a month. Last month, he resumed presidency of the three-party resistance one year after he quit in anger over alleged <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> attacks on his troops. He has since directed recent peace negotiations with <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Phnom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penh </LOCATION> government.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890226-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-26-89 1133EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Bush-ChinaMedia     02-26 0643</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush-China Media,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chinese Media Give Bush Visit Unprecedented Coverage</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Bush Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN POMFRET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s state-run media gave President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s visit unprecedented coverage, broadcasting the first live interview of a foreign leader in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and portraying the new president as a man of the people The two-day visit was front-page news on all of the country's major newspapers Sunday morning, and it led the nation's radio broadcasts throughout the day In an unusual move, stations carried a broadcast of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> speaking in English to a welcoming banquet. A Chinese translation followed. The visit also led the nationwide television news on Saturday and Sunday nights. On Sunday, the broadcast showed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> shaking hands warmly and exchanging toasts with <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was also seen meeting Premier <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> <PERSON> Ziyang </PERSON>. The news also broadcast pictures of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> during and after his television interview. `` With many thanks,'' the president wrote to <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> as the camera zoomed in. `` The biggest audience I've ever had _ by far.'' As with all Chinese reports, sensitive topics were dropped from the written copy. Chinese media made no mention of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s call for respect for individual rights and his opposition to arms sales `` in regions of the world marked by conflict.'' The references, however veiled, were to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> hopes for greater personal freedoms in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and that the nation stop selling arms in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. Still, the coverage was exhaustive. The English-language service of the <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> churned out about 30 stories and one exclusive interview with the president in less than 24 hours. The media blitz is an indication of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>'s hopes for even better ties with <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. It also is a sign of growing Chinese curiosity in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Finally, it shows the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> leadership's fascination with <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> himself, a man they describe as an `` old friend'' and who they openly supported in last year's presidential election. A waving <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> beamed from the front page of the People's Daily, the official organ of the <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and the nation's biggest paper, printing 4 million copies a day It ran three stories on the presidential visit. The <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Daily, the main newspaper for the capital, portrayed the new president as a man of the people. `` If the visit was n't such a short one, maybe President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his wife would ride their ` Flying Pigeon' bicyles once again to <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>,'' the report said. The reference was to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s 13-month sojourn in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> as head of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liaison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> in 1974-75. `` At that time,'' the story said, `` he and his wife, <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON>, often rode their bikes along the big and small roads of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> for exercise, to directly understand Chinese society and have more contact with the people.'' In an editorial, the People's Daily said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has put `` clean government'' and `` cooperation with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>'' on the top of his agenda. An analysis last week said `` the new president has already walked out from under <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s shadow.'' But the top item in the media blitz was <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s 15-minute interview on <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION>. `` I've spoke to the American people about a new breeze blowing,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said in his opening statement before the interview began. `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> was one of the first nations to feel this breeze.'' Sitting in front of a painting of scenic <LOCATION> Guilin </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> smiled often as he answered questions mainly about trade relations with <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. The questions were asked in English and appeared in <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> as subtitles along the bottom of the screen. A <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> interpreter translated for the president. `` This is the first live interview ever with a foreign leader,'' said an editor earlier Sunday. `` We're pretty excited about it here. We're expecting at least 100 million people to be watching.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890226-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-26-89 1134EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Bush-OldFriends Bjt   02-26 0838</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush-Old Friends, Bjt,880</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reporter's Notebook: President Enjoys Light-Hearted Day With Old
Chinese Friends</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE FEINSILBER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Everywhere <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> went on Sunday he ran into old Chinese friends, from Chairman <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON> to the fellow who used to cut his hair and his onetime tennis partner. With <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> engaged in casual chatter and shook off the old chairman's suggestion that they get together for a game of bridge some time. `` You're too good,'' said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. He lived in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> during 1974-75 as head of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liaison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, before establishment of U.S.-Sino diplomatic ties. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> stopped at the International Club to have a word with a `` Mr. <PERSON> Wong </PERSON>,'' the tennis pro, who, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> claimed, has been quoted in the newspapers back home as saying that he used to beat <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> regularly at tennis. `` I had to stop off and talk to him about that story,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said in later apologizing to the staff at the American embassy for being late. He said he also had wanted to look up his barber at the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, a meeting place for foreigners in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. The barber, <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Bo </PERSON>, now assistant manager of the club said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> sends the club greeting cards every new year and Christmas. `` We're old friends,'' he told the official <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agnecy </ORGANIZATION> Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> practiced Chinese `` tai qi'' exercises at the club, the agency said. Enroute from the club to the embassy, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> used a loudspeaker to shout `` Thank You'' from his limousine to Chinese crowds congregated along the way. At the embassy, he said, he was delighted to have run into `` several of our Chinese friends, co-workers that worked with <PERSON> Barabara </PERSON> and me right in this very house.'' In the courtyard on the way out, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> paused to pose with a group of <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cub </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scouts </ORGANIZATION> and Brownies who had waited in the breeze for more than an hour. Who are these kids? someone asked. Replied their adult leader: `` Frozen brownies.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s most emotional reunion came at the pulpit of the <ORGANIZATION> Chongwenmen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, where the Rev. <PERSON> Yin </PERSON> <PERSON> Jizeng </PERSON> led the services. <PERSON> Yin </PERSON> had baptized the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s daughter, <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON>, when the family lived in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. From the pulpit, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> recalled those days. He said he used to arrive at Sunday services on his Flying Pigeon bicycle, instead of at the head of a flashing 20-car motorcade that carried him on Sunday. Back then, only foreigners could attend church services in <LOCATION> Bejing </LOCATION>. Sunday 1,400 worshippers crowded into the octogonal church. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has a billion people; 4 million of them are Protestants. When <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> pulled in at the International Club a handful of Americans awaited him outside. They broke into song: `` God Bless America.'' Among them, symbolic of the new <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and the new relationship with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, was <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Law </PERSON>, a poultry geneticist from <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, who said he was involved in a joint business venture to teach the Chinese how to raise their own breeding chickens. The Chinese must import breeders now, but in a few years will be raising 10 million of them, he said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> kidded the staff at the embassy about the exhaustive preparations that are made when a president comes calling. `` I know something about a visit from a president,'' he said. `` We had one when I was out here before this was an embassy. And I sure was glad to see him go!'' The visiting president in <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s past case was <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>. `` And if that was n't enough,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> added in reference to the former globetrotting secretary of state, `` we survived two -LRB- visits -RRB- from <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON>!'' That was the sort of day it was for the visiting American president _ light-hearted interludes between bouts of diplomacy. When <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who had gone off by herself to see the <LOCATION> Forbidden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, joined him for lunch at the Great Hall of the People, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was just finishing shaking the hands of some Chinese potentates. He saw her, and shook hers, too. `` How do you do?'' he asked her with artificial formality. She gave him a look, and a friendly pat on the back. With tiny Chairman <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>, who comes up about to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s midriff, the talk was exceptionally casual. <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> is famous for his interest in playing bridge. During the Cultural Revolution, when he was ousted from power, he passed his days at a bridge table. <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> told <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> it is a sport they have in common. He challenged the president to a game sometime. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>: `` You're too good.'' <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>:'' It's hard to say We have n't played together. But even if we play bridge together, it will be a friendly game.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>: `` I gave up bridge a long time ago. Too complicated. Too difficult. You are the expert.'' Then they went off to one of those big Chinese luncheon banquets. Afterward, as he hurried down the steps of the Great Hall to his limousine, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was asked how it went at lunch. `` Ate too much,'' was the cryptic reply.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890226-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-26-89 1148EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Fed-InterestRates Bjt   02-26 0669</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fed-Interest Rates, Bjt,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>More Inflation-Fighting Moves, Higher Interest Rates Seen Likely</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NANCY BENAC</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>'s decision last week to boost its key lending rate to combat inflation is likely to be followed by further credit-tightening moves and even higher interest rates, many analysts believe. They say the central bank's move to increase the discount rate by a half-percentage point to 7 percent on Friday came too late and was too mild to effectively quell an inflation spiral, and that further steps to cool the overheating economy will be necessary. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> is signaling that it's definitely trying to encourage higher rates in order to fight the inflationary pressure,'' said <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Ratajczak </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forecasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Georgia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` The only question is whether they're signaling a little late and a little timidly,'' he said. `` They definitely are late and a half-point -LRB- increase -RRB- is a little timid.'' Boosting the discount rate, the fee the central bank charges for short-term loans to banks, is the strongest signal the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> can send of its concern about inflation. The <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> also has been employing more subtle credit-tightening moves for the past year, reducing the availability of cash and thus driving up the interest rates that banks charge when making loans. Major banks last week boosted their prime rate _ charged to the most credit-worthy commercial customers _ for the second time in two weeks to 11.5 percent as lenders continue to pass along their higher costs for funds. A variety of lending rates covering everything from home mortgages to new cars are expected to ratchet upward as a result of the latest round of <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> tightening, and the pattern is expected to repeat itself. `` Until the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> sees some clear evidence that the economy is slowing down, it is going to continue to tighten,'' said economist <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Wyss </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Data </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>. `` It believes the economy is running too fast, inflation is accelerating and it's going to put on the brakes But it takes awhile for the brakes to work.'' Higher interest rates are used to gradually moderate economic growth in an effort to avoid the higher prices caused by tight labor markets and supply bottlenecks. Concern about inflation heightened last week after the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> reported that consumer prices were up 0.6 percent in January, the biggest increase in two years. Earlier reports showed wholesale prices were up 1 percent last month and indicated the economy has yet to slow down in response to the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION>'s efforts to maneuver a so-called `` soft landing'' to the 6-year-old economic expansion. <PERSON> Ratajczak </PERSON> said that with inflation unlikely to flag in the near future, interest rates are bound nowhere but up. `` I think we're going to see some more bad inflation numbers and I think we're going to see some higher interest rates,'' he said. `` Cumulatively, the higher interest rates will slow down the economy.'' A similar theme was sounded by economist <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Aubrey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> G. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lanston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, who said the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION>'s latest action brought it `` at best, roughly even with the inflation curve.'' `` The inflation numbers will continue to show a tendency to accelerate and it will require further <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> tightening steps,'' <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said. Most economists are expecting inflation this year to be in the range of 5 percent to 5.5 percent, up from 4.4 percent in the last two years. While still far short of the double-digit levels of the 1970s, the current inflation rates have been labeled `` unacceptable'' by <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON>. `` If inflation emerges, I think a recession will move up on us much more quickly than we can imagine and when it occurs it will be a prolonged one,'' he warned in congressional testimony last week. <PERSON> Wyss </PERSON> said that while boosting interest rates is not the ideal cure for inflation, `` it's the only lever the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> has.'' `` I do n't think they have much alternative but to pull it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890226-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-26-89 1217EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--CheapSteak     02-26 0124</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Cheap Steak,0125</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thousands Enjoy 42 Cent Steak Dinner At Tokyo Restaurant</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thousands of people jammed a restaurant in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> on Sunday that sold $ 15 steak dinners for 55 yen, or 42 cents, to celebrate its 55th anniversary. Lines began forming outside the <LOCATION> Suehiro </LOCATION> restaurant in the <LOCATION> Ginza </LOCATION> shopping district three hours before the steak house opened late Sunday morning. Three hours before the 10 p.m. closing time, 8,000 people had enjoyed a steak dinner, and the total was expected to reach more than 30,000 before the three-day offer ended Tuesday, said one restaurant official, <PERSON> Masao </PERSON> <PERSON> Moriyasu </PERSON>. The bargain dinner included seven ounces of imported beef, salad and rice. The restaurant usually serves about 3,000 people a day, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890226-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-26-89 1225EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-BarbaraBush     02-26 0750</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Barbara Bush,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>First Lady Tours Beijing</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Bush Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
