<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890412-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-89 2329EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-SriLanka     04-12 0530</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Sri Lanka,0547</SECOND>
<HEAD>26 Sinhalese Militants Surrender</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PATRICK CRUEZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COLOMBO, Sri Lanka (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government on Wednesday declared a week-long cease-fire with Sinhalese and Tamil rebels, and an official said 26 Sinhalese militants surrendered under President <PERSON> Ranasinghe </PERSON> <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON>'s peace plan. The militants, belonging to the <ORGANIZATION> Marxist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, gave themselves up at temples and government offices Wednesday, said the military official, who can not be identified under briefing rules. He did not give details. <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON>, seeking to end six years of ethnic violence that has claimed 12,500 lives, announced a general amnesty and unilateral cease-fire to Sinhalese and Tamil rebels. The offer was part of a peace package that included seats in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> and jobs for the militants. The cease-fire began a day before Sinhalese and Tamils celebrate a common new year. The government also set up 228 centers at schools, temples and government offices across the country where the rebels could give themselves up. The front has not yet responded to the truce offer but the largest Tamil militant group, campaigning to set up an independent state in Northern and Northeastern Provinces, rejected it outright Tuesday. However, `` the militants have a week to surrender and it is too early to make a decision about the response to the surrender call,'' the military official said. No militants surrendered in the capital. The chief priest of <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> temples in <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION> said `` nobody turned up'' at the shrines where reception centers were set up for receiving the rebels. An official at a reception center in <LOCATION> Weligama </LOCATION>, 85 miles south of <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION>, said on the telephone: `` We have a whole lot of armed police here but nobody to surrender.'' The south is the Sinhalese heartland where the Marxist rebels are most active. The extremists have been blamed for more than 2,500 political killings since January and most of the victims have been government officials and security men. The militants have been trying to topple the government since July 1987 when it signed a peace accord aimed at ending the Tamil separatist campaign. The left-wing extremists say the accord gave the minority Tamils too many concessions. They also say the presence of Indian troops, deployed to disarm the Tamil rebels and enforce the 1987 accord, compromises the country's independence. An Indian High Commission or embassy offical said <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> troops will continue to carry out operations against the Tamil rebels. But the troops will not hinder the `` process of surrendering,'' said the offical who can not be identified under briefing rules. The dominant Tamil rebel group, <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tigers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tamil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Eelam </ORGANIZATION>, said Tuesday: `` We will not agree to any cease-fire so long as the Indian army remains in <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>.'' <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> became involved in the conflict because of the sympathies of its own 60 million Tamils to the rebel cause. Tamil militants launched a campaign in 1983 for an independent homeland, citing discrimination by the majority Sinhalese in employment and education. Tamils comprise 18 percent of <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>'s 16 million people. Most live in the Northern and <LOCATION> Northeastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Provinces </LOCATION>, where they want their homeland. Sinhalese make up 75 percent of the island's population and control the government and military
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890412-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-89 2332EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Afghanistan 1stLd-Writethru a0613 04-12 0673</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Afghanistan, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0613,0690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Says Troops Forced Guerrilla Retreat from Jalalabad</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 5 grafs to UPDATE with rebel government to move inside
Afghanistan. Picks up 3rd pvs, `Mohammad Karim...' ADDS 3 grafs on rebels
ask Security Council to stay clear.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SHARON HERBAUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KABUL, Afghanistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Moslem guerrillas fired rockets and heavy artillery into the eastern city of <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION>, but Afghan troops returned fire and forced the guerrillas to retreat, a government spokesman said Wednesday. Also Wednesday, Iran-based guerrilla leaders were quoted as saying plans were under way for an offensive near <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION>, an <LOCATION> Afghan </LOCATION> resistance leader, <PERSON> Gulbuddin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hekmatyar </PERSON>, said the resistance plans to shift its interim government this week from <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> to the `` liberated'' <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> provinces of <LOCATION> Kunar </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Paktia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hekmatyar </PERSON>, foreign minister of the interim government set up in February by several guerrilla groups, told a news conference Wednesday that the entire Cabinet would move within the `` next two to three days,'' some ministries to <LOCATION> Asadabad </LOCATION>, capital of <LOCATION> Kunar </LOCATION>, and others to a site still be decided in <LOCATION> Paktia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hekmatyar </PERSON> was in <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> on an eight-nation tour to seek recognition for his government. <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION> announced Tuesday if will formally recognize the interim government. <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Karim </PERSON> <PERSON> Khalili </PERSON>, spokesman of the Iran-based guerrillas, said at a news conference in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> that `` forces in the city of <LOCATION> Meidan </LOCATION>, near <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, and in <PERSON> Ghazi </PERSON> and areas to the north of the capital are preparing to start operations, and soon a new front will be opened near <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>,'' <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> radio reported. The guerrillas are split into the Iran-based Shiite coalition and the larger Sunni alliance based in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. The two have been at odds over the formation of a guerrilla government, in which the Shiite alliance is not represented. An unidentified official of the Shiite alliance was quoted by <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s official <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> as saying that `` plans to attack <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> have been drawn up and efforts are under way to unite all mujahedeen groups for delivering the coup de grace.'' Pakistan-based guerrilla groups have been engaged in heavy fighting for <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION> since March 6. <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Nabi </PERSON> <PERSON> Amani </PERSON> said 19 civilians died and 15 were wounded in the latest rebel attack on <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION>, 45 miles from the border with <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. `` Government forces counterattacked and forced the opposition to halt their offensive and retreat,'' he said. <PERSON> Amani </PERSON> said there were no casualties among government soldiers. He said 271 guerrillas were killed and 201 were injured. The information could not be independently confirmed. The guerrillas, known as mujahedeen, or Islamic holy warriors, have been fighting nearly 11 years to topple <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s Marxist government. Capturing <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION> is considered a key element in their strategy because it would give the guerrillas their first major urban foothold. <PERSON> Amani </PERSON> also said <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> checkpoints will be set up at six points along the Afghan-Pakistani border to check for aid <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> alleges is flowing to the guerrillas illegally from <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> agreed Tuesday to allow the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> to set up permanent monitoring posts along the border. It denies the Afghan allegations. The checkpoints will be manned by the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Good </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mission </ORGANIZATION> to <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, which monitored the withdrawal of Soviet troops from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Khalili </PERSON> said the Iran-based forces oppose the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> deployment. <PERSON> Rasul </PERSON> <PERSON> Sayyaf </PERSON>, prime minister of the rebels' provisional government, told <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Secretary-General <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> on Wednesday to stay clear of what he called a dying <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> government's desperate tactic to draw the <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> into a domestic war. In a letter, he asked the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> chief to pre-empt a <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> debate and if that was not possible, then to `` steer the debate on the right course _ <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> interference in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>.'' <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s ruling Marxists charged in an emergency session of the <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> Tuesday that <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> was waging a `` full-fledged war'' against <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> and intervening in the war by sending Pakistani army and milita to the battlefront. <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> denied these charges, which have repeatedly been leveled by the <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> government.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890412-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-89 0339EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AP-Bismarck     04-12 0139</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP-Bismarck,0143</SECOND>
<HEAD>AP Names Phyllis Mensing Correspondent In Bismarck</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BISMARCK, N.D. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> Mensing </PERSON>, day supervising editor in the <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> bureau of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, has been named correspondent in charge of the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Bismarck </LOCATION> bureau. The appointment was announced Tuesday by <PERSON> Tena </PERSON> <PERSON> Haraldson </PERSON>, chief of bureau for <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mensing </PERSON>, 39, joined the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> as a part-time newswoman while attending school at <ORGANIZATION> Augustana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, S.D. Following graduation and a year teaching, she rejoined the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION> in 1972. Other assignments took her to <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON>, <LOCATION> S.D. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fargo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.D. </LOCATION> _ where she served as correspondent _ and <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mensing </PERSON> is a native of <LOCATION> Mapleton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>. She succeeds <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Brasher </PERSON>, who will transfer to the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> bureau to be a regional reporter for <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890412-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-89 0339EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AP-Indianapolis     04-12 0097</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP-Indianapolis,0100</SECOND>
<HEAD>AP Names News Editor For Indiana</HEAD>
<DATELINE>INDIANAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Huddleston </PERSON>, day supervisor in the <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> bureau of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, has been named news editor for <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>. The appointment was announced Tuesday by <ORGANIZATION> Indianapolis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chief </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Robert </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shaw </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Huddleston </PERSON> succeeds <PERSON> Lindel </PERSON> <PERSON> Hutson </PERSON>, who recently was named chief of bureau in <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Huddleston </PERSON>, 32, is a native of Limestone, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, and a graduate of Centre College of <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>. She worked for The Commonwealth-Journal of <LOCATION> Somerset </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, before joining the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Frankfort </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, in 1984. She transferred to <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> later that year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890412-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-89 0011EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-MassGrave 5thLd-Writethru a0728 04-12 0928</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mass Grave, 5th Ld - Writethru, a0728,0955</SECOND>
<HEAD>Graves Found Near Mexico-U.S. Border, Satanic Sacrifice Suspected</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 15 grafs to UPDATE with victims male, kettles of
human and animal parts found, Kilroy's brain missing, other details; picks
up 11th graf, ``Kiloroy, a pre-medical ...'' Note contents.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos BRO1, HTP1, LaserGraphic 69</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOEL WILLIAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BROWNSVILLE, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Authorities found 12 male bodies in graves at a ranch just south of the Mexican border Tuesday and said the victims were sacrificed by a satanic cult of drug smugglers. `` It was horrible,'' <LOCATION> Cameron </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff <PERSON> Alex </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> told a news conference in this border city. `` It was like a human slaughterhouse.'' <ORGANIZATION> Mexican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judicial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> arrested four people, said sheriff's Lt. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Gavito </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gavito </PERSON> said the suspects were <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Mexican citizens, but did not identify them further. The dead found by the federal police included 21-year-old <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> student <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Kilroy </PERSON>, who vanished during his spring break last month while in the Mexican city of <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Gavito </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Kilroy </PERSON> apparently was chosen at random by drug smugglers who hoped human sacrifices would protect them from harm, <PERSON> Gavito </PERSON> said. He was taken after the cult members `` were told to pick one <ORGANIZATION> Anglo </ORGANIZATION> male that particular night,'' the lieutenant said. The cult had been involved in human sacrifices for about nine months, he said, and prayed to the devil `` so the police would not arrest them, so bullets would not kill them and so they could make more money.'' Authorities found candles and kettles full of body parts and animal bones, said <LOCATION> Oran </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Neck </LOCATION>, chief <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Customs agent in <LOCATION> Brownsville </LOCATION>. A small color snapshot displayed at the news conference showed a caldron containing a dark, red liquid and what appeared to be bones. Another picture showed 12 body bags. Authorities would not identify the other victims, but said all were males. One grave held three bodies another contained two, said Neck. Some victims were shot in the head, while others appeared to have been slain with machetes or sledgehammers, the agent said. The bodies were found Tuesday morning in a field about 20 miles west of <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Gavito </PERSON> said. `` I've been an investigator 15 years and it's one of the worst things I've ever seen,'' he said. <PERSON> Kilroy </PERSON>'s brain was missing, said <ORGANIZATION> Brownsville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> photographer <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Padilla </PERSON>, who said he saw the body at a <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION> funeral home. `` There was nothing inside the skull,'' <PERSON> Padilla </PERSON> said. In some forms of witchcraft, removal of the brain signifies a sacrifice of the victim's soul. <PERSON> Padilla </PERSON> said <PERSON> Kilroy </PERSON>'s legs were cut off at mid-calf and his spine was severed and twisted. <PERSON> Kilroy </PERSON>, a pre-medical student, vanished from a crowded <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION> street shortly after 2 a.m. on March 14 while on a drinking foray with a group of friends in <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION>, a city of 180,000 just across the <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Brownsville </LOCATION>. Law officers on both sides of the border were stumped, with no clues to <PERSON> Kilroy </PERSON>'s disappearance despite an intensive search, the questioning of nearly 100 people and a $ 15,000 reward. The 3-foot-deep grave containing <PERSON> Kilroy </PERSON>'s body was found after Mexican federal police alerted <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials early Tuesday that they had obtained confessions from the suspects, officials said. At least one of the suspects admitted involvement in <PERSON> Kilroy </PERSON>'s death, said Neck The student's parents, <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Kilroy </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, arrived in <LOCATION> Brownsville </LOCATION> on Tuesday following the grisly discovery. <PERSON> Gwen </PERSON> <PERSON> Huddleston </PERSON>, the mother of one of the students with <PERSON> Kilroy </PERSON> the night he vanished, took the <ORGANIZATION> Kilroys </ORGANIZATION> to the airport for the trip. `` <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> -LRB- <PERSON> Kilroy </PERSON> -RRB- of course is very upset after finding out the news that it really was <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> down there,'' she told <ORGANIZATION> KTRK-TV </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> later. `` They went down there in hopes that it would n't be, but it did n't turn out that way.'' Authorities refused to talk about the evidence or pinpoint the location of the grave. The area was sealed, <PERSON> Gavito </PERSON> said. The case is being investigated by Customs, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney General's Office, Mexican federal authorities and local law enforcement agencies on both sides of the border. It was the third drug-related mass killing discovered near the border in less than three weeks. On March 29, Mexican authorities found the bodies of three women and six men on an abandoned ranch near <LOCATION> Agua </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Prieta </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, just across the border from <LOCATION> Douglas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>. Five were at the bottom of a well and four in an earthen septic tank All nine were bound and had been tortured and mutilated, officials said. Mexican and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> investigators said the slayings were drug-related. On April 1, the bodies of three more men killed in similar fashion were fished from the well. All were believed to be Mexican nationals. On March 27, two people from <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> and three from the Mexican state of <LOCATION> Sonora </LOCATION> were found bound and stabbed in a shed in <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION>. Those deaths were also called drug-related. Officials said Thursday it was possible the <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Agua </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Prieta </LOCATION> cases were linked. Herbal medicine and the use of witch doctors, or `` curanderos,'' is common in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. Most markets in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> have stalls where herbs are sold for cures, to cast or remove good or bad spells or to cleanse a home of evil. Human sacrifice, common in the country's pre-Columbian Indian cultures, is little known now, but is not unheard of. It is said to be used occasionally in rituals in which one person is killed as part of curing another. One such case was reported earlier this year in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890412-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-89 0341EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:SittingPretty     04-12 0808</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Sitting Pretty,0827</SECOND>
<HEAD>An Unknown Jerome Kern Musical Comes Back To New York</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL KUCHWARA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Drama Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Imagine <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Webber </PERSON> or <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Sondheim </PERSON> not allowing songs from their latest musicals to be recorded or played on the radio or performed in nightclubs and cabarets. <PERSON> Jerome </PERSON> <PERSON> Kern </PERSON> issued such an edict after the opening of `` Sitting Pretty,'' his 1924 musical written with <PERSON> Guy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bolton </PERSON> and P.G. <PERSON> Wodehouse </PERSON>. Why the ban? <PERSON> Kern </PERSON> was a man who wanted his music played the way he wrote it and not jazzed up or distorted by popular renditions. He was a perfectionist, although some musical comedy historians think the prohibition may have been a ploy by <PERSON> Kern </PERSON> to create more interest in the show. If it was, it did n't work. Despite generally good reviews, the musical had a disappointing run of only 95 performances and promptly was forgotten. Eiht or nine of its songs were published, but much of the score disappeared until it was unearthed in a <LOCATION> Secaucus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, warehouse seven years ago. Now `` Sitting Pretty'' returns to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> for five performances in a concert version at <ORGANIZATION> Carnegie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Recital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- April 13 through April 16 -RRB-. It will be conducted by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McGlinn </PERSON>, the man behind the recent complete and critically praised recording of `` Show Boat.'' The concerts, performed with a 23-piece orchestra and an 18-member cast, star <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaines </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Graae </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Criswell </PERSON> and <PERSON> Paige </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Hara </PERSON>. For <PERSON> McGlinn </PERSON>, `` Sitting Pretty'' is a labor of love, a chance to perform a musical not heard in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> for 65 years. `` Nobody knows the score at all,'' said <PERSON> McGlinn </PERSON> who considers the work an important transition piece, a bridge between <PERSON> Kern </PERSON>'s less serious, early musicals and his masterpiece, `` Show Boat. `` <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, who orchestrated many of <PERSON> Kern </PERSON>'s musicals, would sometimes refer to ` Sitting Pretty' in interviews, saying that it was something that people someday should hear again because it was special,'' he said <PERSON> McGlinn </PERSON> first heard the music in 1980 when <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Tynes </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Amsterdam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Theater </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION> let <PERSON> McGlinn </PERSON> raid his sheet music collection. `` It was so different and so beautiful, and on an emotional plane so far removed from many of the other things <PERSON> Kern </PERSON> was writing at the time,'' he said. `` This score has the deepest emotional depth of anything he wrote until ` Show Boat.' `` I do n't know what part of himself <PERSON> Kern </PERSON> dug down into to create this score, and I should say <PERSON> Wodehouse </PERSON> did as well because the lyrics are as moving and emotional as a lot of the music.'' The creators did n't get it from the frivolous plot, concocted by <PERSON> Wodehouse </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bolton </PERSON>, which involves twin orphans who fall in love with the real and adopted sons of a wealthy old man. `` It's extraordinary because there is this wild dichotomy between the book and parts of the score which are really emotional _ songs like ` There Is n't One Girl,' ` A Year From Today' and ` The Magic Train.' It's the real thing. When the music starts, playtime stops,'' <PERSON> McGlinn </PERSON> said. `` I think it comes from the fact that <PERSON> Kern </PERSON>, by 1924, was ready to flex his muscles. And when he saw opportunities to write truly emotional music, he went for it.'' `` Sitting Pretty'' remained unperformable until the <LOCATION> Secaucus </LOCATION> discovery where a full score for the show as well as a lot of <PERSON> Kern </PERSON>'s working sketches were found. The Carnegie concerts will also include 95 percent of the show's dialogue <PERSON> McGlinn </PERSON> discovered a late draft of the script in the Museum of the City of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Between that script, an early copy filed at the Library of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and the full scores found in <LOCATION> Secaucus </LOCATION>, he was able to piece together a book for the performers to use. <PERSON> Kern </PERSON> has been a major preoccupation of <PERSON> McGlinn </PERSON>'s for a long time. In 1985, he did concert versions at Carnegie of <PERSON> Kern </PERSON>'s `` Oh, Boy!,'' `` Oh, Lady! Lady!!'' and `` Zip! Goes a Million.'' Besides `` Show Boat,'' <PERSON> McGlinn </PERSON> has a recording of Kern overtures, including `` Sitting Pretty,'' coming out in May on EMI-Angel. He also has a complete version of <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> <PERSON> Porter </PERSON>'s `` Anything Goes'' waiting for release on the same label His other upcoming projects include new recordings of <PERSON> Porter </PERSON>'s `` Kiss Me, <PERSON> Kate </PERSON>'' and possibly <PERSON> Irving </PERSON> <PERSON> Berlin </PERSON>'s `` Annie Get Your Gun.'' For the moment, though, he's concentrating on <PERSON> Kern </PERSON> and the concert version of `` Sitting Pretty.'' Musical comedy buffs will savor one number in particular, the title song. It was dropped a week into the musical's original run because leading man <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> Frye </PERSON> had a minor speech impediment. When <PERSON> Frye </PERSON> sang, `` I like to sit, just sit and sit and sit, with you the whole day through,'' it sounded, according to <LOCATION> Kern </LOCATION> biographer <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Bordman </PERSON> `` embarrassingly different.'' <PERSON> McGlinn </PERSON>'s concerts should rescue the song
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890412-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-89 0345EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ChangingFaceOfAIDS     04-12 1165</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Changing Face Of AIDS,1194</SECOND>
<HEAD>AIDS Organizations Coping With New Clientele</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL GEITNER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A group of middle-class men, concerned that friends were dying and nothing was being done, met in <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Village </LOCATION> eight years ago. They called themselves Gay Men's Health Crisis. They had little money and less clout; there was no name for the disease that brought them together. Today, Gay Men's Health Crisis has a $ 10 million budget, its own six-story <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> building and 2,000 volunteers, and the disease has a name: acquired immune deficiency syndrome. After years of hectoring politicians and public health officials to address the problems of people with AIDS, <ORGANIZATION> GMHC </ORGANIZATION> and its cohorts are themselves being challenged to cope with the changing face of that population. Nationwide, more than 87,000 cases of AIDS have been reported, about two-thirds of them among homosexual or bisexual men. But in many cities, especially along the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>, someone diagnosed with AIDS today is about as likely to have become infected by shooting up with dirty needles as through sex. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, intravenous drug abusers comprised an estimated 45 percent of all newly reported AIDS cases last year. `` These projections bear out what we have long known, that the spread of AIDS is fueled by drugs -LRB- and -RRB- that AIDS is accelerating its onslaught upon poor, drug-ravaged neighborhoods and minority communities,'' said city Health Commissioner <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON>. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, IV drug abusers comprised 59 percent of new AIDS cases. What this means to AIDS-service providers is only now being addressed. <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, with the most people with AIDS per capita of any <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> city, wins praise from all quarters for its response to the epidemic. Its Shanti Project, a peer-counseling group for the terminally ill, had one staffer in 1982 and was nearly defunct. Now it has a $ 3 million budget and a paid staff of 70, directing counseling groups and a housing program geared toward independent living for people with AIDS. But <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Day </PERSON>, <PERSON> Shanti </PERSON>'s education director, notes that about 96 percent of AIDS cases in the city are among gay males `` who used to lead relatively normal lives,'' were employed full time and have a firmer footing in society. `` I think that because the impact of AIDS has been primarily, overwhelmingly, on the gay community thus far, we have succeeded so far in developing our resources along with the epidemic,'' he said. `` We do n't have the answers yet on how to best serve the IV drug-user population.'' The situation is similar in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>, and other cities where the number of IV drug users is relatively small, experts say. In <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, things are more difficult. `` What we're dealing with here in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, particularly when we're dealing with the issue of homelessness and destitution, is not the gay community, but blacks, minorities, IV drug users, prostitutes and their families _ people of the streets basically,'' said <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Mascia </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Travelers </ORGANIZATION> and Immigrants Aid, a private group that helps house homeless people with AIDS. `` While we want to adopt some of the programs or utilize some of the models that <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> has, we're talking about working with a different population for the most part,'' <PERSON> Mascia </PERSON> said. Part of the problem is that an IV drug user does not automatically kick the habit when diagnosed with AIDS. But most AIDS organizations require infected drug abusers to enter treatment before they are accepted as clients. `` It's fine for us to deal with you as someone with ARC -LRB- AIDS-related condition -RRB- or AIDS,'' said <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Sweeney </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> GMHC </ORGANIZATION> deputy director for policy. `` But the truth is if you're just leaving our front door and going out and sticking another needle in your arm, we're really not doing you any big favor. `` You've got two illnesses to be dealt with.'' Programs such as <ORGANIZATION> GMHC </ORGANIZATION> and the Shanti Project depend on volunteers, but <PERSON> Sweeney </PERSON> said, `` We are finding now that ... the volunteer model really does n't work with them. They need much more direct, intense case management, much more involvement, usually by a professional staff person to help them set up the structure of their life, so that they're independent.'' The drug abuser also is more likely to be homeless, yet shelters are no place for someone infected with AIDS. Several cities run apartments for people with AIDS capable of independent living, but demand far outstrips supply. People with AIDS who no longer need hospitalization but have no place to go often are sent to single-room-occupancy hotels, where they have no medical supervision and must contend with seedy surroundings and crime. Many are `` discharged from the hospital and can sit on the bench out front,'' said <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON> of Lifelink, a Washington-based AIDS organization. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, a lucky few find room in the highly praised, privately run <ORGANIZATION> Bailey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, the city's only supervised AIDS residence. It opened in 1986 with rooms for 44 people and hopes to add nine more rooms by the summer of 1990. For <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Conklin </PERSON>, 38, a 20-year heroin and cocaine addict diagnosed with AIDS about two years ago, a clean, nicely furnished room at <ORGANIZATION> Bailey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and a treatment program `` was the only thing that saved me.'' Yet even <ORGANIZATION> Bailey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> has evicted several residents because of drug-related problems, said its administrator, <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Hough </PERSON>. `` We consider ourselves a humane society, and I do n't think we should doubly punish a person who's already suffering,'' said <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Doherty </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> for the Homeless board. `` I would be hard pressed to make the argument that every single program has to accept people who ... ` go off the wagon.' Perhaps what we need, maybe, is a house in a community where people who can not stop have a place to go.'' <ORGANIZATION> GMHC </ORGANIZATION> also wants to see a range of services targeted at specific populations, but <PERSON> Sweeney </PERSON> said his organization, despite its position as the nation's largest private AIDS-service organization, ca n't be expected to be all things to all people. Gay and bisexual men still make up 80 percent of <ORGANIZATION> GMHC </ORGANIZATION>'s caseload of 2,500 HIV-infected people, and `` just taking care of that burden alone is extremely daunting,'' he said. Some former volunteers and other AIDS activists have criticized <ORGANIZATION> GMHC </ORGANIZATION> for, among other things, not sharing more of its resources with smaller groups, but <PERSON> Sweeney </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> GMHC </ORGANIZATION> does n't want to appear arrogant. `` We're real conscious of our limitations. We believe in empowerment. We believe in communities taking care of themselves and getting the resources and asserting their own leadership ... `` The future is to get a bigger pie and to get other people involved with the disease ... A lot of the policy and advocacy work that we're doing is around this issue of budgets and getting money out to communities who do n't have the access and the political organizing skills that we do ... `` I think we are around for a much longer fight than maybe some people anticipated.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890412-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-89 0300EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-EastGermanEcology     04-12 0702</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-East German Ecology,0725</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pollution In East Germany Extends Westward As Far As North Sea</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GIRARD C. STEICHEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LEIPZIG, East Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Air and water pollution have reached crisis proportions in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, and Western experts sy pollutants are taking a heavy toll in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> as far as the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>. West German officials are considering an offer of money and technology to help the East German communist government clean it up. `` The water quality of the <LOCATION> Elbe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> is particularly critical when it reaches <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> <PERSON> Huthmacher </PERSON>, a spokesman for the West German <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>. `` Air pollution has also reached dangerous levels.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION> ecological group's West German branch said the <LOCATION> Elbe </LOCATION> carries wastes to the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>, where `` plant and animal life are seriously threatened and destroyed.'' It also said human health is also increasingly at risk from contaminated drinking water. In <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION> and many East German cities, power plants using high-sulphur brown coal belch out huge clouds of smoke that stings the eyes and coats buildings with black soot. Heavy exhaust fumes from cars, trucks and buses further foul the air. Western studies indicate that <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> pumps more pollution into the atmosphere than any other country in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, including nearly 5 million tons a year of sulphur dioxide, according to West German surveys. After the oil price rises in the 1970s, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> increasingly turned to its considerable brown coal reserves. Statistics on the extent of pollution are not made public in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, but the government is under pressure to release them. An East German ecological group called the <ORGANIZATION> Green </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arche </ORGANIZATION> has demanded that the government `` stop treating evidence of environmental pollution as state secrets.'' Underground ecology newspapers detailing local pollution problems are frequently seized. While East German officials have shown an increased willingless to work with <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> on environmental problems, Western experts say they are still a long way from concrete and effective measures. `` Working groups from both sides are still working to come up with an acceptable program to help reduce the problems,'' said <PERSON> Marlene </PERSON> <PERSON> Muehe </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the West German <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION>. East German officials said at a recent environmental conference in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> that a number of new projects had been launched to reduce river pollution and that the <LOCATION> Elbe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> would likely be cleaned up by 1992. <PERSON> Hans </PERSON> <PERSON> Reichelt </PERSON>, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s Minister for <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION>, was quoted in the state-run media as saying that all new and refitted power plants would be equipped with filtration devices beginning next year. But West German officials say that in order to make any substantial progress soon, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> will have to provide the East Germans with technology and financial assistance. While <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> was the first Eastern European nation to enact strict environmental laws, the guidelines are rarely enforced, Western officials say. West German government studies indicate that cleanup tasks will be difficult because <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> has largely abandoned environmental protection programs in recent years. `` The last two five-year plans have contained neither a detailed environmental program nor funds to carry out projects outlined in earlier plans,'' a West German government study said. `` Because of increasing economic pressures, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> has made industrial growth and increased production a priority over environmental protection.'' West German officials, who are grappling with the heavily industrialized nation's own formidable environmental problems, say the East German pollution is of grave concern. `` Our own efforts to correct environmental problems are made significantly more difficult because of the East German pollutants,'' <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Huthmacher </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION>, referring to efforts to clean up the nation's rivers and to reduce emissions that cause acid rain. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s forests have suffered considerable damage because of acid rain. Environmental experts also say East German factories dump tons of untreated industrial wastes into waterways where it mixes with the runoff from fields treated with nitrate fertilizers. Many major rivers flow into <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. According to <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION>, more than 100 tons of waste _ including heavy metals, industrial sludge, raw sewage and pesticides _ flow into the <LOCATION> Elbe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> each day in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890412-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-89 0349EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Spill-Defenders     04-12 0670</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Spill-Defenders,0691</SECOND>
<HEAD>Battle Against Oil Slick: Lonely And Frustrating</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By FRED BAYLES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP National Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ABOARD THE COMMITMENT (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For 11 days, <PERSON> Guido </PERSON> <PERSON> Casciano </PERSON> has fought the battle of <LOCATION> Sawmill </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, riding herd on wave after wave of oil with his nimble 27-foot fishing boat. For 11 nights, he has slept in the boat's tiny cabin so he'd be ready at first light to continue the deadening routine of coralling oil away from the salmon hatchery up the bay. `` It's fairly boring, but hopefully we're doing some good here,'' he said. <PERSON> Casciano </PERSON> and his fellow fishermen have done some good. But their rescue of the hatchery is a brief skirmish in a losing fight to limit the damage of 10 million gallons of crude oil spilled from the tanker <PERSON> Exxon </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON>. `` It's really frustrating when you consider what little you're accomplishing with all the effort here,'' said <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON>, who had his 48-foot Sound Adventure working with Casciano's Commitment on Monday `` When you think about what little oil you've picked up, it blows your mind.'' The view from above Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON> speaks to the seeming futility of the cleanup effort. The lower end of the sound is a checkerboard of oil. Rainbow swirls of oil nudge the shore in the hundreds of lonely bays and inlets. Mud-colored oil streamers stripe the deep green water of the open sound. The powerful forces of nature have taken man's mistake and scattered it hundreds of miles. No one knows this better than fishermen like <PERSON> Casciano </PERSON> and <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON>, neighbors from <PERSON> Cordova </PERSON> who have looked to the sound for their living. While officials dusted off contingency plans and held assessment meetings, the fishermen of the sound streamed out of towns like <PERSON> Cordova </PERSON> and <PERSON> Seward </PERSON> to do what they could. Most went without knowing they would be compensated for their efforts. Casciano and <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> were at <LOCATION> Sawmill </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> for five days before they received contracts from <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>, the only contact they have had with the company responsible for the spill. `` All of us figured that if nothing else, at least we're out here doing something,'' said <PERSON> Casciano </PERSON>. The independent fishermen organized their own battle plan. Booms were floated across the inner bay. The fishing boats took what materials they could get and began collecting the oil, using the same techniques they have used for years for fishing. A yellow, oil-smeared boom was attached at one end to Commitment, the other to Sound Adventure. Using hand signals and radio calls, the two boats moved in graceful ballet until clumps of oil, resembling greasy brown oatmeal, were snared in the boom. The strategy is similar to the way two boats can use seining nets to trap schools of salmon and herring. The oil was then floated to a `` sucker boat,'' a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> skimmer that sluices the oil from the water and into a small barge. But often, over the past two weeks, there has been no skimmer to feed. The special boats can only swallow 32 barrels of oil before their tanks are filled and they have to go unload. Whatever the fishermen are paid for the effort will fall short of the cost of what the spill may do their way of life. <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> lost at least $ 40,000 when the spill canceled the herring harvest. In normal times, his wife and daughter would be on the boat with him for weeks, helping catch fish. <PERSON> Carolyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> was aboard Sound Adventure on Monday after flying out to be with her husband. `` Everybody back at town is worried that our way of life may be over,'' she said. Both the <ORGANIZATION> Raymonds </ORGANIZATION> and Casciano are pessimistic about what their efforts mean against the massive amount of oil and unrelenting forces of nature. But they say it is better to be on the water, doing something, then sitting ashore. `` Maybe what you do is not going to make a dent, but you've got to try to do something to help,'' said <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890412-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-89 0302EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-India-Missiles     04-12 0644</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-India-Missiles,0669</SECOND>
<HEAD>Residents Refuse To Move From Homes Near Missile Launch Site</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DILIP GANGULY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHANDIPUR, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As dusk descends on this seaside village, men light kerosene lamps and women keep conch shells handy for a night vigil against the enemy _ a ballistic missile. It is not from an enemy country. Chandipur's 12,000 villagers want to stall the test-firing of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s first long-range ballistic missile. They say it is potentially dangerous and eventually will make them homeless. They fear the missile named `` AGNI,'' which means `` fire'' in <LOCATION> Hindi </LOCATION>, may carry nuclear warheads. The test-firing scheduled later this month will bracket <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> along with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in ballistic missile capability, military experts say. It also will enhance the power of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s 1.36 million-strong army and the country's geopolitical influence in the region, they say. `` It is more a technology demonstration, but it can be used in defense should the country require,'' said V.S. <PERSON> Arunachalam </PERSON>, who has overseen <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s defense research since 1982. `` Will it carry nuclear warheads?'' he asked. `` If you want, you can carry a nuclear warhead even on a bullock cart.'' Since April 1987, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> successfully has tested three types of surface-to-air and surface-to-surface missiles, with ranges varying from 5 -LCB- to 155 miles. Villagers in <LOCATION> Chandipur </LOCATION> are being lured with money and promises of free food and popular film videos if they leave their homes during launch time and move to temporary camps set up in the area. But they refuse to budge, and the battle of wits shows no sign of settlement. At the maximum-security launch site on the Bay of <LOCATION> Bengal </LOCATION> about 300 scientists and technocrats are putting final touches to the missile. They expect it to travel between 370 miles and 1,550 miles, a scientist said on condition of anonymity. The missile will carry a one-ton payload. `` The project is one of great national importance,'' Lt. Gen. R.S. <PERSON> Deswal </PERSON>, chief of <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Test </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Range </ORGANIZATION>, said in an interview. `` This is what we are telling the villagers.'' Military test-firing is nothing new to this village, where the colonial British set up an arms and ammunition test range 95 years ago. Scientists have been experimenting with two other missiles that were test-fired in 1987 and in 1988. But what sparked the controversy surrounding the new missile was an official announcement earlier this year asking villagers to vacate their homes. `` For the past three years, we are asking the government what is happening,'' said <PERSON> Arun </PERSON> <PERSON> Dey </PERSON>, a former legislator who heads the main anti-missile group. `` Their stock reply was ` nothing major, just routine firing and enlarging the facilities.' Now out of the blue they are telling us that they will fire a real big missile.'' Most Chandipur residents are fishermen or farmers who arrived here after the 1942 <LOCATION> Bengal </LOCATION> famine, which killed up to 1 million people. `` Let them fire the missile, but we not going to leave our homes,'' said <PERSON> Gaur </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Chandipur </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. `` They will have to fire a missile first at us and then they can fire another at the sky. `` We have said we will not go,'' he said. `` We maintain a nightlong vigil because we fear that they may force us out.'' Conch shells are blown to alert people in other hamlets. The government wants the people living in a two-mile radius of the launch pad to vacate their homes for four hours during the launch. But villagers fear it is a ploy. `` We are not asking them to leave for good, just during the launch period,'' said the general, who said officials have offered every adult $ 5.20 and each child $ 2.60 as compensation. <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> said: `` It is good money, no doubt, but should you trade your existence for that?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890412-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-89 0348EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--TokyoPopulation     04-12 0083</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Tokyo Population,0083</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tokyo's Population Declines for Second Year</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The city's population has declined for the second consecutive year, apparently because of high real estate prices in the capital. <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>'s population as of Jan. 1 was 11,718,720, down by 21,641 from a year earlier, the metropolitan government announced Tuesday. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> says the average land price in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> is $ 630 a square foot. In neighboring areas, the average price ranges from $ 180 to 255 a square foot.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890412-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-89 0348EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--AiredBedding     04-12 0141</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Aired Bedding,0142</SECOND>
<HEAD>Swiss Housewife Appeals Fine For Airing Duvet</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GENEVA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A housewife is appealing a $ 25 fine for airing her bedding after 10 a.m., saying the 30-year-old law that prohibits the practice is outdated. The woman has enlisted the help of a biochemist to back her claim that heavy pollution during morning rush hour makes it impossible to air her bedding `` legally,'' <ORGANIZATION> Geneva </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Suisse </ORGANIZATION> newspaper reported. Under 1955 public hygiene regulations in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>, anyone living in an urban area who hangs duvets or carpets out of windows or over balconies in public view after 10 a.m. can be fined. The clause, which remained in obscurity, made headlines in Swiss newspapers Tuesday when the housewife, identified only as <PERSON> Claudine </PERSON>, appealed the fine she received after a zealous policeman spotted her offending duvet 30 minutes after the deadline.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890412-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-89 0348EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Koran     04-12 0171</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Koran,0176</SECOND>
<HEAD>Record Price For A Koran</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A miniature Koran by an unknown 10th century scribe was bought at auction for a record $ 297,000 for a European collection, <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s said. The auction house said the price paid Tuesday for the little book of 332 vellum pages, less than three inches tall and written in Eastern kufic script, was the highest ever paid for a Koran or part of one. `` Finely written small Korans are much prized and very saleable,'' said <PERSON> Caroline </PERSON> <PERSON> Blyth </PERSON>, the firm's head of Islamic manuscripts. `` This one was very old and had the status of coming from the estate of Crown Prince <PERSON> Muhammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Hasan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mirza </PERSON> <PERSON> Qajar </PERSON>, the sole pretender to the throne of the Qajar dynasty in <LOCATION> Persia </LOCATION> which ended in the 1920s,'' she said. The buyer was only identified as representing a European collection. <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s had put a top estimate on the Koran of $ 169,000. A single decorated leaf from a large Koran made the previous record of $ 268,000 in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> in October.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890412-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-89 0236EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     04-12 0505</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0516</SECOND>
<HEAD>CBS Drives for Hoop, but NBC Slam-Dunks Another Week</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHRYN BAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Last year, the <ORGANIZATION> NCAA </ORGANIZATION> championship basketball game gave <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> a rare first place for the week in the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> television ratings. This year's game, in which <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> defeated Seton Hall by one point in overtime, was in the top 10. But it was n't enough to knock <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> out of first place, where it has been for 42 straight weeks. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> won the week that ended Sunday with a 15.4 rating. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> had a 13.0 and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 12.5. For the season, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> has a 16.0 rating, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 12.9 and CBS 12.6. The week was fairly typical, except that the onset of daylight saving time seemed to affect the earlier shows since viewers tend to be less eager to plop in front of the tube when it's still light outside. Therefore, `` The Cosby Show,'' which starts off the night for <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday, found itself in second place behind <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roseanne,'' which is broadcast an hour later on Tuesday night, even though `` Cosby'' had a bigger share of the audience `` Roseanne'' had the highest rating _ 23.3, but a 35 share. `` Cosby'' had a 22.4 rating, but a 38 share. The rating is a percentage of the nation's 9.4 million homes with television. The share is a percentage of sets actually in use. Daylight saving time also affected the news ratings, all were down somewhat. `` ABC World News Tonight'' was first with a 10.1 rating and a 20 share, slightly ahead of the `` CBS Evening News'' with a 9.9 and 20 share. `` NBC Nightly News'' had an 8.9 and 18 share. The top 10 prime-time shows last week were: `` Roseanne'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, `` The Cosby Show'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` Cheers'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` A Different World'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` 60 Minutes'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, `` <ORGANIZATION> NCAA </ORGANIZATION> Championship _ <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> vs. <ORGANIZATION> Seton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION>'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, `` Golden Girls'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` Empty Nest'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` L.A. Law'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> and `` Murder, She Wrote'' CBS. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Columbo'' came in 12th for the week, a good showing. The bad news for <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> is `` Moonlighting,'' which was in the bottom 10. `` Moonlighting'' went on hiatus earlier this year, then moved to Sunday night where it had a 6.2 and 10 share last week. Only two other prime-time shows, both on <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, rank lower: `` HeartBeat'' and `` Men.'' Even <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> had three shows with higher ratings than `` Moonlighting.'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> got a so-so performance out of the premiere of `` The Robert Guillaume Show'' which finished 46th. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> won the Sunday movie battle with a repeat of `` Romancing the Stone.'' It was 15th, out-rating <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Perry </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> movie, at 18th. CBS' `` Bridge to Silence,'' starring <PERSON> Marlee </PERSON> <PERSON> Matlin </PERSON> in her first speaking role, ranked 35th. CBS' Sunday schedule was pushed back because of an overrun of the Masters golf tournament. The lowest-rated shows of the week were: `` Hard Time on Planet Earth,'' `` Mission Impossible,'' `` Rock' n' Roll Mom,'' `` Quantum Leap,'' `` Sesame Street: 20 and Still Counting,'' `` Great Circuses of the World,'' `` A Man Called Hawk,'' `` Moonlighting, `` HeartBeat'' and `` Men.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890412-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-89 0227EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     04-12 0594</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0675</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's TV Shows Ratings</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Season-to-date rankings not available.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of April 3-9. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, rating for the week, and total homes. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 90.4 million TV homes. 1. `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 23.3 rating, 21.1 million homes. 2. `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 22.4, 20.2 million homes. 3. `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 22.2, 20.1 million homes. 4. `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 21.5, 19.4 million homes. 5. `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 21.3, 19.3 million homes. 6. `` <ORGANIZATION> NCAA </ORGANIZATION> Championship: <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> vs. Seton Hall,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 21.2, 19.2 million homes. 7. `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.6, 18.6 million homes. 8. `` Empty Nest,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.9, 18.0 million homes. 9. `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.7, 17.8 million homes. 10. `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 19.3, 17.4 million homes. 11. `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.2, 17.4 million homes. 12. `` Columbo'' _ `` ABC Mystery Movie,'' 19.1, 17.3 million homes. 13. `` Wonder Years,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.6, 16.8 million homes. 14. `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.4, 16.6 million homes. 15. `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.2, 16.4 million homes. 15. `` Romancing the Stone'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' 18.2, 16.4 million homes. 17. `` Unsolved Mysteries,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.9, 16.2 million homes. 18. `` <PERSON> Perry </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>: The Case of the Musical Murder'' _ `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 17.4, 15.7 million homes. 19. `` Anything But Love,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.1, 15.5 million homes. 20. `` In the Heat of the Night,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.0, 15.4 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 21. `` Matlock,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.8. 22. `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.1. 23. `` Knots Landing,'' CBS, 15.9. 24. `` The <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.7. 25. `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.3. 26. `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.1. 26. `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.1. 28. `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.0. 28. `` <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> and The Fatman,'' CBS, 15.0. 30. `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.6. 30. `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 14.6. 30. `` NBC Movie: Pretty in Pink,'' 14.6. 33. `` Masters Golf Tournament,'' CBS, 14.3. 34. `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.2. 35. `` Bridge to Silence'' _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' 13.9. 36. `` Midnight Caller,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.8. 36. `` My Two Dads,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.8. 38. `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.7. 38. `` thirtysomething,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.7. 40. `` Family Ties,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.5. 41. `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.4. 42. `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.3. 43. `` Nightingales,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.2. 44. `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.0. 44. `` Just the Ten of Us,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.0. 46. `` <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Guillaume </PERSON> <PERSON> Show </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.6. 47. `` Day By Day,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.3. 48. `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.1. 48. `` The Equalizer,'' CBS, 12.1. 50. `` Wiseguy,'' CBS, 12.0. 50. `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 12.0. 52. `` Falcon Crest,'' CBS, 11.8. 53. `` Parent Trap III'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> Magical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.5. 54. `` Coach,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.9. 55. `` CBS Movie: Rocky IV,'' 10.8. 56. `` Beauty and the Beast,'' CBS, 10.7. 57. `` UNSUB,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.0. 57. `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 10.0 59. `` 48 Hours: Toy Money,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 9.3. 60. `` Live-In,'' CBS, 9.1. 61. `` National Lampoon's European Vacation'' _ `` CBS Saturday Movie,'' 8.8. 62. `` Heartland,'' CBS, 8.6. 63. `` Paradise,'' CBS, 8.5. 64. `` Tour of Duty,'' CBS, 8.3. 65. `` Hard Time on Planet Earth,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 8.2. 66. `` Mission: Impossible,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.1. 66. `` ABC Movie: Rock ` N' Roll Mom,'' 8.1. 68. `` Quantum Leap,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.0. 69. `` Sesame Street: 20 and Still Counting,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.7. 70. `` Great Circuses of the World,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.5. 71. `` A Man Called Hawk,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.4. 72. `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.9. 73. `` Moonlighting,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.2. 74. `` COPS,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.1. 74. `` Heartbeat,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.1. 76. `` <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shandling </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.7. 77. `` Men,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 4.1. 78. `` Beyond Tomorrow,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.0. 79. `` The Reporters,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.8. 80. `` <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.7. 81. `` Duet,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.1.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890412-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-89 0021EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-LAMayor 1stLd-Writethru a0670 04-12 0674</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-LA Mayor, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0670,0694</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bradley Seeks Fifth Term as Mayor, Low Voter Turnout Reported</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 8 grafs to UPDATE with Bradley early leader, UPDATE
turnout; picks up 3rd graf, ``Although virtually ...''</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto LA10</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JUDY FARAH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> was the early leader in his campaign for a historic fifth term as mayor of the nation's second-largest city, capturing 54 percent of the absentee vote in a race characterized by low voter turnout <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, 71, the city's first black mayor, needed at least 50 percent of the vote to avoid a June 6 runoff. Forty-five minutes after the polls closed at 8 p.m., <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> was in the lead with 13,146 absentee ballots, or 54 percent, according to the City Clerk's Office. The next-closest contender was freshman City Councilman <PERSON> Nate </PERSON> <PERSON> Holden </PERSON>, who received 5,014 absentee votes, or 20.66 percent. Former <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Supervisor and television commentator <PERSON> Baxter </PERSON> <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> had 4,800 votes, or 19.7 percent. Although virtually no observers believed the mayor could lose, one newspaper reported that a secret poll conducted by <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>'s campaign last week showed the mayor with just 53 percent of the vote <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> pollster <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Maullin </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Examiner </ORGANIZATION> that the polls conducted April 2 and 3 contained questions checking the impact of a city attorney's office ethics investigation of <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>. But, <PERSON> Maullin </PERSON> said, `` None of the results showed <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> not winning outright.'' City Clerk <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> had predicted a 25 percent to 30 percent turnout _ `` a historical low for a mayoral election.'' Voters faced morning low clouds and drizzle, and the turnout by 4 p.m. was only 11.6 percent of the city's 1.9 million registered voters. A poll taken recently by The <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> showed 78 percent of Hispanics, 70 percent of whites and 68 percent of blacks had a favorable impression of the Democratic mayor. That led <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> to be dubbed the `` Teflon mayor,'' because he is apparently not blamed for the city's mounting urban problems. The only currently elected official challenging <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, freshman City Councilman <PERSON> Nate </PERSON> <PERSON> Holden </PERSON>, was considered his only serious opponent in the non-partisan race, but hardly a threat to the 16-year mayor. Other candidates included a former county supervisor, a socialist oil field worker and a singer-dancer who used to cavort in a green bikini across the street from City Hall every day. The winner of Tuesday's mayor's race will oversee <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> at least into the early 1990s, leading a city with a population that is swelling past 3 million people.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Pollsters and would-be opponents such as City Councilman <PERSON> Zev </PERSON> <PERSON> Yaroslavsky </PERSON> agree that <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>'s low-key image has kept him from being linked in voters' minds with <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>' growing problems, including criminal gangs, illegal drug trade, traffic congestion and a failing sewage system. <PERSON> Yaroslavsky </PERSON> had widely been considered <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>'s leading challenger, but backed out of the race after apparently deciding that he could n't win. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>'s image even appeared untarnished by an ethics investigation by the city attorney's office, which learned that the mayor had performed consulting work with <ORGANIZATION> Far </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> East </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>, which did business with the city. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> returned the $ 18,000 in fees he was paid by the bank and called the charges politically motivated. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, the son of a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> sharecropper and the grandson of slaves, was first elected mayor of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> in 1973. A track star at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, he first entered public service as a <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> police lieutenant, and later was elected to the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> City Council. He was defeated in his first run at mayor in a bitter 1969 race against incumbent <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Yorty </PERSON> that critics said was tinged with racism, but came back to beat <PERSON> Yorty </PERSON> the next time around. At the end of his current term, <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> will become the first mayor in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> history to have served four full terms. He has run twice for governor, but was defeated in 1982 and 1986 by Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890412-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-89 0222EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Budget Bjt   04-12 0570</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Budget, Bjt,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Budget Negotiators Resorting to Gimmicks, Sales</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Budget negotiators from the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> are turning to accounting gimmicks and asset sales for a major portion of their budget package, after failing to reach agreement on strong deficit-reduction steps. The group is struggling to wrap up more than a month of talks aimed at shaving about $ 28 billion from the fiscal 1990 deficit. That would reduce red ink to about $ 100 billion next year as mandated by the Gramm-Rudman law, according to White House estimates. Budget experts agree that any long-term solution to the huge deficit problem requires a meaningful shift in fiscal policy. Translation: either significant new taxes or reductions in federal programs or a combination of the two. But with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> opposing new taxes or cuts in military spending or foreign aid, and the Democratic-controlled <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> sure to reject deep cuts in domestic programs, the negotiators are able to only nibble at the edges of major policy changes this year. That scenario has been reinforced directly in recent days as members of the negotiating team have presented ideas to their constituencies in the White House or on congressional committees. In many cases, they've been told to look elsewhere to reduce the deficit or face rejection, said sources familiar with the closed-door meetings. So in an effort to avert a crisis, such as violating Gramm-Rudman and triggering its automatic spending cuts, the talks have turned increasingly toward the smoke and mirrors approach to budgeting. They are considering: _ Moving payment of some farm subsidies ahead so the checks are written this fiscal year instead of next, a shift that makes fiscal 1990 look nearly $ 1 billion trimmer _ Taking the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION> Postal Service `` off-budget,'' knocking nearly $ 2 billion in red ink off the books next year. _ Making an accounting change in the food stamp program to `` save'' another $ 500 million _ Selling off nearly $ 6 billion in government assets _ a policy which often brings in money at first but then costs money in the long run Other items on the list that take advantage of federal accounting methods include claiming credit for $ 2 billion trimmed from the <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> program by simply extending existing cost controls, and about $ 600 million by continuing a retirement policy for federal employees. The group is even prepared to claim $ 100 million in savings because <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> earlier this year rejected a pay raise for itself and other top federal officials, according to one source. Rep. <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Panetta </PERSON>, the chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, declined to discuss any specifics, but conceded the negotiators were struggling. `` We've got to reach this goal in a credible way, and it's not easy,'' he said. `` Under the circumstances we are working with, we are reaching the best possible solution.'' But, he added, `` There's no question that this -LRB- package -RRB- is going to send a message that more needs to be done.'' The budget negotiations have dragged on longer than planned, and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will not meet its April 15 deadline for passing a budget resolution. The budget serves as a blueprint for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' annual spending bills and tax legislation. Under the Gramm-Rudman law, if the president and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> fail to enact legislation that will reduce the deficit to within $ 10 billion of next year's $ 100 billion target, the administration must make across-the-board spending cuts to make up the difference.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890412-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-89 0232EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     04-12 0833</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>Big Foreign Purchases of Feed Corn Offset Domestic Drop</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Foreign buyers are gobbling up huge amounts of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> corn supply, but domestic livestock feeders are easing back on use of the mighty feed grain. A new supply-and-demand analysis by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> showed Tuesday that corn exports may total 2.1 billion bushels in the marketing year that began last Sept. 1. The new forecast was up by 100 million bushels from indications a month ago and 21 percent more than the 1.73 billion shipped in 1987-88. Exports at that level would be the highest since corn shipments totaled 2.4 billion bushels in 1980-81. About 4 billion bushels of corn are expected to be used as livestock feed this year, down from 4.3 billion forecast in March and well below the record of 4.74 billion bushels consumed a year earlier. According to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> records, that would put feed use at the lowest since 3.82 billion bushels were fed to livestock in 1983-84. Corn is the largest and most important field crop grown by American farmers. As livestock feed it helps produce the bulk of the meat, poultry and dairy products that reach consumers. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> stockpile at the beginning of the new corn marketing year this coming Sept. 1 is forecast at 1.83 billion bushels, up from the 1.66 billion bushels indicated in March. Last Sept. 1, before the drought-shriveled 1988 corn harvest was added to the supply, the corn carryover was 4.23 billion bushels. With a reduced supply, corn prices shot up from an average of $ 1.94 per bushel in 1987-88 to a projected range of $ 2.45 to $ 2.70 this season. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat carryover on June 1, the beginning of the new wheat marketing year, was indicated at 549 million bushels, up slightly from 534 million forecast last month but far below the 1.26 billion bushels in the inventory last June 1. Wheat exports and domestic use are down, but the main impact has been the reduced 1988 harvest. Wheat prices are expected to average $ 3.65 to $ 3.80 per bushel this season, up from $ 2.57 in 1987-88. The soybean situation reflects a bare-bones level of supply, with the carryover on Sept. 1, the beginning of the 1989-90 marketing year, expected to be about 145 million bushels, compared with 302 million last Sept. 1. Drought reduced last year's production, forcing prices higher. The report forecast soybeans might average $ 7.20 to $ 7.60 per bushel this season, compared with $ 5.88 in 1987-88. Exports and domestic use are both down. The report also said that total meat production this year is now expected to be about 0.2 percent less than forecast last month because of a decline in poultry prospects. Even so, 1989 combine production of poultry and red meat is expected to reach a record level.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says a vaccine has been invented to make pigs piggier. Pigs immunized with the experimental vaccine ate an average of 22.5 pounds more feed and gained 11 pounds more weight than pigs without the treatment, the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> reported on Tuesday. `` If a commercial product results from this venture and is approved by regulator agencies, it could mean more quality pork produced at lower cost and in less time,'' said animal physiologist <PERSON> Jerome </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pekas </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> agency has signed a three-year cooperative agreement with <ORGANIZATION> Codon </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> biotechnology firm, for development and further testing of the vaccine. <PERSON> Pekas </PERSON>, who works at the agency's meat animal research center in Clay Center, <LOCATION> Neb. </LOCATION>, said the vaccine is made partly from a fragment of cholecystokinin, a natural appetite-limiting hormone made in the upper intestinal tract of pigs and humans. When the fragment, called CCK-8, is joined to a larger foreign carrier protein, the animal's immune system recognizes the fragment as a foreign molecule and produces antibodies that block the natural CCK hormone, he said. When that happens, there is nothing to tell pigs when they've had enough to eat So they keep on eating.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says the orange harvest for the 1988-89 crop season is estimated at about 207.8 million boxes, down 1 percent from the March forecast but 4 percent above last year's production. <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> production, based on April 1 indications, was estimated at 144.3 million boxes, down 1 percent from last month but 5 percent more than last season, the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> said Tuesday. The <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> harvest was estimated at 60 million boxes, down almost 2 percent from the March forecast but 2 percent more than produced in 1987-88. The <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> crop was indicated at 1.55 million boxes, down 22 percent from the previous forecast for <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> in January _ which had been carried forward into February and March _ and 14 percent less than last season. <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> production, at 1.9 million boxes, was unchanged from the March forecast but was 33 percent above last season's harvest.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890412-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-89 0353EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--AussieEarl     04-12 0181</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Aussie Earl,0185</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Australian Sheep Sheaper Given Tour of Family Seat as New
Earl</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LINCOLN, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The new Earl of <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> _ a retired Australian sheep shearer _ received a guided tour of his family seat in northeast <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> and called it a nice place. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Fiennes-Clinton </PERSON>, 75, visiting <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> for the first time Tuesday and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> for the second time, said he hopes to take advantage of the only real perk offered by his title _ a seat in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lords </ORGANIZATION>, the unelected upper chamber of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>. When the <ORGANIZATION> Duke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newcastle </ORGANIZATION>, who was also the Earl of <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON>, died last Christmas, historians began a frantic search for the new earl. It led to <PERSON> Fiennes-Clinton </PERSON>'s shack in <LOCATION> Bunbury </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, l00 miles south of <LOCATION> Perth </LOCATION>. `` My wife thought it was a joke,'' said <PERSON> Fiennes-Clinton </PERSON>, who before retiring worked as a sheep shearer, gold miner and milkman. `` It has n't changed my life. My mates take me for what I am. One said ` You're a big man now,' but I have n't grown any taller,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890412-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-89 0308EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TourGuideBush     04-12 0615</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tour Guide Bush,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Bush Giving Visitors the Grand Tour</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new sightseeing business has arrived on the scene in the nation's capital: guided tours conducted by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has been taking his guests to see the sights, something predecessor <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> rarely did. For <LOCATION> Egyptian </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Hosni </PERSON> <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON>, it was a trip by helicopter to nearby <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> for a baseball game. There, the two presidents sat in a box and ate hot dogs and hamburgers and debated <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s high-and-outside season-opening pitch. For <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>, it was a trip past the <LOCATION> Tidal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Basin </LOCATION> for a glimpse of the city's famed cherry blossoms and then to the Air and Space Museum, one of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s most-visited attractions The two joined springtime tourists in the museum's wide-screened theater to watch the movie `` To Fly.'' Excited conversation rippled through the audience as people realized who was in their midst, and those who had cameras used them for snapshots. Next week, <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>'s King <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> will be in town. And it's anyone's guess where the president might take him `` <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> is a city of 1,000 monuments,'' said White House press secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>. `` We may end up visiting them all.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> plans to take <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> to his vacation home in <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, next month. And he threw open the doors of the presidential retreat at Camp David, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, to <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> set the theme early in his presidency, when he opened the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to the public the Saturday after his inauguration. And, at one reception for members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> used a Polaroid camera to take instant photos of lawmakers in the Lincoln Bedroom. On the way to the Air and Space museum, the Bush-Shamir motorcade passed a line of life-sized standup photographs that have proliferated in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> over the past few years. For instance, for a $ 5 fee you can have your picture taken with a cutout of President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, the first lady or both. In the final photograph, it looks like you were standing next to the first family in front of a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> landmark. At the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, there have been such cutouts for several years: first the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION>, and now the Bushes. For a while, a cutout of <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> also appeared, but popular demand trailed off and it has been removed. But outside the Air and Space museum, <PERSON> George </PERSON> and <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> now share sidewalk space with other celebrities, including cutouts of wrestling star <PERSON> Hulk </PERSON> <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> and actor <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Selleck </PERSON>, and a new addition: Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. It would have been hard for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to miss the life-sized likeness of the Soviet leader. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> was right on the corner, just feet from the official motorcade. But if the president had any reaction, it went unreported. The president is often out and about town, frequently taking guests with him in his limousine. And, since he has a habit of stopping at red lights when he's on a social or recreational call, his motorcade often produces expressions of surprise and delight from other motorists and passersby as they realize the man in the stopped car alongside them is none other than the president. Those on the street might have done a double take one day last week. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, wearing exercise clothes, took his motorcade to the <ORGANIZATION> Rayburn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Office Building, where he played racquetball in the House gym. Running late for a formal dinner at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> emerged from the gym two hours later wearing a tuxedo.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890412-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-89 0301EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TerrorismReport     04-12 0606</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Terrorism Report,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>1988 Set Record For Incidents, State Department Tells Congress</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Terrorism rose to record heights in 1988, as the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> suffered a substantial increase and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> remained the favorite target, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> reported to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The bombing of a <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> jetliner in December over <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>, which the department's office of counter terrorism said probably was a terrorist incident, and the Palestinian uprising on the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> helped push the total of incidents to a new high of 856, up 3 percent from 1987. In all, 658 people were killed and 1,131 wounded, an increase in fatalities from 633 in 1987 but a decrease in injuries from 2,272. The casualty figures include terrorists themselves who were killed or wounded during attacks as well as attacks by <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> against <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ally which funneled <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> weapons to Afghan guerrillas. In all, the citizens and property of 79 nations were attacked in 60 countries. Businessmen and tourists accounted for 77 percent of the victims. The weapon used most often by terrorists was the bomb. It was used in 48 percent of the attacks, said the report released Tuesday. The <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s top uniformed lawyer contends that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military can legally attack terrorists without violating a 1976 presidential order that bans assassinations of individuals abroad, Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Overholt </PERSON>, the service's judge advocate general, argued in an eight-page draft memorandum that because of changes in `` the nature of the threat,'' action against terrorists can be justified on grounds of national self-defense. <PERSON> Overholt </PERSON>'s memorandum was disclosed Monday by the newsletter <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Week </ORGANIZATION> and confirmed by <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> officials. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> report said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> remained a primary target for international terrorism last year, as the number of anti-U.S. incidents rose from 149 in 1987 to 185. They resulted in 192 persons killed and 40 wounded, compared with seven Americans killed and 47 wounded in 1987. The increase in deaths was due largely to the attack on U.S.-bound <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> 103 in which 259 people aboard the jumbo jet and 11 on the ground perished. Of the victims 189 were Americans. <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> was the area showing the largest percentage of incidents against <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens and property _ 60 percent. On the whole, the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> again had the highest incidence of international terrorism, with 313 attacks. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, including the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>, again was the main target, accounting for 29 percent of the attacks. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> credited <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> with a substantial reduction in direct involvement in terrorism last year, but said both countries continued to provide safe haven and training to terrorist organizations. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s decision to end its war with <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> and expand ties to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> lessened Iranian involvement in terrorism, but <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> continued to include terrorism among its foreign-policy tools, the report said. At year's end, 20 foreigners were listed as political hostages being held in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, two others possibly were dead, while 13 were released during the year. Ranked behind <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, in order, as sites for the most terrorist incidents were <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. The 10 countries accounted for 75 percent of the incidents during the year, the report said. The Palestinian uprising, which began in December 1987 and continued through last year in the Israeli-held <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>, should be viewed overall as a `` civil insurrection,'' the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said. But the report said since it contained `` elements of terrorism'' in some instances, all civilian casualties were included in the 1988 statistics.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890412-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-89 0309EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Drugs-Housing     04-12 0673</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drugs-Housing,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Housing Officials Say Money Needed More than Policy Changes</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
