<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880215-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-15-88 2340EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Egypt-MiddleEast     02-15 0654</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Egypt-Middle East,0679</SECOND>
<HEAD>Egypt and Jordan Criticize U.S. Plan</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DALIA BALIGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAIRO, Egypt (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> said Monday the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should not advance interim solutions to the Palestinian problem and urged that any <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> peace plan aim for a final settlement through an international conference. President <PERSON> Hosni </PERSON> <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and Prime Minister <PERSON> Zaid </PERSON> <PERSON> Rifai </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> separately outlined that position in remarks to reporters. <PERSON> Rifai </PERSON> arrived in <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION> Monday for a one-day visit. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> will visit the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> at the end of this month. Officials in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> have said a new <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> peace plan was outlined to Arab and <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> leaders by <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, the assistant secretary of state for near <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> affairs. The Egyptian president visited <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> last month and held talks in <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION> with <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> last week. However, <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> said: `` The Americans have not given us a specific -LRB- peace -RRB- plan.'' `` But we have taken the position that any plan must clearly include: first, an overall settlement of the problem and, second, an international conference as a framework without any attempt to outflank it.'' For any peace plan to succeed, <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> said, it must envisage `` the final outcome, and we must stay away from any words or provisions that were in the Camp David agreements because they are outdated and finished.'' He referred to an autonomy plan outlined in one of the U.S.-mediated 1978 Camp David accords between <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. It provided for an interim arrangement under which the 1.5 million Palestinians in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>, captured by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> in 1967, would exercise self-rule for five years. The plan also provided that negotiations begin not later than the third year of autonomy to consider the final status of the two territories. Reports from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> last week said a two-stage plan carried by <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> suggested an accelerated version of the Camp David formula. The reports said the plan proposed talks, to be held under international sponsorship, on limited Palestinian self-rule as an interim measure. Those talks would begin in April and negotiations on the final status of the two territories would be held in December, the reports said. After his 90-minute meeting with <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON>, <PERSON> Rifai </PERSON> said that <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> opposed `` partial solutions or projects for self-rule'' in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> wants a final settlement through an international conference, he added. The state-owned <ORGANIZATION> Middle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> East </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> reported that <PERSON> Rifai </PERSON> carried a message to <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> from King <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>. <PERSON> Rifai </PERSON> did not comment on any message. The <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> reports suggested that <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>'s tour will be to sell the two-stage plan to <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> leaders. <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON>'s remarks on Monday appeared to reflect serious reservations about the reported plan. `` <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> is coming and if he is bringing proposals to offer to the parties concerned, I hope they will keep away from Camp <PERSON> David </PERSON> and will cover a final solution,'' he said. He said an international conference `` would give all parties confidence.'' Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> opposes an international conference, contending it would pressure <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> into making territorial concessions. If a peace plan does not seek a final settlement through an internatiuonal conference, <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> said, `` the consequences will not be good. `` I do not wish for any initiative to fail. I wish for an initiative that aims for a final solution establishing just peace in the region.'' <PERSON> Rifai </PERSON> reiterated <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>'s demand for a United Nations-sponsored international conference with the participation of the <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>'s five permanent members and all concerned parties, including the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>. `` We are against any plan dealing with partial solutions or projects for self-rule. We seek a final settlement ... Our assessment of any initiative will depend on how close it comes to the position I have stated.'' Since Palestinian demonstrations against Israeli rule broke out Dec. 8, more than 50 Arabs have died of Israeli gunfire.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880215-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-15-88 0029EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Robertson'sArmy     02-15 1184</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Robertson's Army,1213</SECOND>
<HEAD>It Dawns On Them: Maybe They Can Elect A President</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report. In 13th graf, Billye is correct.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MIKE FEINSILBER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 In <LOCATION> Ottumwa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Pietraszewski </PERSON> stood in the doorway at the place where the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> caucus was held last Monday night to encourage shy voters to cross the threshhold for <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>. She was a soldier in <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s `` invisible army.'' `` There were two of mine that could n't come because they were sick, but there were four who surprised me,'' says Mrs. <PERSON> Pietraszewski </PERSON>, 35, mother of two. `` I knew them all as they came in; I went out and personally met them so they would n't be afraid to go to the caucus.'' When the heads were counted, there were 64, and 43 of them gave the nod to <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>. Statewide, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> finished second, behind <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> but ahead of Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ a shock to many, but not to some <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> people who like Mrs. <PERSON> Pietraszewski </PERSON> had been working for their candidate for months. -LRB- `` I told my family there will be lots of other Christmases, but this one's different.'' -RRB- The <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> ground troops, new to politics and excited by success, are starting to ask themselves if they have it within their power to put their man in office. `` A lot of people have said, well, I agree with <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s stands, but I do n't want to waste my vote,'' the Rev <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Holder </PERSON>, pastor of the <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baptist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> told the <LOCATION> Concord </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.H. </LOCATION> -RRB- Monitor. `` That was before <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>. My impression is now he's a little more electable. There may indeed be a groundswell.'' The Rev. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Fortin </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Faith </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Bedford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.H. </LOCATION>, puts it this way: `` If <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> is God's man then somehow he's going to get in there But not without a lot of hard work and prayer.'' And the Rev. <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Borchers </PERSON>, pastor of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Methodist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> in </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ashland </ORGANIZATION>, tells of a lunch that a group of clergymen had with <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>. After getting to know him as a person, <PERSON> Borchers </PERSON> said, `` We all laid our hands on him and prayed for him. We prayed for strength and guidance and prayed if it is God's will, that he be elected.'' <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hadden </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> sociologist and a <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> biographer, says <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> came up with a masterstroke in insisting that three million followers sign petitions before he would decide to run. The tactic gave <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> an army. `` He asked people to pledge that they'd work for him, pray for him and give him money,'' says <PERSON> Hadden </PERSON>. `` Political historians may view it as one of the most ingenious things a candidate ever did.'' These days, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> soft pedals the church-based foundation of his candidacy. He says he should be thought of as a television network executive and the chancellor of a fully accredited graduate university. To call him merely a TV evangelist, he protests `` is bigotry and it's an insult. And it denigrates who I am and what I am and I'm sick of it.'' For all that, most of <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s followers come out of the evangelical churches of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. They know him best as a man of God _ and they speak of him, often, in language unblushingly tinged with theology. `` I just believe <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> is going to win,'' says <PERSON> Gloria </PERSON> <PERSON> Widmann </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Waterloo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>. `` He operates in miraculous wonders in terms of what the Bible says _ prophecy, healing, miracles. He operates just like <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> did and he loves just like <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> did. And we need a man of God in the office.'' In <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Huron </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Billye </PERSON> <PERSON> Knoik </PERSON>, who quit her job as a church secretary to work for <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, scoffs at the term the press has given <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s political flock. `` These are just your common, everyday folks from various and sundry backgrounds and <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> is touching these people,'' she says. Mrs. <PERSON> Knoik </PERSON>, mother of three grown children, got to know <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> from watching the 700 Club on the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, where on Tuesday <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> faces his first test in a primary, Mrs. <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Farris </PERSON>, 37, of <LOCATION> Londonderry </LOCATION>, town chairman and <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s local coordinator, says the conventional wisdom _ that <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> will have trouble in a primary election _ has missed the point. `` It's there,'' she says of a <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> post-Iowa surge. `` There's a tremendous force that has n't been really identified in the normal political process.'' Registration ended last weekend in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> and city and town clerks say they were so busy for three weeks they did n't have time to leave their offices and grab lunch. The lines were long. Nearly 1,000 people registered in <LOCATION> Manchester </LOCATION> on a Saturday. Many are first-time voters. Many registered undeclared, meaning they can vote Democrat or Republican. Secretary of State <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON> estimates the late surge added 15,000 to 25,000 voters in a state where <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> won the primary in 1980 with 73,000 votes. <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON> ca n't guess how many of the new registrants are <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> supporters. The Rev. <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Marsh </PERSON>, a pastor at the <ORGANIZATION> Dartmouth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Area </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fellowship </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hamsphire </LOCATION>, says in 1986 about 50,000 residents of the state gave money to the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>. After <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, all the candidates flew to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, but <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> went to <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, which holds caucuses Feb. 23 and where a strong `` pro-life'' movement has ties to fundamentalist churches. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> co-chairman, <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Ludeman </PERSON>, says <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> is no longer <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s greatest threat. `` We feel that in <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> we have only one competitor in grass roots organization, that's <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>.'' In <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> won overwhelmingly in the Feb. 4 Republican caucuses, <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Chong </PERSON> credits a 60 percent rise in party registration tp <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s appeal. Says <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> co-chairman <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Ward </PERSON>: `` We draw from mainstream conservatives, evangelicals and those who know <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> from the 700 Club.'' In <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, retiree <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Underwood </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Des </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Moines </LOCATION>, a lay pastor, says <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s appeal politicized the non-political _ like himself. `` I've got to get with it,'' <PERSON> Underwood </PERSON> tells a reporter. `` I've got to get involved I'm ashamed to say that's the first caucus I ever attended.'' Were <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> people in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> told to be evasive to pollsters so the <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> strength would come as a surprise? No, <PERSON> Underwood </PERSON> says: `` People have a little bit of a problem with the role of the media. They were tight-lipped on the thing.'' <PERSON> Guy </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodgers </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Shenandoah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, a <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> activist who has worked for a number of Christian causes: `` We had a lot of people support <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> who we referred to as closet supporters. I saw that in my own precinct. I saw people we had n't identified, people we did n't know. There were extra numbers here that we were n't aware of.'' The Rev. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelms </PERSON>, pastor a <ORGANIZATION> Des </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Moines </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baptist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, says evangelical churches did n't outright support <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, but they sure gave up preaching that politics is securlar business to be shunned in favor of the Lord's work. `` For years, we heard Christians should stay out of politics,'' he says. `` Of late, our leaders have encouraged the opposite.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880215-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-15-88 2350EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PlannedParenthoodSuit     02-15 0458</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Planned Parenthood Suit,0469</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rule Barring Abortion Advice Dealt Blow By Federal Judge</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DENIS M. SEARLES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DENVER (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal judge Monday temporarily barred enforcement of a new federal rule that prevents federally funded family planning clinics from advising pregnant women on abortion. The ruling applies to three organizations in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> that brought suit. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Court Judge <PERSON> Zita </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinshienk </PERSON> granted the motion by the three birth control services groups seeking a preliminary injuction against the new rule scheduled to go into effect March 3. `` The order just says the government can not put these regulations into effect until we have a chance to hear it in a final hearing,'' <PERSON> Weinshienk </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. The judge said she expected new hearing dates to be set within a week. She also said two other similar cases are before federal judges in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Filing the suit against the government were Rocky Mountain Planned Parenthood based in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>, Planned Parenthood of <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Women </LOCATION>'s Health Clinic. The ruling temporarily barring enforcement of the rule applies only to those three organizations, <PERSON> Weinshienk </PERSON> said. The suit claims new federal ruling violates the Federal Title X statute and the intent of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, censors free speech rights at family planning clinics and violates the right of privacy of clinics and their patients. The <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> had ruled that beginning March 3, family planning programs receiving federal funds could not provide pregnant women with information on abortion or refer them to other sources, even if they ask. Administration officials have said the rule is intended to make sure federal funds are not used to promote abortion, even indirectly. <PERSON> Weinshienk </PERSON> said she based her decision on many <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> rulings that said there could not be rules that `` dictated to doctors what they say to patients, which is what the regulations attempted to do.'' `` Based on that finding, and the fact that all of these cases indicated that such attempted regulation was unconstitutional, I found irreparable injury. The last two prongs for such a preliminary injunction are a balancing of harms to the plaintiff and against harms to the defendant,'' the judge said. The order will be in writing and out by the end of the week, she said. The judge said she made the ruling on a holiday, Presidents' Day, because it was the only date when the two sides and she could get together `` The government wanted it heard as soon as possible. The plaintiffs ... wanted it heard before the regs -LRB- regulations -RRB- went into effect on March 3. I said fine, if you want to come in on a holiday, I will too,'' <PERSON> Weinshienk </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880215-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-15-88 0037EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Robertson'sRevue     02-15 0533</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Robertson's Revue,0550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Robertson's Slick Campaign Show Now Playing In New Hampshire</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Robertson's Army</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE ESPER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CONCORD, N.H. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s campaign bus pulls into shopping malls, the driver turns on his tapes of <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Sousa </PERSON> marches and passers-by strut on the sidewalks. Inside, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> and his aides are busy passing out a different type of cassette _ his positions on issues ranging from abortion to defense. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s campaign for the Republican nomination for the presidency is as much showmanship as it is politics. It's one of the slickest shows in town now finishing its run in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> and heading South next. At a major rally to fire up supporters, <PERSON> Randall </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON>, who starred as <PERSON> Annie </PERSON> in the smash Broadway musical 10 years ago, sings the hit song, `` Tomorrow.'' And as the song goes, you can bet your bottom dollar that <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> is hoping the sun will come out tomorrow, er Tuesday, in the form of a strong showing in the New Hampshrie primary. At a rally in <LOCATION> Concord </LOCATION> Saturday night, you'd have thought <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> had already won his party's nomination. It had all the trappings, the straw hats and <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> placards, of a nominating convention. Eight hundred supporters clapped, stomped their feet and chanted: `` We want <PERSON> Pat </PERSON>! We want <PERSON> Pat </PERSON>!'' `` Go, <PERSON> Pat </PERSON>, go! Go, <PERSON> Pat </PERSON>, go!'' Then, of course, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> came out on stage and whipped the crowd into a frenzy. `` When I look at your faces and see this enthusiasm, I believe we are going to see victory in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` I'm talking to people who love <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> This state represents what's good in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> because it stands for faith in God It stands for strong family values. It stands for preservation of life for the unborn.'' And when you ask around in the malls and at the rallies about <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, his followers tell you he stands for all those things. Simple as that, they say. <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> <PERSON> Griswold </PERSON>, a mother of five children from <LOCATION> Londonderry </LOCATION>, sang a couple of inspirational songs for <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>. One of them was `` Ca n't We Be Friends.'' _ `` Ca n't we be friends. Life's too short. Too soon it ends. And good friends are so hard to find. Ca n't we be friends. Someone like you is one of a kind.'' The second one, `` Eagle Song,'' she wrote herself: `` An eagle tucked with golden wings is flying on his way upward, heavenward bound.'' `` I feel that's what <PERSON> Pat </PERSON>'s calling is,'' she said later. `` That's what I believe <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> is meant to do. He's my man.'' <PERSON> Martha </PERSON> <PERSON> Greer </PERSON> drove 30 miles from <LOCATION> Laconia </LOCATION> to see <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> this night. She explained that she was an `` 8_88.'' That means she found eight more voters to support <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> in'88. `` He's a solid man,'' she said. `` He stands for a lot of good things. He stands on the Bible for one thing. He's a good Christian man.'' At the malls, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> works the crowds relentlessly. He's in pizza parlors, bookstores and barber shops, smiling, shaking hands, embracing voters. At a candy shop, he wishes voters a happy Valentine's Day, then matter-of-factly says to them, `` I need some help on Tuesday.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880215-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-15-88 0038EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TornadoChurch     02-15 1029</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tornado Church,1063</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congregation Resists Scorn, Patiently Awaits God's Tornado</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By THOMAS P. WYMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GARY, Ind. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Annie </PERSON> <PERSON> Sims </PERSON>, the preacher's wife, delivered the prophecy at a noon prayer meeting late in December: `` The Lord said he was going to send a tornado, and many shall die,'' she recalls, saying <PERSON> God </PERSON> spoke through her during the prayer service. `` He was going to send his fury and vengeance on the people.'' So 17 faithful members of the Repairer of the <ORGANIZATION> Breach </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> God </ORGANIZATION> in Christ gathered at their small westside church _ a converted two-story frame house _ on Jan. 3 to await the wrath of God. The congregation has been waiting, faithfully, peacefully, ever since. Any day now, any moment, members believe, <PERSON> God </PERSON> will send a tornado spinning down from the heavens to smite the wicked and spare the righteous. And spare their church. Their number includes a school teacher, a recent college graduate, a college freshman, and a restaurant worker with a management degree. They have sacrificed jobs and education, as well as the respect of family and friends who question their sanity. The congregation has been challenged by the power of the state, too. Five members have been removed under court order _ though two of them have returned since undergoing forced psychiatric examinations. Two children were taken from their mother and returned to school, and a 51-year-old man was ordered to undergo kidney dialysis treatment. But unlike a Mormon polygamist clan in <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> whose recent resistance of police ended in a shootout that killed one officer, these religious fundamentalists have quietly accepted the intrusions. `` We're not against the court,'' says M.L. <PERSON> Sims </PERSON>, the church elder and preacher, the husband of <PERSON> Annie </PERSON>. `` If God allows it to happen, then that's it.'' <PERSON> Sims </PERSON>, 36, says he's also lost the support of national church headquarters in <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, which ordered him to take down a sign proclaiming affiliation. `` Until the Lord says to move it, it's going to be up,'' he says. A woman who answered a call at the <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> headquarters said no one was available to discuss the matter. Despite the challenges from outsiders, <PERSON> Sims </PERSON> and the church members welcome visitors and talk freely. All profess an unshakeable belief in the tornado. None say they want to leave. The 39-year-old Mrs. <PERSON> Sims </PERSON> first prophesied the tornado would strike Jan. 3, then Jan. 24. Both dates passed uneventfully. The <PERSON> Simses </PERSON> now say God delayed the tornado to gain time to spread the warning. No new date has been set. `` It'll be pretty soon,'' says <PERSON> Sims </PERSON>. `` It's nationally known now.'' No one's faith is shaken by the delay, or by meteorological precedent. `` Tornadoes can occur anytime, but most of the tornadoes in this area occur from March through June, and then again late in the fall,'' said <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> forecaster <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Mowery </PERSON>, who says he ca n't recall a midwinter tornado ever striking the area. Religion professor <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Olivelle </PERSON>, chairman of the department at <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, says apocalyptic visions are common religious themes. `` Of course there are always reasons why the end never comes,'' he said. `` I always tell my students that religion is not logic, and you can not put logical questions to that.'' One of those waiting in the church, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON>, a 24-year-old graduate of <ORGANIZATION> Grinnell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> with a major in Spanish, said, `` There's no doubt in my mind, or in anyone's mind that it's going to come.'' <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON> stopped showing up for his bank teller's job after Jan. 3, then called the bank to explain. `` They did n't really understand it,'' he said. `` But after the tornado comes they'll understand, and they'll congratulate us for standing up for the Lord.'' The family of <PERSON> Ruschell </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> school teacher, and her 16-year-old daughter, <PERSON> Jeanetta </PERSON>, won the court order compelling the two to undergo psychiatric evaluation. `` Really, at the time, they felt I was so deeply under the influence of pastor that we could n't do our own thinking,'' she said. `` If I believe something, and it's different from what you believe, does that make me insane and you not?'' Mrs. <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> said she and her daughter returned voluntarily to the church after a psychiatrist found them competent. `` I'm 47 years old. I've been teaching for 20 years. I've taken my daughter out of school,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> indignantly. `` Do you think I would be here if I did n't believe it?'' <PERSON> Jeanetta </PERSON> says it does n't matter she's missing out on school. `` It does n't bother me because after the tornado, the school may not be there.'' A court gave custody of <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanders </PERSON>' two sons, <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON>, 13, and <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON>, 12, to a brother, who will return them to school. Child welfare authorities took the children from the church. `` I do n't fight that. They're just doing their job,'' says Mrs. <PERSON> Sanders </PERSON>. `` They do n't understand, because this is spiritual.'' The days are occupied with informal services, talking and just waiting. `` Praise God, because this world is coming to an end, and we want to be right,'' chanted <PERSON> Elder </PERSON> <PERSON> Sims </PERSON> during one service. `` People say we're strange, they say we're crazy, that we're crackpots,'' he intones, mopping sweat from his face with a towel thrown around his beefy shoulders. `` But we're just doing what <PERSON> God </PERSON> says to do.'' `` Better be so ready, you may not know the day,'' sings the congregation, now a choir whose voice reverberates off bright blue-painted plaster walls. There is no television or radio in the church, and no newspapers. Adult members take turns preparing meals in the fully equipped kitchen, and the teen-agers clean up. The <PERSON> Simses </PERSON> live upstairs. At night, the others fold up the metal chairs and spread out bedding. The cramped quarters are part of the sacrifice. `` We've all sacrificed here,'' says 18-year-old <PERSON> Falease </PERSON> <PERSON> Lemon </PERSON>, who dropped out of <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Univerity </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> campus. `` God is going to pay us in return.'' <PERSON> Jacqueline </PERSON> <PERSON> Sims </PERSON>, the preacher's 18-year-old daughter, says the waiting will be ended soon. `` We'll be out there after the tornado,'' she says. `` Then the world will be a better place to live, with everybody doing <PERSON> God </PERSON>'s will.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880215-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-15-88 0039EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-UncleFrancois     02-15 0689</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Uncle Francois,0711</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Mitterrand Cult, or How to be Loved Without Really Trying</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ELAINE GANLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The French, known for fickleness in politics and love, have become so enamored of President <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> that they affectionately call him Uncle and his following often is compared to a cult. With presidential elections less than three months away, <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> is a phantom candidate. He says he has not decided on seeking re-election, but draws celebrities, scientists and ordinary citizens onto his bandwagon in an effortless non-campaign. Politicians who have spoken with the 71-year-old Socialist say he will declare his intentions in early March. The first-round vote is set for April 24. Meanwhile, <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> is called more and more by the nickname <PERSON> Tonton </PERSON>, an affectionate term for uncle. He has become a sort of political superstar, imperturbable and lovable in his presidential grandeur. Lacking a declared rival in the Socialist opposition, Premier <PERSON> Jacques </PERSON> <PERSON> Chirac </PERSON> and former Premier <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Barre </PERSON> have a problem. The two leading conservatives are reduced to shadow-boxing with the avuncular <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> image at the risk of looking like family bullies. `` <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> would be well advised to give an answer soon,'' <PERSON> Chirac </PERSON> said recently. `` A presidential election is an important affair.'' <PERSON> Barre </PERSON> has criticized `` the often abusive use of an image, that of the nice old uncle. It's both charming and fuzzy. It's sweet tonton.'' <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON>'s popularity has risen since his Socialist government lost power to the <PERSON> Chirac </PERSON> conservatives in March 1986. He has led opinion polls for months, but the phenomenon called `` Mitterrandolatry'' or `` Tontonmania'' is recent. With the <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> not conducting an official campaign, independent committees began springing up around the country, gathering signatures and putting up <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> posters. Groups of noted scientists, intellectuals, homosexuals and others advertised their support. Actor <PERSON> Gerard </PERSON> <PERSON> Depardieu </PERSON> said he never votes, but he bought a full-page newspaper ad declaring: `` Mitterrand or nothing.'' The rock star <PERSON> Renaud </PERSON> sponsored a similar ad, urging the president to `` hang in there.'' <PERSON> Dominique </PERSON> <PERSON> Jamet </PERSON>, editor of the right-wing newspaper <PERSON> Quotidien </PERSON> de <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, was among hundreds of people who signed an appeal saying, `` Do n't Leave Us.'' He was fired immediately. Justice Minister <PERSON> Albin </PERSON> <PERSON> Chalandon </PERSON> compared the president's relationship with the French to that of Marshal <PERSON> Philippe </PERSON> <PERSON> Petain </PERSON>, head of the <LOCATION> Vichy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> government that collaborated with the German occupation in World War II Many of the French were scandalized by the comparison. <PERSON> Chalandon </PERSON> called the situation `` irrational'' and said the campaign climate risked becoming one of `` soft, vague demagogy.'' Indeed, pro-Mitterrand letters being published speak of `` Dr. <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON>,'' his `` intellectual firmness'' and his `` cultural finesse.'' A quarterly magazine named Influence quoted a former dancer at the <ORGANIZATION> Crazy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Horse </ORGANIZATION> nightclub as saying <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> is not a sex symbol, `` but he is so soft, with such a watchful air, that it gives him in my eyes great charm. Without mentioning his intelligence, which seduces me completely.'' Historian <PERSON> Jacques </PERSON> <PERSON> Julliard </PERSON>, who studies public opinion and contemporary political culture, says `` Tontonmania'' is explainable. `` Always in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> there is the role of the providential man,'' he said in a telephone interview. As a president sharing power with a conservative premier, <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> has a high profile without the blame for unpopular government policies. `` He is a president who does n't govern,'' <ORGANIZATION> Julliard </ORGANIZATION> said. `` When he officially becomes a candidate, he'll start losing points.'' One of many recent polls indicated 61 percent of <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> people want <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> as president, 48 percent prefer <PERSON> Barre </PERSON> and 40 percent favor <PERSON> Chirac </PERSON>. In early 1986, when a Socialist government still was in power, <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON>'s support was 39 percent. `` If <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> is not officially a candidate, it is to make himself desired,'' wrote <PERSON> Serge </PERSON> <PERSON> July </PERSON>, editor of the leftist newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION>, reflecting the view that the president's refusal to declare himself is a political tactic <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> has made few comments about `` Tontonmania,'' saying only that he had no hand in the private efforts on his behalf. As he put it in late December: `` It's very nice of them. They did n't consult me and so I have neither to say go ahead nor to stop them.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880215-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-15-88 0040EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CorporateExit     02-15 1040</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Corporate Exit,1069</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cost of Living Forces Corporations To Look Elsewhere</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LINDA STOWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Business Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>STAMFORD, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two decades ago, affordable housing and a good highway system lured dozens of major companies to <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>'s suburbs of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Today, highways are clogged, $ 500,000 homes are considered pedestrian, and a corporate exodus may be on the horizon. The waves of growth from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s global market, which once brought treasures to <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>'s `` Gold Coast,'' now threaten to erode some of its most precious economic gains. Over the past year, at least a half dozen big companies have announced plans to close or relocate their <LOCATION> Fairfield </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> operations and many more are said to be considering such moves. A recent survey of 300 local manufacturers found a third considering partial or total relocations. The main gripe: The suburbs, which used to have the location without the cost of the Big Apple, have grown so clogged with people and cars that life here is no longer a bargain. `` Most people who make a move do a lot of looking and if they're after big cost differences, there's no longer a big cost difference between <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Fairfield </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Helie </PERSON>, chief operating officer of the <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Pitt </PERSON> real estate company, which has 16 offices in <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> `` So, if they're looking for a lower-cost area, they're bound to move off the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>.'' Housing prices have soared so that many homes are out of the reach of even some two-income families. In <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION>, the average price of a home has risen from $ 86,730 in 1970 to $ 706,150 last year, said <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Klein </PERSON>, publisher of the <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Record </LOCATION> of Real Estate Sales. He said the `` American Dream'' _ a four-bedroom home on one acre of land in <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION> _ costs a family about $ 540,000 today. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>, a state senator from <LOCATION> Bridgeport </LOCATION> and chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, describes the situation on <ORGANIZATION> Interstate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> 95 </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> Merritt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Parkway </LOCATION> _ the region's major highways _ as `` absolutely horrendous. `` It's gridlock from 6:30 a.m. to after 8:30. A ride from <LOCATION> Bridgeport </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Stamford </LOCATION> that should take 25 minutes takes more than one hour, and if every aspect of mass transportation was used by the year 2000, we'd still have hopeless gridlock,'' <PERSON> Owens </PERSON> said. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Woodside </PERSON>, former chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Primerica </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, said if some of these trends are n't stemmed, <LOCATION> Fairfield </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> could become a pasture for top executives with little commerce because people who work in the trades, restaurants and other businesses wo n't be able to afford to live here. <ORGANIZATION> Woodside </ORGANIZATION>, who moved <ORGANIZATION> Primerica </ORGANIZATION>'s headquarters to <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION> in 1970 when it was <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Can </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, is chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Regional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, an economic planning organization for the tri-state region of <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jesey </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. He said that when companies moved to <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> in the 1970s, housing was affordable, land was plentiful and an ample labor pool was available. `` The county has changed dramatically already,'' he said. `` <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION> has closed schools in the last 10 years and they do that because they no longer have enough kids to use the schools. No young people can afford to live in these cities.'' Evidence of a possible corporate exodus cropped up in 1987, when at least six companies pulled out of the area: _ <ORGANIZATION> Georgia-Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> announced it would move most of its regional operations from <LOCATION> Darien </LOCATION> to its corporate headquarters in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> The Fortune 500 forest products company employed 320 people in <LOCATION> Darien </LOCATION>, making it the town's single largest employer. _ <ORGANIZATION> Revere </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Copper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brass </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, which had moved from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Stamford </LOCATION> about two years ago, said it planned to relocate its headquarters in the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> Penn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> said it would move its headquarters from <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> Stauffer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> announced it would close its headquarters in <LOCATION> Westport </LOCATION> Its three main businesses were split up and the headquarters are moving to <LOCATION> Shelton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wilmington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Del. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. _ <ORGANIZATION> Electrolux </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> said it would shift its headquarters from <LOCATION> Stamford </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> Iomega </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> returned to <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> only a year after moving its headquarters to <LOCATION> Stamford </LOCATION> Most cited the need for `` consolidation'' as the reason for leaving, but one knowledgeable observer said the high cost of staying in the area was a contributing factor. `` Essentially those who can break away and have no need to be in the command center of the global market are finding other locations and being in a sense pushed out or at least costed out by those who have to have that location,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Keith </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Regional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. A survey by the <ORGANIZATION> Southwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Area </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, a coalition of business groups and the state, said last year that twice as many manufacturers moved out of <LOCATION> Fairfield </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> as moved in during the past five years. Manufacturing generates $ 10 billion in revenues and provides 36 percent of the jobs in the county, said <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Petrikas </PERSON>, president of the Wilton-based <ORGANIZATION> Vitta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and chairman of the task force that directed the survey. But <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitovich </PERSON>, president and chief executive officer of <LOCATION> SACIA </LOCATION>, said he does n't believe `` the bloom is completely off the rose'' in <LOCATION> Fairfield </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. `` When people look at the region and see some traffic patterns, some people like to attribute the erosion -LRB- of businesses -RRB- to traffic or cost, but that's not completely it. There's a range of things happening,'' he said. <PERSON> Mitovich </PERSON> said some of the companies that moved to the region in the 1970s are no longer here because they have been merged with others or bought out. Corporate executives at companies that have not announced any plans to move decline to discuss the possibility of relocating because it worries their employees. But when <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION>, the survey research firm in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, asked chief executive officers to name the best major metropolitan area in which to locate a business, none of the 403 executives ranked any <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> cities in the top tier. They said <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> was the best location. `` Overall, the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> area, which includes <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, does get a pretty bad rap,'' said <PERSON> Merl </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, executive vice president of <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880215-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-15-88 0049EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-States-Lotteries     02-15 0924</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-States-Lotteries,0950</SECOND>
<HEAD>States With Lotteries Are Pleased, But They Still Have To Hustle</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 As six states and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> launch a new multistate Lotto game, <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> bureaus in 26 states checked on their states' experience with legal wagering.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BARR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Twenty-six states are now wheedling extra dollars from their taxpayers with lottery games, helping senior citizens in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, schools in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and economic development in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>. Total sales exceeded $ 12 billion last year. Eight states sell $ 1 billion or more in lottery tickets a year, keeping a third or more of that amount to support state programs. Within the last year, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> have joined the club, and <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> will begin games this year. Though most states report rising income from wagering, some have to hustle to keep bettors interested. Last week, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> scrapped a lotto game that had sold $ 2.2 billion worth of tickets since 1982 and launched a `` Wild Card Lotto'' game. Players in the old game picked six numbers out of 40, but the new game has 48 choices. That changes the odds of winning from one in 1.9 million to one in 6.1 million. That, in turn, increases the chances of creating one of those humongous $ 30 million or $ 40 million jackpots that inspire frantic ticket sales. `` We've had so many people who've won a million or more, it now takes a pot of $ 10 million to generate the interest that $ 5 million did once,'' says <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> <PERSON> Kipp-Klecha </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the lottery in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, where on Sunday officials said someone was holding a $ 17 million ticket after the latest drawing. `` People like to spend a dollar to have a shot at the moon,'' said <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Rem </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> lottery. That's also the theory behind the new six-state `` Lotto America'' game, launched last week in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>. With more bettors to lose money, the game can offer bigger prizes _ a minimum of $ 2 million. `` Our motivation is to offer Oregonians a chance to play in games they could play in one of the big states,'' said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Davey </PERSON>, whose state lottery faces big-jackpot competition along the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> border. No one picked all seven numbers to win the jackpot in the first <LOCATION> Lotto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> drawing held Saturday night. More than 2 million tickets were sold, spokesman <PERSON> Brett </PERSON> <PERSON> Voorhees </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Des </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Moines </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> legislators, who have seen lottery sales slump from $ 136.9 million in the first year, 1982-83, to as low as $ 105.3 million in fiscal 1985, are debating a big-jackpot lotto game this year. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bean </PERSON>, assistant director of the <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> lottery, credits the state's `` Super Lotto'' game with helping build ticket sales from $ 100 million in the first year, 1974-75, to $ 1.07 billion last year. There are seven other states in the billion-dollar club: <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> has the most lucrative games, earning $ 666.8 million on sales of $ 1.46 billion, a 45 percent profit, in the fiscal year ending March 31, 1987. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> all extract more than 40 percent from their games as well. However, <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>'s 2-year-old lottery has run into problems because the state constitutional amendment authorizing the games requires that 45 percent of the proceeds go to the state and that no more than 10 percent go to administration. An independent audit commissioned by the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> concluded that the game would fail early in 1989 unless more money was offered as prizes and more money was available for administration. An amendment reflecting those recommendations will be on the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> ballot later this year. The <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> lottery earned $ 80 million last year, far less than the $ 250 million a year some legislators had forecast. Even a successful operation such as the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> lottery contributes only 2.5 percent of the state's general fund budget, and there is no reason to believe that lotteries have been a substitute for tax increases. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s game began at the same time sales, personal income and corporate taxes were rising in the free-spending years of Gov. <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> Rockefeller </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state's lottery came with a package of tax increases in 1982, when the state was hard-pressed for cash. <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON>, spokesman for the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> lottery, recalled that the lottery was promoted in 1971 as a way of avoiding a sales tax increase from 3 percent to 4 percent. In 1975, the sales tax went up to 5 percent _ part of a program by newly elected Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> to eliminate a $ 600 million deficit. <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>'s receipts are earmarked for senior citizen programs such as tax subsidies and prescription drugs. Despite projected growth of 11 percent next year, revenues were lagging behind program requirements, and Gov. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> has recommended returning some of the senior citizen programs to general funding. <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> decided not to depend on lottery profits for state operations. Instead, `` <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> Plan'' proceeds go into one-time economic development programs such as grants to new or expanding businesses. Oregon also directs its lottery profits _ $ 47.3 million last year _ to economic development. <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, which began its lottery last month, has a novel clause making things more difficult for unscrupulous prize winners. It provides for prizes to be awarded to dependents if the winner is a child-support deadbeat. Already, $ 70,000 has been earmarked for dependents.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880215-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-15-88 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lotteries-Scandals     02-15 0263</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lotteries-Scandals,0270</SECOND>
<HEAD>Scandals Have Been Rare</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-States-Lotteries</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 State lottery games have had few scandals, but inevitably someone is tempted to try to shorten the odds. One of the more recent scandals was in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, where four workers in the lottery division's mailroom were caught intercepting stubs in a `` second-chance'' and putting their own names on them. The four were fired. In 1975, all 318 lottery workers in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> were laid off and the games were suspended after it was discovered that tickets with duplicate numbers had been printed for one drawing. The games resumed the next year. The chairman of <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jersey </ORGANIZATION>'s lottery commission was indicted in 1983 for submitting false letters to a state ethics committee. The panel was investigating whether the chairman, <PERSON> Reese </PERSON> <PERSON> Palley </PERSON>, had a business relationship with lottery contractors or potential contractors. <PERSON> Palley </PERSON> pleaded guilty to a single conspiracy charge. In <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, a former official was convicted of mail fraud in 1980 along with an accomplice for rigging a game. He was found out when lottery employees noticed that the official's fiancee had won $ 21,000. <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> had a loaded ping-pong ball scandal in 1980. Eight people were convicted of rigging a Daily Number drawing and winning $ 3.5 million. Greed was their undoing _ investigators said heavy betting by the conspirators gave the game away. Last month, <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>'s `` High Card'' game suffered an embarrassing boo-boo when it was discovered that numbers could be read on a scratch-card game without having to scratch. The cards were withdrawn.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880215-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-15-88 0106EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-TankerWar     02-15 0700</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tanker War,0718</SECOND>
<HEAD>Who's Shooting What? Gulf Tanker Targets Laden With Confusion</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By NABILA MEGALLI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAMA, Bahrain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 There was no question the Danish supertanker <PERSON> Kate </PERSON> <PERSON> Maersk </PERSON> had a gaping hole in its hull, that a crewman was dead, that the burning and crippled ship needed to be towed from the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>. But the question that perplexed the gulf shipping community is one that has become increasingly characteristic of the increasingly confusing Iran-Iraq war: Which nation staged the attack? `` It's confusing, and it will grow more confusing,'' said a Dubai-based shipping executive who spoke on condition of anonymity according to company rules. `` Both sides are diversifying the style of the attacks and the weapons they have been using.'' Initially, the gulf shipping community almost unanimously considered the tanker a victim of an Iranian raid on Thursday. It was a logical target for <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, which attacks neutral vessels in retaliation for <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s attacks on Iranian tankers. It also left the sort of damage characteristic of Iranian Silkworm missiles. But by Sunday, the prevailing opinion among shipping executives was that the ship was the victim of an Iraqi raid _ the latest, perhaps, in a series of errant Iraqi missile attacks. The executives said a key clue came on Friday, when an Iraqi jet bomber, a Soviet-made Badger, fired two C-601 missiles within eight miles of the destroyer USS Chandler, which was escorting a convoy of reflagged <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> oil tankers. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> began escorting the tankers last July to protect them from <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, which considers <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> an ally of <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> in the seven-year Iran-Iraq war. The Iraqis were n't known previously to have had the C-601s, an air-to-ground version of the anti-ship Silkworms favored by <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> normally uses French-built Exocet missiles. Such changing weaponry on both sides _ and the propensity for mistaken targets _ is clouding the gulf picture. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, for example, until lately has relied mainly on speedboats equipped with guns to stage its attacks. But earlier this month, a U.S.-made Phantom jet of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s made a sudden reapearance on the gulf, the first Iranian jet spotted in the region in a year and a half. Shipping executives also believe Iranians now possesses substantial numbers of <ORGANIZATION> U.S.-designed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mavericks </ORGANIZATION>, an air-to-surface missile that can cause as much damage as the missiles used by <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. The Iranians also have equipped frigates with Italian-made Seakiller missiles, which can cause more damage to a ship's hull than cannon shells, rocket-propelled grenades or machine guns that their speedboats normally use. And they have the Silkworms, deployed at the southern and northern extremities of the gulf, but mobile and therefore effective from any point along the 600-mile gulf coast. But mistaken targets are what <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officers said they fear most in the gulf. Last May 17, an Iraqi missile strike killed 37 Americans aboard the USS Stark, a frigate. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> said the attack was a mistake, and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> accepted its apology. On Feb. 7, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military officers said the battle cruiser <PERSON> Richmond </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> had a `` tense moment'' when the the firing and subsequent explosion of what was believed to be an Iraqi missile could be viewed from the ship. There have been other instances in which <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> missiles fired from long range at a mere radar blip have wound up devastating ships linked to their Arab allies, such as <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> also once blasted a fishing trawler. The Iranians are n't immune from mistakes. On Jan. 22, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> attacked the Norwegian-owned Havpil as it headed toward the Iranian port of <PERSON> Bandar </PERSON> <PERSON> Abbas </PERSON> with a shipment of refined petroleum products that were, in fact, for <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. So with the weapons changing _ and not necessarily being pointed in the right direction _ the gulf shipping community has now become more cautious about determining who is shooting what, and why. `` We tend to immediately say it's an Iranian attack once a victim of the tanker war is related to <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> or when the location of the attack is away from the Iranian shipping lanes, but we are growing more careful now,'' said the <LOCATION> Dubai </LOCATION> executive.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880215-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-15-88 0110EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-TheStalkerAffair     02-15 1017</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-The Stalker Affair,1044</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Policeman's Story: Mauled In The `Jungle' Of Northern Ireland</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARCUS ELIASON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 By ordinary <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> standards, the six Roman Catholics killed by police near the end of 1982 would not stand out among the 2,620 other people who have died during the 20-year conflict. But the six men were unarmed, and the murky circumstances of the police ambushes in which they died have left an ugly mystery that has resurfaced to batter <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s reputation for justice and fair play. Critics allege that the shootings, in three separate incidents over a three-week period, were deliberate; that the policemen who did it escaped punishment; and that a senior police officer sent in to investigate was hounded out of uniform because he got too close to the truth. The controversy was rekindled on Jan. 25 when the British government, while denying that police mounted a `` shoot-to-kill policy'' in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, admitted in a statement that there had been a conspiracy to pervert the course of justice. This admission, coupled with a refusal on national security grounds to prosecute the killers, has provoked outcry in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, and plunged relations between the two governments to their lowest ebb in nearly six years. In February, the investigating officer, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalker </PERSON>, published his book, `` Stalker,'' a portrayal of <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> as <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s unruly backyard, where the normal rules of policing and justice are routinely flouted Critics say the book reaffirms the belief that British rule in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> is unjust toward the <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> minority, and there are worries that the affair will set back recent progress toward reconciliation, most notably the 1985 Anglo-Irish Agreement giving <LOCATION> Dublin </LOCATION> a say in governing the province. On Nov. 11, 1982, three guerrilla suspects were shot dead by police as they drove through <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Armagh </LOCATION>. A month later, two more died in similar circumstances in the same area, notorious as a hotbed of guerrilla activity. In between, a teen-ager with no guerrilla connections was killed in a <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Armagh </LOCATION> hayshed that served as a guerrilla explosives hideout, having apparently stumbled innocently into a police ambush. At first the police said all the deaths occurred in the normal course of anti-terrorist warfare. But subsequent evidence suggested the killings were deliberate and avoidable. Sir <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hermon </PERSON>, chief constable of the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Constabulary </ORGANIZATION>, ordered an inquiry, and in May 1984, Stalker, the deputy chief constable of the <LOCATION> Manchester </LOCATION> police force, arrived from the mainland with a six-man investigation team. In his book, the lean, bespectacled Englishman says he was put on his guard from the outset when <PERSON> Hermon </PERSON> told him: `` Remember, Mr. <PERSON> Stalker </PERSON>, you are in a jungle now.'' <PERSON> Hermon </PERSON> has refused repeatedly to comment on Stalker's book. Stalker says he faced constant obstruction from a police force that resented him as an intruder, and from <PERSON> Hermon </PERSON> who, Stalker believes, was determined to protect his beleaguered force at any cost. Nonetheless, after two years of investigation he felt he had uncovered enough to suspect the killings were `` the act of a Central American assassination squad _ truly of a police force out of control.'' Stalker writes that he had evidence that at least 11 officers were involved in a conspiracy to pervert justice and commit perjury. Then, he says, `` the investigation came to an end for me like a car hitting a brick wall.'' In May 1986 he was abruptly dumped from the inquiry and suspended for `` disciplinary offenses.'' The offenses concerned his use of police vehicles and his past acquaintance with people who had minor police records. The panel that sat in judgment threw out the charges and immediately reinstated him. But he was not restored to the <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> inquiry. And he does not believe the government's insistence that his suspension had nothing to do with <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>. On March 13, 1987, just before his 48th birthday, Stalker quit the force and began writing his book. Partially serialized in a mass-circulation <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> newspaper, it has become an immediate best seller. The respected <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dublin </ORGANIZATION> calls it `` almost a morality play. On the one side, the dark, violent and brutalized struggle between a paramilitary police force and a ruthless guerrilla organization. On the other, the honorable, relentless quest for truth by the unarmed bobbies from <LOCATION> Manchester </LOCATION>.'' Stalker's critics say he was naive to think he could march into the middle of a terrorist war and apply his English standards. Stalker responds: `` I'm a pragmatic, hard-nosed copper but I draw the line at murder.'' The Royal Ulster Constabulary has issued a statement reiterating that no `` shoot-to-kill'' policy ever existed, and saying it had no hand in Stalker's suspension. The statement denied Stalker's investigation was obstructed, and said `` there are many other matters'' in his book and statements `` which the police do not accept as being accurate.'' It did not elaborate. Stalker says he believes a high-level government decision was taken to oust him, and he says he can understand why. He says he recognizes that if his recommendations had been taken up, they would have devastated the police force at a delicate juncture in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> politics. He believes that there was no `` formal, officially endorsed shoot-to-kill policy,'' but that the constabulary, under constant attack by guerrillas, was pervaded by `` a feeling of ` let's do it to them before they do it to us.''' He also agrees with the decision not to prosecute, saying too much time has passed for a fair trial to be held. Stalker believes the problem lies in expecting policemen to be soldiers. In <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, where Stalker has received a hero's welcome, he told a TV interviewer: `` It was this hypocrisy that annoyed me. If somebody had said to me, ` Mr. <PERSON> Stalker </PERSON>, these are soldiers fighting a war and this set of standards must apply,' then I could have taken that into account. `` But they did n't. They said: ` This investigation is to be done in the same way as you would do in <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Liverpool </LOCATION>,' and that's what I did.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880215-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-15-88 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SAfrica-Change     02-15 0910</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SAfrica-Change,0940</SECOND>
<HEAD>White Leaders Feel Pressure Has Eased, Shift To Long-Term Tactics</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID CRARY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAPE TOWN, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government is going out of its way to dampen expectations for rapid change, in contrast to past years, when hints of political breakthroughs proved wrong. The pressures of unrest and sanctions are waning, white officials say, and there is time to crack down on pockets of opposition while trying to persuade blacks to accept less than majority rule. In the week since the 1988 Parliament session opened, President P.W. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> and his Cabinet have sought to turn the spotlight away from black grievances and focus it on a new economic program that advocates a public-sector wage freeze and privatization of state monopolies. During a string of speeches by <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> ministers, scant mention was made of the persistent grass-roots struggle by blacks for political rights. Instead, there were generalized endorsements of democracy coupled with explanations that it could be extended to blacks only in a slow, circumscribed manner that would leave whites with a final say on national policy. `` Reform can not take place at the same rate as one can brew instant coffee,'' said <PERSON> Stoffel </PERSON> <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> der </PERSON> <PERSON> Merwe </PERSON>, a deputy minister assigned by <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> to woo black leaders into negotiations. `` The capacity for people to digest change is limited.'' Compared with the hardline apartheid rhetoric of a decade ago, the current talk of sharing power with blacks borders on the revolutionary. But the government also has clarified its non-negotiable bottom line _ continuation of segregated schools, hospitals and living areas, and a political system in which whites could never be dominated by blacks. The nation's blacks number 26 million and their population growth rate is nearly triple that of the 5 million whites. `` The -LRB- political -RRB- model we will develop is not intended to seek the approval of the outside world,'' said one government official, speaking on condition of anonymity. `` We ca n't have a political dispensation based simply on majority rule.'' Anti-apartheid activists already have dismissed as inadequate one of the few pending pieces of reform legislation _ a proposal to allow communities the option of integrating, subject to approval by residents and the government. Most of the official talk about reform is now presented in terms of the new economic program, which proponents say will free large sums of capital for projects benefiting blacks. `` Reform Costs Money'' has become an unofficial government slogan, with the implication that economic progress must precede a major political shift. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>, in full-page newspaper advertisements Sunday, called on <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africans </LOCATION> to `` tighten our belts'' to build the economic foundation for social and political change. But <PERSON> Sampie </PERSON> <PERSON> Terreblanche </PERSON>, a leading economist who last year quit <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, suggested in a column in the nationally circulated Sunday Times that the economy was being stressed `` to detract attention from the tragic failure of the government's political reform. Extreme-right politicians have condemned the economic plan as a disguised attempt to redistribute wealth from whites to blacks. The government's new approach contrasts with periods in the past three years when at least some officials indicated dramatic political moves were imminent. There were suggestions that <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>, jailed leader of the <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, might be freed and that the government might negotiate with the outlawed guerrilla movement. Particularly embarrassing was <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>'s highly promoted 1985 speech in which he said <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> was `` crossing the Rubicon'' away from apartheid, then disappointed people who expected specific, momentous concessions. Now government officials believe the <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION>'s military strength is waning and claim to have triumphed over the international sanctions campaign. The white liberal opposition is in disarray and anti-government unrest in black townships is down sharply after 20 months of state-of-emergency detentions and security force patrols. There is breathing space, the government believes, to concentrate on long-term plans and confront the challenge by the extreme-right <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in three upcoming parliamentary by-elections. <PERSON> Gerrit </PERSON> <PERSON> Viljoen </PERSON>, minister for black education and development, told foreign journalists that the best way to counter the far-right threat is to promote orderly, effective reform. But the government also is preparing an array of tough moves against its political foes on the left _ moves which could boost its standing on the right. The targets include: _ Militant black trade unions. Pending legislation would make it harder for unions to stage legal strikes and easier for employers to fire strikers. _ Universities. State subsidies are being sharply reduced this year, and further cuts are threatened unless university officials crack down on anti-government campus protests. _ The press. Home Affairs Minister <PERSON> Stoffel </PERSON> <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> defended regulations that have subjected anti-government newspapers to threat of closure, and he criticized mainstream English-language papers for a `` venomous vendetta'' against his censorship rules. _ Anti-apartheid organizations. Officials indicate that legislation is being drafted that would prohibit the receipt of foreign funds by certain anti-government groups, a move that could devastate those whose supporters within <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> are mostly poor. `` If one gets large amounts of money which is channeled from overseas into the South African political process, then one gets too many foreign shareholders,'' said <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> der </PERSON> <PERSON> Merwe </PERSON>. `` If people want to be active on the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> African </LOCATION> political front, they must do so with money they raise in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Crary </PERSON>, news editor for The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>, has been reporting from <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> since 1985.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880215-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-15-88 0113EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Exercise-Puberty     02-15 0673</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Exercise-Puberty,0690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Delaying Puberty With Exercise May Prevent Breast Cancer</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DANIEL Q. HANEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Girls should be encouraged to exercise vigorously enough to delay their puberty, because this may help protect them from breast cancer and other diseases later in life, a researcher says. Grade school girls who play strenuous sports often have their first menstrual period, or menarche, later than usual. Even after adolescence starts, they may miss periods if they work out regularly. Although delayed or missing menstruation is often thought to be abnormal, some experts now say that it is natural and even desirable, because it may protect the body from the damaging effects of sex hormones. American girls have been going through puberty at increasingly early ages throughout this century. Dr. <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Frisch </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> said Sunday that typically American girls now have their first period at age 12 -LCB-. But if they exercise in such vigorous sports as tennis, running, basketball or soccer, their average age at menarche is 15 -LCB-, the same as it was 100 years ago. And <PERSON> Frisch </PERSON> said a simple rule seems to apply: The more menstrual cycles a woman has over her lifetime, the greater her chance of breast cancer, the biggest cancer killer among <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> women. So anything that delays the start of menstruation should lower the cancer risk. `` I suggest that regular exercise starting early in elementary school would have a long-term spin-off in reduced risk of breast cancer and, from our data, a reduced risk of diabetes and cancer of the reproductive system,'' <PERSON> Frisch </PERSON> said. She and other experts who study the effects of exercise on reproduction presented their work at a meeting of the American Association for the Advancement of Science. Recent federal statistics suggest that the risk of dying from breast cancer may actually be increasing. Dr. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Fishman </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Rockefeller </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> said breast cancer may take 40 years to develop. `` What you do in puberty can be very relevant to what happens in breast cancer after menopause,'' he said. <PERSON> Frisch </PERSON> based her recommendation, in part, on a study she conducted on 5,398 women who graduated from 10 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> colleges. She found that those who had been athletic in college and high school had only about half as much cancer of the breast and reproductive system later in life as those did n't get regular exercise. Those who have delayed or irregular periods during their teen-age years seem to suffer no long-term problems. <PERSON> Frisch </PERSON>'s study found that athletic women had just as many children as those who were less active. Dr. <PERSON> Tenley </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Albright </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> surgeon who was an Olympic skating champion, said coaches and parents often consider delayed or missing periods to be a disorder, while young athletes often do not. She said the condition should be thought of as an `` appropriate adaptive response'' by the body, not a defect. The relationship between exercise and fertility is complex. Experts believe that very lean and muscular women sometimes can not get pregnant because their bodies do not have enough fat to nourish a growing fetus. They must slow down their exercise and put on some weight to become fertile. Studies have also found that lean women make more of a non-potent kind of estrogen than do fatter women. Estrogen is a key sex hormone that is essential for fertility but also plays a role in cancer of the breast and reproductive system. Experts suggest that even though lean women may be fertile, they produce less active estrogen. And this may reduce the growth of cells in their breast and reproductive tissues. When these cells proliferate less, there is also less chance of a cell dividing abnormally and starting a tumor. Some researchers also believe that among men, extreme exercise can diminish the production of male sex hormones and might interfere with sperm production. However, the effects of exercise on male fertility appears to be much less dramatic in men than in women.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880215-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-15-88 0007EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Paraguay-Election 5thLd-Writethru a0923 02-15 0649</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Paraguay-Election, 5th Ld-Writethru, a0923,0667</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stroessner Wins Eighth Term With 89 Percent Of Vote</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 7 grafs to RESTORE reference to length of
Stroessner's rule, move up allegations of rigged balloting. Picks
up 7th graf pvs, `The Colorado ...' EDITS thereafter to conform.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM H. HEATH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ASUNCION, Paraguay (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gen. <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hemisphere </LOCATION>'s longest-ruling head of state, won an eighth consecutive term as president by a landslide Sunday. Opposition leaders said the balloting was rigged. Interior Minister <PERSON> Sabino </PERSON> <PERSON> Montanaro </PERSON>, head of the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, said the party's list of candidates led by the 75-year-old president won 982,316, or 89 percent of the ballots counted. <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> has ruled the nation of 3.8 million people since taking power in an army coup in 1954. The <ORGANIZATION> Radical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, whose candidate was Sen. <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Vega </PERSON>, received 78,141 votes, or 7 percent. The <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, led by candidate Rep. <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferreira </PERSON> <PERSON> Ybarra </PERSON>, was third with 32,403 votes, or 3 percent. A total of 1,445,822 voters in this landlocked country were registered to participate in Sunday's national elections to pick a president, 36 Senators and 72 members of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputies </ORGANIZATION>. No one doubted that <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> would win. The overwhelming majority of registered voters belong to his party and he won the last elections in 1983 with 90.06 percent of the vote. Opposition leaders had urged voters to cast blank votes in protest. Both <PERSON> Ybarra </PERSON>, 54, and <PERSON> Vega </PERSON>, 65, acknowledged beforehand that they had no chance of winning. The <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> said it was suspending its unofficial count for the night. The official <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> was expected to release final vote tabulations Monday. <PERSON> Jorge </PERSON> <PERSON> Hicks </PERSON>, election overseer at a polling place in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s law school in <LOCATION> Asuncion </LOCATION>, said voting was peaceful. `` Everything went normally,'' <PERSON> Hicks </PERSON> said shortly before the polls closed at 6 p.m., 11 hours after opening. Fifty official and unofficial observers from 12 countries monitored the voting. A <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> observer, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Andersen </PERSON> of the Washington-based <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION>, complained to <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Clyde </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> that a car in which he and opposition politicians were riding was stopped in <LOCATION> Ypacarai </LOCATION>, 15 miles east of <LOCATION> Asuncion </LOCATION>, by a group of men in plainclothes and police uniforms. `` We were mistreated without provocation and treated in a beastly fashion,'' said <PERSON> Andersen </PERSON>. He said the car's driver, <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Romero </PERSON> <PERSON> Perreira </PERSON>, leader of a dissident faction of the governing <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, was struck several times. <PERSON> Jo </PERSON> <PERSON> Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Greisgaber </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> consultant for the institute, said she and a group of Uruguayan observers witnessed several election violations in the Col. <LOCATION> Oviedo </LOCATION> area, including voting by underage voters. `` We also were told the area cotton farmers had been advised that cotton prices would not be increased if they did not vote or that they would not be able to sell their crops,'' she said. In Col. <PERSON> Oviedo </PERSON>, farmer <PERSON> Froilan </PERSON> <PERSON> Miranda </PERSON> told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> he was voting `` because we have a government that says you ca n't work if you do n't vote. The small center-left <ORGANIZATION> Febrerista </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> urged voters to abstain or to cast blank ballots to protest what it said would be a fraudulent election. The party winning the largest percentage of votes gets two-thirds of the seats in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The rest are divided according to the percentage won by other parties. About 100 voters applauded when the president dropped his sealed ballot in a wooden box at a polling station in <LOCATION> Asuncion </LOCATION>'s middle-class <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION> neighborhood He pointed to the box and said, `` This is democracy.'' In <LOCATION> Caaguazu </LOCATION>, 110 miles east of <LOCATION> Asuncion </LOCATION>, about 100 people at a Roman Catholic church chanted anti-government slogans and denounced the detention of <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON> <PERSON> Laino </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Authentic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Laino </PERSON>, the country's leading opposition spokesman, was placed under house arrest Thursday for 24 hours in <LOCATION> Asuncion </LOCATION>. Police declined to comment.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880215-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-15-88 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BilingualSitcom     02-15 0368</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bilingual Sitcom,0376</SECOND>
<HEAD>CBS and Columbia Hope `Trial and Error' is a Hit in Two Languages</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By FELIX GUTIERREZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new CBS-TV series looking for laughs in two languages will be the first prime-time network show produced with both English and Spanish soundtracks, a production spokesman says. `` Trial and Error,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> midseason replacement sitcom about a Hispanic odd couple, is scheduled to debut March 15 with a Spanish radio simulcast to the nation's six top Hispanic markets. <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> officials are contacting radio stations in target cities and testing sound delivery, <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> DeMesquita </PERSON> said Thursday. If it works, viewers in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, will be able to listen in English or Spanish. `` CBS will feed to its affiliates the episodes of ` Trial and Error.' They would feed the second language, Spanish, on an audio channel,'' <PERSON> DeMesquita </PERSON> said. `` Then the local <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> affiliate would feed the second audio channel to a participating radio station over a telephone line.'' `` Hispanic homes would be able to turn down the volume on their TV and turn up the volume on the radio and watch the program in Spanish,'' <PERSON> DeMesquita </PERSON> said. CBS has contracted for seven episodes of the program, which stars <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Velez </PERSON> as a young lawyer and <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> as a T-shirt vendor. While geared for a mainstream audience, the jokes and dialogue were written with an awareness they would also air in Spanish. The show revolves around <PERSON> Velez </PERSON>'s position as the only Hispanic lawyer in a prestigious <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> law firm and <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>'s steady wheeling and dealing to sell more shirts. The bilingual plans mark the first time an English-language network program has been produced with a Spanish-speaking Hispanic audience in mind, <PERSON> DeMesquita </PERSON> said. DeMesquita hopes <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> eventually sends the Spanish soundtrack to all affiliates so stations elsewhere can arrange simulcasts. But network officials want to see if the bilingual broadcasts work in the test markets before making a broader commitment to <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION>. `` It's something the studio brought to us. It's an experiment,'' said <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Morfogen </PERSON>. `` One would have to see how it works.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880215-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-15-88 0125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SovietScience     02-15 0543</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet Science,0559</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Scientists Attend U.S. Scientific Meeting</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RAEBURN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Editor</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mathematics, theoretical physics and oceanography are among the fields in which American scientists are likely to learn much from their <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> colleagues during upcoming exchanges, according to a delegation of Soviet scientists. The Soviet researchers were in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> Sunday to describe current Soviet research at the annual meeting of the American Association for the Advancement of Science. Seven administrators from the most prestigious Soviet science institutes answered a wide range of questions from reporters in a rare meeting with the press Saturday. The researchers seemed relaxed, and they answered questions without hesitation, including difficult questions on Soviet development of a Star Wars defense system. `` The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> does not intend to develop a system like the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is working on,'' said <PERSON> Andrey </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kokoshin </PERSON>, deputy director of the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Canada </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>. A few moments later, when another Soviet researcher demonstrated a flashlight-sized laser pointer of the type used by speakers to call attention to details on projected slides, <PERSON> Kokoshin </PERSON> elicited laughter when he said, `` This is our SDI -LRB- Strategic Defense Initiative -RRB-.'' Asked about development of chemical lasers, which might be used in a missile defense system, <PERSON> Kokoshin </PERSON> said, `` They are not very promising, I would say.'' On Jan. 12, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Press </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Guriy </PERSON> <PERSON> Marchuk </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION>, signed a five-year agreement providing for scientific exchanges and cooperation. Under the terms of that agreement, joint scientific workshops will be held during the next two years on such topics as vaccine development, earthquake prediction, planetary science, biotechnology and astrophysics. <PERSON> Konstantin </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Frolov </PERSON>, vice-president of the <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> U.S.S.R. </ORGANIZATION>, said that mathematics, theoretical physics and laser and semiconductor technology are some of the traditional strongholds of Soviet science. `` The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has developed a number of sophisticated scientific instruments,'' he said, speaking through a translator. Computer software useful in oceanography has also been developed in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, he said. In the upcoming scientific exchanges, he said, `` these are areas where the Soviet side could bring something to the table.'' He proposed that joint ventures be established to develop computer manufacture. `` There was quite a gap in the introduction of computers in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, particularly personal computers,'' he said. <PERSON> Yuriy </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ossipyan </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Solid </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Physics </ORGANIZATION>, said that Soviet scientists had developed a new description of the interaction of materials in certain high-temperature superconductors. He said that research on superconductivity is being actively pursued at his institute and elsewhere in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. In a presentation Sunday, <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ivanov </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Microbiology </ORGANIZATION>, said that the Soviet union has built industrial plants for the production of animal feed through yeast fermentation. Bacteria are being used to leach metals from poor quality ores, to decrease potentially dangerous levels of methane gas in coal mines and to enhance oil recovery, <PERSON> Ivanov </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Galeev </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> described the planned launch in July of a spacecraft to study the Martian moon Phobos, which may be an asteroid that got trapped in orbit around <LOCATION> Mars </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880215-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-15-88 0126EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FarmDating     02-15 0595</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Dating,0612</SECOND>
<HEAD>Group Helps Agriculture Folks Find Dates, Friends</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>MARYANN MROWCA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WAUSAU, Wis. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
