<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880214-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-14-88 2338EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-India-Cabinet     02-14 0336</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-India-Cabinet,0348</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gandhi Shuffles Cabinet; Inducts New Ministers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prime Minister <PERSON> Rajiv </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> inducted 13 people into his <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministers </ORGANIZATION> on Sunday and reshuffled the portfolios of existing ministers. The reshuffle is the 12th since <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> was sworn into office in January 1985 and comes one week before <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>'s annual budget session is due to start. <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> told reporters the council's expansion was meant to give more representation to various regions of the country and social groups. `` Since the last reshuffle, a lot of people had dropped out of the Cabinet and this had upset the balance. In this reshuffle we have tried to restore the balance,'' the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> news agency quoted him as saying. However, no Cabinet minister was named to head the External Affairs Ministry. <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> himself handles the portfolio, aided by a junior minister. <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> denied that the changes were a prelude to early elections to <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>. `` A snap poll is definitely out,'' <ORGANIZATION> UNI </ORGANIZATION> quoted him as saying. There are now 63 ministers in the council with 15 holding Cabinet rank, excluding <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>. Three of the new ministers were inducted at Cabinet rank. These include <PERSON> Bindeshwari </PERSON> <PERSON> Dubey </PERSON> and <PERSON> Motilal </PERSON> <PERSON> Vora </PERSON>, who resigned as chief ministers of two Indian states Saturday. <PERSON> Dubey </PERSON>, who quit as chief minister of eastern <LOCATION> Bihar </LOCATION> state, was named as Law and Justice Minister while <PERSON> Vora </PERSON>, who resigned from central <LOCATION> Madhya </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pradesh </LOCATION> state, was given the Health and Family Welfare portfolio. The third, <PERSON> Dinesh </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, re-entered the <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> after 15 years as the Water Resources Minister. Cabinet Communications Minister <PERSON> Arjun </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> was named <ORGANIZATION> Madhya </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pradesh </ORGANIZATION> Chief Minister on Saturday. <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> dropped Agriculture Minister <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dhillon </PERSON> from the Cabinet Sunday and also relieved a junior minister, <PERSON> Ram </PERSON> <PERSON> Dulari </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinha </PERSON>. Mrs. <PERSON> Sinha </PERSON> has been asked to become governor of southern <LOCATION> Kerala </LOCATION> state, a largely ceremonial post. The other inductions included four junior ministers and six deputy ministers. The other changes were mainly exchanges of portfolios between existing Cabinet ministers and junior ministers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880214-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-14-88 2359EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0862 02-14 1252</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0862,1294</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: ADDS Loewe death. AMs separates moved on Goldberg, a0807;
Astorga, a0894; Hawkins, a0846, and Loewe, a0910.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Arthur Mizener</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Mizener </PERSON>, who revived interest in <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON> with the acclaimed first biography of the Jazz Age novelist, died Thursday at age 80. `` The Far Side of Paradise,'' <PERSON> Mizener </PERSON>'s best-selling biography of <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON>, was published in 1951 by <PERSON> Houghton </PERSON> <PERSON> Mifflin </PERSON>, a decade after a heart attack ended <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON>'s downward spiraling career. <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON>, now considered one of the great American novelists of the 20th Century, wrote `` This Side of Paradise,'' `` The Great Gatsby,'' `` Tender Is the Night'' and `` The Last Tycoon,'' as well as numerous short stories. <PERSON> Mizener </PERSON>, who died in a <LOCATION> Bristol </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> R.I. </LOCATION>, nursing home, taught English at <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> from 1951 until his retirement in 1975. He wrote scores of essays and book reviews. He graduated from <ORGANIZATION> Princeton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in 1930, received his master's degree from <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> in 1932 and earned a doctorate from <ORGANIZATION> Princeton </ORGANIZATION> in 1934.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Virgil Hawkins</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OCALA, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Virgil </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>, a black man who waged a 28-year battle to practice law in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and helped break the color barrier at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, died Thursday at age 81. In 1949, at age 41, he applied to the all-white law school in <LOCATION> Gainesville </LOCATION> and was rejected. He challenged the segregated school system and in 1956 the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruled that he should be admitted. But the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> invoked states' rights to deny him admission and the state adopted rigid entrance requirements that made it impossible for <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON> to enroll. In 1976 the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bar </LOCATION> urged the state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> to allow <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON> to take the bar exam even though he had attended an unaccredited law school in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> 20 years earlier. The bar said he deserved special consideration because of ill treatment in 1949. The <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> waived a requirement that he take the exam. <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON> opened a practice in <LOCATION> Leesburg </LOCATION>, but in 1984 the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> censured <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON> and placed him on probation for two years for errors he made in his first cases. <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>, facing two more complaints, resigned from the bar in 1985.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Nora Astorga</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Nora </PERSON> <PERSON> Astorga </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> ambassador who gained fame during the Sandinista revolution for luring a general to his death, died of cancer Sunday in <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>, said a spoksman for the Nicaraguan government. She was 39. In <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION> in 1978, Ms. <PERSON> Astorga </PERSON> lured Gen. <PERSON> Reynaldo </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> Vega </PERSON>, deputy commander of the National Guard, to her bedroom, where guerrillas cut his throat. <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> Vega </PERSON> had held the post in the regime of President <PERSON> Anastasio </PERSON> <PERSON> Somoza </PERSON>, who was ousted by the leftist <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> in 1979. In 1984, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> rejected her as the proposed ambassador to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. She held the rank of deputy foreign minister at the time. She was appointed <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> ambassador in 1986. Before the revolution, she earned a law degree at <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION> and worked for an engineering firm there.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Leon Goossens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Goossens </PERSON>, an oboist who redefined the instrument's potential and inspired composers to write music to showcase it, died Friday at age 90. A <ORGANIZATION> Liverpool </ORGANIZATION> native born into a family rich in musical talent, <PERSON> Goossens </PERSON> played with some of the finest orchestras of the day. By 1927, he was a soloist with the <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> Philharmonic. In his youth, the <ORGANIZATION> Liverpool </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orchestra </ORGANIZATION>, paid him 22 cents a night plus 9 cents for tackling the cor anglais solo in <PERSON> Rossini </PERSON>'s `` William Tell Overture. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Elgar </PERSON>'s 1934 Soliloquy for Oboe and Strings, one of his last works, was composed in honor of his friend <PERSON> Goossens </PERSON>. <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Britten </PERSON> and <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Poulenc </PERSON> also dedicated works to him. <PERSON> Goossens </PERSON> was made a Commander of the Order of the British Empire in 1950. He toured the world until 1962, when a car accident temporarily halted his career. <PERSON> Goossens </PERSON> played and recorded for many top orchestras and bands, including <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Hylton </PERSON>'s jazz orchestra at <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s plush <ORGANIZATION> Kit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>. He was the son of conductor <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Goossens </PERSON>. Survivors include two sisters, both harpists, <PERSON> Marie </PERSON>, 93, and <PERSON> Sidonie </PERSON>, 87, who was principal harpist with the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. Symphony Orchestra for 50 years
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Dorothy Kurgans Goldberg</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kurgans </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON>, an author, artist and wife of former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Supreme Court Justice <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON>, died of lung cancer Saturday at age 79. Mrs. <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON>'s `` The Creative Woman,'' published in 1963, was an early feminist novel. She also wrote `` A Private View of a Public Life,'' and a story for children, `` <PERSON> Lola </PERSON> and the Moving Stairs.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON>, who lived in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, recently completed the manuscript for a fourth book, about international negotiations on human rights. In 1977-78 she served as a delegate to the <LOCATION> Belgrade </LOCATION> Conference on Security and Co-operation in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, which reviewed the <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION> human rights accords. Her paintings were exhibited in several one-person shows, and in the late 1940s she helped found of the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Artists </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gallery </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. She graduated from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> in 1932, a year after she married <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON>. He served on the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> from 1962 to 1965, when he became ambassador to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Nelson Benton</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> Benton </PERSON>, a broadcast journalist who covered the Vietnam War, the civil rights movement and the nation's capital in more than 20 years with <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, died of cardiac arrest Saturday He was 63. <PERSON> Benton </PERSON> began his career at radio station <ORGANIZATION> WSOC </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C </LOCATION>. In 1960, he joined <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> as an assignment editor and reporter. He worked in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> when President <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was assassinated in 1963 and became <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> bureau manager and reporter in 1964. He covered the civil rights movement in the South and the Vietnam War from <LOCATION> Saigon </LOCATION>, then spent the next decade as a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> correspondent. In 1982, he left <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> to become an anchorman at <ORGANIZATION> WMAR-TV </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>. He left in 1984 and worked for the <ORGANIZATION> Mutual </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> System </ORGANIZATION> as White House correspondent. Most recently, he was co-anchor of `` America Today,'' a daily <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> news program broadcast overseas.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Frederick Loewe</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PALM SPRINGS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> Loewe </PERSON>, who created the unforgettable tunes for <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Lerner </PERSON>'s lyrics in such Broadway hits as `` Camelot,'' `` My Fair Lady,'' `` Brigadoon'' and `` <PERSON> Gigi </PERSON>,'' died Sunday at age 86. `` I Could Have Danced All Night,'' `` On the Street Where You Live,'' `` I've Grown Accustomed to Her Face'' and `` If Ever I Should Leave You'' were among the classic songs produced by the 18-year partnership. <PERSON> Lerner </PERSON> and <PERSON> Loewe </PERSON>'s collaboration began with a one-night flop in <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> in 1942. They parted bitterly after `` Camelot,'' their last Broadway hit, in 1960. In between came `` Brigadoon'' in 1947 and `` My Fair Lady'' in 1956. <PERSON> Lerner </PERSON> and <PERSON> Loewe </PERSON> reunited in 1973 for the Broadway production of `` <PERSON> Gigi </PERSON>,'' and remained friends. <PERSON> Loewe </PERSON> retired in 1974. <PERSON> Lerner </PERSON> died in 1986. <PERSON> Loewe </PERSON> was born in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>, the son of a tenor and an actress. He began piano lessons at age 5 and composition at age 7. At 13 he became the youngest pianist to appear as soloist with the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Symphony. <PERSON> Loewe </PERSON> came to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1924 with hopes for a career as a piano soloist. After his debut at <ORGANIZATION> Town </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> was ignored, he embarked on a bohemian life, playing piano in clubs and movie houses and working as a busboy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880214-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-14-88 0127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PassengerOverboard     02-14 0224</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Passenger Overboard,0230</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman Killed In Fall From Cruise Ship</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONG BEACH, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A cruise ship passenger fell overboard and drowned as the ship steamed toward <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> reported Saturday. Foul play was not suspected, authorities said. The identity of the 27-year-old woman, whose body was recovered by a <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> cutter, was withheld until relatives could be contacted, Petty Officer <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> said. The woman fell overboard about 3 a.m. when the ship was 30 miles southwest of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> said. The Long Beach-based cutter Point <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON>, along with a <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> helicopter and jet, immediately began a search. After four searches, the Point <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> recovered the woman's body at 12:30 p.m., <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> said. The body was taken to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> for autopsy. There was no evidence of foul play, <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> said. He had no further details. The Star Dancer, which docked in <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> Saturday, was carrying about 900 passengers and was completing a cruise along the Mexican coast, <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> said. He added it was n't immediately known which port the ship had sailed from or how long it had been at sea. The Star Dancer regularly makes cruise runs between <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. The Star Dancer is owned by Admiral Cruises of <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> said. Officials for Admiral Cruises were unavailable Saturday night.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880214-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-14-88 0138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-RaileyInterview 1stLd-Writethru a0703 02-14 0555</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Railey Interview, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0703,0563</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Minister: `I'm Not Guilty Of Anything'</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 2nd-3rd grafs to CLARIFY that stories based on interview
published Saturday and Sunday, sted Saturday. Picks up 4th graf,
`After Billie...'.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A former Methodist minister accused in a civil suit of trying to choke his wife to death says he is innocent and has avoided his <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> apartment to dodge reporters, not court officials. `` My response to the allegations in the suit are the same they have been all along: I'm not guilty of anything and do n't have anything to fear on that point,'' <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> <PERSON> Railey </PERSON> said in an interview in the <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> Morning News. `` I regret the lawsuit because it puts all the family _ the <PERSON> Nicolai </PERSON> family and me _ under an even added amount of pressure,'' <PERSON> Railey </PERSON> said in his first interview since he moved to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> in November. Stories based on the interview were published in the newpaper's Saturday and Sunday editions. After <PERSON> Billie </PERSON> <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicolai </PERSON>, <PERSON> Railey </PERSON>'s mother-in-law, filed the lawsuit Feb. 2, <PERSON> Railey </PERSON> began living in hotels and with friends instead of in his apartment. <PERSON> Railey </PERSON>, former senior minister of the <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Methodist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in downtown <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, said he has stayed away from the apartment because news reporters and photographers have staked it out. `` I'm keeping a low profile because people are sitting out in front of my flat and I resent that,'' <PERSON> Railey </PERSON> said. `` I know the press is doing its job and I'm just trying to live my life. At this point, there seems to be difficulty in making both of those things work.'' The constant attention and news reports have made him weary and resentful, he said. `` I'm in a situation where my silence makes people wonder and, when I talk, the way it's used -LRB- in the media -RRB- also makes people wonder,'' <PERSON> Railey </PERSON> said, describing his position as being `` between the devil and the deep blue sea.'' <PERSON> Railey </PERSON> has said he found his wife, <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> `` </PERSON> <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON><PERSON> '' </PERSON> <PERSON> Railey </PERSON>, near death the night of April 21 in their garage. Mrs. <PERSON> Railey </PERSON> has been comatose since the attack and is in a Tyler nursing home. The lawsuit by Mrs. <PERSON> Nicolai </PERSON>, <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Railey </PERSON>'s mother, seeks unspecified damages. Court officers have been unable to locate <PERSON> Railey </PERSON> to serve him formal notification of the civil suit, but <PERSON> Railey </PERSON> denied `` trying to dodge the papers.'' He declined to review a copy of the lawsuit offered by the Morning News and said he wanted to first discuss it with his <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> attorney, <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulder </PERSON>. <PERSON> Railey </PERSON> declined to give an account of the night his wife was attacked, and he also declined to talk about his relationship with psychologist <PERSON> Lucy </PERSON> <PERSON> Papillon </PERSON>, who told a grand jury in July that she had been having an affair with <PERSON> Railey </PERSON>. Late last year and <PERSON> Railey </PERSON> signed a one-year lease on a <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> flat. Before his wife was attacked last April, the prominent minister reported to police that he was receiving death threats that he blamed on his strong pro-civil-rights stance. Police later concluded that the threatening notes were typed on a church typewriter. The morning that police were planning to question <PERSON> Railey </PERSON> about the attack on his wife, he took an overdose of sleeping pills but later recovered. <PERSON> Railey </PERSON> has since resigned his church position.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880214-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-14-88 0028EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Poll 2ndLd-Writethru a0683 02-14 0318</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Poll, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0683,290</SECOND>
<HEAD>Poll Shows Dukakis Increasing Lead</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: New thruout with Boston Globe poll</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has a solid lead in the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hampshire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> primary, while Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> are locked in a tie on the Republican side, according to two polls released Saturday. The latest <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News-Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> poll, completed Friday night, put <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> at 40 percent with Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> and Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> each with 16 percent. The poll was based on interviews with 375 likely Democratic primary voters and 373 likely Republican primary voters over the three days ending Friday. The survey of Republicans found that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> were tied for the lead in the Republican race at 29 percent. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> and former <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> du </PERSON> <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> were tied for third with 12 percent. The remaining candidates in the race had single-digit support in the poll, which has a margin of error of plus or minus five percentage points for the Democrats and six percentage points for the Republican sample. Meanwhile, the <ORGANIZATION> Sunday </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION> said its poll of 789 <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> voters also showed <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> with a comfortable lead and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> with almost even support. The random telephone survey was conducted Thursday, Friday and Saturday before the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> debate at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Anselm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>. A significant number of voters said they were still undecided and nearly a third of those in each party said they might change their mind. Thirty-nine percent of the 387 Democratic voters favored <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>; <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> had 14 percent and <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> 13 percent. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> was favored by 32 percent of the 402 likely <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> voters, and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had 28 percent. Ten percent of the voters were undecided. The poll had a margin of error of plus or minus 5 percentage points.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880214-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-14-88 0044EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-PoliticalRdp 6thLd-Writethru a0685 02-14 1306</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Political Rdp, 6th Ld-Writethru, a0685,1,240</SECOND>
<HEAD>Candidates Making Final Push In New Hampshire</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Subs 13-14 grafs bgng: Meanwhile an ... with 5 grafs to
UPDATE with Globe poll. Picks up 15th graf pvs bgng: At his ...,
editing to tighten</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CONCORD, N.H. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Presidential candidates plunged Saturday into the final weekend of campaigning before <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hampshire </ORGANIZATION>'s do-or-die primary, with Democrats staging a spirited debate and Republican Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> encountering hecklers from opposition camps <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, locked in a tight race in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> with Vice President <PERSON> Geroge </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, was campaigning at a shopping mall in <LOCATION> Bedford </LOCATION> when he found himself surrounded by chanting supporters of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>. The scene quickly became a shouting contest with sign-waving supporters from the three campaigns vying for attention. The shouting cointinued in the parking lot after <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s motorcade departed. The Democratic debaters engaged in a little shouting of their own, with <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> acting as peacemaker and urging his rivals to stick to the issues and stop playing `` how bruised I am.'' The debate heated up quickly with Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> and Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> continuing their running dispute over <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> commercials that attack <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>. Then Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> had a run-in over remarks <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>'s campaign manager made about <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hampshire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> front-runner <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> attacked <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> for accepting money from political action committees and also for supporting an oil import fee. At times it was hard to distinguished who was shouting at whom. `` What's your energy policy,'' former front-runner <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> asked the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor. `` This is a budget issue,'' chimed in former Gov. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>. `` Can I finish my answer?'' asked <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. The nationally televised one-hour debate, sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Voters </ORGANIZATION>, took place at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Anselm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Goffstown </LOCATION>. The League was sponsoring a Republican debate at the college on Sunday. Meanwhile, two polls showed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> locked in a tie for the lead in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>'s Republican primary, with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> enjoying a solid advantage among Democrats. An <ORGANIZATION> ABC-Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> poll gave <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> each 29 percent. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> and former <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> du </PERSON> <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> were tied for third with 12 percent. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had 40 percent with <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> and <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> each at 16 percent. The poll was based on interviews with 375 likely Democratic primary voters and 373 likely <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> primary voters over three days ending Friday. It had a margin of error of plus or minus five percentage points for the Democrats and six percentage points for the Republican sample. The Sunday <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION> said its poll of 789 <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> voters surveyed Thursday, Friday and Saturday showed 39 percent of the Democrats for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, with 14 percent for <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> and 13 percent for <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> was favored by 32 percent of the likely <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> voters, and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had 28 percent. Ten percent were undecided. The poll had a margin of error of plus or minus 5 percentage points. At his first campaign stop of the day, <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, the winner in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> last Monday, warned his rivals _ particularly <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> _ that negative campaigning now could hurt the party's chance to win the presidency. `` We're not going to win this if we're brawling in the mud,'' said <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, who has been the target of <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> commercials focusing on the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> congressman's votes in favor of the B-1 bomber and nuclear power. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, whose candidacy hinges on the support of <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hampshire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> voters on Tuesday, unveiled a new television commercial attacking <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> for not being effective enough in the fight to get congressional approval of aid to the Nicaraguan Contras. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON> described <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> as `` relatively passive on the issue'' of Contra aid. When the congressman was asked if his candidacy could survive a finish behind <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> on Tuesday, he replied: `` He's not going to beat me in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>.'' Dog sled races in <LOCATION> Laconia </LOCATION> drew <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, while du <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> went rummaging for votes at the <LOCATION> Bedford </LOCATION> town dump. Noticing campaign workers for <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> passing out literature at the dump, which attracts 400 to 500 people on a Saturday, du <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> said, `` Here's a real candidate.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, at an appearance in <LOCATION> Dover </LOCATION>, shrugged off criticism in a <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> television commercial that called him `` one of the biggest tax raisers in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> history.'' `` I've cut taxes five times in the last four years,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said, adding that he did not want to see the Democrats letting themselves `` disintegrate into the kind of backyard squabbling that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> have been involved in.'' <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> toured shopping malls on the seacoast, shaking hands and telling people, `` I need some help on Tuesday.'' The former evangelist told reporters, `` It's a horserace all the way, and I think we might see some surprises come Tuesday night. But the momentum is on my side right now and that's the good way to be at this stage.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> appeared at a high school in <LOCATION> Wolfeboro </LOCATION> with Gov. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> and Hall of Fame baseball player <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> and was on the offensive against <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>. `` I think <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> is making some statements that are pretty extravagant,'' said the vice president. `` <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> says when <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> wants something done he calls <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>. But when he wanted somebody to be the vice presidnt of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, he called me.'' In addition to his campaigning, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> was the candidate featured this weekend in the televised interviews by <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Frost </PERSON>, part of the series called, `` The Next President.'' Asked about <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Moammar </PERSON> <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON>, the former television evangelist said, `` I would n't have hesitated to kill him. He's a madman and he was a terrorist.'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> picked up the endorsement of former <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION> secretary <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Rumsfeld </PERSON> who dreamed of being one of the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> candidates but eventually decided against entering the race. Also appearing with <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> at <PERSON> Jaffrey </PERSON> was former Secretary of State <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, who dropped out of the race on Friday and endorsed the Kansan. Addressing a rally at <ORGANIZATION> Conant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said, `` Some people say <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> is pretty tough. You better hope I'm tough. We're talking about our future. We're talking about our children's future We're talking about our grandchildren.'' It was clear that <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s victory in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> coupled with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s embarrassing third-place finish had blown away the big edge the vice president once held in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> surveys <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> could be a last stand for <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> and du Pont, as well as for two Democrats, former Gov. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> and former Sen. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> said he was confident he'd finish ahead of <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> in the primary. Asked if he also had to beat <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> or <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, he replied, `` No, I've got to be competitive. I've got to be up in the pack among the leaders. And that's what our goal is.'' `` You have to do well, you have to start beating somebody,'' conceded du <PERSON> Pont </PERSON>, who finished fifth in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> and is running the same in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> surveys. The new <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> ad took swipes at both <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on the Contra aid issue. The commercial said that in the recent <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> vote that rejected President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s request for more money for the Contras, eight <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> supporters were among those who voted against the money. The ad also quoted <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> as telling the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION> `` he was n't concerned about -LRB- Nicaraguan president <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> or his army Is that leadership?'' When reporters asked how <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> could attack <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, when the senator had voted for Contra aid, <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON> said, `` Sure he's voted in the right place. But this guy has run for the last year on leadership. ... <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> has been relatively passive on this issue.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880214-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-14-88 0048EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Dole-Owen     02-14 0269</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Dole-Owen,250</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dole Campaign Continues Business With Owen's Daughter</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KANSAS CITY, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican presidential contender Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> has continued to spend thousands of dollars with a travel agency owned by the daughter and son-in-law of a former <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> political aide, a newspaper report said Sunday. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> cut political ties with <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Owen </PERSON>, his former chief fund-raiser and a former <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> lieutenant governor, after questions were raised last month about <PERSON> Owen </PERSON>'s business dealings. But according to <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> records, the campaign of <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Kan </LOCATION>., paid more than $ 80,000 in the last quarter of 1987 to International Tours of <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Kansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> reported A <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> spokesman said the campaign decided it would be unfair to stop buying travel services from <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tours </ORGANIZATION>, which is owned by <PERSON> Owen </PERSON>'s daughter, <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON>, and his son-in-law, <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> <PERSON> Wells </PERSON>. `` It seemed remarkably unfair to make <PERSON> Debbie </PERSON> suffer more than she already has on a personal level,'' said <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, the campaign's chief counsel. `` The agency has been providing services from the start,'' <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> said. He said <LOCATION> Campaign </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s political action committee, had used International Tours and it `` seemed a natural continuation'' to use the travel agency in <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s presidential bid. <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> said the campaign gets no price breaks on travel services, and said nothing was wrong with the relationship. A <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> spokesman generally agreed. `` As long as they're paying the going rate, there's no problem,'' said <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Eiland </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>'s chief spokesman <PERSON> Eiland </PERSON> said such special treatment by a company could violate campaign finance laws against corporate contributions or individual contributions exceeding $ 1,000.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880214-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-14-88 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Bangladesh 1stLd-Writethru a0564 02-14 0469</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bangladesh, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0564,0483</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bangladesh Strike Leaves One Dead, At Least 34 Injured</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Bangladesh-Stalemate, Bjt</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 5 grafs to UPDATE with one death, general strike
continuing Sunday. Picks up 4th graf pvs, `The government ...' SUBS
9th graf pvs to conform.
^By HASAN SAEED</NOTE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DHAKA, Bangladesh (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Protesters fought police and detonated homemade bombs Saturday as opposition parties renewed their drive to oust President <PERSON> Hussain </PERSON> <PERSON> Muhammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Ershad </PERSON>. One person was killed and at least 34 injured. A general strike that continued Sunday shut down most shops and businesses in <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION> and other major cities. Since the major opposition parties launched their anti-Ershad campaign last Nov. 10, there have been 24 days of general strikes. There were no reports of violence Sunday morning. Saturday's violence, in which nine people were arrested, comes on the heels of bloody street battles during local elections last Wednesday. The government on Saturday raised its official death toll from the election-day melees to 101. Most of the deaths occurred in clashes among supporters of rival opponents for seats on more than 4,370 village councils. Unofficial death counts in <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION> newspapers put the figure at 135. Hundreds were injured. <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Hasina </PERSON>, leader of the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Awami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>, said Saturday she had reports of more than 350 deaths in the Wednesday rampages. In addition, confrontations between protesters throwing bricks and bombs and police firing rifles and tear gas have killed 25 people by the government's count, 100 by <PERSON> Hasina </PERSON>'s count, since Nov. 10. On Saturday, like last Wednesday, much of the damage was done by homemade bombs, which are being used increasingly by political protesters here. One person was killed and at least 14 injured by a bomb thrown at a state-run bus in <LOCATION> Mirpur </LOCATION>, a northern suburb of <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION>, witnesses and hospital officials said. <PERSON> Rahul </PERSON> <PERSON> Amina </PERSON>, a student who accompanied one of the bus victims to a hospital, said some injured passengers fled the scene for fear of being asked by police to be witnesses. Another bomb injured 10 people in central <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION>. Ten other injuries were reported after police wielding batons clashed with about 100 slogan-shouting demonstrators near the capital's central office, witnesses reported. Police posted outside <ORGANIZATION> Dhaka </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> accused students of hurling homemade bombs toward shuttered shopping centers nearby. No casualties were reported. Twenty-one of the country's major opposition parties began their campaign more than three months ago to force <PERSON> Ershad </PERSON> to resign. <PERSON> Ershad </PERSON>, 58, a former army general, took power in <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION> in a bloodless coup in 1982. He was elected to the presidency in 1986 in an election the opposition contends was rigged. In an effort to appease his political opponents, <PERSON> Ershad </PERSON> dissolved <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> and called for fresh elections March 3. The main opposition leaders say they will boycott the vote.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880214-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-14-88 0140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Mummy-HealthCult     02-14 0580</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mummy-Health Cult,0594</SECOND>
<HEAD>Health Cult Linked To Knox County Mummy</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A family that secretly kept a mummified body in their home for more than eight years has been linked to a cult that preaches use of nutrients and exorcism in place of traditional medicine, investigators said. `` I think we are touching on something, a group that has n't been known before _ a group that is almost a secret society,'' <LOCATION> Knox </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Shearer </PERSON> said in a story published in Sunday's <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Shearer </PERSON> said those involved in the cult, known as the `` Holistic Society,'' included several suburban <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> dentists, but he would not identify them because of pending investigations. <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, the man whose withered corpse was found in bed last month in his rural <LOCATION> Knoxville </LOCATION> home, was a diabetic who was persuaded to rely on vitamins and powdered mixes in place of his daily insulin injections, according to investigators and family members. His body was found more than eight years after he died May 12, 1979, at age 40. His brother also died at a relatively young age, and investigators were told that his death may also be related to unorthodox health practices. The <ORGANIZATION> Holistic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> disdains traditional health methods and relies instead on an extreme form of `` holistic health care,'' in which the mind and body are treated with only natural vitamins, herbs and nutrients, <PERSON> Shearer </PERSON> said. Treatments are administered in a quasi-religious fashion that involve the use of healing crystals, the exorcism of `` black souls or Satan,'' and `` channeling'' to communicate with spirits, <PERSON> Shearer </PERSON> said. There is no evidence that the health cult is violent or guilty of anything other than encouraging bizarre health practices for the unwary, <PERSON> Shearer </PERSON> said. In the weeks before his death, <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> had cut his daily insulin intake in half and was taking up to 20 vitamin pills a day, according to an aunt, <PERSON> Frances </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennelly </PERSON> of <PERSON> Lambe </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Mo </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, who had been a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Knoxville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION>, died after vomiting a `` black substance,'' his 42-year-old wife, <PERSON> Carole </PERSON>, told investigators. The only criminal charges in the case were lodged against Mrs. <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, a former nurse, and former <LOCATION> Aurora </LOCATION> dentist <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kunce </PERSON>, 56. Both are charged with forging the dead man's name on legal and bank documents and with cruelty to children. The <ORGANIZATION> Stevenses </ORGANIZATION>' teen-age son and daughter lived in the house with the mummified corpse. <PERSON> Kunce </PERSON>, who is in custody, and Mrs. <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, who is out on bond, have already pleaded guilty to a misdemeanor charge of failing to report <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>' death. In another twist to the case, investigators say they found a `` travel permit'' from the right-wing Posse Comitatus anti-tax group in the wallet of <PERSON> Kunce </PERSON>, who moved in with the <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> family 18 months ago as their `` spiritual leader.'' <PERSON> Kunce </PERSON> was introduced to the <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> family by <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>' brother, <PERSON> Roger </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Charles </LOCATION> lawyer who was apparently the first family member to become involved in the health cult, <PERSON> Shearer </PERSON> said Investigators and family members said <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> persuaded his brother to use the vitamins and powdered mixes in place of his daily insulin injections, and said <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> even began selling the substances from his office. <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> died at age 43 in 1985 at a <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> hospital. His death was attributed to gastrointestinal hemorrhage and hepatic cirrhosis. But a nurse who cared for him told investigators, `` I think it was his diet that killed him,'' according to the <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880214-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-14-88 0210EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-BombThreat     02-14 0265</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bomb Threat,0272</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Threatens to Detonate Explosives in Lounge</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ARLINGTON, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man who threatened to blow himself up in a bar with dynamite he'd strapped to his body was taken into custody by police early Sunday after four hours of negotiations. Authorities later found no explosives. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Allgood </PERSON>, 33, of <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION> walked out of the Plaza Lounge shirtless, following police instructions, and surrendered to authorities at about 12:10 a.m., said <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION> police spokesman <PERSON> Dee </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>. `` The officers did not find any explosives. They did find a hoax device. People in the bar had seen something so we knew <PERSON> Allgood </PERSON> had something,'' <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> said. Bartender <PERSON> Ina </PERSON> <PERSON> Silloway </PERSON> said the man came into the bar shortly after 8 p.m. and walked around for a few minutes before ordering a 12-pack of beer to go. When she returned with the beer, she said, he handed her a Valentine's greeting card. `` It said something to the effect of, ` This is no joke. I have six sticks of dynamite strapped to me. If you look at me, I will show you,'' Ms. <PERSON> Silloway </PERSON> said. `` At that point I looked up and he showed me,'' she said, adding that the man told her he planned to `` commit police suicide.'' Police say <PERSON> Allgood </PERSON>, who was alone inside the bar, threatened to harm no one but himself. Police cordoned off the area, but because other nearby businesses were closed Saturday night there was no need for any evacuation, said officer <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Burton </PERSON>. Charges were pending against <PERSON> Allgood </PERSON>, <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> said, but he would not specify what they involve.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880214-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-14-88 0247EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Nixon-Election 1stLd-Writethru a0708 02-14 0276</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nixon-Election, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0708,0276</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former President Says Kennedy Should Run</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 5th graf to give Kennedy's date of birth.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> said in the Sunday Times that Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> should run for president this year and his character would be his greatest asset. In the first of a series of articles on the elections, <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> predicted if there is an economic recession this year, `` any one of the Democrats will win. If there is not a recession, the Democrats can not win without a charismatic candidate such as <LOCATION> Kennedy </LOCATION> or -LRB- <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>.'' Drafting <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> `` would bring the still potent magic of the <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> name to a party that had been demoralized by six months of fruitless campaigning,'' <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> wrote. `` <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s eloquence could bring the party together.'' The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Democrat `` will turn 57 in eight days,'' <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> wrote. `` If he is ever going to run for President, a 1988 draft would be his best shot.'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, who was born Feb. 22, 1932, is `` the least discussed but most logical candidate for a draft. ... His greatest strength would be the character issue, both its negative side and especially its positive side,'' the Republican former president wrote. `` No one will ever forget <LOCATION> Chappaquiddick </LOCATION>,'' he wrote, referring to a July 1969 auto accident in which he was the driver and a woman passenger was killed. `` The question is whether people have forgiven him for it,'' he wrote. `` If the media hound <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> over that tragic accident 19 years agothey might well help him rather than hurt him _ and also land themselves in the political doghouse.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880214-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-14-88 0518EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Sweden-Estonians 1stLd-Writethru a0713 02-14 0226</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Sweden-Estonians, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0713,0227</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Authorities Expel Two Estonian Nationalists</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS last graf to CORRECT date of annexation.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>STOCKHOLM, Sweden (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet authorities Saturday expelled to <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> two <LOCATION> Estonian </LOCATION> activists who were trying to organize an independant Estonian party, a human rights group and the Swedish national news agency <ORGANIZATION> TT </ORGANIZATION> reported. The two men, Buddhists with shaven heads, arrived on an Soviet Aeroflot flight and were greeted by a crowd of about 15 Estonian exiles. The Stockholm-based <ORGANIZATION> Baltic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Helsinki </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> quoted <PERSON> Eke-Part </PERSON> <PERSON> Nomm </PERSON> as saying he and <PERSON> Vello </PERSON> <PERSON> Vaartnou </PERSON> had been told by the Soviet authorities to leave the country or face imprisonment. Mr. <PERSON> Nomm </PERSON>, 22, said they were pressured into leaving probably because he had read an appeal to form an <ORGANIZATION> Estonian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Independence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> at a meeting in <LOCATION> Tartu </LOCATION> Feb. 2, the human rights group reported. Numm and <PERSON> Vaartnou </PERSON>, 36, belong to a group of 16 Estonians who work for the formation of a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Independence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> TT </ORGANIZATION> reported. The expulsions came shortly before the 70th anniversary of <LOCATION> Estonia </LOCATION>'s pre-Soviet independence day on Feb. 24, which is expected to lead to celebrations and demonstrations. Similar activities are planned in <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>, whose independence day falls on Feb. 16. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> annexed the three independent Baltic states <LOCATION> Estonia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Latvia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION> in 1940 in a secret pact with <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880214-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-14-88 0817EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Obit-Mizener     02-14 0239</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Obit-Mizener,0247</SECOND>
<HEAD>Noted Biographer of of F. Scott Fitzgerald Dies</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Retransmits a0726 to make cycle designator BC, sted PM</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Mizener </PERSON>, author of the acclaimed first biography of <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON>, has died at the age of 80. <PERSON> Mizener </PERSON> died of congestive heart failure Thursday at the <LOCATION> Bristol </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> R.I. </LOCATION>, nursing home where he had lived. `` The Far Side of Paradise,'' <PERSON> Mizener </PERSON>'s best-selling biography of <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON>, was published in 1951 by <PERSON> Houghton </PERSON> <PERSON> Mifflin </PERSON>, a decade after a heart attack ended the downward spiraling career of the chronicler of the Jazz Age of the 1920s. The biography was credited with reviving interest in <LOCATION> Fitzgerald </LOCATION>, now considered one of the great American novelists of the 20th Century. <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON> wrote `` This Side of Paradise,'' `` The Great Gatsby,'' `` Tender Is the Night'' and `` The Last Tycoon,'' as well as numerous short stories. Mizener taught English at <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> from 1951 until his retirement in 1975. He wrote scores of essays and book reviews for many publications. Born in <LOCATION> Erie </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, he graduated from <ORGANIZATION> Princeton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in 1930, received his master's degree from <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in 1932 and returned to <LOCATION> Princeton </LOCATION>, where he received his doctorate in 1934. A memorial service is to be held at noon on Feb. 27 at the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congregational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Compton </LOCATION>. He is survived by a daughter, <PERSON> Rosemary </PERSON> <PERSON> Colt </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Compton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> R.I. </LOCATION>; a sister, <PERSON> Virginia </PERSON> <PERSON> Jarecki </PERSON> of Erie and three grandchildren.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880214-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-14-88 1010EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Cyprus-Bomb 1stLd-Writethru a0732 02-14 0293</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Cyprus-Bomb, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0732,0298</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Killed in Cyprus Bombing</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: UPDATES thruout with PLO saying victims were PLO members; PLO
official blaming Israel for bombing. No pickup.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three men were killed Sunday when a bomb exploded in their car in the southern port city of <LOCATION> Limassol </LOCATION>, police said. A <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> official in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION> said the victims were members of <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Fatah </ORGANIZATION> group, the main <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> guerrilla faction. The official, speaking on condition of anonymity, identified the victims as <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Sultan </PERSON>; <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Buheis </PERSON>, also known as <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Hassan </PERSON> <PERSON> Kassem </PERSON>; and <PERSON> Marwan </PERSON> <PERSON> Kayyali </PERSON>. He said <PERSON> Kayyali </PERSON> was a member of the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s military council. Police, however, identified one of the victims as an Arab named <PERSON> Ghazi </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Hazem </PERSON> and said the other two victims' bodies were burned beyond recognition. They said they believed the other victims also were Arabs. There was no explanation for the discrepency in identifications. The police said they did not believe the blast was related to the <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> presidential elections Sunday, and they said it did n't disrupt voting A sizeable number of Arabs, mainly Lebanese and Palestinians, live in <LOCATION> Limassol </LOCATION>, which has a population of 121,000. Police said the bomb went off shortly before noon as the driver tried to start the car, which was outside an apartment building. In <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Bassam </PERSON> <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharif </PERSON> accused <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> of being behind the slayings. `` <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> started this open war after losing the secret war concerning the ship,'' he said, referring to <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> plans to sail a group of Palestinian deportees back to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>. The trip has been delayed several times, and the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> has accused <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> of waging a `` secret war'' against the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> to prevent the ship's sailing.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880214-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-14-88 1028EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Tanzania-Hijacking     02-14 0354</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Tanzania-Hijacking,0366</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pilot Tricks Would-be Hijackers; Four Arrested</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ADARSH NAYAR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DAR ES SALAAM, Tanzania (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Four men tried to hijack a <ORGANIZATION> Tanzania </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> jet to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> but were overpowered Sunday after the pilot duped them into thinking he had flown them out of the country, sources said. Capt. <PERSON> Dominic </PERSON> <PERSON> Ngandile </PERSON> was stabbed in the neck and hand and his co-pilot, <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Mnika </PERSON>, suffered cuts on his hands when the hijackers slashed at them after realizing they had been tricked, said airline and security sources who spoke on condition of anonymity. They said the injuries were not serious. None of the passengers on board the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 737 was injured. Officials said there were 70 passengers, including the hijackers, and a crew of six. The sources said the hijacking occurred Saturday night aboard a <ORGANIZATION> Tanzania </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION>' flight between <LOCATION> Dar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> es </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salaam </LOCATION>, the capital, and <PERSON> Kilimanjaro </PERSON>, the northern town near the <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> border. Passengers said at 9:17 p.m., about midway through the 50-minute flight, four men forced their way into the cockpit and threatened the captain and co-pilot with knives. Airline sources said the men demanded to be flown to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, with a stop in <LOCATION> Addis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ababa </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Ethiopian </LOCATION> capital, so the plane could be refueled. <PERSON> Ngandile </PERSON> told the hijackers that the plane did not have enough fuel to reach <PERSON> Addis </PERSON> <PERSON> Ababa </PERSON> and suggested he refuel instead at a small airport at <LOCATION> Ludwar </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION>, the sources said. The hijackers agreed. Instead of heading for <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Ngandile </PERSON> flew the plane in a wide arc and headed back to <LOCATION> Dar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> es </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salaam </LOCATION> airport. He also managed to send a secret distress signal to the control tower at <LOCATION> Dar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> es </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salaam </LOCATION>. Airport officials turned off the terminal lights and some of the runway lights to give the appearance that the plane was landing at a small airport. The jet landed at about 10:30 p.m. Security forces called to the airport stormed the plane and took the men into custody. The four hijackers were described as residents of the semi-autonomous island of <LOCATION> Zanzibar </LOCATION>. They were believed to be between the ages of 16 and 20.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880214-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-14-88 1135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a AM-BRF--Raid-Sting     02-14 0142</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Raid-Sting,0146</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Haven Police Get Two-For-One In Undercover Operation</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW HAVEN, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Opportunity came knocking for undercover police officers who raided a house looking for drug dealers and ended up arresting their customers as they came to the door. The police street-crime unit had arrested four suspected drug dealers Friday and were searching their house when the first customer knocked on the door, said Lt. <PERSON> Rafael </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>. Over the next few hours, the impromptu sting operation resulted in 18 unexpected drug arrests, police said. <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> said the undercover cops intended only to arrest the dealers, but when the first would-be buyers knocked `` we decided to do a reverse sting operation.'' Seized from the house were about 80 bags of heroin, an unspecified amount of cocaine, $ 2,900 in cash, a loaded .38 - caliber revolver and assorted drug paraphernalia, police
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880214-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-14-88 1136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Tootsie's     02-14 0347</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tootsie's,0357</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Says Building Owners Have Right To Name Of Legendary Saloon</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The owners of the building that housed <PERSON> Tootsie </PERSON>'s Orchid Lounge, a legendary honky-tonk frequented in its heyday by country music celebrities, also own the right to the tavern's name, a judge has ruled. Chancellor <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brandt </PERSON> ruled Friday that <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodson </PERSON>, son of the late club owner <PERSON> Hattie </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> `` </PERSON> <PERSON> Tootsie </PERSON>'' <PERSON> Bess </PERSON>, lost his right to use the name when he closed the tavern in 1985 and did not renew the trade name registration his mother had filed 10 years earlier. <PERSON> Dodson </PERSON> had filed suit in 1986 charging that the building's owners, <PERSON> Mollye </PERSON> <PERSON> Ashe </PERSON> and her brother, <PERSON> Abe </PERSON> <PERSON> Stein </PERSON>, were illegally using the name of the tavern which his mother had operated there for 25 years `` What I want is my mother's name back,'' <PERSON> Dodson </PERSON> said when he filed the suit in <ORGANIZATION> Chancery </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. But <PERSON> Brandt </PERSON> said Ms. <PERSON> Ashe </PERSON> and her brother did not invade <PERSON> Dodson </PERSON>'s rights by registering the name `` World Famous Tootsie's Orchid Lounge'' with the secretary of state's office in July 1985, four months after <PERSON> Dodson </PERSON> closed the club Ms. <PERSON> Ashe </PERSON> and <PERSON> Stein </PERSON> have leased the building to others, who have continued to operate the tavern since August 1985. Tootsie's was located across the alley from the backstage door of the Ryman Auditorium where the Grand Ole Opry was performed from 1943 to 1974. Parts of the movie `` Coal Miner's Daughter'' were filmed there, depicting the life of country music star <PERSON> Loretta </PERSON> <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON>. `` Mrs. <PERSON> Bess </PERSON> was famous for her hospitality and generosity, and her tavern became a well-known refuge for aspiring entertainers, musicians and songwriters, many of whom went on to achieve fame and fortune,'' <PERSON> Brandt </PERSON> wrote. But when the Opry moved to the Opryland theme park complex in the suburbs, country stars dropped in less often and business in general dropped off. Mrs. <PERSON> Bess </PERSON> died in 1978. Her son's decision to close the bar `` received considerable coverage in both the local and national news media. From all indications, <PERSON> Tootsie </PERSON>'s was closed for good,'' <PERSON> Brandt </PERSON> wrote.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880214-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-14-88 1137EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-RadioactiveJewelry     02-14 0361</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Radioactive Jewelry,0374</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jewelry from Radium Dials Hot Item, Dangerous for Wearers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A fad for jewelry made from the dials of old watches may pose a danger to unsuspecting wearers: Many of the old watches used radium to make them glow in the dark, and the radioactivity can cause cancer, health officials say. `` We're finding more and more of this stuff,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON>, supervisor at the <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION> regional office of the <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radiation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION>. `` People suddenly think it's cool to have necklaces, earrings, bola tie clasps and other things made with old watches.'' But the radium on some old watch dials can cause cancer, either on the skin or internally if the substance is inadvertently inhaled or swallowed. `` Like calcium, radium powder seeks the bone,'' he said. `` Radium jewelry definitely poses an increased risk of cancer,'' <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> said. Radium was used in watches to make the hands and numbers glow, he said. Watch makers have since developed other ways to cause fluorescence. When the watches were intact, with glass covering the dial, they were relatively harmless because the glass acted as a shield. But the risk has increased since the watches have been dismantled to make jewelry, and the risk is even greater to jewelers and other people who work with the timepieces than it is to buyers, he said. Three workshops in the <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> area that were found to be handling the watches all registered some radioactive contamination, he said. Workers were getting the radium on their fingers and clothes, <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> said. `` We found several places in the work areas that were hot'' with contamination, he said. `` We're sure there are other places out there,'' he said. The work is illegal as well as hazardous, <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> said. People who handle radioactive materials must have a state license and to get one, an applicant must take stringent precautions against contamination. The radiation control bureau did not issue citations but told companies to remedy the contamination, <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> said. Officials at the <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> regional office in <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION> offered free testing of jewelry for radiation and free disposal of contaminated pieces, <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880214-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-14-88 1137EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Britain-NuclearSub     02-14 0265</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Britain-Nuclear Sub,0271</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: Nuclear Submarine Was Close To Disaster</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A nuclear accident was averted with minutes to spare aboard a <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> submarine in <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> last month, the Observer newspaper reported Sunday. The <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> denied there had been a crisis. No public announcement had been made earlier about the incident. On Sunday, a ministry spokesman who would n't be identified said: `` There was no emergency. There was no possibility of anybody, crew or general public, being subjected to any radiation problems. There was a minor electrical malfunction but no radioactive material was released.'' The spokesman said the weekly was incorrect in claiming a nuclear accident was averted by minutes. The Observer said that, on Jan. 26, at the nuclear submarine base at Faslane near <LOCATION> Glasgow </LOCATION>, a fault developed in the primary cooling system of the nuclear reactor power plant on HMS Resolution, the oldest of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s four operational nuclear submarines, commissioned in 1967. The fault led to heat building up in the reactor's core, threatening a meltdown, and potential disaster was only averted when two of the crew ran to start up a diesel generator to provide alternative power for the cooler, the report said. It said there was only between 1 -LCB- and 7 minutes for the crew to take action and one of the two crewmen had to be scrubbed down for 24 hours afterward because he was exposed to radiation. A meltdown could have released radioactivity contaminating 2,000 square miles with `` devastating consequences'' for the 13,000 people living within a five-mile radius of the base, the report said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880214-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-14-88 1138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-HandleShop     02-14 0649</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Handle Shop,0668</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wooden Handle Company Uses A Blend Of New And Old In Business</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRETT J. BLACKLEDGE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JAY, Okla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Round Springs Road is n't what most people would call a road. It's a path that winds around the bluff and dips twice into Round Springs before it reaches the <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Handle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. That's twice suppliers, buyers, and the occasional visitor have to drive through the shallow creek to get to the company located just outside <PERSON> Tia </PERSON> <PERSON> Juana </PERSON>, a small northeastern <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> community east of Disney There are a few electric saws and automated lathes and sanders at the wooden handle mill to hint that the Industrial Revolution once visited. And a home computer used in the office is proof the Computer Age stopped by. Of course, making wooden handles for tools and farm implements is a business that has n't changed much since <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Willhite </PERSON> started the company in 1934. The only difference now is how fast a handle can be made with the help of machines, he said. <PERSON> Willhite </PERSON> made some of the electric equipment used in the mill and other machinery was bought through the years as the company expanded. `` This is just a baby company compared to some of the others,'' <PERSON> Willhite </PERSON> said. But co-owner <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, who bought the company from the <PERSON> Willhite </PERSON>'s in 1981, is proud of this mill, the only company of its kind in <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>. `` We do n't try to compete with the others. We just make our product and do what we can,'' <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> said. The 90-year-old <PERSON> Willhite </PERSON> has been retired since 1961. He turned the business over to his two oldest sons, who ran it for more than 20 years before selling it to <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> and <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>. The two had 20 years with the company between them when they took it over. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> said business is fair at the mill, with 15 employees working on the three-acre operation producing an average of 5,000 handles a day that range from a 10-inch machinist handle to a 60-inch pitch fork handle. But business is n't as good as it was in 1975 when <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> joined a 35-man crew that produced as much as 10,000 handles a day. He blames that on a depressed state economy that has forced most businesses to cut back. The mill now operates on a temporary three-day work week in the slow winter season, but it wo n't be long before business picks back up and the company is flooded with orders, <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> said. `` Right now we're trying to stockpile our supply so we can meet the demand in the spring when it comes,'' he said. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> said the company sells to lumber yards, hardware stores and other handle companies. State prisons also buy from the mill for their farming projects. <PERSON> Willhite </PERSON> said he thinks the mill has manufactured and sold enough handles over the years to `` make a rick 8-foot high from here to <LOCATION> Tulsa </LOCATION>,'' a stretch of some 60 miles. <PERSON> Willhite </PERSON> started the company in 1934 `` with a shave horse and a knife,'' making about a dozen handles a day. In 1942, they moved west to the remote wooded area it's nestled in now. `` We could n't get any good white hickory out of <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>,'' he said. These days, the <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Handle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> gets an ample supply of hickory, ash, and red and white oak from <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, and some from <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Willhite </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Handle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> really still is in the <PERSON> Willhite </PERSON> family because he's married to <PERSON> Willhite </PERSON>'s granddaughter and calls him grandpa. And many of the employees are related or have the <PERSON> Willhite </PERSON> name, he said. `` You're the one who started this thing,'' <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> told <PERSON> Willhite </PERSON>. `` Sometimes we've got to get him in here to straighten things out.'' `` I may have started it, but I ca n't take all the credit,'' <PERSON> Willhite </PERSON> said. `` I'm not the one who finished it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880214-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-14-88 1139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Vietnam-Tet     02-14 0255</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Vietnam-Tet,0262</SECOND>
<HEAD>Authorities Observe 20th Anniversary of Tet Offensive</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s communist leaders observed a minute of silence at a ceremony in the former <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> capital of <LOCATION> Saigon </LOCATION> to mark the 20th anniversary of the Tet Offensive, a report seen Sunday said. <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Nguyen </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Linh </PERSON> and Prime Minister <PERSON> Pham </PERSON> <PERSON> Hung </PERSON> attended the ceremony Friday in <LOCATION> Ho </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Minh </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, which <LOCATION> Saigon </LOCATION> was renamed after the 1975 communist victory, the official <ORGANIZATION> Vietnam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said. It said <PERSON> Vo </PERSON> <PERSON> Tran </PERSON> <PERSON> Chi </PERSON>, the secretary of the city's party committee, told participants that the 1968 offensive against <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and South Vietnamese forces `` had created the necessary prerequisites for the entire party, army and people to advance in the following years to total victory.'' `` The participants observed a minute of silence in memory of those compatriots and combatants who had fought heroically and laid down their lives in the fierce battles 20 years ago,'' the report said. An exhibition of photographs and relics of the offensive has been opened to mark the anniversary, the report added. The communists took enormous casualties in launching the Tet, or lunar new year, offensive beginning on Jan. 30, 1968, striking at more than 100 cities and towns across <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and South Vietnamese forces turned them back, but the offensive convinced some Americans that the war was unwinnable and fueled the antiwar movement. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military withdrew in 1973. The North Vietnamese won the war with a lightning invasion of the south in April 1975.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880214-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-14-88 1146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-SocialSecurity     02-14 0873</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Social Security,860</SECOND>
<HEAD>Debate Over Social Security Reform Remains Major Issue in Campaign</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CONNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> primary could be the last hurrah for several presidential candidates who have suggested radical changes in Social Security ranging from letting young workers opt out of the system to taxing all of affluent retirees' benefits But even if the candidates who stumped for those ideas are gone, Social Security will remain a hot issue in this presidential race, just as it was in 1984 and in the last three congressional elections. The likelihood is that it will also be a provocative topic in 1992 and every four years after that for the foreseeable future. Too many Americans have too much at stake in Social Security for it to be otherwise. `` This issue may be with us for the rest of our lives,'' said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Maslin </PERSON>, pollster for <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> candidate <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>. In the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> caucuses, the candidates most closely associated with calls for changes in Social Security, Republican <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> du </PERSON> <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> and Democrat <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON>, took a shellacking. Republican <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, who like du Pont favors privatizing some of Social Security, finished a strong second, but it was his stand on moral issues, not pensions, that galvanized his <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> supporters. <PERSON> Du </PERSON> <PERSON> Pont </PERSON>, who contends the system will crash in the next century under the weight of the retired baby boomers unless they are allowed to save their own retirement funds, finished a distant fifth. Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, the Republicans' most vigorous defender of the status quo in Social Security, was fourth, but hoping to move up in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> with his unbridled attacks on Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> and Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for supporting a freeze on Social Security in 1985. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, on the other hand, is telling voters everywhere he goes about his role on the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reform </ORGANIZATION> in 1983, when the <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> senator helped hammer out a last-minute compromise that put Social Security back in the black. `` You do n't have to worry about it being broke. You do n't have to worry about getting your checks. And there I made a difference,'' says <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, who never fails to add that <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> voted against the Social Security rescue plan. The <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> congressman says he did so because of its increase in payroll taxes. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> also argued that it was the improved economy and reduced unemployment that revived Social Security's fortunes. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s hard-hitting ad campaign against <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Social Security has rekindled memories of the way <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Pepper </PERSON> hammered <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and other Republicans for backing deep Social Security cuts in 1981. <PERSON> Du </PERSON> <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> has accused <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> of repeatedly misrepresenting his plan to allow workers to set up tax-free savings accounts if they relinquish future Social Security benefit rights. <PERSON> Du </PERSON> <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> says <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s attacks `` remind me of the demagoguery practices by the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in the 1982 elections.'' Some Republicans, including <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, have said it was the Democrats' pounding on senior citizens' fear of Social Security cuts or freezes that cost the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> control of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in 1986. On the Democrats' side, <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON> has called for `` a universal needs test to discipline government programs,'' including Social Security, and suggested making wealthier retirees pay income tax on all their benefits instead of half. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> also has suggested taxing 85 percent of the benefits. The other Democrats generally have been vowing to safeguard Social Security and its <ORGANIZATION> COLA </ORGANIZATION>'s. `` We're going to keep it away from the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> budget knives forever,'' promises <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>. Social Security's trust funds, which started 1988 with $ 67 billion, are expected to swell to $ 104 billion by the start of 1989 and to top $ 400 billion by 1994 and $ 1 trillion before the end of the decade. Ultimately, Social Security's trust fund is expected to peak at $ 12 trillion _ $ 2.5 trillion in today's dollars _ around 2020, then be drawn down to nothing by 2050 to help pay the baby boomers' retirement <PERSON> Du </PERSON> <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> have argued that even before the trust funds are depleted, there will be nothing in there but government IOU's. To pay off those IOU's _ actually, interest-bearing <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> bonds _ du <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> says, `` we face a big tax increase.'' When du <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> asked 80 people at a debate in <LOCATION> Manchester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.H. </LOCATION>, how many thought Social Security would be there for them at 65, three people raised their hands. More scientific polls have shown young workers remain dubious about their personal prospects for Social Security. But that sentiment has not translated into support for politicians such as du Pont and <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON> who suggest overhauling or even tinkering with Social Security. <PERSON> Maslin </PERSON>, the <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> pollster, said, `` The elites have attempted to move the debate in a direction the voters do n't want to move yet.'' Young voters do n't expect to get Social Security themselves, <PERSON> Maslin </PERSON> said, but they do expect it to be there for their parents. `` For all of the provocation, the voters are still on the side of protection,'' said <PERSON> Maslin </PERSON>. `` They understand that if the government does not provide those benefits, they are going to have to pay for their parents' retirement or health problems.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880214-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-14-88 1144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a AM-BRF--NoParties     02-14 0143</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--No Parties,0145</SECOND>
<HEAD>URI Frats Drop Thursday Night Parties</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Retransmits a0737 to fix cycle designator</NOTE>
<DATELINE>SOUTH KINGSTOWN, R.I. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rhode </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION>'s traditional Thursday night fraternity parties have succumbed to the complaints of professors who teach Friday morning classes The <ORGANIZATION> Interfraternity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> voted last week to stop holding the beer blasts after professors complained that too many students were sleeping in class or skipping it entirely the next day. `` We feel that the fraternity system has a commitment to education, and Thursday night parties seemed to hinder us in attaining that goal,'' said <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Andreozzi </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Phi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gamma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION>, president of the council. In addition, Thursday night parties dated from a time when most URI students were <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> residents who headed home on Friday, but more students these days are likely to live on campus, <PERSON> Andreozzi </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880214-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-14-88 1148EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Panama-Economy     02-14 0703</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama-Economy,0720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Panama's Fiscal Problems Grow</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By REID G. MILLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, skating on the edge of a fiscal disaster, was awaiting word from private bankers this week on whether they will accept a bailout scheme that could keep the country out of default. <PERSON> Ricaurte </PERSON> <PERSON> Vasquez </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s planning minister, met in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> late last week with a committee representing 150 commercial bank creditors in a new effort to keep the country afloat by delaying loan interest payments. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> owes the private banks $ 200 million in interest this year, with the bulk of it scheduled to come due in mid-March. But the country's dollar reserves are virtually depleted and it is unlikely it can meet its commitments. <PERSON> Vasquez </PERSON> first met with the creditor committee in December and asked that $ 100 million of the interest due this year be added to the principal for future payment. The bankers were said to have shown little interest in that plan. It was not known if <PERSON> Vasquez </PERSON> offered the bankers a new bailout plan last week, but he said recently that his government might have to dismiss as many as 15,000 public employees next month to reduce its cash flow. One out of every four Panamanian workers is employed by the government, many owing their jobs to loyalty to the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, which has close ties to the country's de facto leader, Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. `` Much of what little popularity <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> still retains comes from the public sector,'' said a <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> diplomat. `` If the government is forced to make layoffs in that sector, it obviously wo n't help <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s image.'' <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> has been under pressure to resign since last summer from a broad but loose coalition known as the National Civic Crusade. It counts more than 200 civic, business, professional, labor and other groups as members. The opposition's charges of corruption against <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> were given added weight earlier this month when he was indicted by federal grand juries in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, on charges of drug smuggling, money laundering and racketeering. The general, who dominates the counry's civilian government as head of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>, sent his army into the streets last year to quell demonstrations by the Civic Crusade, and the opposition has increasingly turned to what one official called `` economic warfare.'' The tactics, which have added to the government's fiscal woes, include removal of deposits from state banks and the avoidance or late payment of utility fees and taxes. The Civic Crusade also has called several nationwide strikes, but none has been particularly successful. `` The Crusade's activities are an annoyance, I'm sure,'' said the diplomat, speaking on condition of anonymity. `` But that's a really small part of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s problem.'' The problem, which <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> inherited, comes from a huge public debt rolled up by a predecessor, Gen. <PERSON> Omar </PERSON> <PERSON> Torrijos </PERSON>, who came to power in a 1968 coup and began an ambitious program of building schools, health clinics, roads and other public facilities. The <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> put <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s total foreign debt at $ 4.8 billion at the end of 1986, the latest year for which figures are available. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says the government declared itself in `` informal, indefinite default'' to all governmental lenders last year, meaning it made no interest or principal payments. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> halted all aid to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s government last year, and the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monetary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION> also cut off lending programs pending compliance by <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> with an <ORGANIZATION> IMF </ORGANIZATION> demand for a restructuring of its social security programs. Diplomats and private economists say the government has been loathe to make the reforms for fear of losing further popular support, particularly among the lower and middle classes who benefit most from the programs. The government's fiscal crisis appears to have had little effect on the private economy, particularly among the more than 120 foreign banks that maintain offices here and make <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> one of the Western Hemisphere's largest banking centers. `` The banking sector could face problems if the crisis deepens because it is highly dependent on a sense of confidence and stability,'' the diplomat said. `` But so far there have been no failures, nobody has pulled out and deposits remain relatively stable.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880214-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-14-88 1151EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Philippines     02-14 0392</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines,0405</SECOND>
<HEAD>Philippines Prepares To Conclude Violent, Month-Long Elections</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The military said Sunday it sent 4,000 troops to protect voters in the southern island province of <LOCATION> Sulu </LOCATION>, the last area to vote in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>' violence-marred regional elections. The island's 214,000 voters are to choose three governors, 18 mayors and 126 members of town councils Monday in the final stage of balloting that began four weeks ago. About 50 Moslem bandits Friday attacked the southern island town of <LOCATION> Maimbun </LOCATION>, about 600 miles south of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>, said Col. <PERSON> Romeo </PERSON> <PERSON> Abendan </PERSON>, head of the Philippine Constabulary of <LOCATION> Sulu </LOCATION>. He said four people were killed, three of them members of the Moslem rebel <ORGANIZATION> Moro </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>. On Saturday, bandits attacked <LOCATION> Kulasi </LOCATION> village just outside <LOCATION> Maimbung </LOCATION>, but no casualties were reported, he said. In nearby Luuk, rival political groups traded fire with automatic weapons, but there were no reported fatalities, he said. Col. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Elias </PERSON> said 4,000 marine and army troops have joined constabulary and special forces to prevent violence during voting in the largely Moslem province and Moro stronghold. `` We expect some disturbance after the voting, which is normal, especially when trends begin to show,'' <PERSON> Elias </PERSON> told reporters. Most Filipinos voted Jan. 18 in an election that President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> said restored full democracy nearly two years after the ouster of President <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>. But voting was postponed in 11 of the 73 provinces because of fears of violence from communist rebels and regional warlords. In <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramos </PERSON> said Saturday that his department was studying proposals to assist the military against the 24,000-member communist <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Ramos </PERSON> did not specify what measures were under review, but he previously has called for restoring the death penalty for rebels. <PERSON> Ramos </PERSON> also has proposed an unspecified `` package of legal weapons'' to enable the military to crush the 19-year insurgency. Such calls have led to speculation that the government was considering a limited state of emergency in some provinces. Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> told reporters Friday she would await recommendations from <PERSON> Ramos </PERSON> before deciding whether to impose emergency measures. Human rights groups have denounced such proposals. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> imposed martial law from 1972 to 1981 and said it was to prevent a communist takeover. The move helped fuel opposition to the administration that culminated in the February 1986 uprising that toppled <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880214-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-14-88 1154EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-PresidentialRecession Bjt   02-14 0848</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Presidential Recession, Bjt,830</SECOND>
<HEAD>Next President May Lack Recession-Fighting Tools</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Economics Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
