<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880216-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-88 0046EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SchoolArsonist 2ndLd-Writethru a0703 02-16 0716</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-School Arsonist, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0703,0732</SECOND>
<HEAD>Someone Is Burning Omak's Churches and Schools</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Inserts 1 graf after 7th graf pvs, `One of...', with comment
from police chief on investigation, picking up 8th graf pvs,
`Firefighters on...'.
^By JAMES L. ENG</NOTE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OMAK, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An arsonist who burned the town's elementary school and damaged a church that opened its doors to students may have set a fire Monday that destroyed another church and its classrooms, authorities said. Omak, a central <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> town of 4,000 that boasts <LOCATION> Okanogan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>'s only stoplight, has been terrorized by the arson spree. `` It's affected everyone in town. People are very, very grim,'' said <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>, managing editor of the weekly Omak Chronicle. `` They were somber as they drove by it going to work this morning. It was still burning.'' The <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Omak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> was heavily damaged in a January fire, its second in two months. In the past two weeks, two churches and a church parsonage have been set afire. `` They're a kook ... someone who is unbalanced,'' said <PERSON> Vic </PERSON> <PERSON> Power </PERSON>, superintendent of Omak's school district. School officials have checked through their records for any former employee or student who has a grudge but have turned up nothing, he said. `` One of the interesting things in Omak is we have n't had any particular problems with people, have n't had anyone out there we could identify who had been on our case for any particular reason,'' <PERSON> Power </PERSON> said. Police Chief <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Sirois </PERSON> said police are looking at two or three `` persons of interest'' at this point. Police have interviewed about a dozen people so far, he said. He declined to say why the `` persons of interest'' might have wanted to harm the schools or churches. Firefighters on Monday extinguished the latest fire, which destroyed the $ 1.5 million Omak Presbyterian Church. The church and the <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Methodist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> had served as temporary classrooms after the fire at the elementary school, which served students in kindergarten though second grade. Last week, the Methodist church sustained about $ 200,000 in damage. A fire set there Saturday and at the parsonage next door on Sunday caused an additional $ 30,000 in damage, said <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Cramer </PERSON>, assistant chief of the eight-person Omak police force. `` It's got everybody on the edge,'' said pastor <PERSON> Elbert </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Harlow </PERSON>, who lives across the street from his Presbyterian Church. `` They're nervous ... waiting to see what's going to happen next.'' Church officials met Sunday night and made sure all doors and windows were locked, <PERSON> Harlow </PERSON> said. A security guard woke him Monday with news of the fire. The blzae apparently was set by someone who broke into the basement through a window hidden by two evergreen trees beside the three-story, red-brick church, Omak Fire Chief Cal Bowling said. But Bowling said he'd rather not discuss the investigation with reporters. `` Whoever set these fires is going to read your report, and I'd just hate to let him know what this has done to the community,'' Bowling said The latest fire was too hot Monday for the fire marshal to determine what caused it, <PERSON> Cramer </PERSON> said. `` We have a strong feeling but we ca n't draw any conclusions yet,'' he said. Authorities hope to determine the cause by Tuesday. But there was no doubt that an arsonist had set the earlier fires, <PERSON> Cramer </PERSON> said. The fires are beginning to take a psychological toll on residents and on the 1,800 students, including 450 from North Omak Elementary, <PERSON> Cramer </PERSON> said. `` It's having a bad effect on everybody. When the first fire hit the school it devastated the kids. It was tough for them to move. Now they're going to have to again,'' he said. Electricians and plumbers helped set up temporary buildings as classrooms, said <PERSON> Cramer </PERSON>, who added that nighttime patrols have been expanded with the help of the Okanogan Sheriff's Department. `` It only seems to happen while Omak sleeps,'' <PERSON> Cramer </PERSON> said. `` In a way that's good, because the buildings are empty and, so far, no one has been hurt.'' The Rev. <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Lund </PERSON>, pastor of <ORGANIZATION> Foursquare </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gospel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, which also housed <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> students, said he does n't `` want to guess what the arsonist is thinking. `` I think everyone's concerned about saying anything,'' he said. `` You do n't want to motivate the person.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880216-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-88 2337EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-NH-Hart     02-16 0345</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-NH-Hart,330</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hart: ``Today's Defeat Can Become Tomorrow's Victory''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EVA PARZIALE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CONCORD, N.H. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, who was catapulted to national prominence in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> in 1984, finished way behind his five <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> rivals Tuesday but vowed to stay the course, saying: `` Today's defeat can become tomorrow's victory.'' `` We're going to take this fight all the way across this nation _ into the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>, into the industrial <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> and then we're going to head West, where I live,'' <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> told a roomful of supporters. In nearly complete returns, the former <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> senator had 4 percent in the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> primary. He put the best face on it. His showing, he said, was `` 500 percent better than <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>,'' where he won barely 1 percent of the vote in last week's caucuses. Four years ago, <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> stunned the political establishment by upsetting front-runner <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> in the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> primary, gaining status as a credible candidate. He said he never expected to do that well again this year. `` We have just begun. We are committed,'' said <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, who has labeled himself a maverick, offering fresh thinking. Earlier, <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> said his faltering campaign had enough money to last until delegate-rich Super Tuesday on March 8. `` I've always mentally prepared for a long-term gain, not a break-through early on,'' <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> said. Campaign manager <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> said the candidate had $ 400,000 in his campaign treasury _ enough, she said for three weeks of campaigning prior to the 20 Super Tuesday states. `` I do n't have to do what other candidates have to do,'' <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> said during a campaign stop earlier in the day in <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>. `` Other candidates have to make a certain showing to get money and get support. We have support in 50 states,'' and money in the bank. <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> dropped out of the race last May after questions surfaced about his relationship with model <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Rice </PERSON>. He returned to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> to re-enter the race in December, soared for a time in the polls, then slumped to the back of the pack.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880216-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-88 2337EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-France-Hostages     02-16 0415</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-France-Hostages,0425</SECOND>
<HEAD>France Commemorates 1,000 Days of Captivity For Journalist</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELAINE GANLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Politicians, journalists and schoolchildren commemorated on Tuesday journalist <PERSON> Jean-Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Kauffmann </PERSON>'s 1,000 th day as a hostage in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> But both French and Iranian officials suggested there was no end in sight to the drama. `` It is important that the captors know that all of <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> is united,'' <PERSON> Kauffmann </PERSON>'s wife <PERSON> Joelle </PERSON> said at a gathering of public figures and sympathizers outside a barge on the <LOCATION> Seine </LOCATION>, where the Association of Friends of <PERSON> Jean-Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Kauffmann </PERSON> is headquartered. Twenty-seven runners, ending a 1,000-kilometer trek from <LOCATION> Brittany </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> northwest </LOCATION> <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, arrived Tuesday morning at the barge carrying a large chain to symbolize <PERSON> Kauffmann </PERSON>'s captivity. The <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>, the Prague-based <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journalists </ORGANIZATION> and the Journalists' Committee for the <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> French </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hostages </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> all issued statements appealing for the freedom of <PERSON> Kauffmann </PERSON> and other captives. `` We would like even more to be close to them, to tell them to hold on, that nothing will be neglected and nothing is,'' President <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> said on television. <PERSON> Kauffmann </PERSON>, 43, a reporter for the newsweekly Evenement <PERSON> du </PERSON> <PERSON> Jeudi </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Seurat </PERSON>, 39, were taken hostage as they drove from the <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> airport following <PERSON> Kauffmann </PERSON>'s arrival. On March 5, 1986, the <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jihad </ORGANIZATION> group claimed <PERSON> Seurat </PERSON> had been killed. Two other French hostages, diplomats <PERSON> Marcel </PERSON> <PERSON> Carton </PERSON>, 64, and <PERSON> Marcel </PERSON> <PERSON> Fontaine </PERSON>, 45, kidnapped March 22, 1985, have passed their 1,000 th days as captives <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, chief <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> correspondent for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, is the longest held of the 24 foreign hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. He was captured March 16, 1985. In a related development in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION> Director General <PERSON> Federico </PERSON> <PERSON> Mayor </PERSON> on Tuesday told representatives of Western journalists that he will take an active role on behalf of three reporters held hostage in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, one of those present at the meeting said. The press group representatives met with the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> official to seek his intervention on behalf of <LOCATION> Kauffmann </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> and British television cameraman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>. <PERSON> Mia </PERSON> <PERSON> Doornaert </PERSON>, president of the Brussels-based <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journalists </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Mayor </PERSON> promised to hold meetings with the governments concerned _ those whose citizens are hostages and those with influence in the area. The names of specific countries were not mentioned, according to participants, but it was common knowledge that <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> exercises some influence over the Shiite Moslem groups holding foreign hostages. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> is a member of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Educational </ORGANIZATION>, Scientific and Cultural Organization.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880216-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-88 2345EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-UN-Journalists     02-16 0184</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-UN-Journalists,0190</SECOND>
<HEAD>UN Commission Told Of Harassment Of Journalists</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GENEVA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Journalists have received widespread persecution and harassment, executives of three leading international organizations defending press freedom told the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday. The reports marked the first concerted move to have examination of such abuses placed before the 43-nation panel. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Galliner </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, cited a survey listing 25 journalists killed in 1987, 10 kidnapped or disappeared, and 675 arrested, expelled or otherwise harassed. He said last year alone the institute sent 63 protests to 31 countries. The president of the <ORGANIZATION> Inter-American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Ignacio </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> said freedom of the press was a basic human right and that the commission's support in defending it is essential. `` It is our hope that you would keep defense of freedom of expression on your permanent agenda,'' <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Galliner </PERSON> said the situation in countries such as <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and some other African countries continued to be of special concern. Also represented was the Paris-based <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publishers </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880216-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-88 2346EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Bush 1st-LdWritethru a0920 02-16 0406</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush, 1st-Ld Writethru, a0920,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Victorious Bush Vows to `Rise Again' in South'</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Subs lead to CORRECT dateline</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE ESPER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANCHESTER, N.H. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A victorious <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, flushed with a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> primary win, vowed Tuesday night to `` rise again'' when the presidential campaign moves South. Frequently interrupted by chants of `` We want <PERSON> George </PERSON>,'' and `` We're Number One,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spoke of polls that had him slightly behind <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Minority Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> in the Republican presidential race. `` Tonight, I feel I have a lot in common with <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Twain </PERSON>,'' he said. `` Reports of my death were greatly exaggerated.'' With 94 percent of the precincts reporting, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had 38 percent to 29 percent for <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>. Others trailed far behind. `` And now I'm going home to change the laundry and on to the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>, where we're going to rise again,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told cheering supporters. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> thanked the voters of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> and in a personal note said, `` I'll never forget you.'' `` You have n't chosen a man,'' he said, his wife, <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON>, by his side. `` You've chosen a course, to expand our prosperity, to see that it touches every hamlet, every home ... You've chosen to back a strong <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, an <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> strong enough to bring peace to the entire world.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> planned to spend Wednesday in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and then campaign on Thursday in <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, two Super Tuesday states. Once the commanding front-runner in polls in the first primary state, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> saw himself fall into a virtual dead-heat with <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> after <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s victory in the Feb. 8 <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> caucuses. Beaten 2-1 by <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also trailed former television evangelist <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> in the caucuses. The post-Iowa <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> sought more contact with voters, making improptu stops at shopping malls, sitting at the wheel of a big truck and a forklift, and declaring that he had strong feelings even if he does n't always show them. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s national campaign manager, <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>, said the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> win would wipe out the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> loss. `` <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> is the big enchilada in American politics,'' <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> said. He attributed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s win to the vice president `` talking about issues'' while <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> `` was talking about all this momentum jazz.'' As he prepared to retire for the night, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told supporters, `` I leave you with four little words that will be on my mind when I take the oath 11 months from now: Thank you, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880216-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-88 2359EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-UNESCO-Journalists     02-16 0453</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-UNESCO-Journalists,0466</SECOND>
<HEAD>Groups Say UNESCO Will Act on Behalf of Hostages</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-French Hostage</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY DUNPHY</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Associated Press Writer = <LOCATION> PARIS </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION> Director General <PERSON> Federico </PERSON> <PERSON> Mayor </PERSON> on Tuesday told representatives of Western journalists that he will take an active role on behalf of three reporters held hostage in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, a press representative said The group met with Mayor to seek his intervention on behalf of <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, chief <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> correspondent for the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, British television cameraman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> and French magazine writer <PERSON> Jean-Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Kauffmann </PERSON>, who marked his 1,000 th day in captivity Tuesday <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, missing since March 16, 1985, is the longest held of the 22 foreign hostages in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> has been missing since April 17, 1986. The group met with Mayor for a 40-minute closed-door session. The journalists were led by <PERSON> Mia </PERSON> <PERSON> Doornaert </PERSON>, diplomatic correspondent of the Dutch newspaper <ORGANIZATION> De </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Standaard </ORGANIZATION> and president of the Brussels-based <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journalists </ORGANIZATION>. It included <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Conroy </PERSON>, general secretary of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journalists </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Gerard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gatinot </PERSON>, a Frenchman representing the the Prague-based <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journalists </ORGANIZATION> Ms. <PERSON> Doornaert </PERSON> said <PERSON> Mayor </PERSON> promised to hold meetings with the governments concerned _ those whose citizens are hostages and those with influence in the area. The names of specific countries were not mentioned, according to participants, but it was common knowledge that <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> exercises some influence over the Shiite Moslem groups holding foreign hostages. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> is a member of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Educational </ORGANIZATION>, Scientific and Cultural Organization. <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION> has a special human rights group that takes up imprisonment cases with member governments. It also has sponsored meetings in the past involving the two journalists' federations on professional issues. Two officials of the <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Dale </PERSON>, the president, and <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Perlik </PERSON>, immediate past president, were unable to attend because of visa problems. In prepared remarks for the meeting, <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> said: `` The Newspaper Guild ... takes this occasion to reaffirm its commitment to the freedom of <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> and the other journalists held hostage in the <LOCATION> Middle-East </LOCATION> as well as the release of <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> journalists currently imprisoned in Israeli occupied territories. `` We are approaching the third anniversary of <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>'s imprisonement He and the other journalists who share his fate are prisoners without guilt, sometimes to terms that now exceed those meted out to many violent criminals. `` The conscience of the world can not permit this to continue. It cries out for the immediate freeing of <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jean-Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Kauffmann </PERSON>, not as part of any quid pro quo arrangement between governments but out of elementary consideration of human justice and decency. In the same spirit, we urge the release of all Arab journalists held in Israeli prisons,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880216-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-88 0153EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ConstitutionCelebrations Bjt   02-16 0820</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Constitution Celebrations, Bjt,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iran-Contra, Bork Hearings Called Constitution in Action</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PHYLLIS MESSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The official celebration of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Constitution's 200th birthday was largely ceremonial, but historians say the true tribute actually came during the congressional hearings into the Iran-Contra affair and the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> nomination of <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Bork </PERSON>. The Commission on the Bicentennial of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Constitution, the official sponsor of the tribute to the 200-year-old document, got some credit from historians for reaching out to the people with such things as its pocket-size copies of the Constitution. But others faulted it for paying too little attention to serious scholarship. Most of the historians interviewed in recent weeks about the bicentennial celebration agreed that Americans learned more about the Constitution and its workings through watching the Iran-Contra hearings on television and reading about the debate on the <PERSON> Bork </PERSON> nomination than through any planned activity. `` My sense is that the commission's work was not particularly substantive,'' said <PERSON> Laurence </PERSON> <PERSON> Tribe </PERSON>, a constitutional law professor at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, who testified to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> against the <PERSON> Bork </PERSON> nomination. `` Nonetheless, what the country experienced proved to be extraordinarily profound because of the Iran-Contra hearings and the <PERSON> Bork </PERSON> hearings. `` You ca n't help observing how much the public became involved in discussions on the meaning of the Constitution, the role the courts should play, the fundamental relationships between the executive and legislative branches,'' <PERSON> Tribe </PERSON> said. `` Those topics usually are discussed just by lawyers.'' <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, professor of law and history at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION>, agreed that the <ORGANIZATION> Bicentennial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>'s efforts `` were largely ceremonial.'' `` The ones that have come to my attention basically are on a kind of superficial, ceremonial level,'' he said. In comparison, he said, `` the <PERSON> Bork </PERSON> hearings were one of the major contributors _ unconsciously so _ to the constitutional debate.'' <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Woodford </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a political science professor at <ORGANIZATION> Johns </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hopkins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, recalled that when he went to parties last summer and fall, all that people wanted to talk about were the Bork or Iran-Contra hearings. `` This was the Constitution in action,'' <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said. `` Both hearings really drove home the fact that the Constitution is not just a document, or a fossil, but something that is enduring.'' Former Chief Justice <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Burger </PERSON>, who gave up his place on the court to devote full time to heading the <ORGANIZATION> Bicentennial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, said he believes its work did have an impact on Americans' understanding of the document that guarantees their freedoms `` My guess will be there's a higher awareness, a higher consciousness, not necessarily of the details,'' he said in a recent interview in his office. `` If a free people do n't look from time to time at their liberties and how they got them, they take the risk of losing them. `` Although we succeeded in creating greater awareness, that does n't mean detailed knowledge necessarily,'' <PERSON> Burger </PERSON> added. A coffee table in Burger's office in the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> building was covered with recently published books and pamphlets on the Constitution. On it, too, was a cereal box with a short historical message, copies of placemats from fast-food restaurants with short constitutional quizzes and a bicentennial calendar. <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Harlan </PERSON>, a history professor at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maryland </ORGANIZATION> and president-elect of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Historical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, was one of the historians critical of the commission's work. `` The parades and fireworks have faded into history,'' he said, `` but the commission has failed to give us something that will endure and be of use to future generations.'' <PERSON> Burger </PERSON> countered that the commission's work will lead to a wider audience for scholarly works and noted that other government agencies have financed studies on the Constitution. The commission stated at the start of its work that it wanted to teach Americans more about the Constitution. It cited a survey that found that about half of the public could not identify the purpose of the Constitution or explain what the Bill of Rights is. <PERSON> Burger </PERSON> said no survey of Americans' knowledge of the document has been taken in the wake of last year's tribute, which reached a zenith last Sept. 16 with a party on the Capitol steps in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and with a ceremony in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> the next day. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Steele </PERSON> <PERSON> Commager </PERSON>, a historian at <ORGANIZATION> Amherst </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, said he did not believe it was possible to measure the success of the bicentennial activities. `` What is the criterion for success for a party?'' he asked. `` If you want to know if people learned anything, who knows? Obviously, the lessons of Watergate did n't teach Mr. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> anything about the Constitution.'' <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said the mood of the country for the Constitution's bicentennial was one of introspection `` We were worrying about whether we have dropped the torch, and I think the Iran-Contra hearings and <PERSON> Bork </PERSON> hearings really brought that feeling home. `` This time, we had the Constitution in action,'' <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> added. `` Those hearings brought the Constitution to life.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880216-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-88 0201EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AIDSDebate Bjt   02-16 0781</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS Debate, Bjt,770</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congressional AIDS Debate Resumes</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JILL LAWRENCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> resumes its struggle toward a national AIDS policy this week with two sharply contrasting Californians at the extremes of disputes over issues ranging from discrimination to testing. On one side is Democratic Rep. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, the liberal and influential chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> health subcommittee, whose <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> district is ethnically diverse and big-city tolerant. Across the ideological gulf but geographically next door is Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Calif </LOCATION>., a conservative from straight-laced and suburban <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Their differences will be aired Friday at what <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON> is calling a `` refresher hearing'' on his bill to provide money for voluntary AIDS tests, guarantee confidentiality for those tested, and protect AIDS victims and carriers from discrimination. The hearing follows a series of canceled work sessions last year that <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON> claims were scratched because <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON> did n't have enough votes to win approval of his bill. `` If he ca n't achieve his objective ... of anti-discrimination status for those with the virus, he will not move a bill in the 100th <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON> said. `` We had other things pressing on us,'' <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON> responded when asked why the sessions were canceled. He said he expects to finish work on the AIDS bill within two months. Though he maintained he is `` always open to discussion,'' <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON> indicated he would not compromise on the measure's confidentiality or civil rights provisions and said he detected little support for <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON>'s positions. `` The whole public health world has concluded we need to protect against discrimination,'' <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON> said. `` The only people likely to come in for tests if there is no protection are people at low risk'' of having AIDS. <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON> calls it `` inappropriate and absurd'' to legislate anti-discrimination safeguards because of what he contends is the `` unstable status'' of information about AIDS transmission. While <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON> quotes the prevailing view of virtually all public health authorities that AIDS can not be transmitted by casual contact, <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON> asserts that those authorities are rethinking `` their dogmatic pronouncements that the AIDS virus is not a threat in the workplace.'' <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON> says employers should be free to decide whether to fire an AIDS victim or carrier. `` The civil rights of the uninfected are entitled to just as much protection as the infected,'' <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON> said. He also asserted that protecting AIDS victims from discrimination conflicts with `` the heterosexual ethic.'' Going against the grain of prevailing psychiatric thought, he contended that homosexuals voluntarily choose their sexual preference and said schoolchildren should be taught that `` homosexuality is a perverse lifestyle, it's an unhealthy lifestyle. That's a fact. We should tell that to kids.'' <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON> has introduced a bill requiring AIDS testing of marriage license applicants, hospital patients, people being treated for venereal disease and people convicted of drug or sex crimes. He has also sponsored a bill that requires reporting by name of every individual who has AIDS or tests positive for antibodies to the AIDS virus. <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON> said <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON> and others who promote such reporting requirements `` seem to want these names for some other purpose'' and that suspicion would discourage high-risk individuals from being tested. `` We have a clear danger of hysterical over-reaction where many people might find themselves persecuted for being infected,'' <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON> said. `` We ca n't get sidetracked into an anti-gay crusade when our real job is to stop the spread of this terrible disease.'' <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON> said the biggest concern at this point is not the transmission of AIDS among homosexuals but its spread among intravenous drug users `` and their sexual contacts in the underclass.'' <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON> contended that strong homosexual lobbies are hobbling <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and some state legislatures in their handling of the disease. He said AIDS victims have received kid-glove treatment that flies in the face of traditional ways to halt epidemics. `` If 73 percent of the -LRB- AIDS -RRB- cases were presented by people with gray eyes, a highly disorganized group in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, three years ago we would have witnessed large-scale quarantine of anyone who had the virus,'' he said. <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON> also condemned an educational film created by the Gay Men's Health Crisis in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. He distributed videotaped copies to reporters and said the film uses tax dollars to promote homosexuality. The tape features blunt language, a demonstration of condom use on a cucumber and a scene of two men kissing in a shower. <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON> said he had not seen the tape but added, `` I would n't know how to design a message to the gay community I do n't think Mr. <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON> would know how to design it. ... But we'd better start getting the message across and not pull our punches because we're fearful of talking about sex.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880216-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-88 0203EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     02-16 0835</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,830</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fast-Food Franchises Go Worldwide</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The odds are increasing rapidly that Americans traveling abroad can find a fast-food place that bears a familiar name. `` McDonald's in <LOCATION> Munich </LOCATION>, Pizza Hut in <LOCATION> Fiji </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Taco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION> are just three examples of the trend toward expanding foreign markets for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> restaurant fanchises,'' says an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> report. In 1985, there were 6,122 international franchise units, up 36 percent from 3,943 in 1980. Figures by the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> show that <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> account for almost half, with <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> ranking next. The report was written for the department's <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Review </ORGANIZATION> magazine by two economists, <PERSON> Charlene </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hal </PERSON> <PERSON> Linstrom </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. `` As you might expect, the popularity of the different restaurants varied around the world,'' the report said. `` For example, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> was the largest market for hamburger units, and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> accounted for the greatest share of the chicken market. Austalians and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealanders </LOCATION> enjoyed pizza.'' <ORGANIZATION> McDonalds </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> Fried Chicken, <PERSON> Burger </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> and <PERSON> Wendy </PERSON>'s _ the four largest <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> restaurant chains _ accounted for 31 percent of the world total, franchising 4,626 restaurants internationally by 1986, up from 272 in 1974, the report said. As the largest food service organization in the world with about 9,400 establishments, <ORGANIZATION> McDonald </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> led the international scene with about 2,138 outlets, compared with 370 five years earlier, the report said. <ORGANIZATION> Kentucky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fried </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicken </ORGANIZATION>, a division of <ORGANIZATION> PepsiCo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, operated more than 6,500 units, including 1,854 in 54 foreign countries. Burger King, part of <ORGANIZATION> Pillsbury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foodservice </ORGANIZATION>, operated 4,744 outlets in 1986, including 403 in 24 foreign countries and <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Wendy </PERSON>'s, which grew to the world's fourth-largest restaurant chain in 17 years, operated almost 4,000 outlets, including 231 in 17 foreign countries. Of the four largest franchisers, only <ORGANIZATION> Kentucky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fried </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicken </ORGANIZATION> operated outlets in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> in 1986, and also held sole position in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> countries, the report said. `` Franchise growth overseas will continue in existing markets,'' the report said. `` At the same time, some chains are entering previously untapped areas. <ORGANIZATION> Kentucky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fried </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicken </ORGANIZATION> and Pizza Hut, for instance, recently negotiated with the Chinese and <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> governments to bring fast food to those countries.'' Most franchise restaurant companies probably will keep expanding their menus and services abroad as well as in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, particularly to meet a growing interest in diet and `` light'' foods. `` Strong growth in Mexican and oriental foods may also mean introduction of new menu items,'' the report said. `` Following the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trend, breakfast offerings are also likely to increase in overseas restaurants.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A shot or two of carbon dioxide _ the stuff used in some fire extinguishers _ may be just the thing to help sensitive plants such as raspberries and blueberries survive the stress of heat therapy, says an Agriculture Department plant pathologist. The result one day could be a new assortment of plants for nurseries and home gardeners. Heat is used in special chambers to rid fruit and vegetable plants of viruses. At 100 degrees Fahrenheit, the heat forces the plants to grow faster than the viruses lurking in them, said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Converse </PERSON>, who works for the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Corvallis </LOCATION>, Ore. But that's too hot for blueberries and many raspberries, he said in a recent report by the agency. If carbon dioxide is raised to 1,100 parts per million in the chamber from the 350 parts normally present in the air, the plants are able to withstand the heat. <PERSON> Converse </PERSON> said the process of raising carbon dioxide levels had been used previously by Australian scientists to heat-treat grape plants. He is hopeful that the procedure can be used to eliminate viruses from apples, oranges, potatoes, onions and bulb crops such as iris and lilies.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Poultry processors soon will be allowed more options in repackaging and relabeling federally inspected fowl and poultry products for final distribution to consumer outlets, says the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. As it is right now, poultry products can only be repacked and relabeled at federally inspected plants. `` Warehouses and distribution centers are often more conveniently located than federally inspected plants,'' said <PERSON> Lester </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Crawford </PERSON>, administrator of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inspection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. `` So, allowing certain facilities to repackage and relabel poultry products with inspectors present means savings in time and money and a safe product. We believe the savings in transportation costs could ultimately mean lower prices for consumers.'' The optional operations will also have to be done under the supervision of federal inspectors, he said. The new rule will take effect on March 11. The processors will pay <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> for the inspection at the repackaging operations. <PERSON> Crawford </PERSON> said the optional service has been available to the meat industry but has not been allowed under poultry inspection regulations. Repacking and relabeling allow bulk shipments of federally inspected products to be divided into consumer packages and to have brand names placed on the products.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880216-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-88 0204EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-GayCongressman Bjt   02-16 0616</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gay Congressman, Bjt,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Homosexual Congressman Raises Funds While GOP Looks For A
Challenger</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CALLAHAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rep. <PERSON> Barney </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, who acknowledged last year that he is a homosexual, is busy raising money for his re-election campaign while the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> is still looking for someone to oppose him. At this point, the only <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> publicly talking of running against the liberal <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Democrat is a conservative gadfly who withdrew from the 1986 <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> gubernatorial race after admitting he had lied about his military record. `` I do n't know what the Republicans plan to do about it, but the reading we have -LRB- from polling -RRB- is that voters care about performance in office'' and not personal issues like sexual preference, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> said. `` And that's certainly consistent with the reading I've gotten from people.'' <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Democrats say the homosexual disclosure will have little impact on voters who have sent <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> with increasingly convincing victory margins _ 52 percent, 60 percent, 74 percent and 89 percent. And they note that the disclosure was not news to many constituents. Republicans, however, are talking about how <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> could be defeated in the state's 4th District, which includes Democratic strongholds on the outskirts of <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, upper-class Republican enclaves like <LOCATION> Wellesley </LOCATION>, and mill towns like <LOCATION> Fall </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> near the <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> border. <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Malone </PERSON>, executive director of the state <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION>, said the homosexual issue could be exploited by a Republican challenger, not by attacking <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s sexual preference but by telling voters he is focusing too heavily on `` gay issues'' at the expense of other congressional work. `` I've always thought it's a case of how the congressman votes, and if his sexuality slants his voting in such a way that he no longer represents his district,'' <PERSON> Malone </PERSON> said. `` In many cases he has chosen to pursue issues that have an effect on the gay community to the detriment of issues that affect the typical constituent in his district,'' he added. However, <PERSON> Malone </PERSON> could not immediately provide any examples. And <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s supporters point to his work on several major bills in 1987 to counter that argument. They credit him with playing major roles in passage of a measure requiring that any low-income federal housing demolished under urban renewal be replaced; a bill requiring a special prosecutor be appointed to investigate alleged wrongdoing by administration figures; and legislation prohibiting the government from denying visas based on politics. While Republicans talk about <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s vulnerability, there is no declared candidate with the election nine months away. The only politician publicly considering a challenge to <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> is <PERSON> Royall </PERSON> <PERSON> Switzler </PERSON>, who would carry considerable political baggage into any race. <PERSON> Switzler </PERSON> made a name for himself by taking on leaders of the Democratic-controlled <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> _ often alone _ during his years in the state <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION>. The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> GOP enlisted <PERSON> Switzler </PERSON> in 1986 to run against popular Democratic Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, but he was forced to bow out after admitting he was a sergeant in peacetime <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, not a Green Beret captain in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, 47, is taking nothing for granted. Campaign reports filed with the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> show that his spending and fund-raising in 1987 were more than double his campaign receipts and expenditures during 1985, the last non-election year. The fourth-term congressman raised $ 144,300 during 1987, compared to $ 71,400 in 1985. He spent $ 106,400 last year compared to $ 49,800 in 1985. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> also paid $ 7,000 for an October poll to measure voter reaction to the disclosure of his homosexuality. `` The general finding is that overwhelmingly people in the district will judge me on how I do my job as a member of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and not anything else,'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880216-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-88 0205EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ReaganLibrary Bjt   02-16 0669</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan Library, Bjt,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Library Still in Search of a Home</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SIMI VALLEY, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Planners of the <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> Presidential Library, forced to abandon a site at <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> after widespread protests, are running into skepticism from some city officials about their proposal to build the library near this <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> city. The 100-acre site, donated by the real estate development firm of <PERSON> Blakeley-Swartz </PERSON>, impinges on a greenbelt area that is protected from large-scale development by a decade-old, non-binding agreement among <LOCATION> Simi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Moorpark </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Thousand </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Oaks </LOCATION>. `` We do not want the library project used as means for further land-use concessions on any property within the greenbelt,'' <LOCATION> Moorpark </LOCATION> officials wrote on Jan. 7 to the <ORGANIZATION> Ventura </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supervisors </ORGANIZATION>, which must approve the project. Moorpark Mayor <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Galloway </PERSON> said similar letters were sent by officials of Thousand Oaks and <LOCATION> Simi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Swartz </PERSON>, a partner in the developing firm, said in a telephone interview from <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, `` We have seen the letter and I think we can live within the scope of that.'' But <LOCATION> Moorpark </LOCATION> City Councilman <PERSON> Clint </PERSON> <PERSON> Harper </PERSON>, a mathematics teacher at <ORGANIZATION> Moorpark </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` We are concerned as a council that the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> library may be used as a lever to get additional land development.'' However, he added that he thinks the $ 60 million library could be `` consistent with the greenbelt if that is the only anticipated use.'' <PERSON> Galloway </PERSON> expressed surprise at a report in the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> on Sunday that <PERSON> Blakeley-Swartz </PERSON> plans to build a 300-room hotel and conference center on 540 acres adjacent to the library site. `` We are going to have real concerns about that,'' the <LOCATION> Moorpark </LOCATION> mayor said. <PERSON> Swartz </PERSON> said only about 40 acres of the Blakeley-Swartz property lie within the greenbelt. Nevertheless, previous efforts to develop the property have been rebuffed by local officials who argued such development would affect the integrity of the greenbelt agreement. The strongest concerns have been expressed by <LOCATION> Moorpark </LOCATION>, which officials say would be most affected by development of the property because of its location. `` I think in general people are very supportive of the library,'' said <LOCATION> Simi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON> `` One of the reasons the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> liked the area was that it was so unspoiled, so development would be contradictory to the president's wishes. To a certain extent, that will help maintain it as a greenbelt.'' The greenbelt, covering about 1,200 acres, embraces an area of rolling hills covered with brush, beavertail cactus and wildflowers. The heights command a sweeping view of surrounding valleys, and on a clear day <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s offshore <LOCATION> Channel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> can be seen in the distance. Although surrounded by more development, the site is in itself much like the country around the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION>' ranch, about 80 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Simi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, where the president and first lady <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> are taking a brief vacation. Selection of the site climaxed a search which began after the <ORGANIZATION> Ronald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reagan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Presidential </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> abandoned the Stanford location in the face of opposition from students, faculty and homeowners. Reasons for the opposition ranged from politics to traffic. Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was driven to the new site during a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> vacation in August and approved it. The president gave his approval after flying over, planners said. The foundation has not yet filed a plan with <LOCATION> Ventura </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> officials for development of the site, but has said it hopes to start construction in July. Local officials say they will be concerned if roads and other facilities for the library would support additional development. `` This is the first time that we have had the prospect of quite such a prestigious proposal,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Simi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Valley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> member <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Rock </PERSON>. `` This is n't something that comes along every day. So I'm assuming that the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> foundation indeed is serious `` Now what I do n't know, if they have a fairly intense land-use plan, is whether or not they are going to get the go-ahead from <LOCATION> Ventura </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. That may be discouraging.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880216-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-88 0205EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Robertson-Fears Bjt   02-16 0659</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Robertson-Fears, Bjt,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Robertson Draws Fervent Support, But Also Stirs Deep Fears</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EVANS WITT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DOVER, N.H. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> had just finished a strident anti-communist sermon to the <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> when <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> stood up and told the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> candidate what was on his mind. `` I'm shaking,'' he said. `` I'm sitting here really afraid when you start talk about going to war.'' It was a dramatic moment on the eve of the crucial <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> primary, where <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> hoped for another surprising finish in the wake of his upstart second-place showing in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>. After several minutes of back-and-forth, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> told <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>: `` I do n't know what else to say except that peace will come through strength. ... Maybe would you prefer to live under communism? I do n't know. I'd rather be free.'' The confrontation with the <LOCATION> Portsmouth </LOCATION> merchant highlighted the strong reaction some have to <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s foreign policy positions. It also came as the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> hopeful was embroiled in a controversy about Soviet missiles and <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said during a Sunday night debate that Soviet medium-range missiles are still based on the island, although he backed off the assertion Monday, saying he had no such first-hand knowledge. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> drew criticism from his opponents for the comment, in tones that echoed <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>' fears. `` This is a very serious allegation,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said in an interview on a <LOCATION> Manchester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.H. </LOCATION>, radio station. `` You keep hearing these outrageous charges ... which are designed to scare the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people.'' Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> called it `` a rather rash and unsupportable charge.'' White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said SS-4 and SS-5 missile sites established in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> in 1962 `` were confirmed as having been destroyed in that year.'' At the <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> candidate forum, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> gave his standard speech, with a strong defense of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and strong denunciations of communism as the greatest evil the nation faces. After hearing what <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> had to say, this was <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>' reaction: `` He advocates using weapons and war as a solution to all the problems in the world ... That's is n't a solution _ that's annihilation. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> talked of the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall, calling it an abomination that the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> should have stopped. `` Had I been president when that was done, there would have been <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> tanks on the move to knock that thing down,'' <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said. And that was too much for <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, who runs an office furniture store. `` I'm sitting here really afraid when you start talk about going to war the way you just talked about it, the result of taking tanks to the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall,'' said <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>. `` With all that talk of war, not understanding the threat we face today from nuclear weapons ... We can no longer do it.'' Part of the audience of 250 applauded <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> asked who he supports and <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> GOP Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> nodded and went on to compare the current situation to the challenge posed by <PERSON> Adolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> in the 1930s. `` Had we been resolute in the face of dictatorship that would never have happened. I am for peace with all of my heart,'' <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> broke in: `` There were not nuclear weapons when <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> was there. You need to address the root cause before it comes up to a <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>, not afterward with weapons.'' The former television evangelist was clearly irritated by <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>' questions but pressed on `` You have somebody who is every bit as bad as <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> in charge of many nations of the world,'' <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said. `` Communism is just as bad as the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION>. ... If we want to have peace in our world, it is absolutely essential that we stand up resolutely to communism.'' Several times later during the appearance, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> returned to <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> to address his concerns. At one point, he said: `` This gentleman had all the concerns. Sir, I want to eliminate nuclear weapons from the face of the earth.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880216-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-88 0206EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Robertson-Missiles     02-16 0612</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Robertson-Missiles,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Robertson Backpedals On Cuban Missile Assertion, Saying No One
Really Knows</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DOVER, N.H. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> says he has no first-hand evidence that there are Soviet missiles in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, as he had claimed in a debate over the weekend with his Republican presidential rivals. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> came under fire Monday for the assertion, made Sunday, which fellow <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> candidates termed `` rash'' and `` outrageous.'' The White House emphatically denied the claim and the man identified by the <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> campaign as the candidate's source said the existence of such weapons in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> has not been confirmed. The former television evangelist initially said Monday that he would not `` back off'' his claim. But later in the day, he began revising it until he was saying that he had been asking a question, not making an assertion, when he alleged that <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> has nuclear weapons pointed at the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` I was asking in the debate is this true,'' he said. `` I have no sources other than what I've said, so there was no categorial statement per se.'' In the debate, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> was attacking the intermediate-range missile treaty signed last December by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Soviet Leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> when he made the claim. `` Somehow in all this brilliant negotiations which these gentlemen are so proud of they left that out of the treaty,'' he said. `` And it seems to me nukes pointing at the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> are more vital to our security than nukes pointing to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>.'' Pressed by reporters here, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said he had no first-hand evidence that there are such weapons in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>. `` My contention is there might be missiles in the caves; they may have brought in missiles on some other transport vessel or possibly a submarine. I do n't know the exact sizing of it, but nobody can say for certain that those missiles are n't there,'' he said. Later, interviewed on <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Larry King Live,'' <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said it is possible there are Soviet missiles in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>. `` I do n't think, frankly, there's anybody in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> right now that I'm aware of who can say categorically that there are or they're not there,'' he said. Earlier Monday, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> had told a <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> candidate's forum here that `` the least we can do in this is get those nuclear weapons out of <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>,'' a reiteration of the statements he had made during Sunday's debate in <LOCATION> Goffstown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.H. </LOCATION> `` I'm not going to back off from that. I'd be happy to have somebody prove me wrong,'' he told an interviewer. White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said SS-4 and SS-5 missile sites established in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> in 1962 `` were confirmed as having been destroyed in that year. We also are confident that the missiles were removed from <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> at that time. `` We have had extensive intelligence collection directed at <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> since 1962 and have no evidence that SS-4, SS-5 or other strategic missiles have been deployed there,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. Asked whether he was denying any offensive nuclear weapons are deployed in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said, `` Exactly.'' Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said in an interview Monday that `` I'm confident this -LRB- <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> assertion -RRB- is not true,'' and added: `` You keep hearing these outrageous charges ... which are designed to scare the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people.'' Another GOP presidential candidate, Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, called it `` a rather rash and unsupportable charge.'' Officials with <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s campaign said his contention was based on information supplied by <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>, a staff member of the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> minority on the Democratic-controlled <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Foreign Relations Committee. But <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said Monday in an interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> that `` we do not know whether nuclear weapons are in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> or not.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880216-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-88 0207EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-PuertoRicoGOP     02-16 0316</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Puerto Rico GOP,310</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dole Backers Denounce Puerto Rico GOP Straw Poll As Illegal; Bush
Wins</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN JUAN, Puerto Rico (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Supporters of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> are claiming an overwhelming victory in a Republican straw poll, but <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s backers boycotted the vote and say they'll win when it counts _ on primary election day. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> garnered 731 votes while <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> got 32 in the presidential straw poll, which <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> supporters denounced as illegal. `` This proves that <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> is <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> country,'' said <PERSON> Josito </PERSON> <PERSON> Dapena </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign director for <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> supporters minimized the importance of the poll _ which is not binding _ saying the real test is March 20, when <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> holds its primary. `` We do n't participate in straw polls,'' said <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Devine </PERSON>, a pro-Dole observer at the assembly. There was a bitter dispute when <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committeeman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Edison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Misla </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aldarondo </ORGANIZATION>, a <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> backer, tried to address the gathering to question whether there was a quorum. He was told he had not registered as a delegate and could not speak. <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferre </PERSON>, the local <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> chairman, said the presence of 750 of the 1,500 delegates in the general assembly would constitute a quorum. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> supporters said there were only 682 delegates registered but the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> forces said more than 900 attended. The <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> campaign in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> issued a statement saying <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> backers had `` failed ... in an attempt to convene and illegally poll Puerto Rico Republicans.'' Monday's assembly was originally scheduled to chose the 14 delegates to the Republican convention instead of waiting for March 20. However, the local <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> went to court to prevent the primary from being advanced. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s national campaign manager, <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>, said the <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> results would give the vice president a lift going into the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> primary and also `` send a positive signal to other Hispanic voters throughout the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880216-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-88 0209EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-EconomicVote     02-16 0439</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Economic Vote,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Analysts Say Economic Conditions Could Be Big Factor In NH Primary</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CONNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Last week the political spotlight was on a farm state whose economy has fared poorly during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> years. Now it turns to a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> state that has been booming. Political analysts say economic circumstances may have a bigger impact on the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> primary than any momentum from the Feb. 8 caucuses in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, where Democrat <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> and Republican <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> came in first, with Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> falling back to third place behind <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> on the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> side. `` <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> was a state that voted for change,'' says <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON>, a fellow at the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>. `` The status quo candidates were <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and they both did fairly or very poorly. `` The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> legacy and the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> miracle did n't sell in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON> said. But <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> is `` at the other extreme, with the lowest unemployment rate in the country and a boom economy. The status quo is much more popular.'' <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON> said exit polling in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> by the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> showed, `` the more dissatisfied you were with the way things were going, the more you voted for <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> or <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> on the Republican side _ if you were realy unhappy, you voted for <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> _ and for <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> on the Democratic side.'' <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, a Republican analyst, agreed that <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> was `` a considerable portrait of discontent.'' `` <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s screaming one-fifth of the vote was the only vote that you could really read as support of the president. That's pretty low for an incumbent vice president,'' said <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>. `` On the Democratic side, it's pretty clear that <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> and <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> did better than early expectations. The guy who ran a little bit behind early expectations was Mr. New England Good News, the man with the purring economy whose message is for the yuppies, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, `` what <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has to worry about is falling short of expectations,'' like <PERSON> Muskie </PERSON> in 1972, he added. <PERSON> Stu </PERSON> <PERSON> Eizenstat </PERSON>, a top policy adviser in the <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> administration, predicted that the combined <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hampshire </ORGANIZATION> results may only show the strength of regional candidates _ Midwesterners <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> and <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> in the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Englander </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dukakis </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. If <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, the two Democrats with the strongest Southern ties, emerge as the big winners on Super Tuesday, then the Democrats may be `` left with no one candidate showing a national base and strength.'' `` We'll have sorted out regional candidates with no base anywhere,'' <PERSON> Eizenstat </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880216-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-88 0210EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p BC-NewHampshire-Tables Advisory   02-16 1541</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-New Hampshire-Tables, Advisory,</SECOND>
<HEAD>EDITORS:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> will carry results Tuesday of the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> presidential primary. The results will be provided to the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> by <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, a consortium of television networks and news services. Here is how the AP will report the results: The results of the primary will directly govern the allocation of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>'s delegates to the Republican and Democratic national conventions. The GOP presidential candidates are competing for 23 delegates from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, while the Democratic candidates are vying for the state's 18 delegates in that party. The <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> will summarize the results this way:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Republican state raw vote summary:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>BC-NH-GOP-Pres-Sum,100</HEAD>
<HEAD>02-16-88 XX:XX</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest, unofficial results in the Republican presidential caucuses in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 0 of 298 precincts reporting - 0 percent <ORGANIZATION> Du </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pont </ORGANIZATION>, 0,000 - 0 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Haig </PERSON>, 0,000 - 0 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, 0,000 - 0 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, 0,000 - 0 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, 0,000 - 0 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 0,000 - 0 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Democratic state raw vote summary:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>BC-NH-Dem-Pres-Sum,100</HEAD>
<HEAD>02-16-88 XX:XX</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest, unofficial results in the Democratic presidential caucuses in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 0 of 298 precincts reporting - 0 percent <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, 0,000 - 0 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, 0,000 - 0 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, 0,000 - 0 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, 0,000 - 0 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, 0,000 - 0 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON>, 0,000 - 0 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, 0,000 - 1 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 The AP will report the number of national convention delegates for each candidate this way:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Democratic delegates:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>BC-NH-Dem-Deleg-Sum,100</HEAD>
<HEAD>02-16-88 XX:XX</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the delegates won by each candidate in the Democratic presidential caucuses in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> on Wednesday.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 0 percent of precincts reporting.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> 0 <ORGANIZATION> Dukakis </ORGANIZATION> 0 <ORGANIZATION> Gephardt </ORGANIZATION> 0 <ORGANIZATION> Jackson </ORGANIZATION> 0 <ORGANIZATION> Gore </ORGANIZATION> 0 <ORGANIZATION> Babbitt </ORGANIZATION> 0 <ORGANIZATION> Hart </ORGANIZATION> 0 Total 00
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Republican delegates:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>BC-NH-GOP-Deleg-Sum,100</HEAD>
<HEAD>02-16-88 XX:XX</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the delegates won by each candidate in the Republican presidential caucuses in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> on Wednesday.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 0 percent of precincts reporting. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> 0 <ORGANIZATION> Dole </ORGANIZATION> 0 <ORGANIZATION> Du </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pont </ORGANIZATION> 0 <ORGANIZATION> Kemp </ORGANIZATION> 0 <ORGANIZATION> Robertson </ORGANIZATION> 0 <ORGANIZATION> Haig </ORGANIZATION> 0 Total 00
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Finally, when the delegate numbers from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> are firm, they will be included in the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s national delegate count. That is summarized in the following table:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>AM-US-Deleg-Sum,200</HEAD>
<HEAD>02-16-88 XX:XX</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is the current breakdown of the presidential preference of the delegates to the Democratic and Republican national conventions. The preferences are based on delegates' public statements or binding state laws or party rules.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>DEMOCRATIC</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Total Changes Today 7 days 30 days <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON> 4 0 0 0 <ORGANIZATION> Dukakis </ORGANIZATION> 35.50 0 0 13 <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> 33 0 0 20 <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> 10.55 0 0 0 <ORGANIZATION> Hart </ORGANIZATION> 0 0 0 0 <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> 9.80 0 0 0 <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> 30 0 0 17 Others 0 0 0 0 Uncommitted 274.40 0 0 2
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Needed to nominate: 2,082 Total delegate votes: 4,162 Chosen thus far: 397.25 Yet to be chosen: 3,764.75
</TEXT>
<HEAD>REPUBLICAN</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Total Changes Today 7 days 30 days <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> 47 0 0 47 <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> 34 0 0 34 <ORGANIZATION> du </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pont </ORGANIZATION> 0 0 0 0 <ORGANIZATION> Haig </ORGANIZATION> 0 0 0 0 <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> 32 0 0 32 <ORGANIZATION> Robertson </ORGANIZATION> 8 0 0 8 <ORGANIZATION> Others </ORGANIZATION> 0 0 0 0 <ORGANIZATION> Uncommitted </ORGANIZATION> 8 0 0 8
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Needed to nominate: 1,139 Total delegate votes: 2,277 Chosen thus far: 129 Yet to be chosen: 2,148
</TEXT>
<HEAD>The AP</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880216-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-88 0210EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-NewHampshirePrimary Advisory   02-16 0179</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-New Hampshire Primary, Advisory</SECOND>
<HEAD>EDITORS:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> primary presidential elections take place today. Here is a tentative listing of stories we plan for Wednesday PMs. PM-NH Primary Roundup, by <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Rothberg </PERSON>. Our main story will wrap together results from both primaries. PM-NH Primary-Analysis. By <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mears </PERSON>. PM-NH Primary-Delegates. Who won how many; where the delegate races stand now. By <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Vernaci </PERSON>. PM-NH Primary-Republicans; reaction and impact. By <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> <PERSON> Witt </PERSON>. PM-NH Primary-Democrats; ditto, by <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Welch </PERSON>. PM-NH Primary Polls, by <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> Writer <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Langer </PERSON>. PM-NH Primary-Also Rans, results for the men whose candidacies may have been at stake in NH. -LRB- <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, du Pont, <PERSON> Haig </PERSON>. -RRB- PM-Onto the South. A look at the calendar ahead. In addition, we will transmit candidate separates, but the PM-NH Primary Republicans and PM-NH Primary Democrats are intended for use by editors who want a wrap up on reaction and a look-ahead on impact. PM-NH Quotebox. FYI, an advisory on table formats __ BC-New Hampshire-Tables __ on tabular material moved previously and is being repeated this cycle. The AP
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880216-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-88 0129EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Reactor-Roof     02-16 0479</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Reactor-Roof,0492</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reactor Building Roof Fractured by Malfunctioning Fan, Officials
Say</HEAD>
<DATELINE>RICHLAND, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The roof of the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Public Power Supply System No. 2 nuclear reactor building cracked because of a malfunctioning fan, but the mishap posed no danger, officials said Monday night. During a safety check of a circuit breaker Sunday night, an air supply fan came on inadvertently and within a few minutes had built enough pressure to pop about 200 bolts that fasten an interlocking grid of steel panels in the roof of the building, said <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Oxsen </PERSON>, operations director. The bolts are about a quarter-inch in diameter and an inch long, he said. No loud noise accompanied the fracture, and it was discovered only as a reactor operator noticed the bolts on the floor while making a routine hourly inspection less than an hour later, <PERSON> Oxsen </PERSON> said. The pressure pushed the roof upward a few inches, and when it fell back into place there were two seams in a rough T-shape, one seam about 40 feet long and the other about 25 feet long, said <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Mathews </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> WPPSS </ORGANIZATION>. The Nuclear Regulatory Commission was notified immediately, but there was no danger to workers or the public, Ms. <PERSON> Mathews </PERSON> said. The plant was shut down at the time. <PERSON> Oxsen </PERSON> said repairs could cost more than $ 1 million, `` a couple of hundred thousand dollars a day -LRB- for -RRB- up to a week.'' `` These -LRB- roof -RRB- panels, I should add, are designed to do exactly what they did,'' he said. `` These bolts are designed to pop'' when internal pressure reaches a specified level. He explained that the pressure system and roof design are intended to protect the reactor from inward collapse in the event of a tornado or other severe storm. He said an initial inspection indicated the only repairs needed would be to bolt the panels back into place and restore the foam, tar and gravel on top of the roof, which is about 120 feet off the ground. `` The whole building is pressurized,'' he said. <PERSON> Oxsen </PERSON> said similar accidents had occurred at other reactors, including the <LOCATION> Oyster </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> plant in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> about 19 or 20 years ago. He said he did not know the cost of repairs in that or other instances. The plant at the nearby <LOCATION> Hanford </LOCATION> nuclear reservation was shut down Saturday to fix leaks in two condenser tubes in the cooling system, so `` it was an opportune time to do some other maintenance,'' <PERSON> Oxsen </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> had directed <ORGANIZATION> WPPSS </ORGANIZATION> to check for potential problems in some <ORGANIZATION> Westinghouse </ORGANIZATION> circuit breakers, including the one linked to the errant supply fan, he said. Both exhaust fans and the other supply fan were turned off at the time, he said. <PERSON> Oxsen </PERSON> said the control panel initially failed to show the supply fan had come on, and an automatic cutoff system apparently failed as well.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880216-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-88 0035EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Israel-Violence Bjt   02-16 0749</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Violence, Bjt,0776</SECOND>
<HEAD>Palestinian Wounded In Jerusalem; Leaflets Call For `Day of Wrath'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KARIN LAUB</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Riot police battled Arabs in violent clashes in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, and leaflets distributed in the occupied territories called on residents to step up protests and attack Jewish settlements in a `` day of wrath.'' The leaflets, which appeared Monday, also asked Arabs to hold commercial strikes and stay home from their jobs today, <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> media said. In another development, the army on Monday questioned an Arab youth who said he and three other residents of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> village <LOCATION> Kfar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salem </LOCATION> were buried alive by <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers using a bulldozer after a riot Feb. 5. `` I am afraid. I thought I was going to die,'' said the youth, <PERSON> Abdel </PERSON> <PERSON> Latif </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahmoud </PERSON> <PERSON> Ishtiah </PERSON>, 19. `` I dream about it all the time.'' Relatives charge that 20 soldiers grabbed the four Palestinians after the riot, beat them, forced them to lie on the ground and then poured sand over them with a bulldozer. The four were unconcious when relatives rescued them after several minutes, according to villagers quoted in Israeli newspapers. Two soldiers have been detained in the case, and further detentions were expected, the army said. The <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>'s army commander, Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Amram </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitzna </PERSON>, who ordered the investigation, said that `` even in my worst dreams I would never imagine such a thing.'' Defense Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> on Monday attacked left-wing legislators who said soldiers had the right to refuse to obey orders they considered illegal. `` There is nothing more dangerous to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> than soldiers deciding what is bad and what is good, which orders to accept and which orders to reject,'' <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION> quoted <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> as saying. In interviews with <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> media, a number of soldiers have said they were troubled by orders to use beatings instead of bullets to quell Arab protests. In a related development, the Hadashot newspaper on Monday said three soldiers of the elite <PERSON> Golani </PERSON> brigade were sentenced to jail terms of at least 21 days for using excessive force against Palestinians. The army said it had no information on the case. In <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, riot police fired tear gas and rubber bullets in several locations Monday to disperse stone-throwing Arabs. Police spokesman <PERSON> Rafi </PERSON> <PERSON> Levy </PERSON> said police did not use live ammunition, but a border police officer told photographers that forces fired gunshots to subdue protesters in the <LOCATION> Anata </LOCATION> neighborhood. Officals at <LOCATION> Mukassad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> said they treated a 23-year-old resident of the city's <LOCATION> Shufat </LOCATION> refugee camp for gunshot wounds to the abdomen. The Arab-run <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said the man was shot during a clash at <LOCATION> Shufat </LOCATION>. It was the first report of bloodshed in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> since anti-Israeli protests began Dec. 8. In <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Sur </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bahir </LOCATION> neighborhood, border police fired tear gas to disperse Palestinians who erected roadblocks of twisted metal and burning tires. Residents said border police broke into homes. They showed reporters smashed windows, an overturned television set and the shattered glass panels of a china cabinet. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio said 21 Arabs were arrested in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> on Monday, bringing to 437 the number of demonstrators detained in the holy city since Dec. 8. During that period, 54 Arabs have been killed by Israelis in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>, according to <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> figures. In <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, members of the Gush Emunim settlement movement said they were printing flyers to be distributed in Arab areas. The leaflets contain threats that if the protests continue, Arabs might be ousted from the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> television said. In the political arena, Foreign Minister <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> on Monday called on his political rival, Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>, to work out a joint Israeli reaction to the new <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> peace initiative. `` It does n't look so good that when <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> envoys come here, it appears there are two governments,'' <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> told <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> television. `` With the arrival of -LRB- Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> -RRB- </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, despite our differences of opinion, we need to sit together,'' <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> is expected to visit the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> later this month to seek support for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> plan. The proposal calls for an international opening in April to launch direct talks on an interim solution for the occupied territories. Negotiations of a final settlement would begin in December, regardless of the outcome of the interim talks. <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> has accepted the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> plan while <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> opposes key elements as well as statements by <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> must be ready to trade land for peace.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880216-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-88 0040EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-FirstVotes 1stLd-Writethru a0669 02-16 0414</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-First Votes, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0669,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>Residents of Tiny Hamlet First to Vote in New Hampshire Primary</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: TOPS with results. Picks up 3rd graf pvs, ``In the ...''
^By EVA PARZIALE</NOTE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DIXVILLE NOTCH, N.H. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Midnight voters in the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> mountain hamlet of Dixville Notch gave Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Democrat <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> the winning votes in the nation's 1988 leadoff presidential primary. More often than not, Dixville's votes have been a bellwether for candidates seeking the presidential nomination. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> received 11 votes, <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> 4. In the rest of the Republican field, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> had 6, <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> 5, <ORGANIZATION> Pete </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> du </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pont </ORGANIZATION> 2, <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> 2, <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> 1. Among Democrats, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> received 3. No other Democrats received votes. `` In the primary, Dixville has a pretty good record in choosing the eventual candidates for each party,'' Town Clerk <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Tillotson </PERSON> said of past elections. `` It's just when we came to November, we'd frequently be in the wrong party. Since 1960, Dixville Notch voters have sided with the loser in all but three presidential elections. They picked the winners in 1972, when they favored <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> over <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> McGovern </PERSON>, and in 1980 and 1984, when they sided with <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. Few residents of the resort town in northern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> were willing to discuss in advance how they might cast their ballots. `` Because so many people are asking, the voters tend to not be committal, even amongst themselves,'' said <PERSON> Tillotson </PERSON>, a supporter of Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <PERSON> Tillotson </PERSON>'s father, <PERSON> Neil </PERSON>, came up with the idea in 1960 of making Dixville Notch the first town in the first primary state to cast ballots. Now 89 and the town moderator, the elder <PERSON> Tillotson </PERSON> _ who owns The <LOCATION> Balsams </LOCATION> resort hotel where the votes are cast and a surgical glove factory that is the town's only industry _ incorporated Dixville Notch that year to push the village into the national spotlight. Every four years, most of the candidates or their surrogates make their way five hours north of <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> to Dixville Notch, population 47, to woo the handful of voters living 15 miles south of the <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION> border. They are followed by more reporters, photographers and TV camera crews than there are residents in town. Residents take seriously their place in political history. They make sure to be in their voting booths by 11:45 p.m. so they can drop their ballots into the ballot box at the stroke of midnight.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880216-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-16-88 0143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     02-16 0893</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0928</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Redford </PERSON> says <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> is probably his best friend, and he'd like to do another movie with the blue-eyed actor. `` He's the greatest,'' <PERSON> Redford </PERSON> said in an interview with <ORGANIZATION> Esquire </ORGANIZATION> magazine. `` Not much I would n't do for him.'' The actor said he's awed by his co-star in `` Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid'' and `` The Sting.'' After a recent evening with <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>, he said, he found himself thinking, `` God, here's old <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>. ... He looks great, feels great, has lots of money, gives to great causes, he's in love with his wife, he races his cars when he wants to, makes a movie when he wants to, he's incredibly happy and still has that face that looks the way it did when he was 20. `` God, by the time we got home, I wanted to shoot myself.'' `` I'd love to make one more movie with him,'' <PERSON> Redford </PERSON> added. `` Just one more. The two of us.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Country music singer <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenwood </PERSON> turned the state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> chamber into a concert hall when he sang the national anthem and his hit, `` God Bless the <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION>,'' in a special ceremony. <PERSON> Greenwood </PERSON>'s performance won a standing ovation from senators during Monday's ceremony celebrating Presidents' Day. `` It gives me great honor to be here on the floor and to be able to sing this humble song that I wrote in 1983, which was more or less representative of my feelings about how I feel about all of us who call ourselves Americans,'' <PERSON> Greenwood </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> unanimously adopted a resolution to honor <PERSON> Greenwood </PERSON> and his career in country music. `` You keep the spirit going,'' Lt. Gov. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> said as he presented <PERSON> Greenwood </PERSON> with a plaque.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WEST PALM BEACH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Roxanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pulitzer </PERSON>'s version of her ill-fated entry into high society and her headline-making divorce has hit The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> best-seller list, but her ex-husband says he's too busy to read it. `` The Prize Pulitzer: The Scandal That Rocked <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> _ The Real Story'' reached No. 10 on the national non-fiction best-seller list Sunday. The book, which calls <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> a `` Buffet Society Babylon,'' is full of gossip about the rich and famous, from <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Bloomingdale </PERSON> to Barbra Streisand. Asked Monday about his former wife's literary success, <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> `` <PERSON> Peter </PERSON><PERSON> '' </PERSON> <PERSON> Pulitzer </PERSON> said, `` I have no comment on that. `` I have two young boys to bring up. That's a full-time job,'' said Pulitzer, contacted by telephone at his estate in <LOCATION> Okeechobee </LOCATION> in central <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. Pulitzer, who has remarried, said he has n't read the book, then hung up <PERSON> Roxanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pulitzer </PERSON> noted with satisfaction that bookstores on upscale Worth Avenue quickly sold out their first shipments of the book. `` The book is selling tremendously well there,'' she said, laughing. `` I do n't know who's buying it because everyone there says they're not going to read it.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>GARDEN GROVE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
