<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880212-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-88 2344EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Vietnam-Amnesty     02-12 0398</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Vietnam-Amnesty,0411</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reports Former Saigon Officials Released from Re-education Camp</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 150 former officers of the overthrown South Vietnamese government have been released from a re-education camp after 13 years of detention, the official <ORGANIZATION> Vietnam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> reported Saturday. The report from <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION>, monitored in <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION>, did not give specific figures, but said those freed Friday included an ex-Cabinet minister, a deputy minister, 10 generals, 115 field-grade officers and 25 chaplains. It quoted Col. <PERSON> Luu </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Ham </PERSON>, director of the Nam Ha camp south of <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION>, as saying all 700 former South Vietnamese officials who had been held at the camp now have been released. They were among 1,014 South Vietnamese who were to be released from re-education camps under an amnesty announced by the Communist government to mark Tet, the lunar new year that begins Feb. 17. The <ORGANIZATION> Vietnam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> report said many foreign journalists and a delegation from the <ORGANIZATION> Australia-Vietnam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Friendship </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> attended the Nam Ha release ceremony. It said Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Nguyen </PERSON> <PERSON> Vinh </PERSON> <PERSON> Nghi </PERSON>, former commander of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Third </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION>, and Col. <PERSON> Tran </PERSON> <PERSON> Duc </PERSON> <PERSON> Minh </PERSON>, former director of the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Infantry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Officers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, expressed `` gratitude to the government for its humane treatment in spite of the fact that most of them -LRB- detainees -RRB- had committed heinous crimes against the country and people.'' The prisoners had been held without formal charges or trial since <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> defeated the U.S.-backed South Vietnamese government in April 1975, ending the Vietnam War. Communist authorities had called the prisoners war criminals and said they had to learn how to become citizens of the new society. Small numbers had been released occasionally without publicity but the government announced last year that 480 political prisoners would be freed to mark National Day on Sept. 2. On Thursday, Vice Minister of Information <PERSON> Phan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quang </PERSON> said 1,014 would be released under the Tet amnesty. He reported a total of 150 prisoners would remain in the camps, which he said once held 100,000. `` Depending on their repentance, they will gradually be released within a short period of time,'' <PERSON> Quang </PERSON> said. He said many of the former inmates would return to their families in <LOCATION> Ho </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Minh </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, formerly the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vietnamese </LOCATION> capital of <LOCATION> Saigon </LOCATION>. The amnesties apparently are part of efforts by <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Nguyen </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Linh </PERSON> to heal internal divisions and improve <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s image abroad.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880212-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-88 0308EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-IowaFallout Bjt   02-12 0816</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iowa Fallout, Bjt,800</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iowa Caucus Results Shake Up New Hampshire Race</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GARY LANGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The ripples from the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> precinct caucuses are spreading to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, boosting winners and damaging losers in the final days before the nation's first primary, polls indicate. Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who was slipping in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> even before his third-place <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> finish, lost more ground in polls this week. Democratic third-place finisher <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> also lost support, but not as much. <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, meanwhile, has boosted the candidacies of Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> and Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, the Democratic and <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> winners, and has aided <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>'s surprise second-place <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> finisher, the polls indicate As recently as two weeks ago, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> commanded the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> GOP field. A <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News-New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> poll in the last week of January had him 22 percentage points over <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, the same place he'd held in polls since November and earlier But a crack appeared last week, when an <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News-Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> poll found <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s lead sharply diminished, to 7 percentage points. After <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>'s vote Monday, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> found the spread down to 4 percentage points: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 33, <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, 29. In a poll with an error margin of 6 percentage points, that amounted to a dead heat. Another survey, done for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION> this week by pollster <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Orren </PERSON>, had essentially he same result: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> 29, <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> 27. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday had it as <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> 35, <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> 27 _ still a big drop for the vice president. `` <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> got a very big kick out of <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>; more than that, there is some reluctance in the support for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Orren </PERSON> said Thursday. `` He's shown vulnerability, and that's sort of arousing doubts people have about him.'' `` The unanswered question is how far <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will fall,'' <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Morin </PERSON>, polling director for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. `` The expectation is that he will continue to drop. That's been the clear direction.'' If voters were leaving <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> before <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, it was not clear where they were going, <PERSON> Morin </PERSON> said. This week the chief gainers turned out to be <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, whose support was up to 10 percent in the <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> and CBS polls, from 6 percent last week and 4 percent two weeks ago. Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> held steady at 13 percent in the <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> poll, and fell from 16 percent to 12 percent in the <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> poll. Analysts said he now may be challenged by <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> for third place in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>. `` <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> was gaining last week. <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> ended that,'' said <PERSON> Morin </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>'s effect on the Democratic race probably is in the battle for second place, not first, pollsters said. <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, despite finishing third in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, maintained a strong lead in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> _ but he no longer had the huge 49 percent support indicated in an <ORGANIZATION> NBC-Wall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Street </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> poll in November. Three polls indicated a drop in support for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, to 36 percent in the <ORGANIZATION> ABC-Post </ORGANIZATION> survey this week from 41 percent last week; to 35 percent in the <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION>'s survey, from 38 percent last week; and to 38 percent in the <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> poll, from 40 percent in late January. A fourth new poll, however _ done for <ORGANIZATION> WBZ-TV </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> WRC-TV </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> _ said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' support had risen from 36 percent at the end of January to 44 percent this week. `` It's a big lead for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> no matter whose poll you're looking at _ and a strong one, too,'' said <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Alderman </PERSON>, chief of polling for <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> He said 58 percent of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' backers told <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> they supported him strongly. The win in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> transformed <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, who had single-digit support in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> as recently as last month. The <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> poll had him at 19 percent, up from 7 percent in late January; <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s poll put him this week at 22 percent, up from 13 percent last week The Globe had him at 18 percent, up from 8, and the <ORGANIZATION> WBZ </ORGANIZATION> poll had him at 17, up from 8 last month. Poll results were more mixed on <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>'s chief rival, Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, the second-place finisher in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>. He moved to 18 percent from 13 percent in <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s poll, to 13 from 11 in <ORGANIZATION> WBZ </ORGANIZATION>'s and fell in the <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION>'s, to 12 from 17 He held about even in the <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> poll, at 15 percent this week. Movement is taking place at the bottom as well as the top of the pack. Former Sen. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, who had 11 percent in the <ORGANIZATION> WBZ </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION> polls last week, fell to single-digit support after winning just 1 percent in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> and former <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON>, also a poor finisher in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, went from 7 percent in <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> poll last week to 4 percent this week
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880212-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-88 1456EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SuitDropped     02-12 0363</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Suit Dropped,0372</SECOND>
<HEAD>Parents Of Slain Man Drop Lawsuit Against Mexican Drug Lord</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FORT WORTH, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The parents of a student slain when he apparently stumbled onto a reputed Mexican drug lord's party have dropped a $ 2 billion lawsuit against the man, saying a trial would rekindle painful memories. <PERSON> Alberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Radelat </PERSON>, a dental student, and journalist <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> were tortured and killed in February 1985 in <LOCATION> Guadalajara </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, and authorities there said they believed the men were executed because they were mistaken for drug agents. On Jan. 29, Dr. <PERSON> Felipe </PERSON> <PERSON> Radelat </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Ana </PERSON>, filed a wrong death action against reputed drug lord <PERSON> Rafael </PERSON> <PERSON> Caro </PERSON> <PERSON> Quintero </PERSON>, whom authorities have blamed for the deaths. The younger <PERSON> Radelat </PERSON> and <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> had apparently entered a restaurant where <PERSON> Quintero </PERSON> was holding an after-hours party. A witness told the Radelats that their son and <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> were stabbed with icepicks and switchblades before they were dumped in a crude grave outside <LOCATION> Guadalajara </LOCATION>, where their bodies were found in June 1985. On Thursday, <PERSON> Radelat </PERSON> said he dropped the suit a week after filing it because it would revive memories the family had tried to put behind them. `` My wife had settled down, and this brought it all up again,'' he said. `` We do n't want any more bad memories. It was a sad experience. I hope no one ever has to go through it.'' <PERSON> Quintero </PERSON> was among nine people indicted Jan. 6 by federal officials in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> in connection with the <ORGANIZATION> deaths </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> agent <PERSON> Enrique </PERSON> <PERSON> Camarena </PERSON> and his pilot, who were killed about a week after <PERSON> Radelat </PERSON> and <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> were slain. <PERSON> Quintero </PERSON> is in a Mexican jail charged with all four deaths; <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> authorities indicted him and the others in <PERSON> Camarena </PERSON>'s death in an effort to bring them to justice if Mexican authorities do n't prosecute them <PERSON> Radelat </PERSON> said he filed the lawsuit because the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government had not indicted <PERSON> Quintero </PERSON> in the other deaths. `` We were disappointed they -LRB- <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials -RRB- indicted <PERSON> Quintero </PERSON> just for the drug agent, not the other Americans,'' <PERSON> Radelat </PERSON> said. `` We wanted to do this -LRB- suit -RRB- not so much for the money but just to do justice for our son.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880212-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-88 1637EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-PeanutSupports     02-12 0155</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Peanut Supports,150</SECOND>
<HEAD>Peanut Price Supports Will Go Higher This Year</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Price supports for peanuts grown under 1988 quotas will be $ 615.27 per ton, an increase of $ 7.80 from last year, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said Friday. Deputy Secretary <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> said the increase was required by a formula in the law which takes rising production costs into consideration. The annual quota is set at a level equal to the estimated quantity of peanuts that will be needed for domestic edible uses, seed and related purposes. Production of non-quota peanuts, which can be grown for peanut oil and meal, and for export, will be supported at $ 149.75 per ton, unchanged from last year, <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> said. In setting the support for non-quota peanuts, officials are required to consider certain factors, including the demand for oil and meal, the expected prices for other vegetable oils and meals, and the foreign demand for peanuts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880212-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-88 1642EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-Haig'sCampaign     02-12 0610</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Haig's Campaign,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Haig Endured Failing Campaign With Wit and Verbosity</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Haig Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The end was bitter, his helmet dented from the combat of the campaign, and true to form, retired four-star Gen. <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> reined in his dark horse quest for the presidency in a pugnacious mood. <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> made clear that his new objective was not to seek the keys to the White House for himself but to deny them to Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. From the very beginning, when he announced, `` I'm throwing my helmet into the ring,'' the 63-year-old former secretary of state never rose above the low single digits in public opinion polls. He stopped campaigning in the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> caucuses in frustration that his message and his personality had not taken hold. `` This is hangover day,'' <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> said, when the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> votes were counted and he ended up with less than 3 percent of the vote in the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> field. Throughout his campaign, <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> described himself as `` the darkest of dark horses.'' His political picture never brightened, perhaps because he failed to find a way to do what he himself said he had to do to win. `` I've learned the secret of life ... It's in marketing,'' <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> told a <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> audience early in the campaign. `` And that's what I'm trying to do today _ marketing.'' After <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> had trouble finding a silver lining. `` I'm in it to the bitter end and that bitter end may be the inability to raise enough money to stay in it,'' he said. <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> has been supreme allied commander in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, and White House chief of staff as well as secretary of state and presidential contender. In all of those roles, he demonstrated a vivid _ sometimes pungent _ grasp of the English language. When his hopes for <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> were still high, <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> told audiences: `` I think it's important that a city slicker like <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Haig </PERSON>, who's been abroad and lived in our nation's capital perhaps too long, does n't come out here and tell agricultural experts how to suck eggs. Complaining about the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's supply-side economic policies, he said they bore the mark of `` ideological religiosity.'' He himself described some of his more obscure references and word combinations as `` Haigspeak.'' <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> sensed a measure of public reluctance to put a former four-star general in the White House and his first television commercials were designed to counter that. One listed the names of the dozen generals who have served as president, asserting that none of the nation's eight wars began in their administrations. ` Ive led troops in battle, seen the horror of war, I know the imperative of peace,'' the former general said, asserting the need to elect a president with `` strength, skill and understanding.'' He said the idea of a nuclear-free world is `` bizarre,'' asserting that <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> nuclear weapons can only be detered by other nuclear weapons, not eliminated. When the stock market crashed last October, <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> had sown the seeds of disaster. `` Overnight the famous bull market of the eighties was eaten alive by the most infamous bear market in our financial history,'' he said, attributing the market's nose dive to `` a pervasive lack of confidence in our government's ability to deal with budget and trade deficits.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was a preoccupation for much of the <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> campaign. <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> tried repeatedly to pin down the vice president on what advice he gave to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in the Iran-Contra scandal. `` Were you in the cockpit,'' <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> said in typically colorful language, `` or were you on an economy ride in the back of the plane?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880212-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-88 1644EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-CagedHens     02-12 0159</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Caged Hens,0162</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Rules Caging Hens Is Not Cruelty</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STROEMMEN, Norway (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A court ruled Friday that an egg producer who kept his 2,000 hens in small cages was not guilty of cruelty to animals, as alleged by animal rights activists. `` The verdict is a great relief. It would have been too much to be found guilty of cruelty to my 2,000 hens,'' <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> <PERSON> Wettre </PERSON> was quoted as saying by the national <ORGANIZATION> NTB </ORGANIZATION> news agency after his acquittal. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prevention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cruelty </ORGANIZATION> to Animals claimed that by keeping hens in small cages, <PERSON> Wettre </PERSON> violated national legislation to allow animals' natural development and behavior. But the court found that <PERSON> Wettre </PERSON> observed Norwegian regulations stipulating that a hen should have at least 112 square inches of cage space in which to live. <ORGANIZATION> NSPCA </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Toralf </PERSON> <PERSON> Metveit </PERSON> was quoted as saying: `` I'm disappointed but not surprised. The society was ordered pay $ 15,600 in court costs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880212-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-88 1518EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Kemp'sStrategy     02-12 0654</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Kemp's Strategy,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kemp Strategy To Crack Top Three in N.H. Primary</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Kemp-Robertson Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JONATHAN KELLOGG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NASHUA, N.H. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Strategists for <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s presidential campaign say <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s poor showing in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, coupled with <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s tough-talking ads against <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, could put <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> in the running for the Republican nomination. Before last Monday's <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> caucuses, <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> had been on a roll in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, using an effective advertising campaign and the endorsement of the influential Concord Monitor to help broaden support. But even as his bid to become the conservative alternative to <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> took shape, the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> congressman faced the possibility of being swept out of the race by former television evangelist <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>. Using his second-place finish in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> came in fourth _ <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> was trying to move <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> aside and take the mantle of true conservative. A poll of <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hampshire </ORGANIZATION> voters by the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION> Thursday night indicated <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> had drawn even with <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> among potential <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> voters in next Tuesday's primary. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> campaign manager, says the <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION> congressman wants to finish second or third in a cluster with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>. `` We want to be in the 28-30-31 percent range with them,'' <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> said. He conceded that <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> can not afford another fourth-place finish, saying, `` We need to do well here so we can raise money and continue on to the South. We need to have at least a close third here.'' <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> spent most of the week in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> making his case at coffee klatches, before high school students and in speeches to the party faithful. He is hopeful that his energetic person-to-person style and strong conservative message will make him the conservative alternative. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON> is <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s chief campaign strategist. `` What you saw tonight,'' <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON> said after <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> spoke before 800 Republicans in <LOCATION> Nashua </LOCATION> earlier this week, `` was <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> making an appeal to the heart and soul of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> vote in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>. We consider that to be the largest single vote in the Republican primary electorate.'' <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s third-place finish in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> presented <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> with a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> opportunity he never thought he would see. `` It was a lucky break that the guy who got severely wounded in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> was <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, -LRB- someone -RRB- we never thought we could beat in the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> primary.'' <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s strategy had focused on <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> because, as <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON> put it, <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> is `` extraordinarily vulnerable in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> because of his predilection for raising taxes, his four different positions on oil import fees and his wanting to cut Social Security in a state that has an elderly, Republican electorate.'' `` We learned a lesson last month in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON> said. `` The news media was interested in Bush-Dole, <PERSON> Dole-Bush </PERSON>, Bush-Dole, almost as if they were the only two variables. `` The lesson was that by being very specific on issues in a tough, hard-hitting way, we could pry the door open to get people to take a look at <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> is now running ads in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> saying he is the best alternative to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> and noting that he has already beaten <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>. But <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON> says <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> ca n't repeat his showing in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> because of an inherently negative message that wo n't be effective in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>. `` For all the voters who may be more comfortable with the gloom and doom and dour message of <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, that we're going to hell in a handbasket, there are many more who will respond to a positive conservative message,'' <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON> said. `` I'm a conservative,'' <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> told a living room full of Republicans in <LOCATION> Milford </LOCATION>. `` But I'll tell you what, folks, some things need money spent on them. We've got to shelter the homeless; we've got to feed and clothe and take care of people who ca n't take care of themselves ... and we've got to have a strong defense.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880212-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-88 1648EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-VolcanoCrash     02-12 0184</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Volcano Crash,0189</SECOND>
<HEAD>Seven Killed As Plane Crashes Into Chilean Volcano</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANTIAGO, Chile (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A chartered plane crashed into the snowy flank of a volcano in southern <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION>, killing all seven people aboard, air force rescue officials said Friday. The chartered, two-engine <ORGANIZATION> Piper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seneca </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> II </ORGANIZATION> was reported missing late Wednesday, after taking off from <LOCATION> Temuco </LOCATION>, a city 415 miles south of <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION>. Rescue helicopters were unable to find and reach the crash site, on the <LOCATION> Villarica </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Volcano </LOCATION> about 60 miles south of <LOCATION> Temuco </LOCATION> in the Andes mountains, until Friday noon. `` The crew and passengers died in the accident,'' said a communique issued by the air force's rescue service. <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION> television stations broadcast images of the crash site which showed the plane's charred remains strewn across an icy slope 6,900 feet above sea level. The victims were <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Comandari </PERSON>, president of a Santiago-based bank, <ORGANIZATION> Banco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> del </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacifico </ORGANIZATION>; his 13-year-old son and a 12-year-old daughter; the bank's general manager, <PERSON> Eran </PERSON> <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON>; his wife and 1 -LCB- - year-old son; and pilot <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON>, son of a well-known Chilean diplomat The cause of the crash was under investigation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880212-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-88 1523EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-HomelandCoup     02-12 0540</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Homeland Coup,0560</SECOND>
<HEAD>90 Soldiers Arrested After Coup Attempt In Tribal Homeland</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MMABATHO, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 90 soldiers have been arrested and face possible death sentences stemming from a coup attempt in <LOCATION> Bophuthatswana </LOCATION>, leaders of the tribal homeland said Friday. Rebel soldiers staged the takeover bid Wednesday, detaining homeland President <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> <PERSON> Mangope </PERSON> and several top Cabinet officials for 15 hours before South African soldiers and police rushed to the homeland, rescuing the leaders and restoring them to power. At least three soldiers and two civilians died in the uprising. <LOCATION> Bophuthatswana </LOCATION>'s Minister of Justice <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Godfrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Mothibe </PERSON> told a news conference that those arrested have been charged with high treason and if convicted could be sentenced to death. He said the accused were to appear in court Monday. All those arrested in the coup attempt have been described as young troops, the most senior being a warrant officer. During the coup rebel soldiers installed as head of state Rocky Malebane-Metsing, leader of the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Progressive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peoples </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. Malebane-Metsing escaped capture and his whereabouts remained unknown, officials said. Several unsubstantiated reports said he fled to nearby <LOCATION> Botswana </LOCATION>. Warrant Officer M.T.F. <PERSON> Phiri </PERSON>, described by <PERSON> Mangope </PERSON> as one of the coup leaders, was arrested Friday in <LOCATION> Mmabatho </LOCATION>, capital of the nominally independent homeland, officials said. <LOCATION> Bophuthatswana </LOCATION>, which has a population of 1.7 million spread over seven separate land blocks, is one of 10 tribal homelands in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. About half of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s 26 million blacks live in the homelands, none of which are recognized internationally. <PERSON> Hennie </PERSON> <PERSON> Riekert </PERSON>, the homeland's defense minister, said South African troops were to remain in <LOCATION> Bophuthatswana </LOCATION> but will not become a `` permanent presence.'' <LOCATION> Bophuthatswana </LOCATION>'s Foreign Minister <PERSON> Solomon </PERSON> <PERSON> Rathebe </PERSON> defended <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s intervention. `` The fact that ... the South African government -LRB- was invited -RRB- to assist in this drama is not anything new nor peculiar to <LOCATION> Bophuthatswana </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Rathebe </PERSON> said. `` But why <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, one might ask? Because she is the only country with whom <LOCATION> Bophuthatswana </LOCATION> enjoys diplomatic relations and has formal agreements.'' <PERSON> Mangope </PERSON> described the mutual defense treaty between the homeland and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> as `` similar to the <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> agreement,'' referring to the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> military alliance. He did not elaborate. Asked about the causes of the coup, <PERSON> Mangope </PERSON> said, `` We granted people freedom perhaps ... to the extent of planning a thing like this.'' The uprising began around 2 a.m. Wednesday when rebel soldiers took <PERSON> Mangope </PERSON> and his top ministers from their homes to the national sports stadium. On Wednesday evening, South African soldiers and police stormed the stadium, rescuing <PERSON> Mangope </PERSON> and his Cabinet. South African President P.W. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> and three of his <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> ministers flew to <LOCATION> Mmabatho </LOCATION> late Wednesday and met with <PERSON> Mangope </PERSON>, the homeland's only president since it was declared independent in 1977. The South African government has said, without producing evidence, that the outlawed <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> may be linked to the coup. The <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION>, based in <LOCATION> Lusaka </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Zambia </LOCATION>, dismissed the claims and said <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s actions showed that it maintains tight control over the homeland governments. The group seeks to topple the <LOCATION> Pretoria </LOCATION> government. The African National Congress and other anti-government organizations consider the homelands part of an apartheid system designed to fragment the black majority and deny them political rights in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880212-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-88 1525EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Panama-Resignation     02-12 0502</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama-Resignation,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Diplomat, Citing ``Corruption,'' Breaks with Noriega</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A senior <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> diplomat broke with his country's military-dominated government Friday, declaring he could no longer in good conscience serve a regime stained by `` corruption, illigitimacy and dishonesty.'' <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Chewning </PERSON> <PERSON> Fabrega </PERSON>, minister counselor at <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s mission to the <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION> here, told a news conference his decision to resign was triggered by a speech he was ordered to give at an <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> ceremony on Wednesday <PERSON> Chewning </PERSON> had said in the speech that the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration was attempting to overthrow the Panamanian government and was waging a campaign of `` moral and economic aggresion'' against <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. `` These remarks were not written by me, nor did they represent the way I feel or think,'' <PERSON> Chewning </PERSON> said, adding that they were prepared by <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s ambassador to the <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Leyton </PERSON>, and the Panamanian <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Chewning </PERSON>'s resignation followed an extraordinary week in which Panamanian strongman <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> was indicted by two federal grand juries in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> on drug-related charges and was accused by former associates before a congressional panel of engaging in an array of corrupt activities. Speaking through a translator at <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> headquarters, <PERSON> Chewning </PERSON> said: `` My conscience, my dignity and my deep religious beliefs prevent me from continuing to be used as an instrument of a government characterized by corruption, illigitimacy and dishonesty.'' <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> mission had no statement on <PERSON> Chewning </PERSON>'s resignation, and Ambassador <PERSON> Leyton </PERSON> was not available for comment. <PERSON> Gabriel </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> ambassador who has been lobbying in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> against <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s rule, said <PERSON> Chewning </PERSON>'s resignation proves there are `` worthy individuals'' in the <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> government who refuse to continue supporting <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. <PERSON> Chewning </PERSON> said he did not resign on the day of the <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> ceremony because he felt it was inappropriate, given the nature of the event. The occasion was the formal incorporation of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> into an international agreement designed to guarantee the neutrality of the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> once the waterway comes under Panamanian control in the year 2000. In his speech Wednesday, <PERSON> Chewning </PERSON> had said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, in pursuing a hostile attitude toward the Panamanian government, was attempting to evade its treaty pledge to relinquish control over the canal. On Friday, he said he believes the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will faithfully comply with its commitments. <PERSON> Chewning </PERSON> said he was not seeking political asylum in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and was confident he would not be the target of reprisals by the Panamanian government. He will be ineligible to remain in this country because his visa allowing him to remain here is valid only so long as he maintained his status as a diplomat. He said he has about a month to decide what to do in the future. <PERSON> Chewning </PERSON>, 46, served in the <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> post for a year and a half. He previously had worked in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>, its embassy in <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION> and its embassy in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> accredited to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government. He and his wife are expecting their fourth child.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880212-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-88 1650EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-DuPont     02-12 0415</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Du Pont,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Du Pont Blasts Dole And Kemp In Bid To Keep His Candidacy Alive</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANCHESTER, N.H. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> du </PERSON> <PERSON> Pont </PERSON>, struggling to keep his presidential candidacy alive in the final days before the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> primary, lashed out Friday at fellow Republicans <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>. At a news conference in this snowbound city, du <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> said: `` What <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> says seems to depend on what state he's in.'' He also called <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> `` a big spender.'' With the departure of <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> from the Republican presidential race on Friday, <PERSON> du </PERSON> <PERSON> Pont </PERSON>, a former governor of <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>, ranks at the bottom of the five-candidate field. He conceded that to stay in the race after Tuesday's primary `` you have to do well. You have to start beating somebody.'' <PERSON> Du </PERSON> <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> had kind words for <PERSON> Haig </PERSON>, a former secretary of state, calling him `` a credit to this process'' and saying `` he brought a little spice to the debate.'' But he had no kind words for anyone else. Asked about his prospects, du <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> said, `` All of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>'s in flux now that the vice president is in a free fall.'' Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s standing as the clear front-runner among <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hampshire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republicans </ORGANIZATION> has eroded since his embarrassing third-place finish in the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> precinct caucuses on Monday. <PERSON> Du </PERSON> <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> called the upcoming days `` the four most volatile of this campaign.'' Focusing on <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, du <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> said, `` I do n't think you can go to <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> and talk to farmers about how many dollars you've appropriated and then come to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> and avoid it.'' He also said the <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> senator had told Iowans that he would not pledge to oppose any tax increases and then came to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> and said he would veto a tax increase. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> voters have a reputation for solid opposition to tax increases. <PERSON> Du </PERSON> <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> also said that <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> had supported an import fee on foreign oil in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> but `` in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> he says he'll veto it.'' As for <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, a congressman from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, du <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> said, `` He's a big spender. In fact he's got a spending record in the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> that is even more liberal than <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON> -LRB- a <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> congresswoman from <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> -RRB- or <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> -LRB- the <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> senator who is running for the Democratic presidential nomination -RRB-.'' `` So, I do n't think on Tuesday the people of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> are going to fall for a snow job,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880212-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-88 1746EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Bangladesh     02-12 0359</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bangladesh,0372</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ershad Saddened by Election Day Deaths</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By FARID HOSSAIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DHAKA, Bangladesh (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Hussain </PERSON> <PERSON> Muhammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Ershad </PERSON> said Friday he was saddened by the violence in this week's local elections that left at least 100 people dead, but he added he was heartened by a heavy voter turnout. In a message released by the official <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION> news agency, <PERSON> Ershad </PERSON> said he was sorry at `` the loss of valuable lives and injuries caused to a number of people in some isolated incidents of violence.'' At least 100 people were killed and hundreds injured in clashes among supporters of rival candidates on Wednesday. The voting was to elect representatives to more than 4,370 village councils. Opposition party leaders <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Hasina </PERSON> and <PERSON> Khaleda </PERSON> <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> have blamed <PERSON> Ershad </PERSON> for the violence and accused the government of failure to maintain law and order. The women have led a series of strikes and protests since Nov. 10 to try to oust <PERSON> Ershad </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hasina </PERSON>, daughter of assassinated president <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Mujibur </PERSON> <PERSON> Rahman </PERSON>, and Mrs. <PERSON> Zia </PERSON>, wife of another slain president, have called for general strikes Saturday and Sunday to protest the violence and renew the call for <PERSON> Ershad </PERSON>'s resignation. <PERSON> Ershad </PERSON> on Friday appealed for `` tolerance and patience'' to make the process of democracy a success. `` The enthusiasm and spontaneous participation of the people in the polls was the manifestation of peoples' firm confidence in the constitutional process and democratic norms,'' <PERSON> Ershad </PERSON>'s statement said. According to government reports, voter turnout was as high as 80 percent in areas where there was no violence. <PERSON> Poling </PERSON> was postponed in at least 2,500 of 21,000 voting centers because of election-day clashes. A new date for polling had not yet been set. The list of successful candidates is expected to be ready in about a week, government officials say. <PERSON> Ershad </PERSON>, 58, assumed power in a bloodless coup in 1982. He won election to the presidency in 1986 in balloting the opposition contends was rigged. In an effort to appease the opposition, he dissolved <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> and called for new elections Feb. 3. The opposition called for a boycott, contending the balloting would not be free and fair.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880212-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-88 1754EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-Artukovic     02-12 0606</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Artukovic,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Son Challenges Justice Department To Admit It Wrongly Extradited
Father</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The son of a man who lived nearly 40 years in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and then died in a <LOCATION> Yugoslav </LOCATION> prison after being convicted of Nazi war crimes challenged <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials Friday to admit they wrongly extradited his father to a communist court. <PERSON> Rad </PERSON> <PERSON> Artukovic </PERSON>, in a 135-page report submitted to the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, said the department used fraudulent evidence to send his father, <PERSON> Andrija </PERSON> <PERSON> Artukovic </PERSON>, to face a `` sham trial'' in <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> two years ago. The elder <PERSON> Artukovic </PERSON> died last month at age 88 while awaiting execution in a <LOCATION> Yugoslav </LOCATION> prison. `` The only way the <PERSON> U. </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> government could get him was through fraud,'' <PERSON> Artukovic </PERSON> told a news conference before leaving for <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> to join a federal courthouse vigil in honor of his late father. He said his father has become a hero to people from his native <LOCATION> Croatia </LOCATION>, now a part of <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Andrija </PERSON> <PERSON> Artukovic </PERSON>, who was a cabinet minister in the Nazi puppet state of <LOCATION> Croatia </LOCATION>, was called `` Butcher of the <LOCATION> Balkans </LOCATION>'' by the Yugoslav government and accused of ordering the deaths of thousands of people. During his trial, he was described as as overseer of a grisly network of concentration camps. <PERSON> Rad </PERSON> <PERSON> Artukovic </PERSON>, 39, said his father was minister of the interior, had no military responsibilities and ordered no deaths. He said his father was not mentally competent to stand trial. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials had declared him senile and legally blind when he was extradited. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s criminal division, said a copy of <PERSON> Artukovic </PERSON>'s report had been received by the Office of Special Investigations and was being reviewed by investigators who handle allegations of war crimes. `` He's done a marvelous job of defending his father's reputation, but the matter was dealt with in the courts,'' <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> said <PERSON> Artukovic </PERSON> said in the report that both his father's extradition and the trial in <LOCATION> Zagreb </LOCATION> relied mainly on false testimony from <PERSON> Bajro </PERSON> <PERSON> Avdic </PERSON>, a man who claimed to have been a military escort for his father. The report said <PERSON> Avdic </PERSON> was not an escort and was not in the places he claimed to be when atrocities allegedly occurred. It also claims he made up the killings attributed to <PERSON> Artukovic </PERSON>. `` I ask the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to go into court and revoke the order they obtained through fraud,'' <PERSON> Artukovic </PERSON> said, accusing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials of collusion with the communist government in <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Artukovic </PERSON> said he hopes for a renunciation of the extradition to invalidate the Yugoslav trial. <PERSON> Artukovic </PERSON> said he and two of his four sisters visited their father during his imprisonment in <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> but his mother, <PERSON> Ana </PERSON>, never saw her husband after he was extradited. The family lives in <LOCATION> Seal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. His father for many years had been a bookkeeper for a <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> construction company The younger <PERSON> Artukovic </PERSON>, a stock trader, said he worked for two years to research the report on what he said was false evidence against his father and is sending copies to members of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Foreign Relations Committee. He said the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> went along with whatever was given it by the <LOCATION> Yugoslavian </LOCATION> government but could not collect enough evidence to deport his father. <PERSON> Artukovic </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> accused his father of war crimes to neutralize him as a Croatian political leader. He said most other members of the Croatian wartime cabinet were executed as war criminals but Allied officials found no evidence against him and he was allowed to live freely in <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> and later the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880212-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-88 1753EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Kidnap-Wreck     02-12 0503</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Kidnap-Wreck,0521</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Charged With Kidnapping Four</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Storm Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOWLING GREEN, Ky. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Slippery, ice-covered roads and snarled traffic helped four people escape from a man who abducted them at gunpoint and took their cars, police said Friday. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, 43, of <LOCATION> Logansport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, was arraigned on four counts of kidnapping in <ORGANIZATION> Warren </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> after his arrest in the cases early Friday. He was being held without bond in the <LOCATION> Warren </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jail </LOCATION>, police said. He also was wanted in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> on various charges, including assaulting a police officer in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, kidnapping, theft and drug-related charges, said Trooper <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Strode </PERSON>. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> was traveling on foot and was not armed when he was arrested, <PERSON> Strode </PERSON> said. Strode said <PERSON> Erwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Quirand </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Knoxville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, and a 17-year-old girl from <LOCATION> Sumter </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, jumped from a northbound car Thursday on Interstate 65 while traffic was slowed past the site of a multi-vehicle car-truck pileup in which one person was killed. They ran to police and said they had been kidnapped. <PERSON> Quirand </PERSON> said he had been kidnapped him and his car taken Wednesday at a <LOCATION> Knoxville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, grocery store. He told WBKO-TV in Bowling Green that his abductor said he was `` running for his life.'' The juvenile said she and her car were taken Tuesday. The man sped away but crashed the car four miles north of the accident scene, <PERSON> Strode </PERSON> said. The man then stopped a pickup truck driven by <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Eidson </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, 18, of Bowling Green, and asked <PERSON> Eidson </PERSON> and his passenger, <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Bell </PERSON>, 21, of <LOCATION> Richardsville </LOCATION>, for a ride to get a wrecker. But when they pulled into a service station, <PERSON> Eidson </PERSON> said, the man pulled out a gun and said: `` I'm in a little trouble with the law. Keep going.'' The man then took the wheel but slid off an icy road into a ditch, <PERSON> Eidson </PERSON> said. The three walked to a house and the man tried to persuade someone there to give him a ride to <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>, but was turned down, <PERSON> Eidson </PERSON> said. He said the three then went to the home of <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Comer </PERSON>, where the man asked to borrow their tractor to pull the truck out of the ditch. Mrs. <PERSON> Comer </PERSON> refused, <PERSON> Eidson </PERSON> said, and the gunman then demanded her car and ripped a telephone cord out of the wall. `` I told them the keys were in the car,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Comer </PERSON> said. Her car slid off another road, and <PERSON> Bell </PERSON> and <PERSON> Eidson </PERSON> escaped while pushing it out of a ditch, <PERSON> Eidson </PERSON> said. The gunman later wrecked that car and police lost his trail until running across him early Friday about six miles south of Bowling Green, <PERSON> Strode </PERSON> said. He had been described by <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> authorities as suicidal and wanting vengeance against police officers, <PERSON> Strode </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Eidson </PERSON> said he was afraid during the incident. `` I did n't really know'' what the man would do, he said. `` But he had a gun, you know, and he kept pulling it out.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880212-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-88 1538EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-TerrorTrial Bjt   02-12 0743</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Terror Trial, Bjt,0767</SECOND>
<HEAD>Guerrilla Leader Abu Nidal, Two Followers, Convicted in Airport
Massacre</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By FRANCES D'EMILIO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A court on Friday convicted fugitive guerrilla leader <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Nidal </PERSON> and two of his Palestinian followers in the 1985 grenade and rifle attack that killed 16 people in a crowd of holiday travelers at <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>'s airport. <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Nidal </PERSON> and another fugitive, <PERSON> Rashid </PERSON> <PERSON> el-Hamieda </PERSON>, were sentenced to life in prison. The only defendant in custody, <PERSON> Mahmoud </PERSON> <PERSON> Ibrahim </PERSON> <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON>, was given a 30-year term. More than 80 people were injured in the Dec. 27, 1985 assault on the check-in counters of <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION> and the Israeli carrier <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Al </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Leonardo </LOCATION> da Vinci airport. Four Americans were killed, including an 11-year-old girl on a trip with her family to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. <PERSON> El-Hamieda </PERSON>, described as a top lieutenant in <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Nidal </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Fatah </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, was accused along with <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Nidal </PERSON> of organizing the attack. Neither he nor <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Nidal </PERSON> took part in it. The assault occurred at the same hour as a similar strike at <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>'s airport, also blamed on <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Nidal </PERSON>'s followers. Four people, including two terrorists and an American, died in the <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> attack, and 47 people were injured. Two surviving Palestinian terrorists were convicted of murder by a <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> jury and sentenced to life in prison. The <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> jury of two judges and six civilians apparently heeded a plea for leniency for <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON>, the only survivor of the four-man commando team. He could be released on parole in a little less than 15 years. Earlier in the day, his court-appointed lawyer said he could not possibly ask for acquittal for the 20-year-old <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON>, who admitted his guilt. Instead, the lawyer, <PERSON> Epifanio </PERSON> <PERSON> Ales </PERSON>, reread for the jury <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON>'s own statements about his childhood in a refugee camp in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, his parents' death in an Israeli bombing and his taking up of arms when he was 10 years old <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON> was `` a patriot who wanted a Palestine free of the Israelis,'' <PERSON> Ales </PERSON> said in his plea for mercy. The lawyer asked the jury to remember that Italian courts, for years, were merciful to men who had killed adulterous wives and their lovers under a now vanishing `` crime of honor'' standard. Ales said defending the confessed terrorist was `` an anguished task'' and that it was particularly painful to listen to the testimony of an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> journalist about how his daughter, 11-year-old <PERSON> Natasha </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON>, died in the gunfire. <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON>, news editor for The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, described in court how he threw himself and the girl to the terminal floor in a futile attempt to shield her from the bullets. According to the trial indictment, four Israeli security guards fired back, killing three of the four members of the attack squad and wounding <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON>. The steel-barred holding cage for <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON> was empty on Friday. He chose to stay in his prison cell, exercising his right under Italian law not to attend his trial. He only attended court Dec. 15, the trial's opening session. The trial was based largely on hours of pre-trial statements by <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON>, who told investigators that the terrorists were trained in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s Syrian-controlled <LOCATION> Bekaa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> and took their orders from headquarters in <LOCATION> Damascus </LOCATION>, the Syrian capital. Investigators believed el-Hamieda provided the terrorists with their weapons and gave them final instructions during several meetings in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, then checked out of a hotel and fled <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> at virtually the same hour the raid was launched. Prosecutor <PERSON> Francesco </PERSON> <PERSON> Deleo </PERSON> had requested conviction and life sentences for the three defendants, saying <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON>'s statements made clear the airport strikes were linked to several terrorist attacks in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> this decade. <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> does not have capital punishment. <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Nidal </PERSON>'s group has been blamed for more than 100 attacks across <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> since 1972. He split from <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> in 1973. An international arrest warrant has been issued for <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Nidal </PERSON>, whose real name is <PERSON> Sabri </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Banna </PERSON>. <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Nidal </PERSON> is a nom de guerre which means `` father of the struggle.'' He originally based his group in <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> but was expelled and is believed to operate out of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, with his followers trained in <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>. Lawyers for both fugitive defendants asked the jury for acquittal for lack of evidence. They said they would appeal the verdict. <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON>'s lawyer said he had not yet decided about an appeal. All three defendants were charged with massacre and with illegal possession of arms.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880212-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-88 1758EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Nicaragua     02-12 0281</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nicaragua,0289</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government to Stage Joint Military-Civil Defense Exercises</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By FILADELFO ALEMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAGUA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 15,000 reservists, civilian militia, police and regular army troops will take part soon in civil defense and military maneuvers, the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> newspaper Barricada announced Friday. <PERSON> Barricada </PERSON> said the civilians and military personnel will participate in the exercises in <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION> and its surrounding region. It did not specify on what day they would begin. The maneuvers come at a time of high tension in the city of <LOCATION> Masaya </LOCATION>, about 20 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>, where demonstrators opposing the government's obligatory military draft clashed with <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> supporters and police on Monday and Tuesday. Club-wielding <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> demonstrators first sought to quash the protests in the streets. Police later intervened to break up the demonstrations, and Interior Minister <PERSON> Tomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Borge </PERSON> arrived to monitor the situation. The exercises `` are of a routine nature and are called for under the annual plans to prepare the people in defense,'' <PERSON> Barricada </PERSON> said. It added that participating Sandinista police would patrol `` centers of greater criminal incidences.'' The Regional Committee of the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, the government party, told Barricada the maneuvers would involve peasant militia, factory and neighborhood reservists and mass organizations. Neighborhood <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committees </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Youth </ORGANIZATION> organization members also will take part. Sandinista army troops staged maneuvers at the same time last year, but few civilians participated. <PERSON> Borge </PERSON> referred indirectly to the <PERSON> Masaya </PERSON> demonstrations Thursday, saying he had instructed Sandinista police to act `` with profound respect for the physical integrity of those who provoke them, but at the same time with energy and without vacillation in order to impede vandalism and disorder in the country.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880212-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-88 1840EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BullfrogCounty     02-12 0485</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bullfrog County,0501</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bullfrog County, Population Zero, Is Illegal, Judge Says</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GOLDFIELD, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Empty Bullfrog County, created from scrubland in a bid to assure the state of federal dollars should the government build a nuclear dump in <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>, violates the state constitution, a judge has ruled. Judge <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Zenoff </PERSON> said Thursday the county stretched its legal limits `` every which way,'' and left too many constitutional issues `` hanging in the air.'' <LOCATION> Nye </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, from which unpopulated <LOCATION> Bullfrog </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> was carved, had challenged the 1987 <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION>'s creation of the state's 18th county. <PERSON> Zenoff </PERSON>, a former state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> justice brought in to hear the case, issued the ruling after less than 30 minutes of oral arguments in district court. <PERSON> Zenoff </PERSON> said the governor's authority to appoint three commissioners for the county ran `` contrary to the democratic process,'' and contributed to its failure to provide representative government. `` I can not in good conscience uphold this law,'' he said. `` Obviously, we're very pleased,'' said <LOCATION> Nye </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> District Attorney <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunleavy </PERSON>. `` It confirms what we've been saying all along. As far as I'm concerned, <LOCATION> Bullfrog </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> is dead and it should be.'' Attorney <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Daykin </PERSON>, representing the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Bullfrog </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, said it would be up to the <ORGANIZATION> Legislative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> to decide whether to appeal <PERSON> Zenoff </PERSON>'s ruling to the state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. The commission's next meeting is scheduled for Wednesday. `` We usually do n't accept defeat in the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION>,'' said commission Chairman <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobsen </PERSON>. Legislators created the county out of a 144-square-mile chunk of <LOCATION> Nye </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> as a way of giving the state control over federal funds available for the proposed. <LOCATION> Yucca </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> in southern <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> is one of three sites under consideration. Had Bullfrog County been selected, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government would have had to compensate the state-run county an estimated $ 8 million to $ 25 million a year, officials said. `` Personally, I hope the Legislature does n't appeal it because it's brought enough embarrassment to <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> and should be allowed to lay in peace,'' <PERSON> Dunleavy </PERSON> said. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> needs to rethink its approach to the problem.'' <LOCATION> Nye </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> stands to lose revenue should the new county remain on the books. Gov. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON>, who signed the law creating the county into effect, issued only a brief statement upon learning of <PERSON> Zenoff </PERSON>'s decision `` This apparently resolves the <LOCATION> Bullfrog </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> issue unless the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> chooses to appeal,'' he said. <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Zupon </PERSON>, the governor's press secretary, said <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> `` has always said he'll abide by the court's decision. He's not a party to the suit and he has n't said anything about whether he thinks it should be appealed.'' <LOCATION> Nye </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> challenged the county's creation on 37 different legal grounds in a 92-page brief. Its major complaint was <LOCATION> Bullfrog </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>'s failure to provide representative government. <PERSON> Zenoff </PERSON> agreed, saying it was not `` answerable to the people.'' Among other things, he said the law made no provisions for a judicial district or legislative representation for the county.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880212-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-88 1552EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-US-Mideast Bjt   02-12 0699</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-Mideast, Bjt,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shultz Sets Middle East Peace Trip</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> will go to the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> in two weeks to try to promote two-stage negotiations between <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> on <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> self-rule. A brief <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> announcement Friday said <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> would make the trip at the end of the month `` for the purpose of advancing the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> peace process.'' Other <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said he would set out for the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> about 24 hours after returning from Feb. 21-23 talks in <LOCATION> Mosocw </LOCATION> and visit <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and possibly <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> plans to remain in the area until he joins President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> for a summit meeting with the leaders of the 15 <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> countries in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> beginning March 2. The Soviets have been notified in advance that <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> intends to sound out Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> about an international peace conference that would be a backdrop for <LOCATION> Arab-Israeli </LOCATION> negotiations. Their <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> talks will center mostly on prospects for a treaty to sharply reduce <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet long-range nuclear missiles and for a withdrawal of the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> after an occupation of more than eight years. <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> and <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> have registered their reluctance to having the Soviets play a prominent role in a <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> settlement. But <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>'s King <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> wants the participation of all the big powers, including <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. According to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and other sources who declined to be identified, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> will advance a two-step plan that would open negotiations in April between <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and a mixed <LOCATION> Jordanian-Palestinian </LOCATION> delegation and then resume in December to work on an overall Middle East settlement. All options, including statehood for the <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION>, would be open at that point. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> reaffirmed Monday night in a meeting with <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> foreign policy experts that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> approach to a final settlement is based on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> trading territory for peace. That could cause severe political problems for <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> because many of his supporters are against relinquishing land the Arabs lost to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> in the 1967 Six-Day War. At the same time, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has not endorsed <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> statehood. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s formula, outlined in a 1982 speech and still <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy, proposed linking the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said flatly that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> `` will not support the establishment of an independent Palestinian state'' in the territories and would also `` not support annexation or permanent control by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>'s trip is designed to show a commitment to aiding the 1.5 million Palestinian Arabs who live on the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> and to ending violence in the Israeli-held territories. Sources said <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>'s overriding goal was to promote negotiations between <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Arabs </LOCATION>, possibly in the framework of a <LOCATION> Mideast </LOCATION> peace conference. They stressed that the framework was incidental to holding direct talks on the <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> issue and that all approaches to getting the two sides to the table would be considered. The peace conference idea has drawn objections from <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>, but it has the support of Israeli Foreign Minister <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>, and possibly King <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>. On his last visit to the region in October, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> said he understood why <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> would be reluctant to hold negotations in a way that gave the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> a chance to play an influential role. The Soviets generally side with the Arabs in their dispute with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and do not have diplomatic relations with <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>. About 96 percent of the residents of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> are Palestinian Arabs. Jewish settlers who were banned from the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> during <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>'s control from 1948 to 1967 have established villages, religious schools and synagogues there. <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> has accused the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration of being hopelessly one-sided toward <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. But a recent <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomatic emissary, <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Habib </PERSON>, was reported to have detected a `` positive'' attitude in talks with the king in <LOCATION> Amman </LOCATION>. Assistant Secretary of State <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> returned from the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> on Thursday and reported to <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> on his meetings with leaders of <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Saudia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, as well as with British and French officials.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880212-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-88 1844EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-AfricaAid     02-12 0145</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Africa Aid,0148</SECOND>
<HEAD>Italian Charity Sends Millions For African Drought Relief</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880212-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-88 1845EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-WheatGrowers     02-12 0194</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Wheat Growers,190</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wheat Growers Want Fewer Production Curbs in 1989</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government should ease back on acreage controls for the 1989 wheat crop, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wheat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Growers </ORGANIZATION> said Friday. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Johannsen </PERSON>, association president, said greater acreage should be permitted so the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> can keep filling a growing export demand. For the last two years, wheat farmers have been required to idle 27.5 percent of their base acreage in order to qualify for federal supports. The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is to announce the 1989 wheat program by June 1. <PERSON> Johannsen </PERSON>, a wheat farmer from <LOCATION> Bayard </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Neb. </LOCATION>, said the association wants the acreage reduction be held to no more than 20 percent. <PERSON> Johannsen </PERSON> said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat stockpiles are expected to drop by 30 percent this season, the largest annual decline in more than 20 years. A 1989 acreage reduction of less than 20 percent could be justified if <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> maintains its current export subsidy programs, he said. `` Since we do n't know what will happen after the November elections, our market outlook is somewhat cloudy, thus making it more difficult to forecast export sales opportunities,'' <PERSON> Johannsen </PERSON> said in a statement.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880212-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-88 1849EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-PLOShip 1stLd-Writethru a0665 02-12 0796</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-PLO Ship, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0665,0816</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israelis Arrive For Voyage, But Still No Ship</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 1 graf after 2nd graf to UPDATE with report that
Israeli union threatening boycott; SUBS grafs 19-20 pvs, `Antonis
Dalakogiorgis, ...,' with 5 grafs to UPDATE with comments from
union leader. PICKS up 21st graf pvs, `Shipping sources ...</NOTE>
<HEAD>With AM-Israel, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN RICE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATHENS, Greece (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A member of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> arrived in <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> on Friday to join Palestinian deportees in a planned voyage back to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, but two organizers said they still had not obtained a ship. The president of <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>'s main seamen's union, meanwhile, said <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> agents had used threats and pressure to block the PLO-sponsored trip that would carry 130 Palestians deported by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> port of <LOCATION> Haifa </LOCATION>. Union leader <PERSON> Antonis </PERSON> <PERSON> Dalakogiorgis </PERSON> also revealed that the <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Officers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> had warned they would boycott Greek vessels if Greek seamen continued backing the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> effort. The `` journey of return'' is designed to focus attention on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s use of deportations to punish Palestinians in the territories it captured in the 1967 Arab-Israeli war. Parliament member <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Miari </PERSON> appeared at a news conference at an <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> hotel alongside <PERSON> Bassam </PERSON> <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharif </PERSON>, the chief spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>. <PERSON> Miari </PERSON>, a member of the left-wing Progressive List for Peace, said he was told that `` the Israeli government will put on trial all those who participate in the trip,'' and said there were moves in Parliament to strip him of his parliamentary immunity. Two other parliament members, <PERSON> Tawfiq </PERSON> <PERSON> Zaiad </PERSON> and <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Biton </PERSON>, were among 11 Israelis who arrived Thursday in <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> to join the voyage when it stops there. About 20 Israelis plan to make the trip. The trip is modeled after the voyage of the Exodus, which tried to take Jewish refugees to <LOCATION> Palestine </LOCATION> in 1947 but was turned back by British authorities. <PERSON> Miriam </PERSON> <PERSON> Algazi </PERSON>, one of the Israelis who arrived in <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> on Thursday, also took part in the Exodus voyage. At the news conference, <PERSON> Miari </PERSON> backed `` the right of the deported Palestinians people to return to their homeland.'' He said he hoped the trip would `` open a new window for just peace in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>.'' But there was increasing doubt that any ship would be able to sail soon, although the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> has gathered hundreds of deportees, observers and journalists in <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> to take part. Two members of the nine-member voyage steering committee in <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> that the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> did not have a firm contract to charter a vessel because several companies had backed out of tentative commitments. `` We do n't have a boat yet,'' said <PERSON> Abdul-Jawad </PERSON> <PERSON> Saleh </PERSON>, the deported mayor of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Bireh </LOCATION>. `` There is not a concrete ship as of this moment,'' said another member of the steering committee who insisted on anonymity. The voyage was initially scheduled to start on Tuesday, but the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> diplomatic representative in <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Fouad </PERSON> <PERSON> Al-Bittar </PERSON>, said Thursday the voyage had been delayed because `` many'' shipowners had backed away from contracts. However, he then promised that the voyage would begin by early Saturday morning from <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>'s main <LOCATION> Piraeus </LOCATION> harbor, saying a boat had been found. `` We are still insisting that the boat will sail,'' <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharif </PERSON> said Friday. He reaffirmed the time schedule given by <PERSON> Bittar </PERSON>, but added an element of uncertainty. `` I'm sure we will find _ and have found, according to Mr. <PERSON> Bittar </PERSON> _ a brave captain'' for the voyage, he said. <LOCATION> Piraeus </LOCATION> harbor authority officials said at noon Friday the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> had not submitted documents legally required 24 hours before a ship can be brought in or out. <PERSON> Dalakogiorgis </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Panhellenic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Merchant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seamen </ORGANIZATION>, said that `` Israeli agents'' had threatened Greek shipping companies and individual seamen about the voyage. `` Seamen working on ships that the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> might have chartered received telephone threats from the Israelis and shipping companies were also under intense pressure from them,'' <PERSON> Dalakogiorgis </PERSON> said. `` I personally received threatening phone calls, threatening my life, not to proceed with this,'' <PERSON> Dalakogiorgis </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Dalakogiorgis </PERSON> distributed copies of a telex from the <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Officers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> saying `` we would have no choice but to boycott Greek vessels in Israeli ports'' if the voyage goes as planned. No one from the Israeli union, headquartered in <LOCATION> Haifa </LOCATION>, could be found for comment Friday. Shipping sources in <LOCATION> Piraeus </LOCATION>, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the captain of the first ship chartered to make the voyage had also been threatened. They said that <PERSON> Zannes </PERSON> <PERSON> Kouloumbis </PERSON> of the Maltese-flagged <PERSON> Silver </PERSON> <PERSON> Paloma </PERSON> was warned of an Israeli attack during the voyage and told his life was in danger. The ship's owners, who operate a regular ferry service to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, dropped out.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880212-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-88 1600EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-US-SovietCollisions Bjt   02-12 0845</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-Soviet Collisions, Bjt,830</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Navy Warships Bumped By Soviet Vessels Off Black Sea Coast</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NORMAN BLACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> warships, under orders to assert international navigation rights, were deliberately bumped by two Soviet warships on Friday after moving within 12 miles of <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Black </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> coastline, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> said No one was injured and damage to the two ships was described as light. But the administration immediately lodged a strong protest with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> ambassador here, saying the vessels had done nothing provocative and were operating in accord with international law. `` As Secretary of State -LRB- <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> said just a week ago, we are prepared to deal with the best and worst of Soviet behavior,'' said <PERSON> Rudolph </PERSON> <PERSON> Boone </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. `` We intend to continue exercising our rights under international law. The Soviets are obligated to comply with their international commitments.'' <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> officials said during a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> briefing there was no question that the cruiser USS Yorktown and destroyer USS Caron had been struck deliberately by a Soviet frigate and a smaller coastal patrol boat, respectively. The Soviet warships broadcast a warning beforehand, saying they were authorized `` to strike your ship with one of ours,'' said Capt. <PERSON> Gerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON>, a top aide to the chief of naval operations. The two Soviet ships then closed almost simultaneously on the American vessels, `` which were, as we would say in the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, shouldered out of the way,'' <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON> added. The Yorktown and <PERSON> Caron </PERSON> maintained their course and speed despite the bumping, eventually steaming farther from the Soviet coast, <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON> said. `` The latest report I have now is that both ships are operating routinely in the <LOCATION> Black </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> as planned,'' he said. <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON> and other <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials said they could not recall a similar incident of deliberate bumping during operations in the <LOCATION> Black </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>. The Soviets strongly protested a similar deployment by the same two ships in March 1986, but did nothing at the time to physically interfere with their passage. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> claimed Friday the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> ships violated its border, ignored warnings `` and dangerously maneuvered in Soviet territorial waters.'' `` It was a routine passage and we were doing nothing provocative at all ...,'' <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON> countered. `` We view -LRB- this -RRB- with considerable concern.'' According to Cmdr. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Schiff </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> lawyer who appeared with <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON>, the Yorktown and <PERSON> Caron </PERSON> were operating off the <LOCATION> Crimean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> peninsula </LOCATION> in what the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> calls its `` assertion of rights'' program _ an effort to periodically steam through contested waters to emphasize freedom of navigation on the high seas. Unlike the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, which claims a three-mile territorial limit, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> claims a 12-mile limit along its coast, <PERSON> Schiff </PERSON> explained. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will accept such a claim, but any country claiming 12 miles `` must allow for innocent passage by the ships of all nations,'' he said. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> tries to insist that foreign ships stick to specified sea lanes when making an innocent passage, something it has no right to do, the lawyer said. `` So what our ships were doing there was exercising that right of innocent passage,'' <PERSON> Schiff </PERSON> said. He noted that Soviet intelligence-gathering ships routinely operate within five miles of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> coastline. According to the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, Friday's incident began with the Yorktown and <PERSON> Caron </PERSON> steaming eastward, parallel to each other and about three miles apart, past the <LOCATION> Crimean </LOCATION> peninsula. The <PERSON> Caron </PERSON> was about seven miles off the shoreline and the Yorktown about 10. The two ships had been shadowed by three Soviet vessels and Soviet reconnaissance aircraft ever since entering the <LOCATION> Black </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> through the Turkish Straits on Wednesday. At about 11 a.m. local time Friday _ or 3 a.m. EST _ <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON> said the Soviets broadcast the following warning to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ships: `` Soviet ships have orders to prevent violation of territorial waters. I am authorized to strike your ship with one of ours.'' The <PERSON> Caron </PERSON> responded: `` I am engaged in innocent passage, consistent with international law.'' When neither the <PERSON> Caron </PERSON> or Yorktown changed course, a Krivak-class frigate moved up on the <LOCATION> Yorktown </LOCATION> and a Mirka-class patrol vessel moved on the <PERSON> Caron </PERSON>, `` grazing'' the left sides of the each, <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON> said. American naval forays into the <LOCATION> Black </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> _ each of which must be approved by the president _ are normally ordered at least once a year for two reasons, said <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials who asked not to be named. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> ships are expected to monitor Soviet military operations, frequently employing electronic listening gear, and to assert the right of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warships to navigate through those waters. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> considers the <LOCATION> Black </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> as its own `` lake'' _ even though it is only one of several nations bordering the sea's waters _ and maintains a large naval fleet there According to <PERSON> Boone </PERSON>, Undersecretary of State <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Armacost </PERSON> called in Soviet Ambassador <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> Dubinin </PERSON> Friday morning to `` lodge a strong protest.'' <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON>, who is scheduled to meet with his Soviet counterpart next month, also intends to protest the <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> action, <PERSON> Boone </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880212-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-88 1850EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Soviet-Rights     02-12 0336</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet-Rights,0346</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Union Counterattacks U.S. Over Human Rights</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Kremlin accused the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> on Friday of spreading `` malicious slanders'' about human rights in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has violations of its own. The official news agency <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> carried an interview with <PERSON> Alexei </PERSON> <PERSON> Glukhov </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> in which he discussed the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s annual report on human rights around the world. The report, released Wednesday in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, said the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> government gave its people greater freedom and showed more tolerance toward dissenters in 1987. But it said an all-powerful secret police force remained unchecked. <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said the report `` again contains malicious slanders against the socialist countries, including the U.S.S.R.'' <PERSON> Glukhov </PERSON>, first deputy head of the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>'s Directorate for Humanitarian and Cultural Issues, accused the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> of making the allegations to speed up ratification of the intermediate-range nuclear weapons treaty, which is making its way through the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> signed the treaty in December. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Glukhov </PERSON> noted, conducted a prison amnesty and introduced new rules on emigration and immigration last year. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> ignored these steps and relied on faulty information for its report, he charged. `` Much of the specific information contained in that report is clearly drawn from unclean sources,'' he said, citing what he said was an exaggerated figure of 400 political prisoners in the <LOCATION> U.S.S.R. </LOCATION> `` Obviously, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> again lacks simple objectivity and simple truthfulness in the evaluations,'' he said. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> would like to know why the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has political prisoners, sentences minors to death and prosecutes clergymen for anti-war activities, <PERSON> Glukhov </PERSON> said. `` The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> side is far from the measure of openness and self-criticism demonstrated by the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> on that issue,'' he said, referring to human rights. Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> are to discuss human rights at a meeting in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> on Feb. 21-23.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880212-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-88 1920EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-US-NuclearTests     02-12 0282</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-Nuclear Tests,280</SECOND>
<HEAD>White House Sees Progress in Verifying Test-Ban Treaties</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
